<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16000759</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Survey of bovine enterovirus in biological and environmental samples by a highly sensitive real-time reverse transcription-PCR.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3536</StartPage><EndPage>3543</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3536-43</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Animal enteroviruses shed in the feces of infected animals are likely environmental contaminants and thus can be used as indicators of animal fecal pollution. Previous work has demonstrated that bovine enterovirus (BEV) present in bovine feces contaminates waters adjacent to cattle herds and that BEV-like sequences are also present in shellfish and in deer feces from the same geographical area. However, little information is available about the prevalence, molecular epidemiology, and genomic sequence variation of BEV field isolates. Here we describe an optimized highly sensitive real-time reverse transcription-PCR method to detect BEV RNA in biological and environmental samples. A combination of the amplification procedure with a previously described filtration step with electropositive filters allowed us to detect up to 12 BEV RNA molecules per ml of water. The feasibility of using the method to detect BEV in surface waters at a high risk of fecal pollution was confirmed after analysis of water samples obtained from different sources. The method was also used to study the prevalence of BEV in different cattle herds around Spain, and the results revealed that 78% (78 of 100) of the fecal samples were BEV positive. BEV-like sequences were also detected in feces from sheep, goats, and horses. Nucleotide sequence analyses showed that BEV isolates are quite heterogeneous and suggested the presence of species-specific BEV-like variants. Detection of BEV-like sequences may help in the differentiation and characterization of animal sources of contamination.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jim&#xe9;nez-Clavero</LastName><ForeName>Miguel Angel</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Environmental Virology, Departamento de Biotecnolog&#xed;a, Instituto Nacional de Investigaci&#xf3;n y Tecnolog&#xed;a Agraria y Alimentaria (INIA), Ctra. A Coru&#xf1;a Km 7.5, 28040 Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Escribano-Romero</LastName><ForeName>Estela</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mansilla</LastName><ForeName>Carmen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xf3;mez</LastName><ForeName>Nuria</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>C&#xf3;rdoba</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roblas</LastName><ForeName>Neftal</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ponz</LastName><ForeName>Fernando</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ley</LastName><ForeName>Victoria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xe1;iz</LastName><ForeName>Juan-Carlos</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>GENBANK</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>AY831684</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831685</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831686</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831687</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831688</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831689</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831690</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831691</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831692</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831693</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831694</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831695</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831696</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831697</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831698</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831699</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831700</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831701</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831702</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831703</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831704</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831705</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831706</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831707</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831708</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831709</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831710</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831711</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831712</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831713</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831714</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831715</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831716</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831717</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AY831718</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D023362">Evaluation Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000829" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals, Domestic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002417" MajorTopicYN="N">Cattle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029650" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus, Bovine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004784" MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental Monitoring</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005243" MajorTopicYN="N">Feces</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005374" MajorTopicYN="N">Filtration</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005618" MajorTopicYN="N">Fresh Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008969" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Sequence Data</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012680" MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity and Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017422" MajorTopicYN="N">Sequence Analysis, DNA</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014876" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water Pollution</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16000759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1168977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.7.3536-3543.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">71/7/3536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbaszadegan, M., P. Stewart, and M. Le Chevallier. 1999. A strategy for detection of viruses in ground water by PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 65:444-449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC91045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9925566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen, A. A. 1978. Cross reaction between enterovirus and South African Territories 15 foot-and-mouth disease virus. Am. J. Vet. Res. 39:59-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">204230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergh, O., K. Y. Borsheim, G. Bratbak, and M. Heldal. 1989. High abundance of viruses found in the aquatic environment. Nature 340:467-468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2755508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch, A. 1998. Human enteric viruses in the water environment: a minireview. Int. Microbiol. 1:191-196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10943359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapron, C. D., N. A. Ballester, J. H. Fontaine, C. N. Frades, and A. B. Margolin. 2000. Detection of astroviruses, enteroviruses, and adenovirus types 40 and 41 in surface waters collected and evaluated by the information collection rule and an integrated cell culture-nested PCR procedure. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 66:2520-2525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC110573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10831432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clesceri, L. S., A. E. Greenberg, and A. D. Eaton (ed.). 1998. Standard methods for the examination of water and wastewater, 20th ed. American Public Health Association, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felsenstein, J. 1993. PHYLIP (phylogeny inference package version 3.5c). Department of Genetics, University of Washington, Seattle. (Distributed by the author.)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goens, S. D., S. Botero, A. Zemla, E. Zhou, and M. L. Perdue. 2004. Bovine enterovirus type 2. Complete genomic sequence and molecular modeling of the reference strain and wild type isolate from endemically infected US cattle. J. Gen. Virol. 85:3195-3203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15483232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimenez-Clavero, M. A., C. Fernandez, J. A. Ortiz, J. Pro, G. Carbonell, J. V. Tarazona, N. Roblas, and V. Ley. 2003. Teschoviruses as indicators of fecal contamination of water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 69:6311-6315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14532098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katzenelson, E., B. Fattal, and T. Hostovestky. 1976. Organic flocculation: an efficient second step concentration method for the detection of viruses in tap water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 32:638-639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC170320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King, A. M. Q., F. Brown, P Christian, T. Hovi, T. Hyypi&#xe4;, N. J. Knowles, S. M. Lemon, P. D. Minor, A. C. Palmemberg, T. Skern, and G. Stanway. 2000. Picornaviridae, p. 657-673. In M. H. V. Van Regenmortel, C. M. Fauquet, D. H. L. Bishop, C. H. Calisher, E. B. Carsten, M. K. Estes, S. M. Lemon, J. Maniloff, M. A. Mayo, D. McGeoch, C. R. Pringle, and R. B. Wickner (ed.), Virus taxonomy. Seventh report of the International Committee for the Taxonomy of Viruses. Academic Press, New York, N.Y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowles, N. J., and I. T. Barnett. 1985. A serological classification of bovine enteroviruses. Arch. Virol. 83:141-155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2578783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, S., K. Tamura, and M. Nei. 2004. MEGA3: integrated software for molecular evolutionary genetics analysis and sequence alignment. Brief. Bioinform. 5:150-163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15260895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ley, V., J. Higgins, and R. Fayer. 2002. Bovine enteroviruses as indicators of fecal contamination. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:3455-3461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC126779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12089028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ley, V., and M. A. Jimenez-Clavero. March. 2004. Method to identify environmental contamination by detecting enteric viruses. U.S. patent application 2004/0058312 A1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ley, V., and M. A. Jimenez-Clavero. February. 2004. Method to identify environmental contamination by detecting enteric viruses. European patent publication EP 336 663 A3 (application 03380032.7).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maluquer de Motes, C., P. Clemente-Casares, A. Hundesa, M. Martin, and R. Girones. 2004. Detection of bovine and porcine adenoviruses for tracing the source of fecal contamination. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 70:1448-1454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC368300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15006765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy, F. M., G. A. Smith, and J. S. Mattick. 1999. Molecular characterization of Australian bovine enteroviruses. Vet. Microbiol. 68:71-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10501163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNally, R. M., J. A. Earle, M. McIlhatton, E. M. Hoey, and S. J. Martin. 1994. The nucleotide sequence of the 5&#x2032; non-coding and capsid coding regions of two bovine enterovirus strains. Arch. Virol. 139:287-299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7832636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehnert, D. U., K. E. Stewien, C. M. Harsi, A. P. Queiroz, J. M. Candeias, and J. A. Candeias. 1997. Detection of rotavirus in sewage and creek water: efficiency of the concentration method. Mem. Inst. Oswaldo Cruz 92:97-100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9302419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez, I. I., I. I. Hermann, P. R. Hazelton, and K. M. Coombs. 2000. A comparative analysis of Freon substitutes in the purification of reovirus and calicivirus. J. Virol. Methods 90:59-67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11011081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minor, P. D. 1992. The molecular biology of polio vaccines. J. Gen. Virol. 73:3065-3077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1335021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallanch, M. A., and R. P. Ross. 2001. Enteroviruses: polioviruses, coxsackie, echoviruses and newer enteroviruses, p. 723-775. In D. Knipe and P. Howley (ed.), Fields virology, 4th ed. Williams and Wilkins Publishers, Baltimore, Md.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pianetti, A., W. Baffone, B. Citterio, A. Casaroli, F. Bruscolini, and L. Salvaggio. 2000. Presence of enteroviruses and reoviruses in the waters of the Italian coast of the Adriatic Sea. Epidemiol. Infect. 125:455-462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2869620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11117971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilipenko, E. V., V. M. Blinov, L. I. Romanova, A. N. Sinyakov, S. V. Maslova, and V. I. Agol. 1989. Conserved structural domains in the 5&#x2032;-untranslated region of picornaviral genomes: an analysis of the segment controlling translation and neurovirulence. Virology 168:201-209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2536978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schvoerer, E., F. Bonnet, V. Dubois, G. Cazaux, R. Serceau, H. J. Fleury, and M. E. Lafon. 2000. PCR detection of human enteric viruses in bathing areas, waste waters and human stools in southwestern France. Res. Microbiol. 151:693-701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11081583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schvoerer, E., M. Ventura, O. Dubos, G. Cazaux, R. Serceau, N. Gournier, V. Dubois, P. Caminade, H. J. Fleury, and M. E. Lafon. 2001. Qualitative and quantitative molecular detection of enteroviruses in water from bathing areas and from a sewage treatment plant. Res. Microbiol. 152:179-186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11316372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiroki, K., T. Ishii, T. Aoki, Y. Ota, W.-X. Yang, T. Komatsu, Y. Ami, M. Arita, S. Abe, S. Hashizume, and A. Nomoto. 1997. Host range phenotype induced by mutations in the internal ribosomal entry site of poliovirus RNA. J. Virol. 71:1-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC191017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8985316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siafakas, N., P. Markoulatos, and G. Stanway. 2002. Molecular classification of coxsackie A viruses on the basis of the 5&#x2032;-UTR: structural and evolutionary aspects. J. Mol. Evol. 55:638-652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12486523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner, M. A., V. R. Racaniello, G. Dunn, J. Cooper, P. D. Minor, and J. W. Almond. 1989. New model for the secondary structure of the 5&#x2032; non-coding RNA of poliovirus is supported by biochemical and genetic data that alsoshow that RNA secondary structure is important in neurovirulence. J. Mol. Biol. 207:379-392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2547075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey, M. D., and B. L. Jones. 1979. Concentration of poliovirus from tap water using positively charged microporous filters. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 37:588-595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanway, G., T. Hovi, N. J. Knowles, and T. Hyypi&#xe4;. 2002. Molecular and biological basis of picornavirus taxonomy, p. 17-24. In B. L. Semler and E. Wimmer (ed.), Molecular biology of picornaviruses. ASM Press, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, J. D., D. G. Higgins, and T. J. Gibson. 1994. CLUSTAL W: improving the sensitivity of progressive multiple sequence alignment through sequence weighting, position-specific gap penalties and weight matrix choice. Nucleic Acids Res. 22:4673-4680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC308517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7984417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyn-Jones, A. P., and J. Sellwood. 2001. Enteric viruses in the aquatic environment. J. Appl. Microbiol. 91:945-962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11851802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz, A., and E. F. Kaleta. 2003. Evaluation of virucidal activity of three commercial disinfectants and formic acid using bovine enterovirus type 1 (ECBO virus), mammalian orthoreovirus type 1 and bovine adenovirus type 1. Vet. J. 166:67-78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12788019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zell, R., and A. Stelzner. 1997. Application of genome sequence information to the classification of bovine enteroviruses: the importance of the 5&#x2032;- and 3&#x2032;-nontranslated regions. Virus Res. 51:213-229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9498619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, A. Q., J. R. Smith, and G. W. Burgess. 1990. Blocking enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay for detection of antibodies against bovine enterovirus. Vet. Microbiol. 21:275-281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2154878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>