<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">15870352</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Construction of a cloning system for the mass production of a virus-binding protein specific for poliovirus type 1.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2608</StartPage><EndPage>2615</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2608-15</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>In our previous study, virus-binding proteins (VBPs) demonstrating the ability to strongly bind poliovirus type 1 (PV1) were recovered from a bacterial culture derived from activated sludge. The isolated VBPs would be useful as viral adsorbents for water and wastewater treatments. The VBP gene of activated sludge bacteria was isolated, and the cloning system of the VBP was established. The isolation of the VBP gene from DNA libraries for activated sludge bacteria was achieved with the colony hybridization technique. The sequence of the VBP gene consisted of 807 nucleotides encoding 268 amino acids. Fifteen amino acid sequences were retrieved from 2,137,877 sequences by a homology search using the BLAST server at the National Center for Biotechnology Information. The protein encoded in the isolated genome was considered to be a newly discovered protein from activated sludge culture, because any sequences in protein databases were not perfectly matched with the sequence of the VBP. It was confirmed that Escherichia coli BL21 transformed by pRSET carrying the isolated VBP gene could extensively produce the VBP clones. Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) revealed that the VBP clone exhibited the binding ability with intact particles of PV1. The equilibrium binding constant between PV1 and VBP in the ELISA well was estimated to be 2.1 x 10(7) (M(-1)), which also indicated that the VBP clones have a high affinity with the PV1 particle. The VBP cloning system developed in this study would make it possible to produce a mass volume of VBPs and to utilize them as a new material of the specific adsorbent in several technologies, including virus removal, concentration, and detection.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sano</LastName><ForeName>Daisuke</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Graduate School of Engineering, Tohoku University, Aoba, Sendai 980-8579, Japan. sano@water.civil.tohoku.ac.jp</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Omura</LastName><ForeName>Tatsuo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011991">Receptors, Virus</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011994">Recombinant Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012722">Sewage</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000595" MajorTopicYN="N">Amino Acid Sequence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001483" MajorTopicYN="N">Base Sequence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003001" MajorTopicYN="N">Cloning, Molecular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004926" MajorTopicYN="N">Escherichia coli</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015723" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Library</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008969" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Sequence Data</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017955" MajorTopicYN="N">Poliovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011991" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000096" MajorTopicYN="N">biosynthesis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011994" MajorTopicYN="N">Recombinant Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000096" MajorTopicYN="Y">biosynthesis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012722" MajorTopicYN="N">Sewage</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15870352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1087535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.5.2608-2615.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">71/5/2608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arkowitz, R. A., and M. Bassilana. 1994. Protein translocation in Escherichia coli. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 1197:311-343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7819269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellini, M. S., Z. Deyl, G. Manetto, and M. Kohlickova. 2001. Determination of apparent binding constants of drugs by capillary electrophoresis using &#x3b2;-cyclodextrin as ligand and three different linear plotting methods. J. Chromatogr. A 924:438-491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11521900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betemps, D., F. Mallet, V. Cheynet, and T. Baron. 1999. Overexpression and purification of an immunologically reactive His-BIV capsid fusion protein. Protein Expr. Purif. 15:258-264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10092485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boraston, A. B., A. L. Creagh, M. M. Alam, J. M. Kormos, P. Tomme, C. A. Haynes, R. A. J. Warren, and D. G. Kilburn. 2001. Binding specificity and thermodynamics of a family 9 carbohydrate-binding module from Thermotoga maritima xylanase 10A. Biochemistry 40:6240-6247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11371185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2001. Echovirus type 13&#x2014;United States, 2001. Morb. Mortal. Wkly. Rep. 50:777-780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11570484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2000. Enterovirus surveillance. Morb. Mortal. Wkly. Rep. 49:913-916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11043646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2000. Surveillance for waterborne-disease outbreaks&#x2014;United States, 1997-1998. Morb. Mortal. Wkly. Rep. 49:1-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherkasova, E. A., E. A. Korotkova, M. L. Yakovenko, O. E. Ivanova, T. P. Eremeeva, K. M. Chumakov, and V. I. Agol. 2002. Long-term circulation of vaccine-derived poliovirus that causes paralytic disease. J. Virol. 76:6791-6799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC136293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12050392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edgcomb, S. P., B. M. Baker, and K. P. Murphy. 2000. The energetics of phosphate binding to a protein complex. Protein Sci. 9:927-933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2144640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10850802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enriquez, C. E., C. J. Hurst, and C. P. Gerba. 1995. Survival of the enteric adenoviruses 40 and 41 in tap, sea, and waste water. Water Res. 29:2548-2553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba, C. P., D. M. Gramos, and N. Nwachuku. 2002. Comparative inactivation of enteroviruses and adenovirus 2 by UV light. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:5167-5169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC126408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12324370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass, R. I., J. Noel, T. Ando, R. Fankhauser, G. Belliot, A. Mounts, U. D. Parashar, J. S. Bresee, and S. S. Monroe. 2000. The epidemiology of enteric caliciviruses from humans: a reassessment using new diagnostics. J. Infect. Dis. 181:S254-S261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10804134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahn, R., R. Schlegel, and A. Jungbauer. 2003. Comparison of protein A affinity sorbents. J. Chromatogr. B Analyt. Technol. Biomed. Life Sci. 790:35-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12767319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herath, G., K. Yamamoto, and T. Urase. 1999. Removal of viruses by microfiltration membranes at different solution environments. Water Sci. Technol. 40:331-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horie, H., H. Yoshida, K. Matsuura, M. Miyazawa, Y. Ota, T. Nakayama, Y. Doi, and S. Hashizume. 2002. Neurovirulence of type 1 polioviruses isolated from sewage in Japan. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:138-142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC126552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11772619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karakasyan, C., M. Taverna, and M.-C. Millot. 2004. Determination of binding constants of hydrophobically end-capped poly(ethylene glycol)s with &#x3b2;-cyclodextrin by affinity capillary electrophoresis. J. Chromatogr. A 1032:159-164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15065792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laine, S., S. Salhi, and J.-M. Rossignol. 2002. Overexpression and purification of the hepatitis B e antigen precursor. J. Virol. Methods 103:67-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11906734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong, L. Y. C. 1983. Removal and inactivation of viruses by treatment processes for potable water and wastewater&#x2014;a review. Water Sci. Technol. 15:91-114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. W., Z. T. Xin, X. W. Wang, J. L. Zheng, and F. H. Chao. 2002. Mechanisms of inactivation of hepatitis A virus by chlorine. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:4951-4955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC126388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12324343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H.-M., D.-P. Zheng, L.-B. Zhang, M. S. Oberste, O. M. Kew, and M. A. Pallansch. 2003. Serial recombination during circulation of type 1 wild-vaccine recombination polioviruses in China. J. Virol. 77:10994-11005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC225006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14512548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopman, B. A., G. K. Adak, M. H. Reacher, and D. W. G. Brown. 2003. Two epidemiologic patterns of norovirus outbreaks: surveillance in England and Wales, 1992-2000. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:71-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukashev, A. N., V. A. Lashkevich, O. E. Ivanova, G. A. Koroleva, A. E. Hinkkanen, and J. Ilonen. 2003. Recombination in circulating enteroviruses. J. Virol. 77:10423-10431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC228507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12970427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste, M. S., K. Maher, and M. A. Pallansch. 2004. Evidence for frequent recombination within species Human Enterovirus B based on complete genomic sequences of all thirty-seven serotypes. J. Virol. 78:855-867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC368751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14694117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste, M. S., S. Pe&#xf1;aranda, and M. A. Pallansch. 2004. RNA recombination plays a major role in genomic change during circulation of coxsackie B viruses. J. Virol. 78:2948-2955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC353746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14990713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otaki, M., K. Yano, and S. Ohgaki. 1998. Virus removal in a membrane separation process. Water Sci. Technol. 37:107-116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parashar, U. D., E. G. Hummelman, J. S. Bresee, M. A. Miller, and R. I. Glass. 2003. Global illness and deaths caused by rotavirus disease in children. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:565-572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2972763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12737740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parshionikar, S. U., S. Willian-True, G. S. Fout, D. E. Robbins, S. A. Seys, J. D. Cassady, and R. Harris. 2003. Waterborne outbreaks of gastroenteritis associated with a norovirus. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 69:5263-5268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC194931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12957912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payment, P. 1998. Waterborne viruses and parasites: resistance to treatment and disinfection. In Proceedings of the OECD Workshop on Molecular Methods for Safe Drinking Water, Interlaken, Switzerland. [Online.] http://www.eawag.ch/publications_e/proceedings/oecd/proceedings/Payment.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sano, D., T. Matsuo, and T. Omura. 2004. Virus-binding proteins recovered from bacterial culture derived from activated sludge by affinity chromatography assay using a viral capsid peptide. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 70:3434-3442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC427754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15184141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siehnel, R., N. L. Martin, and R. E. W. Hancock. 1990. Sequence and relatedness in other bacteria of the Pseudomonas aeruginosa oprP gene coding for the phosphate-specific porin P. Mol. Microbiol. 4:831-838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1697017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallet, B., T. Astier-Gin, M. Castroviejo, and X. Santarelli. 2001. One-step chromatographic purification procedure of a His-tag recombinant carboxyl half part of the HTLV-I surface envelope glycoprotein overexpressed in Escherichia coli as a secreted form. J. Chromatogr. B Biomed. Sci. Appl. 753:17-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11302442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, F. B. 1974. Viruses&#x2014;what is their significance in water supplies? JAWWA 66:306-311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, R. H., J. O. Falkinham III, C. D. Norton, and M. W. Lechevallier. 2000. Chlorine, chloramine, chlorine dioxide, and ozone susceptibility of Mycobacterium avium. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 66:1702-1705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10742264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, S. S., J. L. Jackson, M. Suva-Castillo, W. A. Yanko, Z. E. Jack, J. Kuo, C. L. Chen, F. P. Williams, and D. P. Schnurr. 2003. Detection of infectious human adenoviruses in tertiary-treated and ultraviolet-disinfected wastewater. Water Environ. Res. 75:163-170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12772961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 1989. Guidance manual for compliance with the filtration and disinfection requirements for public water systems using surface water sources. Publication no. EPA/570/9-89-018. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection agency. 1999. Method for the recovery and assay of enteroviruses from sewage sludge, p. 117-145. Environmental regulations and technology. Control of pathogens and vector attraction in sewage sludge. Publication no. EPA/625/R-92/013. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worobec, E. A., N. L. Martin, W. D. McCubbin, C. M. Kay, G. D. Brayer, and R. E. W. Hancock. 1988. Large-scale purification and biochemical characterization of crystallization-grade porin protein P from Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 939:366-374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2451538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worobey, M., and E. C. Holmes. 1999. Evolutionary aspects of recombination in RNA viruses. J. Gen. Virol. 80:2535-2543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10573145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., and F. A. Gomez. 2000. Multiple-step ligand injection affinity capillary electrophoresis for determining binding constants of ligands to receptors. J. Chromatogr. A 897:339-347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11128217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., C. Kodama, C. Zurita, and F. A. Gomez. 2001. On-column ligand synthesis coupled to partial-filling affinity capillary electrophoresis to estimate binding constants of ligands to a receptor. J. Chromatogr. A 928:233-241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11587342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>