<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31524309</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1654</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Reviews in medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rev Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Outcomes beyond hospital discharge in infants and children with viral meningitis: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2083</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2083</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/rmv.2083</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Viruses are the commonest cause of childhood meningitis, but outcomes beyond hospital discharge are poorly described. We undertook a systematic literature review of long-term outcomes following paediatric viral meningitis. A search was carried out using MEDLINE, Embase, and Cochrane Review for studies from 1 January 1990 to 31 December 2018. Studies were included where specific outcome measures were available beyond hospital discharge for children &lt;16 years old with viral meningitis. In total, 3588 papers were identified of which 14 were eligible for inclusion. Four studies reported outcomes in children with nonenterovirus 71 meningitis. A US study of 16 cases demonstrated subtle language difficulties at 3-year follow-up in infants in contrast to an Australian study, which revealed no impairment in language. A Fijian study showed that two out of eight cases had sensorineural hearing loss compared with none in a UK cohort of 668 infants. Three studies evaluated outcomes of enterovirus 71 meningitis in China and Taiwan, two showed cases recovered without sequelae, while one demonstrated an increased risk of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder. Two studies including 141 cases of human parechovirus revealed no evidence of neurodevelopmental sequelae. Conversely, an Australian study demonstrated neurodevelopmental sequelae in 11 out of 77 infants with parechovirus meningitis. Most studies identified in this review demonstrated a high proportion of good clinical outcomes following viral meningitis. However, the data are limited, so robustly conducted neurodevelopmental studies are warranted to inform the evidence-based management of viral meningitis beyond hospital discharge.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hudson</LastName><ForeName>Jessica A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, John Radcliffe Hospital, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Broad</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oxford Vaccine Group, Department of Paediatrics, University of Oxford and the NIHR Oxford Biomedical Research Centre, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martin</LastName><ForeName>Natalie G</ForeName><Initials>NG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, University of Otago Christchurch, Christchurch, New Zealand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sadarangani</LastName><ForeName>Manish</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine Evaluation Center, BC Children's Hospital Research Institute, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galal</LastName><ForeName>Ushma</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oxford Vaccine Group, Department of Paediatrics, University of Oxford and the NIHR Oxford Biomedical Research Centre, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kelly</LastName><ForeName>Dominic F</ForeName><Initials>DF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oxford Vaccine Group, Department of Paediatrics, University of Oxford and the NIHR Oxford Biomedical Research Centre, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pollard</LastName><ForeName>Andrew J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oxford Vaccine Group, Department of Paediatrics, University of Oxford and the NIHR Oxford Biomedical Research Centre, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kadambari</LastName><ForeName>Seilesh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3658-7635</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oxford Vaccine Group, Department of Paediatrics, University of Oxford and the NIHR Oxford Biomedical Research Centre, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rev Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1052-9276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015897" MajorTopicYN="N">Comorbidity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitalization</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008587" MajorTopicYN="N">Meningitis, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010351" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Discharge</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063868" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Outcome Assessment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062486" MajorTopicYN="N">Public Health Surveillance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">follow-up</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sequelae</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viral meningitis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31524309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kadambari S, Okike I, Ribeiro S, et al. Seven-fold increase in viral meningo-encephalitis reports in England and Wales during 2004-2013. J Infect June. 2014;69(4):326-332. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2014.05.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawyer MH. Enterovirus infections: diagnosis and treatment. Semin Pediatr Infect Dis. 2002;13(1):40-47. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12118843 Accessed August 26, 2014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlin LE, Rorabaugh ML, Heldrich F, Roberts K, Doran T, Modlin JF. Aseptic meningitis in infants &lt;2 years of age: diagnosis and etiology. J Infect Dis. 1993;168(4):888-892. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/8397269</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun KW, Choi EH, Cheon DS, et al. Enteroviral meningitis without pleocytosis in children. Arch Dis Child. 2012;97(10):874-878. https://doi.org/10.1136/archdischild-2012-301884</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee BE, Chawla R, Langley JM, et al. Paediatric Investigators Collaborative Network on Infections in Canada (PICNIC) study of aseptic meningitis. BMC Infect Dis. 8(1):1-8. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2334-6-68</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rittichier KR, Bryan PA, Bassett KE, et al. Diagnosis and outcomes of enterovirus infections in young infants. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2005;24(6):546-550. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15933567. Accessed August 26, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Podin Y, et al. Human enterovirus 71 disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: a prospective clinical, virological, and molecular epidemiological study. Clin Infect Dis. 2007;44(5):646-656. https://doi.org/10.1086/511073</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadambari S, Braccio S, Ribeiro S, et al. Enterovirus and parechovirus meningitis in infants younger than 90 days old in the UK and Republic of Ireland: A British Paediatric Surveillance Unit study. Arch Dis Child. 2019;104(6):552-557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, et al. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate health care interventions: explanation and elaboration. J Clin Epidemiol. 2009;62(10):e1-e34. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2009.06.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker RC, Kummer AW, Schultz JR, Ho M, Gonzalez del Rey J. Neurodevelopmental outcome of infants with viral meningitis in the first three months of life. Clin Pediatr (Phila). 1996;35(6):295-301. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/8782953 Accessed August 26, 2014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balasubramanian H, Wagh D, Rao S, Keil ADMJ. Developmental outcomes in cerebrospinal fluid proven enteroviral meningitis in neonates &gt;32 weesk of gestation. J Paediatr Child Health. 2016;53(3):327-332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biaukula VL, Tikoduadua L, Azzopardi K, et al. Meningitis in children in Fiji: etiology, epidemiology, and neurological sequelae. Int J Infect Dis. 2012;16(4):e289-e295. https://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2011.12.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Huang L-M, SS-F G, et al. Neurodevelopment and cognition in children after enterovirus 71 infection. N Engl J Med. 2007;356(12):1226-1234. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa065954</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gau SS, Chang LY, Huang LM, Fan TY, Wu YY, Lin TY. Attention-deficit/hyperactivity-related symptoms among children with enterovirus 71 infection of the central nervous system. Pediatrics. 2008;122(2):e452-e458. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2007-3799</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Jiang L, Peng H. Clinical analysis of 134 children with nervous system damage caused by enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2015;34(7):718-723. https://doi.org/10.1097/INF.0000000000000711</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antolin LF, Kadambari S, Braccio S, et al. Increased detection in human parechovirus infection in infants in England during 2016: Epidemiology and clinical characteristics. Arch Dis Child. 2018;103(11):1061-1066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hinsbergh TMT, Elbers RG, van Furth MAM, Obihara CCC. Longitudinal association between human parechovirus central nervous system infection and gross-motor neurodevelopment in young children. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2019;38(2):110-114. https://doi.org/10.1097/INF.0000000000002052</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph L, May M, Thomas M, et al. Human parechovirus 3 in infants: expanding our knowledge of adverse outcomes. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2019;38(1):1-5. https://doi.org/10.1097/INF.0000000000002136</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robin S, Ramful D, Le Seach' F, Jaffar-Bandjee M-C, Rigou G, Alessandri J-L. Neurologic manifestations of pediatric chikungunya infection. J Child Neurol. 2008;23(9):1028-1035. https://doi.org/10.1177/0883073808314151</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rorabaugh ML, Berlin LE, Heldrich F, et al. Aseptic meningitis in infants younger than 2 years of age: acute illness and neurologic complications. Pediatrics. 1993;92(2):206-211. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/8337018 Accessed August 26, 2014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hristeva L, Booy R, Bowler I, Wilkinson AR. Prospective surveillance of neonatal meningitis. Arch Dis Child 1993;69(1 SUPPL.):14-18. http://ovidsp.ovid.com/ovidweb.cgi? T=JS&amp;PAGE=reference&amp;D=emed6&amp;NEWS=N&amp;AN=23232974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao X, Wong V. Brainstem auditory-evoked potential evaluation in children with meningitis. Pediatr Neurol. 1998;19(2):109-112. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0887-8994%2898%2900032-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandran A, Herbert H, Misurski D, Santosham M. Long-term sequelae of childhood bacterial meningitis: an underappreciated problem. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2011;30(1):3-6. https://doi.org/10.1097/INF.0b013e3181ef25f7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christie D, Rashid H, El-Bashir H, et al. Impact of meningitis on intelligence and development: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(8). https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0175024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouchenir L, Renaud C, Khan S, et al. The epidemiology, management, and outcomes of bacterial meningitis in infants. Pediatrics. 2017;140(1):e20170476. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2017-0476</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stockmann C, Ampofo K, Byington CL, et al. Pneumococcal meningitis in children: epidemiology, serotypes, and outcomes from 1997-2010 in Utah. Pediatrics. 2013;132(3):421-428. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2013-0621</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Tan L, Qui PT, Ha DQ, et al. Viral etiology of encephalitis in children in Southern Vietnam: results of a one-year prospective descriptive study. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2010;4(10). https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0000854</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malm G, Forsgren M, Azazi M, Persson A. A follow-up study of children with neonatal herpes simplex virus infections with particular regard to late nervous disturbances. Acta Paediatr. 2008;80(2):226-234. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1651-2227.1991.tb11838.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britton PN, Khandaker G, Khatami A, Teutsch S, Francis S, McMullan BJJC. High prevalence of developmental concern amongst infants at 12 months following hospitalised parechovirus infection. J Paediatr Child Health. 2018;54(3):289-295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sells CJ, Carpenter RL, Ray CG. Sequelae of central-nervous-system enterovirus infections. N Engl J Med. 1975;293(1):1-4. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM197507032930101</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilfert CM, Thompson RJ Jr, Sunder TR. Longitudinal assessment of children with enteroviral meningitis during the first three months of life. Pediatrics. 1981;67(6):811-815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergman I, Painter MJ, Wald ER, Chiponis D, Holland AL, Taylor HG. Outcome in children with enteroviral meningitis during the first year of life. J Pediatr. 1987;110(5):705-709. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/2437277 Accessed August 26, 2014</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedford H, de Louvois J, Halket S, Peckham C, Hurley R, Harvey D. Meningitis in infancy in England and Wales: follow up at age 5 years. BMJ. 2001;323(7312):533. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.323.7312.533</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>