<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23637404</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>87</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structures of the procapsid and mature virion of enterovirus 71 strain 1095.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7637</StartPage><EndPage>7645</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7637-45</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.03519-12</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is an important emerging human pathogen with a global distribution and presents a disease pattern resembling poliomyelitis with seasonal epidemics that include cases of severe neurological complications, such as acute flaccid paralysis. EV71 is a member of the Picornaviridae family, which consists of icosahedral, nonenveloped, single-stranded RNA viruses. Here we report structures derived from X-ray crystallography and cryoelectron microscopy (cryo-EM) for the 1095 strain of EV71, including a putative precursor in virus assembly, the procapsid, and the mature virus capsid. The cryo-EM map of the procapsid provides new structural information on portions of the capsid proteins VP0 and VP1 that are disordered in the higher-resolution crystal structures. Our structures solved from virus particles in solution are largely in agreement with those from prior X-ray crystallographic studies; however, we observe small but significant structural differences for the 1095 procapsid compared to a structure solved in a previous study (X. Wang, W. Peng, J. Ren, Z. Hu, J. Xu, Z. Lou, X. Li, W. Yin, X. Shen, C. Porta, T. S. Walter, G. Evans, D. Axford, R. Owen, D. J. Rowlands, J. Wang, D. I. Stuart, E. E. Fry, and Z. Rao, Nat. Struct. Mol. Biol. 19:424-429, 2012) for a different strain of EV71. For both EV71 strains, the procapsid is significantly larger in diameter than the mature capsid, unlike in any other picornavirus. Nonetheless, our results demonstrate that picornavirus capsid expansion is possible without RNA encapsidation and that picornavirus assembly may involve an inward radial collapse of the procapsid to yield the native virion.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cifuente</LastName><ForeName>Javier O</ForeName><Initials>JO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, The Pennsylvania State University College of Medicine, Hershey, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Hyunwook</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoder</LastName><ForeName>Joshua D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shingler</LastName><ForeName>Kristin L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carnegie</LastName><ForeName>Michael S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoder</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashley</LastName><ForeName>Robert E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Makhov</LastName><ForeName>Alexander M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Conway</LastName><ForeName>James F</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hafenstein</LastName><ForeName>Susan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P41 GM103485</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GM-103485</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K22 AI079271</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K22 A179271</GrantID><Agency>PHS HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AI107121</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002213" MajorTopicYN="N">Capsid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020285" MajorTopicYN="N">Cryoelectron Microscopy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018360" MajorTopicYN="N">Crystallography, X-Ray</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008958" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Molecular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014771" MajorTopicYN="N">Virion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000648" MajorTopicYN="Y">ultrastructure</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23637404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3700288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.03519-12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.03519-12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Schmidt NJ, Lennette EH, Ho HH. 1974. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J. Infect. Dis. 129:304&#x2013;309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reference deleted.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, Cardosa MJ, McMinn P, Ooi MH. 2010. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect. Dis. 10:778&#x2013;790</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SW, Hsu YW, Smith DJ, Kiang D, Tsai HP, Lin KH, Wang SM, Liu CC, Su IJ, Wang JR. 2009. Reemergence of enterovirus 71 in 2008 in Taiwan: dynamics of genetic and antigenic evolution from 1998 to 2008. J. Clin. Microbiol. 47:3653&#x2013;3662</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19776232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyler KL. 2009. Emerging viral infections of the central nervous system: part 1. Arch. Neurol. 66:939&#x2013;948</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19667214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phuektes P, Chua BH, Sanders S, Bek EJ, Kok CC, McMinn PC. 2011. Mapping genetic determinants of the cell-culture growth phenotype of enterovirus 71. J. Gen. Virol. 92:1380&#x2013;1390</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3168283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21346025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwai M, Masaki A, Hasegawa S, Obara M, Horimoto E, Nakamura K, Tanaka Y, Endo K, Tanaka K, Ueda J, Shiraki K, Kurata T, Takizawa T. 2009. Genetic changes of coxsackievirus A16 and enterovirus 71 isolated from hand, foot, and mouth disease patients in Toyama, Japan between 1981 and 2007. Jpn. J. Infect. Dis. 62:254&#x2013;259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19628900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plevka P, Perera R, Cardosa J, Kuhn RJ, Rossmann MG. 2012. Crystal structure of human enterovirus 71. Science 336:1274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3448362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22383808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Peng W, Ren J, Hu Z, Xu J, Lou Z, Li X, Yin W, Shen X, Porta C, Walter TS, Evans G, Axford D, Owen R, Rowlands DJ, Wang J, Stuart DI, Fry EE, Rao Z. 2012. A sensor-adaptor mechanism for enterovirus uncoating from structures of EV71. Nat. Struct. Mol. Biol. 19:424&#x2013;429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3378640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22388738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SC, Li WC, Chen GW, Tsao KC, Huang CG, Huang YC, Chiu CH, Kuo CY, Tsai KN, Shih SR, Lin TY. 2012. Genetic characterization of enterovirus 71 isolated from patients with severe disease by comparative analysis of complete genomes. J. Med. Virol. 84:931&#x2013;939</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22499017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Zou Q, Chen L, Zhang H, Wang Y. 2011. Molecular analysis of virulent determinants of enterovirus 71. PLoS One 6:e26237.10.1371/journal.pone.0026237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0026237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22039449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tee KK, Lam TT, Chan YF, Bible JM, Kamarulzaman A, Tong CY, Takebe Y, Pybus OG. 2010. Evolutionary genetics of human enterovirus 71: origin, population dynamics, natural selection, and seasonal periodicity of the VP1 gene. J. Virol. 84:3339&#x2013;3350</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2838098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20089660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Shimojima M, Tano Y, Miyamura T, Wakita T, Shimizu H. 2009. Human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15:794&#x2013;797</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Yamashita Y, Li J, Hanagata N, Minowa T, Takemura T, Koike S. 2009. Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15:798&#x2013;801</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su PY, Liu YT, Chang HY, Huang SW, Wang YF, Yu CK, Wang JR, Chang CF. 2012. Cell surface sialylation affects binding of enterovirus 71 to rhabdomyosarcoma and neuroblastoma cells. BMC Microbiol. 12:162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3478995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22853823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B, Chuang H, Yang KD. 2009. Sialylated glycans as receptor and inhibitor of enterovirus 71 infection to DLD-1 intestinal cells. Virol. J. 6:141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2751754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19751532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang SL, Chou YT, Wu CN, Ho MS. 2011. Annexin II binds to capsid protein VP1 of enterovirus 71 and enhances viral infectivity. J. Virol. 85:11809&#x2013;11820</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3209289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21900167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan CW, Poh CL, Sam IC, Chan YF. 2013. Enterovirus 71 uses cell surface heparan sulfate glycosaminoglycan as an attachment receptor. J. Virol. 87:611&#x2013;620</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3536405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23097443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Song Z, Qi Y, Feng X, Xu N, Sun Y, Wu X, Yao X, Mao Q, Li X, Dong W, Wan X, Huang N, Shen X, Liang Z, Li W. 2012. Molecular determinants of enterovirus 71 viral entry: cleft around GLN-172 on VP1 protein interacts with variable region on scavenge receptor B 2. J. Biol. Chem. 287:6406&#x2013;6420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3307280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22219187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Wang JC, Taylor MW, Zlotnick A. 2012. In vitro assembly of an empty picornavirus capsid follows a dodecahedral path. J. Virol. 86:13062&#x2013;13069</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3497625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23015694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basavappa R, Syed R, Flore O, Icenogle JP, Filman DJ, Hogle JM. 1994. Role and mechanism of the maturation cleavage of VP0 in poliovirus assembly: structure of the empty capsid assembly intermediate at 2.9 A resolution. Protein Sci. 3:1651&#x2013;1669</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2142606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7849583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Tomas CB, Guttman N, Baltimore D. 1973. Morphogenesis of poliovirus 3. Formation of provirion in cell-free extracts. J. Virol. 12:1181&#x2013;1183</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC356751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4358165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin FH. 1977. Involvement of viral procapsid in the RNA synthesis and maturation of poliovirus. Virology 82:299&#x2013;307</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">199991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold E, Luo M, Vriend G, Rossmann MG, Palmenberg AC, Parks GD, Nicklin MJ, Wimmer E. 1987. Implications of the picornavirus capsid structure for polyprotein processing. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 84:21&#x2013;25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC304133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3467351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson MF, Asso J, Baltimore D. 1970. Further evidence on the formation of poliovirus proteins. J. Mol. Biol. 49:657&#x2013;669</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4318205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop NE, Anderson DA. 1993. RNA-dependent cleavage of VP0 capsid protein in provirions of hepatitis A virus. Virology 197:616&#x2013;623</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8249284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compton SR, Nelsen B, Kirkegaard K. 1990. Temperature-sensitive poliovirus mutant fails to cleave VP0 and accumulates provirions. J. Virol. 64:4067&#x2013;4075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC247868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2166805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamura K, Nishimura Y, Abo M, Wakita T, Shimizu H. 2011. Adaptive mutations in the genomes of enterovirus 71 strains following infection of mouse cells expressing human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1. J. Gen. Virol. 92:287&#x2013;291</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20943886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogle JM. 2012. A 3D framework for understanding enterovirus 71. Nat. Struct. Mol. Biol. 19:367&#x2013;368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22472617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otwinowski Z, Minor W. 1997. Processing of X-ray diffraction data collected in oscillation mode. Methods Enzymol. 276:307&#x2013;326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27754618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navaza J. 1994. AMoRe: an automated package for molecular replacement. Acta Crystallogr. A 50:157&#x2013;163</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams PD, Afonine PV, Bunkoczi G, Chen VB, Davis IW, Echols N, Headd JJ, Hung LW, Kapral GJ, Grosse-Kunstleve RW, McCoy AJ, Moriarty NW, Oeffner R, Read RJ, Richardson DC, Richardson JS, Terwilliger TC, Zwart PH. 2010. PHENIX: a comprehensive Python-based system for macromolecular structure solution. Acta Crystallogr. D Biol. Crystallogr. 66:213&#x2013;221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2815670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20124702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Lasker K, Schneidman-Duhovny D, Webb B, Huang CC, Pettersen EF, Goddard TD, Meng EC, Sali A, Ferrin TE. 2012. UCSF Chimera, MODELLER, and IMP: an integrated modeling system. J. Struct. Biol. 179:269&#x2013;278</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3410985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21963794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sali A, Blundell TL. 1993. Comparative protein modelling by satisfaction of spatial restraints. J. Mol. Biol. 234:779&#x2013;815</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8254673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettersen EF, Goddard TD, Huang CC, Couch GS, Greenblatt DM, Meng EC, Ferrin TE. 2004. UCSF Chimera&#x2014;a visualization system for exploratory research and analysis. J. Comput. Chem. 25:1605&#x2013;1612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15264254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wien MW, Curry S, Filman DJ, Hogle JM. 1997. Structural studies of poliovirus mutants that overcome receptor defects. Nat. Struct. Biol. 4:666&#x2013;674</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9253417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smyth M, Tate J, Hoey E, Lyons C, Martin S, Stuart D. 1995. Implications for viral uncoating from the structure of bovine enterovirus. Nat. Struct. Biol. 2:224&#x2013;231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7773791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muckelbauer JK, Kremer M, Minor I, Diana G, Dutko FJ, Groarke J, Pevear DC, Rossmann MG. 1995. The structure of coxsackievirus B3 at 3.5 &#x212b; resolution. Structure 3:653&#x2013;667</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8591043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendry E, Hatanaka H, Fry E, Smyth M, Tate J, Stanway G, Santti J, Maaronen M, Hyypia T, Stuart D. 1999. The crystal structure of coxsackievirus A9: new insights into the uncoating mechanisms of enteroviruses. Structure 7:1527&#x2013;1538</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10647183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filman DJ, Wien MW, Cunningham JA, Bergelson JM, Hogle JM. 1998. Structure determination of echovirus 1. Acta Crystallogr. D Biol. Crystallogr. 54:1261&#x2013;1272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10089503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdaguer N, Jimenez-Clavero MA, Fita I, Ley V. 2003. Structure of swine vesicular disease virus: mapping of changes occurring during adaptation of human coxsackie B5 virus to infect swine. J. Virol. 77:9780&#x2013;9789</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC224589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12941886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao C, Bator-Kelly CM, Rieder E, Chipman PR, Craig A, Kuhn RJ, Wimmer E, Rossmann MG. 2005. The crystal structure of coxsackievirus A21 and its interaction with ICAM-1. Structure 13:1019&#x2013;1033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16004874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plevka P, Hafenstein S, Harris KG, Cifuente JO, Zhang Y, Bowman VD, Chipman PR, Bator CM, Lin F, Medof ME, Rossmann MG. 2010. Interaction of decay-accelerating factor with echovirus 7. J. Virol. 84:12665&#x2013;12674</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3004353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20881044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold E, Rossmann MG. 1988. The use of molecular-replacement phases for the refinement of the human rhinovirus 14 structure. Acta Crystallogr. A 44:270&#x2013;282</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2856083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleywegt GJ, Zou JY, Kjeldgaard M, Jones TA. 2001. Around O, p 353&#x2013;356 In Rossmann MG, Arnold E. (ed), International tables for crystallography, vol F Kluwer Academic Publishers, Dordrecht, The Netherlands</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xfc;nger AT, Adams PD, Clore GM, DeLano WL, Gros P, Grosse-Kunstleve RW, Jiang JS, Kuszewski J, Nilges M, Pannu NS, Read RJ, Rice LM, Simonson T, Warren GL. 1998. Crystallography and NMR system: a new software suite for macromolecular structure determination. Acta Crystallogr. D Biol. Crystallogr. 54:905&#x2013;921</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9757107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emsley P, Lohkamp B, Scott WG, Cowtan K. 2010. Features and development of Coot. Acta Crystallogr. D Biol. Crystallogr. 66:486&#x2013;501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2852313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20383002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tivol WF, Briegel A, Jensen GJ. 2008. An improved cryogen for plunge freezing. Microsc. Microanal. 14:375&#x2013;379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3058946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18793481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X, Sinkovits RS, Baker TS. 2007. AUTO3DEM&#x2014;an automated and high throughput program for image reconstruction of icosahedral particles. J. Struct. Biol. 157:73&#x2013;82</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1847775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17029842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang G, Peng L, Baldwin PR, Mann DS, Jiang W, Rees I, Ludtke SJ. 2007. EMAN2: an extensible image processing suite for electron microscopy. J. Struct. Biol. 157:38&#x2013;46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16859925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X, Dryden KA, Tang J, Baker TS. 2007. Ab initio random model method facilitates 3D reconstruction of icosahedral particles. J. Struct. Biol. 157:211&#x2013;225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1919437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16979906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goddard TD, Huang CC, Ferrin TE. 2007. Visualizing density maps with UCSF Chimera. J. Struct. Biol. 157:281&#x2013;287</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16963278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wriggers W. 2010. Using Situs for the integration of multi-resolution structures. Biophys. Rev. 2:21&#x2013;27</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2821521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20174447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chacon P, Wriggers W. 2002. Multi-resolution contour-based fitting of macromolecular structures. J. Mol. Biol. 317:375&#x2013;384</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11922671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Guo MS, Lin FH, Hsiao KN, Chang KH, Chou AH, Wang YC, Chen YC, Yang CS, Chong PC. 2011. Purification and characterization of enterovirus 71 viral particles produced from Vero cells grown in a serum-free microcarrier bioreactor system. PLoS One 6:e20005.10.1371/journal.pone.0020005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0020005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3094384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Ohka S, Fujii K, Koike S. 2013. Functional comparison of SCARB2 and PSGL1 as receptors for enterovirus 71. J. Virol. 87:3335&#x2013;3347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3592140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23302872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curry S, Fry E, Blakemore W, Abu-Ghazaleh R, Jackson T, King A, Lea S, Newman J, Stuart D. 1997. Dissecting the roles of VP0 cleavage and RNA packaging in picornavirus capsid stabilization: the structure of empty capsids of foot-and-mouth disease virus. J. Virol. 71:9743&#x2013;9752</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC230284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9371640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao F, Wang YP, Mao QY, Yao X, Liu S, Li FX, Zhu FC, Yang JY, Liang ZL, Lu FM, Wang JZ. 2012. Enterovirus 71 viral capsid protein linear epitopes: identification and characterization. Virol. J. 9:26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3292509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22264266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Chou AH, Lien SP, Lin HY, Liu SJ, Chang JY, Guo MS, Chow YH, Yang WS, Chang KH, Sia C, Chong P. 2011. Identification and characterization of a cross-neutralization epitope of enterovirus 71. Vaccine 29:4362&#x2013;4372</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21501643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLeish NJ, Williams CH, Kaloudas D, Roivainen MM, Stanway G. 2012. Symmetry-related clustering of positive charges is a common mechanism for heparan sulfate binding in enteroviruses. J. Virol. 86:11163&#x2013;11170</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3457184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22855495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson MF, Baltimore D. 1968. Morphogenesis of poliovirus. I. Association of the viral RNA with coat protein. J. Mol. Biol. 33:369&#x2013;378</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4302632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghendon Y, Yakobson E, Mikhejeva A. 1972. Study of some stages of poliovirus morphogenesis in MiO cells. J. Virol. 10:261&#x2013;266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC356458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4342243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marongiu ME, Pani A, Corrias MV, Sau M, La Colla P. 1981. Poliovirus morphogenesis. I. Identification of 80S dissociable particles and evidence for the artifactual production of procapsids. J. Virol. 39:341&#x2013;347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC171342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6268826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafenstein S, Fane BA. 2002. &#x3a6;X174 genome-capsid interactions influence the biophysical properties of the virion: evidence for a scaffolding-like function for the genome during the final stages of morphogenesis. J. Virol. 76:5350&#x2013;5356</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC137031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11991963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>