<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36917029</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Hypothesis-Generating Prospective Longitudinal Study to Assess the Relative Contribution of Common Respiratory Viruses to Severe Lower Respiratory Infections in Young Children.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>396</StartPage><EndPage>404</EndPage><MedlinePgn>396-404</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000003865</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Respiratory viruses such as respiratory syncytial virus (RSV), influenza, parainfluenza and human metapneumovirus are well-established etiologies of acute lower respiratory tract infections (ALRIs; LRI-viruses). In contrast, adenovirus (AdV), rhinovirus/enterovirus (RV/EV) and seasonal human coronaviruses (CoV), collectively termed AdV/RV/CoV, are detected both in healthy children and children with ALRI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">The methods include a prospective longitudinal case-control study, assessing the prevalence of LRI-viruses versus AdV/RV/CoV in ALRI [community-acquired alveolar pneumonia (CAAP) and bronchiolitis] during hospitalization (visit 1), 7-14 days (visit 2) and 28-35 days (visit 3) in 2-17-month-old children. Controls were 2-27-month-old children hospitalized for elective surgery during the same respiratory seasons.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We enrolled 99 infants (37 CAAP, 38 bronchiolitis and 24 controls) and obtained 211 nasopharyngeal swabs. Overall, 163 (77%) had greater than or equal to 1 viruses detected; RV/EV (n = 94; 45%) and RSV (n = 71; 34%) were the most frequently detected viruses. In CAAP, the overall LRI-virus prevalence was 78.4%, 32.4% and 5.4% in visits 1, 2 and 3, respectively; the respective rates in bronchiolitis were 73.7%, 34.5% and 8.0%. In controls, no LRI-viruses were detected. In contrast, the overall AdV/RV/CoV prevalence was high among controls (70.8%) and similar among CAAP (48.6%, 40.5% and 40.5%) and bronchiolitis (47.4, 58.6% and 64.0%) across visits.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Among ALRI cases, LRI-viruses dominated during the acute disease, with prevalence declining within 28-35 days, suggesting their causative role. In contrast, AdV/RV/CoV prevalence was similar during all 3 visits and in controls, suggesting that carriage of these viruses is common during the viral respiratory season. The current study is relatively small and of short duration; however, the findings are supported by other recent studies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ben-Shimol</LastName><ForeName>Shalom</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7690-0991</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Faculty of Health Sciences, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Beer Sheva, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Infectious Disease Unit, Soroka University Medical Center, Beer Sheva, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramilo</LastName><ForeName>Octavio</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Infectious Diseases and Center for Vaccines and Immunity, Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leber</LastName><ForeName>Amy L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Beek</LastName><ForeName>Bart Adriaan</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Shraga Segal Department of Microbiology, Immunology, and Genetics, Faculty of Health Sciences, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Beer Sheva, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Everhart</LastName><ForeName>Kathy</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mertz</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Infectious Diseases and Center for Vaccines and Immunity, Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mejias</LastName><ForeName>Asuncion</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Infectious Diseases and Center for Vaccines and Immunity, Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dagan</LastName><ForeName>Ron</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8888-1046</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Shraga Segal Department of Microbiology, Immunology, and Genetics, Faculty of Health Sciences, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Beer Sheva, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012141" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Tract Infections</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014780" MajorTopicYN="Y">Viruses</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011014" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pneumonia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001988" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bronchiolitis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018113" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Syncytial Virus, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000256" MajorTopicYN="N">Adenoviridae</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012621" MajorTopicYN="N">Seasons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>S.B.-S. has received grants from Pfizer, fees as scientific consultant, participation in advisory board, and educational lectures from Pfizer and MSD, and fees for educational lectures from GSK. O.R. has received research grants from NIH, the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, Merck and Janssen to institution; fees for participation in advisory boards from Merck, Sanofi-Pasteur, Adagio, Lilly and Pfizer; and fees for lectures from Pfizer, Sanofi-Pasteur and AstraZeneca. A.L.L. has received research grants from Biofire, Cephied, Luminex, and Diasorin, and consulting fees from Medscape, Biorad and Biofire. A.M. has received research grants from, NIH, Janssen and Merck to institution, fees for participation in advisory boards from Janssen, Sanofi-Pasteur, and Merck and fees for educational lectures from Sanofi-Pasteur and AstraZeneca. R.D. has received grants from Pfizer, MSD, MedImmune/AstraZeneca, fees as scientific consultant, participation in advisory board, and educational lectures from Pfizer and MSD, as well as fees for educational lectures from Sanofi-Pasteur. The remaining authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36917029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000003865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-202305000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Goto T, Tsugawa Y, Mansbach JM, et al. Trends in infectious disease hospitalizations in US children, 2000 to 2012. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2016;35:e158&#x2013;e163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoefnagels I, van de Maat J, van Kampen JJA, et al. The role of the respiratory microbiome and viral presence in lower respiratory tract infection severity in the first five years of life. Microorganisms. 2021;9:1446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi T, McLean K, Campbell H, et al. Aetiological role of common respiratory viruses in acute lower respiratory infections in children under five years: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Glob Health. 2015;5:010408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Self WH, Williams DJ, Zhu Y, et al. Respiratory viral detection in children and adults: comparing asymptomatic controls and patients with community-acquired pneumonia. J Infect Dis. 2016;213:584&#x2013;591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singleton RJ, Bulkow LR, Miernyk K, et al. Viral respiratory infections in hospitalized and community control children in Alaska. J Med Virol. 2010;82:1282&#x2013;1290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awori JO, Kamau A, Morpeth S, et al. The etiology of pneumonia in HIV-uninfected children in Kilifi, Kenya: findings from the pneumonia etiology research for child health (PERCH) study. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40(9S):S29&#x2013;S39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings LC, Anderson TP, Werno AM, et al. Viral etiology of acute respiratory tract infections in children presenting to hospital: role of polymerase chain reaction and demonstration of multiple infections. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2004;23:1003&#x2013;1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moesker FM, van Kampen JJ, van Rossum AM, et al. Viruses as sole causative agents of severe acute respiratory tract infections in children. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0150776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen RR, Wieringa J, Koekkoek SM, et al. Frequent detection of respiratory viruses without symptoms: toward defining clinically relevant cutoff values. J Clin Microbiol. 2011;49:2631&#x2013;2636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddadin Z, Rankin DA, Lipworth L, et al. Respiratory virus surveillance in infants across different clinical settings. J Pediatr. 2021;234:164&#x2013;171.e2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun KW, Wallihan R, Desai A, et al. Clinical characteristics and etiology of community-acquired pneumonia in US children, 2015-2018. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2022;41:381&#x2212;387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagan R, Danino D, Weinberger DM. The pneumococcus-respiratory virus connection-unexpected lessons from the COVID-19 pandemic. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5:e2218966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagan R, van der Beek BA, Ben-Shimol S, et al. The COVID-19 pandemic as an opportunity for unravelling the causative association between respiratory viruses and pneumococcus-associated disease in young children: a prospective cohort study. medRxiv. 2022:2022.09.06.22279606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danino D, Ben-Shimol S, Van Der Beek BA, et al. Decline in pneumococcal disease in young children during the COVID-19 pandemic in Israel associated with suppression of seasonal respiratory viruses, despite persistent pneumococcal carriage: a prospective cohort study. Clin Infect Dis. 2022;75:e1154&#x2212;e1164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinberger DM, Klugman KP, Steiner CA, et al. Association between respiratory syncytial virus activity and pneumococcal disease in infants: a time series analysis of US hospitalization data. PLoS Med. 2015;12:e1001776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherian T, Mulholland EK, Carlin JB, et al. Standardized interpretation of paediatric chest radiographs for the diagnosis of pneumonia in epidemiological studies. Bull World Health Organ. 2005;83:353&#x2013;359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kneyber MC, Blusse van Oud-Alblas H, van Vliet M, et al. Concurrent bacterial infection and prolonged mechanical ventilation in infants with respiratory syncytial virus lower respiratory tract disease. Intensive Care Med. 2005;31:680&#x2013;685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin D, Tribuzio M, Green-Wrzesinki T, et al. Empiric antibiotics are justified for infants with respiratory syncytial virus lower respiratory tract infection presenting with respiratory failure: a prospective study and evidence review. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2010;11:390&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duttweiler L, Nadal D, Frey B. Pulmonary and systemic bacterial co-infections in severe RSV bronchiolitis. Arch Dis Child. 2004;89:1155&#x2013;1157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorburn K, Harigopal S, Reddy V, et al. High incidence of pulmonary bacterial co-infection in children with severe respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) bronchiolitis. Thorax. 2006;61:611&#x2013;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths C, Drews SJ, Marchant DJ. Respiratory syncytial virus: infection, detection, and new options for prevention and treatment. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2017;30:277&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall CB, Powell KR, Schnabel KC, et al. Risk of secondary bacterial infection in infants hospitalized with respiratory syncytial viral infection. J Pediatr. 1988;113:266&#x2013;271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuppermann N, Bank DE, Walton EA, et al. Risks for bacteremia and urinary tract infections in young febrile children with bronchiolitis. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 1997;151:1207&#x2013;1214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titus MO, Wright SW. Prevalence of serious bacterial infections in febrile infants with respiratory syncytial virus infection. Pediatrics. 2003;112:282&#x2013;284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randolph AG, Reder L, Englund JA. Risk of bacterial infection in previously healthy respiratory syncytial virus-infected young children admitted to the intensive care unit. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2004;23:990&#x2013;994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiegers HMG, van Nijen L, van Woensel JBM, et al. Bacterial co-infection of the respiratory tract in ventilated children with bronchiolitis; a retrospective cohort study. BMC Infect Dis. 2019;19:938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Koff EM, van Houten MA, Sanders EAM, et al. Severity of respiratory infections with seasonal coronavirus is associated with viral and bacterial coinfections. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40:e36&#x2013;e39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heimdal I, Moe N, Krokstad S, et al. Human coronavirus in hospitalized children with respiratory tract infections: a 9-year population-based study from Norway. J Infect Dis. 2019;219:1198&#x2013;1206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heimdal I, Valand J, Krokstad S, et al. Hospitalized children with common human coronavirus clinical impact of codetected respiratory syncytial virus and rhinovirus. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2022;41:e95&#x2212;e101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntosh K. Proving etiologic relationships to disease: another look at the common cold coronaviruses. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2022;41:e102&#x2212;e103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prill MM, Iwane MK, Edwards KM, et al.; New Vaccine Surveillance Network. Human coronavirus in young children hospitalized for acute respiratory illness and asymptomatic controls. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2012;31:235&#x2013;240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Probst V, Datyner EK, Haddadin Z, et al. Human adenovirus species in children with acute respiratory illnesses. J Clin Virol. 2021;134:104716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapia MD, Sylla M, Driscoll AJ, et al. The etiology of childhood pneumonia in Mali: findings from the pneumonia etiology research for child health (PERCH) study. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2021;40(9S):S18&#x2013;S28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhi SA, Klugman KP, Vaccine Trialist G. A role for Streptococcus pneumoniae in virus-associated pneumonia. Nat Med. 2004;10:811&#x2013;813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinberger DM, Givon-Lavi N, Shemer-Avni Y, et al. Influence of pneumococcal vaccines and respiratory syncytial virus on alveolar pneumonia, Israel. Emerg Infect Dis. 2013;19:1084&#x2013;1091.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>