<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23946454</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>87</Volume><Issue>20</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Soluble interleukin-6 receptor-mediated innate immune response to DNA and RNA viruses.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>11244</StartPage><EndPage>11254</EndPage><MedlinePgn>11244-54</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.01248-13</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The interleukin-6 (IL-6) receptor, which exists as membrane-bound and soluble forms, plays critical roles in the immune response. The soluble IL-6 receptor (sIL6R) has been identified as a potential therapeutic target for preventing coronary heart disease. However, little is known about the role of this receptor during viral infection. In this study, we show that sIL6R, but not IL-6, is induced by viral infection via the cyclooxygenase-2 pathway. Interestingly, sIL6R, but not IL-6, exhibited extensive antiviral activity against DNA and RNA viruses, including hepatitis B virus, influenza virus, human enterovirus 71, and vesicular stomatitis virus. No synergistic effects on antiviral action were observed by combining sIL6R and IL-6. Furthermore, sIL6R mediated antiviral action via the p28 pathway and induced alpha interferon (IFN-&#x3b1;) by promoting the nuclear translocation of IFN regulatory factor 3 (IRF3) and NF-&#x3ba;B, which led to the activation of downstream IFN effectors, including 2',5'-oligoadenylate synthetase (OAS), double-stranded RNA-dependent protein kinase (PKR), and myxovirus resistance protein (Mx). Thus, our results demonstrate that sIL6R, but not IL-6, plays an important role in the host antiviral response.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Virology, College of Life Sciences, Wuhan University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xueyuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Yanhua</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hui</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Chengliang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Shi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C508603">IL6R protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019947">Receptors, Interleukin-6</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002478" MajorTopicYN="N">Cells, Cultured</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004266" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA Virus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007113" MajorTopicYN="Y">Immunity, Innate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007963" MajorTopicYN="N">Leukocytes, Mononuclear</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012327" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA Virus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019947" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Interleukin-6</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23946454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3807281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.01248-13</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.01248-13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hatziapostolou M, Polytarchou C, Aggelidou E, Drakaki A, Poultsides GA, Jaeger SA, Ogata H, Karin M, Struhl K, Hadzopoulou-Cladaras M, Iliopoulos D. 2011. An HNF4&#x3b1;-miRNA inflammatory feedback circuit regulates hepatocellular oncogenesis. Cell 147:1233&#x2013;1247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3251960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22153071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters BM, Jacobs S, Ehlers M, Vollmer P, M&#xfc;llberg J, Wolf E, Brem G, Meyer zum B&#xfc;schenfelde KH, Rose-John S. 1996. The function of the soluble interleukin 6 (IL-6) receptor in vivo: sensitization of human soluble IL-6 receptor transgenic mice towards IL-6 and prolongation of the plasma half-life of IL-6. J. Exp. Med. 183:1399&#x2013;1406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2192475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8666898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsson MB. 2005. Interleukin-6, secreted by human ovarian carcinoma cells, is a potent proangiogenic cytokine. Cancer Res. 65:10794&#x2013;10800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1534114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16322225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews V, Schuster B, Schutze S, Bussmeyer I, Ludwig A, Hundhausen C, Sadowski T, Saftig P, Hartmann D, Kallen KJ, Rose-John S. 2003. Cellular cholesterol depletion triggers shedding of the human interleukin-6 receptor by ADAM10 and ADAM17 (TACE). J. Biol. Chem. 278:38829&#x2013;38839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12832423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;llberg J, Schooltink H, Stoyan T, G&#xfc;nther M, Graeve L, Buse G, Mackiewicz A, Heinrich PC, Rose-John S. 1993. The soluble interleukin-6 receptor is generated by shedding. Eur. J. Immunol. 23:473&#x2013;480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8436181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;llberg J, Durie FH, Otten-Evans C, Alderson MR, Rose-John S, Cosman D, Black RA, Mohler KM. 1995. A metalloprotease inhibitor blocks shedding of the IL-6 receptor and the p60 TNF receptor. J. Immunol. 155:5198&#x2013;5205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7594530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horiuchi S, Koyanagi Y, Zhou Y, Miyamoto H, Tanaka Y, Waki M, Matsumoto A, Yamamoto M, Yamamoto N. 1994. Soluble interleukin-6 receptors released from T cell or granulocyte/macrophage cell lines and human peripheral blood mononuclear cells are generated through an alternative splicing mechanism. Eur. J. Immunol. 24:1945&#x2013;1948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8056053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones SA, Novick D, Horiuchi S, Yamanoto N, Szalai AJ, Fuller GM. 1999. C-reactive protein: a physiological activator of interleukin 6 receptor shedding. J. Exp. Med. 189:599&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2192917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9927522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose-John S, Scheller J, Elson G, Jones SA. 2006. Interleukin-6 biology is coordinated by membrane-bound and soluble receptors: role in inflammation and cancer. J. Leukoc. Biol. 80:227&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16707558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kishimoto T, Akira S, Narazaki M, Taga T. 1995. Interleukin-6 family of cytokines and gp130. Blood 86:1243&#x2013;1254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7632928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster B. 2003. Signaling of human ciliary neurotrophic factor (CNTF) revisited. The interleukin-6 receptor can serve as an &#x3b1;-receptor for CNTF. J. Biol. Chem. 278:9528&#x2013;9535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12643274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Cao Z, Chen J, Li R, Cao Y, Zhu C, Wu K, Wu J, Liu F, Zhu Y. 2012. Influenza A virus induces interleukin-27 through cyclooxygenase-2 and protein kinase A signaling. J. Biol. Chem. 287:11899&#x2013;11910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3320938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22343630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crab&#xe9; S, Guay-Giroux A, Tormo AJ, Duluc D, Lissilaa R, Guilhot F, Mavoungou-Bigouagou U, Lefouili F, Cognet I, Ferlin W, Elson G, Jeannin P, Gauchat JF. 2009. The IL-27 p28 subunit binds cytokine-like factor 1 to form a cytokine regulating NK and T cell activities requiring IL-6R for signaling. J. Immunol. 183:7692&#x2013;7702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19933857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garbers C, Spudy B, Aparicio-Siegmund S, Waetzig GH, Sommer J, Holscher C, Rose-John S, Grotzinger J, Lorenzen I, Scheller J. 2013. An interleukin-6 receptor-dependent molecular switch mediates signal transduction of the IL-27 cytokine subunit p28 (IL-30) via a gp130 protein receptor homodimer. J. Biol. Chem. 288:4346&#x2013;4354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3567685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23209286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Yang F, Liu Y, Gong R, Liu L, Feng Y, Hu P, Sun W, Hao Q, Kang L, Wu J, Zhu Y. 2009. Negative feedback regulation of IL-32 production by iNOS activation in response to dsRNA or influenza virus infection. Eur. J. Immunol. 39:1019&#x2013;1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19291698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murono S, Inoue H, Tanabe T, Joab I, Yoshizaki T, Furukawa M, Pagano JS. 2001. Induction of cyclooxygenase-2 by Epstein-Barr virus latent membrane protein 1 is involved in vascular endothelial growth factor production in nasopharyngeal carcinoma cells. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 98:6905&#x2013;6910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC34451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11381123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nu&#xf1;ez O. 2004. Increased intrahepatic cyclooxygenase 2, matrix metalloproteinase 2, and matrix metalloproteinase 9 expression is associated with progressive liver disease in chronic hepatitis C virus infection: role of viral core and NS5A proteins. Gut 53:1665&#x2013;1672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1774290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15479690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lara-Pezzi E, Gomez-Gaviro MV, Galvez BG, Mira E, Iniguez MA, Fresno M, Martinez C, Arroyo AG, Lopez-Cabrera M. 2002. The hepatitis B virus X protein promotes tumor cell invasion by inducing membrane-type matrix metalloproteinase-1 and cyclooxygenase-2 expression. J. Clin. Invest. 110:1831&#x2013;1838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC151651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12488433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed NA, El-Aleem SA, El-Hafiz HA, McMahon RFT. 2004. Distribution of constitutive (COX-1) and inducible (COX-2) cyclooxygenase in postviral human liver cirrhosis: a possible role for COX-2 in the pathogenesis of liver cirrhosis. J. Clin. Pathol. 57:350&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1770276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15047734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L, Jha BK, Wu A, Elliott R, Ziebuhr J, Gorbalenya AE, Silverman RH, Weiss SR. 2012. Antagonism of the interferon-induced OAS-RNase L pathway by murine coronavirus ns2 protein is required for virus replication and liver pathology. Cell Host Microbe 11:607&#x2013;616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3377938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22704621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadler AJ, Williams BRG. 2008. Interferon-inducible antiviral effectors. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 8:559&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2522268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18575461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, Gong R, Qu J, Zhou Y, Liu W, Chen M, Liu Y, Zhu Y, Wu J. 2012. Activation of the Ras/Raf/MEK pathway facilitates hepatitis C virus replication via attenuation of the interferon-JAK-STAT pathway. J. Virol. 86:1544&#x2013;1554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3264379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22114332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden MS, Ghosh S. 2008. Shared principles in NF-&#x3ba;B signaling. Cell 132:344&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18267068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arankalle VA, Lole KS, Arya RP, Tripathy AS, Ramdasi AY, Chadha MS, Sangle SA, Kadam DB. 2010. Role of host immune response and viral load in the differential outcome of pandemic H1N1 (2009) influenza virus infection in Indian patients. PLoS One 5:e13099. 10.1371/journal.pone.0013099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0013099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2948498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20957032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yl&#xf6;stalo JH, Bartosh TJ, Coble K, Prockop DJ. 2012. Human mesenchymal stem/stromal cells cultured as spheroids are self-activated to produce prostaglandin E2 that directs stimulated macrophages into an anti-inflammatory phenotype. Stem Cells 30:2283&#x2013;2296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3448872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22865689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karnowski A, Chevrier S, Belz GT, Mount A, Emslie D, D'Costa K, Tarlinton DM, Kallies A, Corcoran LM. 2012. B and T cells collaborate in antiviral responses via IL-6, IL-21, and transcriptional activator and coactivator, Oct2 and OBF-1. J. Exp. Med. 209:2049&#x2013;2064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3478936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23045607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interleukin-6 Receptor Mendelian Randomisation Analysis (IL6R MR) Consortium, Hingorani AD, Casas JP. 2012. The interleukin-6 receptor as a target for prevention of coronary heart disease: a Mendelian randomisation analysis. Lancet 379:1214&#x2013;1224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3316968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22421340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairo S, Buendia MA. 2012. How transient becomes stable: an epigenetic switch linking liver inflammation and tumorigenesis. J. Hepatol. 57:910&#x2013;912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22668642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Liu Y, Mukhtar MM, Gong R, Pan Y, Rasool ST, Gao Y, Kang L, Hao Q, Peng G, Chen Y, Chen X, Wu J, Zhu Y. 2008. Activation of interleukin-32 pro-inflammatory pathway in response to influenza A virus infection. PLoS One 3:e1985. 10.1371/journal.pone.0001985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0001985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2288676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18414668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue X, Wang H, Zhao F, Liu S, Wu J, Ren W, Zhu Y. 2012. Hepatitis B virus-induced calreticulin protein is involved in IFN resistance. J. Immunol. 189:279&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22661095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Netea MG, Azam T, Lewis EC, Joosten LAB, Wang M, Langenberg D, Meng X, Chan ED, Yoon D-Y, Ottenhoff T, Kim S-H, Dinarello CA. 2006. Mycobacterium tuberculosis induces interleukin-32 production through a caspase-1/IL-18/interferon-gamma-dependent mechanism. PLoS Med. 3:e277. 10.1371/journal.pmed.0030277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.0030277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1539091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16903774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou F, Liu Y, Liu L, Wu K, Wei W, Zhu Y, Wu J. 2007. Retinoic acid activates human inducible nitric oxide synthase gene through binding of RAR&#x3b1;/RXR&#x3b1; heterodimer to a novel retinoic acid response element in the promoter. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 355:494&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17306764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukhtar MM, Li S, Li W, Wan T, Mu Y, Wei W, Kang L, Rasool ST, Xiao Y, Zhu Y, Wu J. 2009. Single-chain intracellular antibodies inhibit influenza virus replication by disrupting interaction of proteins involved in viral replication and transcription. Int. J. Biochem. Cell Biol. 41:554&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18687409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arribas J, Coodly L, Vollmer P, Kishimoto TK, Rose-John S, Massagu&#xe9; J. 1996. Diverse cell surface protein ectodomains are shed by a system sensitive to metalloprotease inhibitors. J. Biol. Chem. 271:11376&#x2013;11382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8626692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett TA, Lynam EB, Sklar LA, Rogelj S. 1996. Hydroxamate-based metalloprotease inhibitor blocks shedding of l-selectin adhesion molecule from leukocytes: functional consequences for neutrophil aggregation. J. Immunol. 156:3093&#x2013;3097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8617927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohler KM, Sleath PR, Fitzner JN, Cerretti DP, Alderson M, Kerwar SS, Torrance DS, Otten-Evans C, Greenstreet T, Weerawarna K. 1994. Protection against a lethal dose of endotoxin by an inhibitor of tumour necrosis factor processing. Nature 370:218&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8028669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones SA, Horiuchi S, Novick D, Yamamoto N, Fuller GM. 1998. Shedding of the soluble IL-6 receptor is triggered by Ca2+ mobilization, while basal release is predominantly the product of differential mRNA splicing in THP-1 cells. Eur. J. Immunol. 28:3514&#x2013;3522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Gong R, Mu Y, Chen Y, Zhu C, Sun Z, Chen M, Liu Y, Zhu Y, Wu J. 2011. Hepatitis B virus induces a novel inflammation network involving three inflammatory factors, IL-29, IL-8, and cyclooxygenase-2. J. Immunol. 187:4844&#x2013;4860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21957142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pauli E-K, Schmolke M, Wolff T, Viemann D, Roth J, Bode JG, Ludwig S. 2008. Influenza A virus inhibits type I IFN signaling via NF-&#x3ba;B-dependent induction of SOCS-3 expression. PLoS Pathog. 4:e1000196. 10.1371/journal.ppat.1000196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1000196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2572141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18989459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prescott J, Hall P, Acuna-Retamar M, Ye C, Wathelet MG, Ebihara H, Feldmann H, Hjelle B. 2010. New World hantaviruses activate IFN&#x3bb; production in type I IFN-deficient Vero E6 cells. PLoS One 5:e11159. 10.1371/journal.pone.0011159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0011159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2887373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20567522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blight KJ, McKeating JA, Rice CM. 2002. Highly permissive cell lines for subgenomic and genomic hepatitis C virus RNA replication. J. Virol. 76:13001&#x2013;13014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC136668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12438626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumpter R, Loo YM, Foy E, Li K, Yoneyama M, Fujita T, Lemon SM, Gale M. 2005. Regulating intracellular antiviral defense and permissiveness to hepatitis C virus RNA replication through a cellular RNA helicase, RIG-I. J. Virol. 79:2689&#x2013;2699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC548482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15708988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong J. 2005. Robust hepatitis C virus infection in vitro. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 102:9294&#x2013;9299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1166622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15939869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Tainsky MA. 2011. Epigenetic silencing of IRF7 and/or IRF5 in lung cancer cells leads to increased sensitivity to oncolytic viruses. PLoS One 6:e28683. 10.1371/journal.pone.0028683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0028683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3237484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22194884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Oberley-Deegan R, Wang S, Nikrad M, Funk CJ, Hartshorn KL, Mason RJ. 2009. Differentiated human alveolar type II cells secrete antiviral IL-29 (IFN-&#x3bb;1) in response to influenza A infection. J. Immunol. 182:1296&#x2013;1304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4041086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19155475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiscott J, Grandvaux N, Sharma S, Tenoever BR, Servant MJ, Lin RT. 2003. Convergence of the NF-&#x3ba;B and interferon signaling pathways in the regulation of antiviral defense and apoptosis. Ann. N. Y. Acad. Sci. 1010:237&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15033728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IL6R Genetics Consortium Emerging Risk Factors Collaboration, Sarwar N, Butterworth AS, Freitag DF, Gregson J, Willeit P, Gorman DN, Gao P, Salaheen D, Rendon A, Nelson CP, Braund PS, Hall AS, Chasman DI, Tybj&#xe6;rg-Hansen A, Chambers JC, Benjamin EJ, Franks PW, Clarke R, Wilde AA, Trip MD, Steri M, Witteman JC, Qi L, van der Schoot CE, de Faire U, Erdmann J, Stringham HM, Koenig W, Rader DJ, Melzer D, Reich D, Psaty BM, Kleber ME, Panagiotakos DB, Willeit J, Wennberg P, Woodward M, Adamovic S, Rimm EB, Meade TW, Gillum RF, Shaffer JA, Hofman A, Onat A, Sundstr&#xf6;m J, Wassertheil-Smoller S, Mellstr&#xf6;m D, Gallacher J, Cushman M, et al. 2012. Interleukin-6 receptor pathways in coronary heart disease: a collaborative meta-analysis of 82 studies. Lancet 379:1205&#x2013;1213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3316940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22421339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronni T, Sareneva T, Pirhonen J, Julkunen I. 1995. Activation of IFN-&#x3b1;, IFN-&#x3b3;, MxA, and IFN regulatory factor 1 genes in influenza A virus-infected human peripheral blood mononuclear cells. J. Immunol. 154:2764&#x2013;2774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7876547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose-John S. 2001. Coordination of interleukin-6 biology by membrane bound and soluble receptors. Adv. Exp. Med. Biol. 495:145&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11774558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taga T. 1997. The signal transducer gp130 is shared by interleukin-6 family of haematopoietic and neurotrophic cytokines. Ann. Med. 29:63&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9073325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Hao Q, Peng N, Yue X, Wang Y, Chen Y, Wu J, Zhu Y. 2012. Major vault protein: a virus-induced host factor against viral replication through the induction of type-I interferon. Hepatology 56:57&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22318991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hata N, Sato M, Takaoka A, Asagiri M, Tanaka N, Taniguchi T. 2001. Constitutive IFN-&#x3b1;/&#x3b2; signal for efficient IFN-&#x3b1;/&#x3b2; gene induction by virus. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 285:518&#x2013;525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11444873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato M, Suemori H, Hata N, Asagiri M, Ogasawara K, Nakao K, Nakaya T, Katsuki M, Noguchi S, Tanaka N, Taniguchi T. 2000. Distinct and essential roles of transcription factors IRF-3 and IRF-7 in response to viruses for IFN-&#x3b1;/&#x3b2; gene induction. Immunity 13:539&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11070172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda K, Takaoka A, Taniguchi T. 2006. Type I interferon gene induction by the interferon regulatory factor family of transcription factors. Immunity 25:349&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16979567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q, Verma IM. 2002. NF-&#x3ba;B regulation in the immune system. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2:725&#x2013;734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12360211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercurio FH. 1997. IKK-1 and IKK-2: cytokine-activated I&#x3ba;B kinases essential for NF-&#x3ba;B activation. Science 278:860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9346484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zandi E, Rothwarf DM, Delhase M, Hayakawa M, Karin M. 1997. The I&#x3ba;B kinase complex (IKK) contains two kinase subunits, IKK&#x3b1; and IKK&#x3b2;, necessary for I&#x3ba;B phosphorylation and NF&#x3ba;B activation. Cell 91:243&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9346241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin J, Liu S, Zhu Y. 2013. An overview of the highly pathogenic H5N1 influenza virus. Virol. Sin. 28:3&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7090813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23325419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinz D, Peters M, Prange R, Gerken G, Rose-John S. 2001. Possible role of human interleukin-6 and soluble interleukin-6 receptor in hepatitis B virus infection. J. Viral Hepat. 8:186&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11380796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;sel M, Quasdorff M, Wiegmann K, Webb D, Zedler U, Broxtermann M, Tedjokusumo R, Esser K, Arzberger S, Kirschning CJ, Langenkamp A, Falk C, B&#xfc;ning H, Rose-John S, Protzer U. 2009. Not interferon, but interleukin-6 controls early gene expression in hepatitis B virus infection. Hepatology 50:1773&#x2013;1782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19937696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galun E, Nahor O, Eid A, Jurim O, Rose-John S, Blum HE, Nussbaum O, Ilan E, Daudi N, Shouval D, Reisner Y, Dagan S. 2000. Human interleukin-6 facilitates hepatitis B virus infection in vitro and in vivo. Virology 270:299&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10792989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohno H, Kaneko S, Kobayashi K, Murakami S. 1997. Human hepatitis B virus enhancer 1 is responsive to human interleukin-6. J. Med. Virol. 52:413&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9260690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>