<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16269717</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enteroviruses and bacteriophages in bathing waters.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6838</StartPage><EndPage>6844</EndPage><MedlinePgn>6838-44</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>A new procedure for detecting and counting enteroviruses based on the VIRADEN method applied to 10 liters of seawater was examined. It improved the efficiency of detection by taking into account both the number of positive isolations and numbers found with traditional methods. It was then used to quantify viruses in bathing waters. A number of bacterial indicators and bacteriophages were also tested. Cultivable enteroviruses were detected in 55% of the samples, most of which complied with bacteriological criteria. In contrast, viral genomes were only detected in 20% of the samples by reverse transcription-PCR. Somatic coliphages outnumbered all other indicators. F-specific RNA phages were detected in only 15% of the samples, whereas phages infecting Bacteroides thetaiotaomicron were detected in 70% of samples. A numerical relationship between the numbers of enteroviruses and the numbers of enterococci and somatic coliphages was observed. In situ inactivation experiments showed that viruses persisted significantly longer than the bacterial indicators. Only somatic coliphages and bacteriophages infecting Bacteroides persisted longer than the viruses. These results explain the numbers of enteroviruses and indicators in bathing waters attending the numbers usually found in sewage in the area. Somatic coliphages show a very good potential to predict the risk of viruses being present in bathing waters.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moc&#xe9;-Llivina</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Biology, University of Barcelona, Avda. Diagonal, 645 Edifici Annex, Planta 0, E-08028 Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lucena</LastName><ForeName>Francisco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jofre</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001435" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacteriophages</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003090" MajorTopicYN="N">Coliphages</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004755" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterobacteriaceae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016983" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterococcus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004926" MajorTopicYN="N">Escherichia coli</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012317" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA Phages</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011998" MajorTopicYN="Y">Recreation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012623" MajorTopicYN="N">Seawater</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013030" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Spain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014776" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Cultivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16269717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1287676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.11.6838-6844.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">71/11/6838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American Public Health Association. 1998. Standard methods for the examination of water and wastewater, 20th ed. American Public Health Association, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beekwilder, J., R. Nieuwenhuizen, A. H. Havelaar, and J. van Duin. 1996. An oligonucleotide hybridization assay for the identification and enumeration of F-specific RNA phages in surface water. J. Appl. Bacteriol. 80:179-186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8642014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkelman, R., G. King, C. Gerba, C. Haas, J. Rose, and M. Sobsey. 4.  August 2004, posting date. Water quality criteria for bacteria for coastal and&#x2009;Great Lakes waters. [Online.] American Society for Microbiology, Washington, D.C. http://www.asm.org/Policy/index.asp?bid=29781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung, H., and M. D. Sobsey. 1993. Comparative survival of indicator viruses and enteric viruses in seawater and sediment. Water Sci. Technol. 27:425-429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contreras-Coll, N. 2000. Bacteri&#xf3;fagos de bacterias ent&#xe9;ricas en aguas de ba&#xf1;o. Ph.D. thesis. University of Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Alessio, D., T. E. Minor, C. I. Allen, A. A. Tsiatis, and D. B. Nelson. 1981. A study of the proportion of swimmers among well controls and children with enterovirus-like illness shedding or not shedding enteroviruses. Am. J. Epidemiol. 113:533-541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7223734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denis-Mize, K., G. S. Fout, D. R. Dahling, and D. Francy. 2004. Detection of human enteric viruses in stream water with RT-PCR and cell culture. J. Water Health 2:37-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15384728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewailly, E., C. Poirier, and F. M. Meyer. 1986. Health hazards associated with windsurfing on polluted waters. Am. J. Public Health 76:662-668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1646791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3706597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson, K. A., D. W. Griffin, and J. H. Paul. 2002. Detection, quantification and identification of enteroviruses from surface waters and sponge tissue from the Florida Keys using real-time PCR. Water Res. 36:2505-2514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12153016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enriquez, C. E., C. J. Hurst, and C. P. Gerba. 1995. Survival of the enteric adenoviruses 40 and 41 in tap, sea and waste water. Water Res. 29:2548-2553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Economic Commission. 1976. The Council of European Economic Communities Directive of 8 December, 1975 concerning the quality of bathing waters. Official J. the European Communities, directive no. 76/160/EEC. Council of European Economic Communities, Brussels, Belgium.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Economic Commission. 2002. Proposal for a Directive of the European Parliament and of the Council concerning the quality of bathing waters. COM(2002) 581 final. Council of European Economic Communities, Brussels, Belgium.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garin, D., F. Fuchs, J. M. Crance, Y. Rouby, J. C. Chapalain, D. Lamarque, A. M. Gounot, and M. Aymard. 1994. Exposure to enteroviruses and hepatitis A virus among divers in environmental waters in France: first biological and serological survey of a controlled cohort. Epidemiol. Infect. 113:541-549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2271328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7995363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gassilloud, B., L. Schwartzbrod, and C. Gantzer. 2003. Presence of viral genomes in mineral water: a sufficient condition to assume infectious risk? Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 69:3965-3969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC165182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12839768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba, C. P., S. M. Goyal, R. L. Labelle, I. Cech, and G. F. Bodgan. 1979. Failure of indicator bacteria to reflect the occurrence of enteroviruses in marine waters. Am. J. Public Health 69:1116-1119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1619291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gow, J. W., W. M. H. Behan, G. B. Clements, C. Woodall, M. Riding, and P. O. Behan. 1991. Enteroviral RNA sequences detected by polymerase chain reaction in muscle of patients with postviral fatigue syndrome. Br. Med. J. 302:692-696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1669122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1850635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IAWPRC Study Group on Health Related Water Microbiology. 1991. Bacteriophages as model viruses in water quality control. Water Res. 25:529-545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Organisation for Standardisation. 1995. ISO 10705-1. Water quality: detection and enumeration of bacteriophages. Part 1: enumeration of F-specific RNA bacteriophages. International Organisation for Standardisation, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Organisation for Standardisation. 2000. ISO 10705-2. Water quality: detection and enumeration of bacteriophages. Part 2: enumeration of somatic coliphages. International Organisation for Standardisation, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Organisation for Standardisation. 2001. ISO 10705-4. Water quality: detection and enumeration of bacteriophages. Part 4: enumeration of bacteriophages infecting Bacteroides fragilis. International Organisation for Standardisation, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, S., R. Noble, and W. Chu. 2001. Human adenoviruses and coliphages in urban runoff-impacted coastal waters of Southern California. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 67:179-184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11133443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuan, M. M. 1997. Detection and rapid differentiation of human enteroviruses following genomic amplification. J. Clin. Microbiol. 35:2598-2601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC230017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9316914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lina, B., B. Pozzetto, L. Andreoletti, E. Beguier, T. Bourlet, E. Dussaix, L. Grangeot-Keros, B. Gratacap-Cavallier, C. Henquell, M. C. Legrand-Quillien, A. Novillo, P. Palmer, J. Petitjean, K. Sandres, P. Dubreuil, H. Fleury, F. Freymuth, I. Leparc-Goffart, D. Hober, J. Izopet, H. Kopecka, Y. Lazizi, H. Lafeuille, P. Lebon, and M. Aymard. 1996. Multicenter evaluation of a commercially available PCR assay for diagnosing enterovirus infection in a panel of cerebrospinal fluid specimens. J. Clin. Microbiol. 34:3002-3006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC229449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8940438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long, S. C., and M. D. Sobsey. 2004. A comparison of the survival of F+RNA and F+DNA coliphages in lake water microcosms. J. Water Health 2:15-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15384726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucena, F., M. Divizia, S. Bisiagos, J. M. Crance, and R. Deloince. 1991. Extraction et concentration des virus des milieux hydriques, p. 71-106. In L.&#x2009;Schwartzbrod (ed.), Virologie des milieux hydriques. Tec &amp; Doc. Lavoisier, Paris, France.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucena, F., A. E. Duran, A. Moron, E. Calderon, C. Campos, and C. Gantzer. 2004. Reduction of bacterial indicators and bacteriophages infecting fecal bacteria in primary and secondary wastewater treatments. J. Appl. Microbiol. 97:1069-1076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15479424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucena, F., C. Finance, J. Jofre, J. Sancho, and L. Schwartzbrod. 1982. Viral pollution of superficial waters (river water and seawater) from the urban area of Barcelona (Spain). Water Res. 16:173-177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick, J. L. 1984. Enteric viruses in water. Monogr. Virol. 15:1-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mena, K. D., C. P. Gerba, C. N. Haas, and J. B. Rose. 2003. Risk assessment of waterborne coxsackievirus. J. Am. Water Works Assoc. 95:122-131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez, J., A. Audicana, A. Isern, J. Llaneza, B. Moreno, M. L. Tarancon, J. Jofre, and F. Lucena. 2004. Standardised evaluation of the performance of a simple membrane filtration-elution method to concentrate bacteriophages from drinking water. J. Virol. Methods 117:19-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15019256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metcalf, T. G., J. L. Melnick, and M. K. Estes. 1995. Environmental virology: from detection of viruses in sewage and water by isolation to identification by molecular biology&#x2014;a trip of over 50 years. Annu. Rev. Microbiol. 49:461-487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8561468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moc&#xe9;-Llivina, L., J. Jofre, X. M&#xe9;ndez, D. Akkelidou, F. Lucena, and G. T. Papageorgiou. 2002. Counting cytopathogenic virus adsorbed to cellulose nitrate membrane filters as a simple method for counting viruses in raw sewage and sewage effluents. J. Virol. Methods 102:83-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11879696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moc&#xe9;-Llivina, L., F. Lucena, and J. Jofre. 2004. Double-layer plaque assay for quantification of enteroviruses. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 70:2801-2805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC404442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15128535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris, R. 1991. The EC bathing water virological standard: is it realistic. Water Sci. Technol. 24:49-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscillo, M., A. Carducci, G. La Rosa, L. Cantiani, and C. Marianelli. 1997. Enteric virus detection in Adriatic seawater by cell culture, polymerase chain reaction and polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis. Water Res. 31:1980-1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble, R. T., S. M. Allen, A. D. Blackwood, W. Chu, S. C. Jiang, G. L. Lovelance, M. D. Sobsey, J. R. Stewart, and D. A. Wait. 2003. Use of viral pathogens and indicators to differentiate between human and non-human fecal contamination in a microbial source tracking comparison study. J. Water Health 1:195-207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15382724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuanualsuwan, S., and D. O. Cliver. 2002. Pretreatment to avoid positive RT-PCR results with inactivated viruses. J. Virol. Methods 104:217-225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12088831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmateer, G. A., B. J. Dutka, E. M. Janzen, S. M. Meissner, and M. G. Sakellaris. 1991. Coliphages and bacteriophages as indicators of recreational water quality. Water Res. 25:355-357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papageorgiou, G. T., L. Moc&#xe9;-Llivina, C. G. Christodoulou, F. Lucena, D. Akkelidou, E. Ioannou, and J. Jofre. 2000. A simple methodological approach for counting and identifying culturable viruses adsorbed to cellulose nitrate membrane filters. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 66:194-198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC91805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10618223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payan, A., J. Ebdon, H. Taylor, C. Gantzer, J. Ottoson, G. T. Papageorgiou, A. R. Blanch, F. Lucena, J. Jofre, and M. Muniesa. 2005. Method for isolation of Bacteroides bacteriophage host strains suitable for tracking sources of fecal pollution in water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 71:5659-5662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1214671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16151173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pina, S., M. Puig, F. Lucena, J. Jofre, and R. Girones. 1998. Viral pollution in the environment and in shellfish: human adenovirus detection by PCR as an index of human viruses. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 64:3376-3382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC106735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9726885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose, J. B., R. L. Mullinax, S. N. Singh, M. V. Yates, and C. P. Gerba. 1987. Occurrence of rotaviruses and enteroviruses in recreational waters of Oak Creek, Arizona. Water Res. 21:1375-1381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaper, M., A. E. Duran, and J. Jofre. 2002. Comparative resistance of phage isolates of four genotypes of F-specific RNA bacteriophages to various inactivation processes. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:3702-3707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC124048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12147462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaper, M., and J. Jofre. 2000. Comparison of methods for detecting genotypes of F-specific RNA bacteriophages and fingerprinting the origin of fecal pollution in water samples. J. Virol. Methods 89:1-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10996634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaper, M., J. Jofre, M. Uys, and W. O. K. Grabow. 2002. Distribution of genotypes of F-specific RNA bacteriophages in human and non-human sources of fecal pollution in South Africa and Spain. J. Appl. Microbiol. 92:657-667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11966906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scientific Committee on Toxicity, Ecotoxicity, and Environment. 2004. Bathing water quality. [Online.] European Economic Commission, Brussels, Belgium. http://www.europa.eu.int/water/water-bathing/index_en.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senouci, S., A. Maul, and L. Schwartzbrod. 1996. Comparison study on three protocols used to concentrate poliovirus type 1 from drinking water. Zentralbl. Hyg. Med. 198:307-317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9353536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinton, L. W., R. K. Finlay, and P. A. Lynch. 1999. Sunlight inactivation of fecal bacteriophages and bacteria in sewage-polluted seawater. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 65:3605-3613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC91541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10427056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, E. M., and C. P. Gerba. 1982. Laboratory methods for the growth and detection of animal viruses, p. 15-47. In C. P. Gerba and S. M. Goyal (ed.), Methods in environmental virology. Marcel Dekker, Inc., New York, N.Y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinner, M. L., and G. D. Di Giovanni. 2001. Detection and identification of mammalian reoviruses in surface water by combined cell culture and reverse transcription-PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 67:3016-3020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11425715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SPSS, Inc. 1999. Statistical package for social sciences. SPSS Inc., Chicago, Ill.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strikas, R. A., L. J. Anderson, and R. A. Parker. 1986. Temporal and geographic patterns of isolates of nonpolio enteroviruses in the United States, 1970-1983. J. Infect. Dis. 153:346-351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3003207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 1986. EPA's ambient water quality criteria for bacteria. EPA 440/5-84-002. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 2000. Male-specific (F+) and somatic coliphage in water by single agar layer procedure. EPA 821.R-00-010. U. S. Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 2004. Water quality standards for coastal and Great Lakes recreation water. 40 CFR Part 31. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Olphen, M., H. A. M. de Bruin, A. H. Havelaar, and J. F. Schiven. 1991. The virological quality of recreational waters in The Netherlands. Water Sci. Technol. 24:201-212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetz, J. J., E. K. Lipp, D. W. Griffin, J. Lukasik, D. Wait, M. D. Sobsey, T. M. Scott, and J. B. Rose. 2004. Presence, infectivity, and stability of enteric viruses in seawater: relationship to marine water quality in the Florida Keys. Marine Pollut. Bull. 48:698-704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15041426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 2003. Guidelines for safe recreational waters. Volume 1. Coastal and fresh waters. World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>