<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">19414569</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2009</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-6596</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2009</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Antimicrobial agents and chemotherapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Antimicrob Agents Chemother</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Novel antiviral agent DTriP-22 targets RNA-dependent RNA polymerase of enterovirus 71.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2740</StartPage><EndPage>2747</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2740-7</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/AAC.00101-09</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) has emerged as an important virulent neurotropic enterovirus in young children. DTriP-22 (4{4-[(2-bromo-phenyl)-(3-methyl-thiophen-2-yl)-methyl]-piperazin-1-yl}-1-pheny-1H-pyrazolo[3,4-d]pyrimidine) was found to be a novel and potent inhibitor of EV71. The molecular target of this compound was identified by analyzing DTriP-22-resistant viruses. A substitution of lysine for Arg163 in EV71 3D polymerase rendered the virus drug resistant. DTriP-22 exhibited the ability to inhibit viral replication by reducing viral RNA accumulation. The compound suppressed the accumulated levels of both positive- and negative-stranded viral RNA during virus infection. An in vitro polymerase assay indicated that DTriP-22 inhibited the poly(U) elongation activity, but not the VPg uridylylation activity, of EV71 polymerase. These findings demonstrate that the nonnucleoside analogue DTriP-22 acts as a novel inhibitor of EV71 polymerase. DTriP-22 also exhibited a broad spectrum of antiviral activity against other picornaviruses, which highlights its potential in the development of antiviral agents.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Tzu-Chun</ForeName><Initials>TC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biotechnology and Laboratory Science, Chang Gung University, 259 Wen-Hua 1st Rd., Kwei-Shan, Taoyuan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Hwan-You</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Pei-Fen</ForeName><Initials>PF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chern</LastName><ForeName>Jyh-Haur</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsu</LastName><ForeName>John Tsu-An</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Chu-Yi</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shih</LastName><ForeName>Shin-Ru</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2009</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Antimicrob Agents Chemother</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0315061</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0066-4804</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000998">Antiviral Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011994">Recombinant Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.7.48</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012324">RNA-Dependent RNA Polymerase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000998" MajorTopicYN="N">Antiviral Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045744" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line, Tumor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002522" MajorTopicYN="N">Chlorocebus aethiops</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004285" MajorTopicYN="N">Dogs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000201" MajorTopicYN="Y">enzymology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006367" MajorTopicYN="N">HeLa Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012324" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA-Dependent RNA Polymerase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="Y">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011994" MajorTopicYN="N">Recombinant Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014709" MajorTopicYN="N">Vero Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19414569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2704669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00101-09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">AAC.00101-09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar, S., Y. F. Chan, and S. K. Lam. 2000. Outbreaks of enterovirus 71 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 342:355-356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10660400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar, S., H. Y. Chee, M. F. Al-Kobaisi, J. Xiaoshan, K. B. Chua, and S. K. Lam. 1999. Identification of enterovirus 71 isolates from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) with fatal cases of encephalomyelitis in Malaysia. Virus Res. 61:1-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10426204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander, J. P., Jr., L. Baden, M. A. Pallansch, and L. J. Anderson. 1994. Enterovirus 71 infections and neurologic disease&#x2014;United States, 1977-1991. J. Infect. Dis. 169:905-908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8133108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita, M., T. Wakita, and H. Shimizu. 2008. Characterization of pharmacologically active compounds that inhibit poliovirus and enterovirus 71 infectivity. J. Gen. Virol. 89:2518-2530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18796721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K. P., K. T. Goh, C. Y. Chong, E. S. Teo, G. Lau, and A. E. Ling. 2003. Epidemic hand, foot and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:78-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., L. M. Huang, S. S. Gau, Y. Y. Wu, S. H. Hsia, T. Y. Fan, K. L. Lin, Y. C. Huang, C. Y. Lu, and T. Y. Lin. 2007. Neurodevelopment and cognition in children after enterovirus 71 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 356:1226-1234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17377160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., T. Y. Lin, K. H. Hsu, Y. C. Huang, K. L. Lin, C. Hsueh, S. R. Shih, H. C. Ning, M. S. Hwang, H. S. Wang, and C. Y. Lee. 1999. Clinical features and risk factors of pulmonary oedema after enterovirus-71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet 354:1682-1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T. C., K. F. Weng, S. C. Chang, J. Y. Lin, P. N. Huang, and S. R. Shih. 2008. Development of antiviral agents for enteroviruses. J. Antimicrob. Chemother. 62:1169-1173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18931391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chern, J. H., K. S. Shia, T. A. Hsu, C. L. Tai, C. C. Lee, Y. C. Lee, C. S. Chang, S. N. Tseng, and S. R. Shih. 2004. Design, synthesis, and structure-activity relationships of pyrazolo[3,4-d]pyrimidines: a novel class of potent enterovirus inhibitors. Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 14:2519-2525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15109643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Clercq, E. 1993. Antiviral agents: characteristic activity spectrum depending on the molecular target with which they interact. Adv. Virus Res. 42:1-55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8430518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Palma, A. M., G. Purstinger, E. Wimmer, A. K. Patick, K. Andries, B. Rombaut, E. De Clercq, and J. Neyts. 2008. Potential use of antiviral agents in polio eradication. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 14:545-551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2570929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18394270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Marco, S., C. Volpari, L. Tomei, S. Altamura, S. Harper, F. Narjes, U. Koch, M. Rowley, R. De Francesco, G. Migliaccio, and A. Carfi. 2005. Interdomain communication in hepatitis C virus polymerase abolished by small molecule inhibitors bound to a novel allosteric site. J. Biol. Chem. 280:29765-29770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15955819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto, T., M. Chikahira, S. Yoshida, H. Ebira, A. Hasegawa, A. Totsuka, and O. Nishio. 2002. Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol. Immunol. 46:621-627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furuta, Y., K. Takahashi, M. Kuno-Maekawa, H. Sangawa, S. Uehara, K. Kozaki, N. Nomura, H. Egawa, and K. Shiraki. 2005. Mechanism of action of T-705 against influenza virus. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 49:981-986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC549233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15728892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber, K., E. Wimmer, and A. V. Paul. 2001. Biochemical and genetic studies of the initiation of human rhinovirus 2 RNA replication: identification of a cis-replicating element in the coding sequence of 2Apro. J. Virol. 75:10979-10990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC114678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11602738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gohara, D. W., C. S. Ha, S. Kumar, B. Ghosh, J. J. Arnold, T. J. Wisniewski, and C. E. Cameron. 1999. Production of &#x201c;authentic&#x201d; poliovirus RNA-dependent RNA polymerase (3D(pol)) by ubiquitin-protease-mediated cleavage in Escherichia coli. Protein Expr. Purif. 17:128-138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10497078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodfellow, I., Y. Chaudhry, A. Richardson, J. Meredith, J. W. Almond, W. Barclay, and D. J. Evans. 2000. Identification of a cis-acting replication element within the poliovirus coding region. J. Virol. 74:4590-4600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC111979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10775595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goris, N., A. De Palma, J. F. Toussaint, I. Musch, J. Neyts, and K. De Clercq. 2007. 2&#x2032;-C-methylcytidine as a potent and selective inhibitor of the replication of foot-and-mouth disease virus. Antivir. Res. 73:161-168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17055073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graci, J. D., K. Too, E. D. Smidansky, J. P. Edathil, E. W. Barr, D. A. Harki, J. E. Galarraga, J. M. Bollinger, Jr., B. R. Peterson, D. Loakes, D. M. Brown, and C. E. Cameron. 2008. Lethal mutagenesis of picornaviruses with N-6-modified purine nucleoside analogues. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 52:971-979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2258490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18180344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harki, D. A., J. D. Graci, J. E. Galarraga, W. J. Chain, C. E. Cameron, and B. R. Peterson. 2006. Synthesis and antiviral activity of 5-substituted cytidine analogues: identification of a potent inhibitor of viral RNA-dependent RNA polymerases. J. Med. Chem. 49:6166-6169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2094219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17034123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M., E. R. Chen, K. H. Hsu, S. J. Twu, K. T. Chen, S. F. Tsai, J. R. Wang, S. R. Shih, et al. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929-935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehle, J., B. Roth, C. Metzger, A. Pfitzner, and G. Enders. 2003. Molecular characterization of an Enterovirus 71 causing neurological disease in Germany. J. Neurovirol. 9:126-128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12587076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirsi, J. J., J. A. North, P. A. McKernan, B. K. Murray, P. G. Canonico, J. W. Huggins, P. C. Srivastava, and R. K. Robins. 1983. Broad-spectrum antiviral activity of 2-beta-d-ribofuranosylselenazole-4-carboxamide, a new antiviral agent. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 24:353-361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC185325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6615611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kishimoto, C., C. S. Crumpacker, and W. H. Abelmann. 1988. Ribavirin treatment of murine coxsackievirus B3 myocarditis with analyses of lymphocyte subsets. J. Am. Coll. Cardiol. 12:1334-1341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2844874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo, C. J., J. J. Shie, J. M. Fang, G. R. Yen, J. T. Hsu, H. G. Liu, S. N. Tseng, S. C. Chang, C. Y. Lee, S. R. Shih, and P. H. Liang. 2008. Design, synthesis, and evaluation of 3C protease inhibitors as anti-enterovirus 71 agents. Bioorg. Med. Chem. 16:7388-7398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7125518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18583140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. H., C. M. Li, P. Ling, F. H. Shen, S. H. Chen, C. C. Liu, C. K. Yu, and S. H. Chen. 2008. Ribavirin reduces mortality in enterovirus 71-infected mice by decreasing viral replication. J. Infect. Dis. 197:854-857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7109938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18279075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, J. Y., M. L. Li, P. N. Huang, K. Y. Chien, J. T. Horng, and S. R. Shih. 2008. Heterogeneous nuclear ribonuclear protein K interacts with the enterovirus 71 5&#x2032; untranslated region and participates in virus replication. J. Gen. Virol. 89:2540-2549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18796723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, J. Y., M. L. Li, and S. R. Shih. 2009. Far upstream element binding protein 2 interacts with enterovirus 71 internal ribosomal entry site and negatively regulates viral translation. Nucleic Acids Res. 37:47-59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2615614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19010963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., S. J. Twu, M. S. Ho, L. Y. Chang, and C. Y. Lee. 2003. Enterovirus 71 outbreaks, Taiwan: occurrence and recognition. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:291-293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12643822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobert, P. E., N. Escriou, J. Ruelle, and T. Michiels. 1999. A coding RNA sequence acts as a replication signal in cardioviruses. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 96:11560-11565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC18073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10500216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason, P. W., S. V. Bezborodova, and T. M. Henry. 2002. Identification and characterization of a cis-acting replication element (cre) adjacent to the internal ribosome entry site of foot-and-mouth disease virus. J. Virol. 76:9686-9694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC136496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12208947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKnight, K. L., and S. M. Lemon. 1998. The rhinovirus type 14 genome contains an internally located RNA structure that is required for viral replication. RNA 4:1569-1584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1369726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9848654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., I. Stratov, L. Nagarajan, and S. Davis. 2001. Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin. Infect. Dis. 32:236-242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P. C. 2002. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 26:91-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul, A. V., J. Peters, J. Mugavero, J. Yin, J. H. van Boom, and E. Wimmer. 2003. Biochemical and genetic studies of the VPg uridylylation reaction catalyzed by the RNA polymerase of poliovirus. J. Virol. 77:891-904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC140777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12502805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raboud, J. M., S. Rae, S. Vella, P. R. Harrigan, R. Bucciardini, V. Fragola, D. Ricciardulli, and J. S. Montaner, et al. 1999. Meta-analysis of two randomized controlled trials comparing combined zidovudine and didanosine therapy with combined zidovudine, didanosine, and nevirapine therapy in patients with HIV. J. Acquir. Immune Defic. Syndr. 22:260-266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10770346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih, S. R., M. C. Tsai, S. N. Tseng, K. F. Won, K. S. Shia, W. T. Li, J. H. Chern, G. W. Chen, C. C. Lee, Y. C. Lee, K. C. Peng, and Y. S. Chao. 2004. Mutation in enterovirus 71 capsid protein VP1 confers resistance to the inhibitory effects of pyridyl imidazolidinone. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 48:3523-3529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC514779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15328120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidwell, R. W., J. H. Huffman, G. P. Khare, L. B. Allen, J. T. Witkowski, and R. K. Robins. 1972. Broad-spectrum antiviral activity of Virazole: 1-beta-D-ribofuranosyl-1,2,4-triazole-3-carboxamide. Science 177:705-706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4340949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smee, D. F., P. A. McKernan, L. D. Nord, R. C. Willis, C. R. Petrie, T. M. Riley, G. R. Revankar, R. K. Robins, and R. A. Smith. 1987. Novel pyrazolo[3,4-d]pyrimidine nucleoside analog with broad-spectrum antiviral activity. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 31:1535-1541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC174985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3435102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staszewski, S., J. Morales-Ramirez, K. T. Tashima, A. Rachlis, D. Skiest, J. Stanford, R. Stryker, P. Johnson, D. F. Labriola, D. Farina, D. J. Manion, N. M. Ruiz, et al. 1999. Efavirenz plus zidovudine and lamivudine, efavirenz plus indinavir, and indinavir plus zidovudine and lamivudine in the treatment of HIV-1 infection in adults. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:1865-1873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10601505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takegami, T., R. J. Kuhn, C. W. Anderson, and E. Wimmer. 1983. Membrane-dependent uridylylation of the genome-linked protein VPg of poliovirus. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 80:7447-7451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC389968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6324172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tedesco, R., A. N. Shaw, R. Bambal, D. Chai, N. O. Concha, M. G. Darcy, D. Dhanak, D. M. Fitch, A. Gates, W. G. Gerhardt, D. L. Halegoua, C. Han, G. A. Hofmann, V. K. Johnston, A. C. Kaura, N. Liu, R. M. Keenan, J. Lin-Goerke, R. T. Sarisky, K. J. Wiggall, M. N. Zimmerman, and K. J. Duffy. 2006. 3-(1,1-dioxo-2H-(1,2,4)-benzothiadiazin-3-yl)-4-hydroxy-2(1H)-quinolinones, potent inhibitors of hepatitis C virus RNA-dependent RNA polymerase. J. Med. Chem. 49:971-983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16451063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, A. A., and O. B. Peersen. 2004. Structural basis for proteolysis-dependent activation of the poliovirus RNA-dependent RNA polymerase. EMBO J. 23:3462-3471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC516629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15306852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomei, L., S. Altamura, L. Bartholomew, A. Biroccio, A. Ceccacci, L. Pacini, F. Narjes, N. Gennari, M. Bisbocci, I. Incitti, L. Orsatti, S. Harper, I. Stansfield, M. Rowley, R. De Francesco, and G. Migliaccio. 2003. Mechanism of action and antiviral activity of benzimidazole-based allosteric inhibitors of the hepatitis C virus RNA-dependent RNA polymerase. J. Virol. 77:13225-13231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC296079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14645579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomei, L., S. Altamura, L. Bartholomew, M. Bisbocci, C. Bailey, M. Bosserman, A. Cellucci, E. Forte, I. Incitti, L. Orsatti, U. Koch, R. De Francesco, D. B. Olsen, S. S. Carroll, and G. Migliaccio. 2004. Characterization of the inhibition of hepatitis C virus RNA replication by nonnucleosides. J. Virol. 78:938-946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC368780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14694125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstrepen, W. A., S. Kuhn, M. M. Kockx, M. E. Van De Vyvere, and A. H. Mertens. 2001. Rapid detection of enterovirus RNA in cerebrospinal fluid specimens with a novel single-tube real-time reverse transcription-PCR assay. J. Clin. Microbiol. 39:4093-4096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11682535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y., M. Yi, D. J. Evans, P. Simmonds, and S. M. Lemon. 2008. Identification of a conserved RNA replication element (cre) within the 3Dpol-coding sequence of hepatoviruses. J. Virol. 82:10118-10128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2566277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18684812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>