<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16757623</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2006</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0095-1137</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>44</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2006</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Combining multiplex reverse transcription-PCR and a diagnostic microarray to detect and differentiate enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2212</StartPage><EndPage>2219</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2212-9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Cluster A enteroviruses, including enterovirus 71 (EV71) and coxsackievirus A16 (CA16), are known to cause hand-foot-and-mouth disease (HFMD). Despite the close genetic relationship between these two viruses, EV71 is generally known to be a more perpetuating pathogen involved in severe clinical manifestations and deaths. While the serotyping of enteroviruses is mostly done by conventional immunological methods, many clinical isolates remain unclassifiable due to the limited number of antibodies against enterovirus surface proteins. Array-based assays are able to detect several serotypes with high accuracy. We combined an enterovirus microarray with multiplex reverse transcription-PCR to try to develop a method of sensitively and accurately detecting and differentiating EV71 and CA16. In an effort to design serotype-specific probes for detection of the virus, we first did an elaborate bioinformatic analysis of the sequence database derived from different enterovirus serotypes. We then constructed a microarray using 60-mer degenerate oligonucleotide probes covalently bound to array slides. Using this enterovirus microarray to study 144 clinical specimens from patients infected with HFMD or suspected to have HFMD, we found that it had a diagnostic accuracy of 92.0% for EV71 and 95.8% for CA16. Diagnostic accuracy for other enteroviruses (non-EV71 or -CA16) was 92.0%. All specimens were analyzed in parallel by real-time PCR and subsequently confirmed by neutralization tests. This highly sensitive array-based assay may become a useful alternative in clinical diagnostics of EV71 and CA16.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Tsan-Chi</ForeName><Initials>TC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Molecular and Genomic Medicine, National Health Research Institutes, Zhunan, Miaoli 350, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Guang-Wu</ForeName><Initials>GW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsiung</LastName><ForeName>Chao Agnes</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Jyh-Yuan</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shih</LastName><ForeName>Shin-Ru</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Yiu-Kay</ForeName><Initials>YK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Juang</LastName><ForeName>Jyh-Lyh</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D023362">Evaluation Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505564</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0095-1137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015342">DNA Probes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015342" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA Probes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="Y">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020411" MajorTopicYN="N">Oligonucleotide Array Sequence Analysis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012680" MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity and Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2006</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2006</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2006</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2006</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16757623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1489440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.02393-05</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">44/6/2212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Altschul, S. F., T. L. Madden, A. A. Schaffer, J. Zhang, Z. Zhang, W. Miller, and D. J. Lipman. 1997. Gapped BLAST and PSI-BLAST: a new generation of protein database search programs. Nucleic Acids Res. 25:3389-3402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC146917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9254694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodrossy, L., and A. Sessitsch. 2004. Oligonucleotide microarrays in microbial diagnostics. Curr. Opin. Microbiol. 7:245-254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15196491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, B. A., M. S. Oberste, J. P. Alexander, Jr., M. L. Kennett, and M. A. Pallansch. 1999. Molecular epidemiology and evolution of enterovirus 71 strains isolated from 1970 to 1998. J. Virol. 73:9969-9975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10559310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant, P. A., D. Venter, R. Robins-Browne, and N. Curtis. 2004. Chips with everything: DNA microarrays in infectious diseases. Lancet Infect. Dis. 4:100-111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14871635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., S. Krishnan, P. H. Tio, D. Perera, and S. C. Wong. 1999. Isolation of subgenus B adenovirus during a fatal outbreak of enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sibu, Sarawak. Lancet 354:987-991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10501361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., D. Perera, B. A. Brown, D. Cheon, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, H. Cho, and P. McMinn. 2003. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 strains and recent outbreaks in the Asia-Pacific region: comparative analysis of the VP1 and VP4 genes. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:461-468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12702227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casas, I., G. F. Palacios, G. Trallero, D. Cisterna, M. C. Freire, and A. Tenorio. 2001. Molecular characterization of human enteroviruses in clinical samples: comparison between VP2, VP1, and RNA polymerase regions using RT nested PCR assays and direct sequencing of products. J. Med. Virol. 65:138-148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11505456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, L. G., U. D. Parashar, M. S. Lye, F. G. Ong, S. R. Zaki, J. P. Alexander, K. K. Ho, L. L. Han, M. A. Pallansch, A. B. Suleiman, M. Jegathesan, L. J. Anderson, et al. 2000. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. Clin. Infect. Dis. 31:678-683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu, P. Y., K. H. Lin, K. P. Hwang, L. C. Chou, C. F. Wang, S. R. Shih, J. R. Wang, Y. Shimada, and H. Ishiko. 2001. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in Taiwan. Arch. Virol. 146:589-600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11338392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daiba, A., N. Inaba, S. Ando, N. Kajiyama, H. Yatsuhashi, H. Terasaki, A. Ito, M. Ogasawara, A. Abe, J. Yoshioka, K. Hayashida, S. Kaneko, M. Kohara, and S. Ito. 2004. A low-density cDNA microarray with a unique reference RNA: pattern recognition analysis for IFN efficacy prediction to HCV as a model. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 315:1088-1096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14985125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desforges, B., I. Hatin, K. Akarid, and M. Sinet. 1996. Competitive reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction for quantifying murine AIDS virus. J. Virol. Methods 62:161-168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9002074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginocchio, C. C., F. Zhang, A. Malhotra, R. Manji, P. Sillekens, H. Foolen, M. Overdyk, and M. Peeters. 2005. Development, technical performance, and clinical evaluation of a NucliSens basic kit application for detection of enterovirus RNA in cerebrospinal fluid. J. Clin. Microbiol. 43:2616-2623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1151940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15956374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorgievski-Hrisoho, M., J. D. Schumacher, N. Vilimonovic, D. Germann, and L. Matter. 1998. Detection by PCR of enteroviruses in cerebrospinal fluid during a summer outbreak of aseptic meningitis in Switzerland. J. Clin. Microbiol. 36:2408-2412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC105134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9705364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iturriza-Gomara, M., B. Megson, and J. Gray. 2006. Molecular detection and characterization of human enteroviruses directly from clinical samples using RT-PCR and DNA sequencing. J. Med. Virol. 78:243-253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16372287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juang, J. L., T. C. Chen, S. S. Jiang, C. A. Hsiung, W. C. Chen, G. W. Chen, S. M. Lin, J. H. Lin, S. C. Chiu, and Y. K. Lai. 2004. Coupling multiplex RT-PCR to a gene chip assay for sensitive and semiquantitative detection of severe acute respiratory syndrome-coronavirus. Lab. Investig. 84:1085-1091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7100734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15195120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., S. Chen, and D. H. Evans. 2001. Typing and subtyping influenza virus using DNA microarrays and multiplex reverse transcriptase PCR. J. Clin. Microbiol. 39:696-704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC87799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11158130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., L. Y. Chang, S. H. Hsia, Y. C. Huang, C. H. Chiu, C. Hsueh, S. R. Shih, C. C. Liu, and M. H. Wu. 2002. The 1998 enterovirus 71 outbreak in Taiwan: pathogenesis and management. Clin. Infect. Dis. 34(Suppl. 2):S52-S57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11938497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long, W. H., H. S. Xiao, X. M. Gu, Q. H. Zhang, H. J. Yang, G. P. Zhao, and J. H. Liu. 2004. A universal microarray for detection of SARS coronavirus. J. Virol. Methods 121:57-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7112900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15350733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loy, A., and L. Bodrossy. 2006. Highly parallel microbial diagnostics using oligonucleotide microarrays. Clin. Chim. Acta 363:106-119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16126187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manzara, S., M. Muscillo, G. La Rosa, C. Marianelli, P. Cattani, and G. Fadda. 2002. Molecular identification and typing of enteroviruses isolated from clinical specimens. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:4554-4560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC154598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12454151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., K. Lindsay, D. Perera, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, and M. J. Cardosa. 2001. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J. Virol. 75:7732-7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., I. Stratov, L. Nagarajan, and S. Davis. 2001. Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin. Infect. Dis. 32:236-242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P. C. 2002. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 26:91-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick, J. L., V. Rennick, B. Hampil, N. J. Schmidt, and H. H. Ho. 1973. Lyophilized combination pools of enterovirus equine antisera: preparation and test procedures for the identification of field strains of 42 enteroviruses. Bull. W. H. O. 48:263-268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2481070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4355401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muir, P., U. Kammerer, K. Korn, M. N. Mulders, T. Poyry, B. Weissbrich, R. Kandolf, G. M. Cleator, A. M. van Loon, et al. 1998. Molecular typing of enteroviruses: current status and future requirements. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 11:202-227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC121380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9457433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijhuis, M., N. van Maarseveen, R. Schuurman, S. Verkuijlen, M. de Vos, K. Hendriksen, and A. M. van Loon. 2002. Rapid and sensitive routine detection of all members of the genus enterovirus in different clinical specimens by real-time PCR. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:3666-3670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC130891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12354863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera, D., Y. Podin, W. Akin, C. S. Tan, and M. J. Cardosa. 2004. Incorrect identification of recent Asian strains of Coxsackievirus A16 as human enterovirus 71: improved primers for the specific detection of human enterovirus 71 by RT PCR. BMC Infect. Dis. 4:11. [Online.] http://www.biomedcentral.com/1471-2334/4/11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC415548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15122971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plumet, S., and D. Gerlier. 2005. Optimized SYBR green real-time PCR assay to quantify the absolute copy number of measles virus RNAs using gene specific primers. J. Virol. Methods 128:79-87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15913798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozo, F., I. Casas, A. Tenorio, G. Trallero, and J. M. Echevarria. 1998. Evaluation of a commercially available reverse transcription-PCR assay for diagnosis of enteroviral infection in archival and prospectively collected cerebrospinal fluid specimens. J. Clin. Microbiol. 36:1741-1745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9620411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigonan, A. S., L. Mann, and T. Chonmaitree. 1998. Use of monoclonal antibodies to identify serotypes of enterovirus isolates. J. Clin. Microbiol. 36:1877-1881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9650928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawyer, M. H. 1999. Enterovirus infections: diagnosis and treatment. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 18:1033-1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10608620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, N. J., H. H. Ho, and E. H. Lennette. 1975. Propagation and isolation of group A coxsackieviruses in RD cells. J. Clin. Microbiol. 2:183-185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC274168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1176625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih, S. R., M. S. Ho, K. H. Lin, S. L. Wu, Y. T. Chen, C. N. Wu, T. Y. Lin, L. Y. Chang, K. C. Tsao, H. C. Ning, P. Y. Chang, S. M. Jung, C. Hsueh, and K. S. Chang. 2000. Genetic analysis of enterovirus 71 isolated from fatal and non-fatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease during an epidemic in Taiwan, 1998. Virus Res. 68:127-136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10958984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S., V. T. Chow, K. P. Chan, A. E. Ling, and C. L. Poh. 2000. RT-PCR, nucleotide, amino acid and phylogenetic analyses of enterovirus type 71 strains from Asia. J. Virol. Methods 88:193-204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10960707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thoelen, I., E. Moes, P. Lemey, S. Mostmans, E. Wollants, A. M. Lindberg, A. M. Vandamme, and M. Van Ranst. 2004. Analysis of the serotype and genotype correlation of VP1 and the 5&#x2032; noncoding region in an epidemiological survey of the human enterovirus B species. J. Clin. Microbiol. 42:963-971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC356875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15004039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, J. D., D. G. Higgins, and T. J. Gibson. 1994. CLUSTAL W: improving the sensitivity of progressive multiple sequence alignment through sequence weighting, position-specific gap penalties and weight matrix choice. Nucleic Acids Res. 22:4673-4680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC308517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7984417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstrepen, W. A., S. Kuhn, M. M. Kockx, M. E. Van De Vyvere, and A. H. Mertens. 2001. Rapid detection of enterovirus RNA in cerebrospinal fluid specimens with a novel single-tube real-time reverse transcription-PCR assay. J. Clin. Microbiol. 39:4093-4096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11682535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. R., Y. C. Tuan, H. P. Tsai, J. J. Yan, C. C. Liu, and I. J. Su. 2002. Change of major genotype of enterovirus 71 in outbreaks of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Taiwan between 1998 and 2000. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:10-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., C. C. Liu, H. W. Tseng, J. R. Wang, C. C. Huang, Y. J. Chen, Y. J. Yang, S. J. Lin, and T. F. Yeh. 1999. Clinical spectrum of enterovirus 71 infection in children in southern Taiwan, with an emphasis on neurological complications. Clin. Infect. Dis. 29:184-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10433583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, K. T., K. B. Chua, and S. K. Lam. 1999. Immunohistochemical detection of infected neurons as a rapid diagnosis of enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. Ann. Neurol. 45:271-272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9989635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>