<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32833231</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9071</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>93</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epidemiological and molecular characteristics of circulating CVA16, CVA6 strains and genotype distribution in hand, foot and mouth disease cases in 2017 to 2018 from Western India.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3572</StartPage><EndPage>3580</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3572-3580</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmv.26454</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hand, Foot, and Mouth disease (HFMD) is a mild exanthematous and febrile disease occurs in children aged &#x2264;10 years old. The present study highlights clinical, epidemiological characteristics, distribution of enterovirus (EV) types, and sub genotypes in HFMD cases reported during 2017 to 2018 in Western India. A total of 93 clinical samples collected from 68 HFMD cases were included. The presence of EV-RNA was determined by 5'UTR based nested reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction followed by molecular typing, sub genotyping by VP1/2A junction or VP1, full VP1 gene amplification, and phylogenetic analysis. The study reports 80.64% (75/93) EV positivity and 94.66% (71/75) typing rate, with a predominant circulation of CVA16 and CVA6 strains. Sequence analysis revealed the presence of coxsackievirus (CV)A16 (57.7%), CVA6 (40.8%), and Echo1 (1.4%) strains. EV infections were predominantly observed in children aged 1 to 3 years old (43.9%). Although cases were reported throughout the year, peaked in July (15.8%) and August (24.6%) months and persisted till September (19.3%). All the CVA16 and CVA6 positive strains were genotyped using full VP1 gene amplification. All CVA16 Indian strains (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;41) were clustered with rarely reported B1c sub genotype and CVA6 strains (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;29) with E2 sub-lineage. The study highlights the genetic characteristics of circulating CVA16, CVA6, and Echo1 strains in HFMD cases from Western India. The emergence of CVA16 B1c genotype and sub-lineage E2 of CVA6 strains and their constant circulation further demands systemic surveillance studies on HFMD from different parts of India to facilitate the rapid diagnosis of CVA16 and CVA6 strains using the molecular and serological based approach and for intervention strategies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gopalkrishna</LastName><ForeName>Varanasi</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4511-5648</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Enteric Viruses Group, Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR), National Institute of Virology, Pune, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ganorkar</LastName><ForeName>Nital</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Enteric Viruses Group, Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR), National Institute of Virology, Pune, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705876</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0146-6615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020121">5' Untranslated Regions</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020121" MajorTopicYN="N">5' Untranslated Regions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="Y">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="Y">Genotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007194" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">India</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058889" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Typing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genotype and subgenotype distribution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand, foot and mouth disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reverse transcription PCR</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32833231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.26454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Zhu R, Qian Y, et al. Comparing enterovirus 71 with coxsackievirus A16 by analyzing nucleotide sequences and antigenicity of recombinant proteins of VP1s and VP4s. BMC Microbiol. 2011;11:246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, Jiang F, Zhong L, Sun J, Ding J. Age patterns and transmission characteristics of hand, foot and mouth disease in China. BMC Infect Dis. 2016;16(1):691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osterback R, Vuorinen T, Linna M, Susi P, Hyypia T, Waris M. Coxsackievirus A6 and hand, foot, and mouth disease, Finland. Emerg Infect Dis. 2009;15:1485-1488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bracho MA, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Candelas F, Valero A, Cordoba J, Salazar A. Enterovirus co-infections and onychomadesis after hand, foot, and mouth disease, Spain, 2011. Emerg Infect Dis. 2011;17:2223-2231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davia JL, Bel PH, Ninet VZ, et al. Onychomadesis outbreak in Valencia, Spain associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by enteroviruses. Pediatr Dermatol. 2011;28(1):1-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yip CC, Lau SK, Woo PC, Yuen KY. Human enterovirus 71 epidemics: what's next? Emerg Health Threats J. 2013;6:19780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Q, Wang Y, Yao X, et al. Coxsackievirus A16: epidemiology, diagnosis, and vaccine. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2014;10(2):360-367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo DH, Luchs A, Machado BC, Carmona RC, Timenetsky MC. Echovirus 4 associated to hand, foot and mouth disease. Rev Inst Med Trop Sao Paulo. 2006;48(4):197-199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, Xu WB, Xu AQ, et al. Molecular epidemiological analysis of echovirus 19 isolated from an outbreak associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD. in Shandong Province of China. Biomed Environ Sci. 2007;20:321-328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui A, Xu C, Tan X, et al. The development and application of the two real-time RT-PCR assays to detect the pathogen of HFMD. PLoS One. 2013;8:e61451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Zhang T, Hu Y, et al. Survey of enterovirus infections from hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in China, 2009. Virol J. 2011;8:508-511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SH, Choi SS, Oh SA, et al. Detection and characterization of enterovirus associated with herpangina and hand, foot, and mouth disease in Seoul, Korea. Clin Lab. 2011;57(11-12):959-967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang ZC, Kou ZQ, Bai YJ, et al. Epidemiological research on hand, foot, and mouth disease in Mainland China. Viruses. 2015;7(12):6400-6411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng Y, Chen W, Huang M, He W, Zheng K, Yan Y. Epidemiology and etiology of hand, foot and mouth disease in Fujian province, 2008-2014. Arch Virol. 2016;162(2):535-542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson CR, Doane FW, Rhodes AJ. Report of an outbreak of febrile illness with pharyngeal lesions and exanthem: Toronto, summer 1957-isolation of coxsackie virus. Can Med Assoc J. 1958;79:615-621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CY, Li LF, Wu MH, Lee CY, Huang LM. Fatal coxsackievirus A16 infection. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2004;23(3):275-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Liu CF, Yan L, Li JJ, Wang LJ, Qi Y. Distribution of enteroviruses in hospitalized children with hand, foot and mouth disease and relationship between pathogens and nervous system complications. Virol J. 2012;9(1):8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian L, Wang Y, Yao X, Mao Q, Xu M, Liang Z. Coxsackievirus A6: a new emerging pathogen causing hand, foot and mouth disease outbreaks worldwide. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2015;13(9):1061-1071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasidharan CK, Sugathan P, Agarwal R, Khare S, Lal S, Jayaram Paniker CKHand. foot and mouth disease in Calicut. Indian J Pediatr. 2005;72:17-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saoji VA. Hand, foot and mouth disease in Nagpur. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2008;74(2):133-135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayaraghavan PM, Chandy S, Selvaraj K, Pulimood S, Abraham AM. Virological investigation of hand, foot and mouth disease in a tertiary care center in South India. J Glob Infect Dis. 2012;4(3):153-161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalkrishna V, Patil PR, Patil GP, Chitambar SD. Circulation of multiple enterovirus serotypes causing hand, foot and mouth disease in India. J Med Microbiol. 2012;61:420-425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar BR, Dwibedi B, Kar SK. An outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Bhubaneswar, Odisha. Indian Pediatr. 2013;50(1):139-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao DC, Naidu JR, Maiya PP, Babu A, Bailly JL. Large-scale HFMD epidemics caused by Coxsackievirus A16 in Bangalore, India during 2013 and 2015. Infect Genet Evol. 2017;55:228-235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganorkar NN, Patil PR, Tikute SS, Gopalkrishna V. Genetic characterization of enterovirus strains identified in hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD): emergence of B1c, C1 subgenotypes, E2 sublineage of CVA16, EV71 and CVA6 strains in India. Infect Gene Evol. 2017;54:192-199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapkal GN, Bondre VP, Fulmali PV, Patil P, Gopalkrishna V, Dadhania V. Enteroviruses in patients with acute encephalitis, Uttar Pradesh, India. Emerg Infect Dis. 2009;15:295-298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste MS, Maher K, Kilpatrick DR, Flemister MR, Brown BA, Pallansch MA. Typing of human enteroviruses by partial sequencing of VP1. J Clin Microbiol. 1999;37(5):1288-1293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casas I, Palacios GF, Trallero G, Cisterna D, Freire MC, Tenorio A. Molecular characterization of human enteroviruses in clinical samples: comparison between VP2, VP1, and RNA polymerase regions using RT nested PCR assays and direct sequencing of products. J Med Virol. 2001;65(1):138-148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nix WA, Oberste MS, Pallansch MA. Sensitive, seminested PCR amplification of VP1 sequences for direct identification of all enterovirus serotypes from original clinical specimens. J Clin Microbiol. 2006;44(8):2698-2704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste MS, Maher K, Williams AJ, et al. Species-specific RT-PCR amplification of human enteroviruses: a tool for rapid species identification of uncharacterized enteroviruses. J Gen Virol. 2006;87:119-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamura K, Peterson D, Peterson N, Stecher G, Nei M, Kumar S. MEGA5: molecular evolutionary genetics analysis using maximum likelihood, evolutionary distance and maximum parsimony methods. Mol Biol Evol. 2011;28(10):2731-2739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang LW, Koh BK, Chan KP, Chua LT, James L, Goh KT. Epidemiology and control of hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore,2001-2007. Ann Acad Med Singapore. 2009;38:106-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan H, Wang J, Wang C, et al. Etiology of multiple non-EV71 and Non-CVA16 enteroviruses associated with hand, foot and mouth disease in Jinan, China, 2009-June 2013. PLoS One. 2015;10(11):e0142733. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0142733</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nag SS, Dutta A, Mandal RK. Delayed cutaneous findings of hand, foot, and mouth disease. Indian Pediatr. 2016;53(1):42-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu PC, Huang LM, Kao CL, Fan TY, Cheng AL, Chang LY. An outbreak of coxsackievirus A16 infection: comparision with other entroviruses in a preschool in Taipei. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2010;43(4):271-277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing W, Liao Q, Viboud C, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China, 2008-12: an epidemiological study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2014;14(4):308-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upala P, Apidechkul T, Suttana W, Kullawong N, Tamornpark R, Inta C. Molecular epidemiology and clinical features of hand, foot and mouth disease in northern Thailand in 2016: a prospective cohort study. BMC Infect Dis. 2018;18(1):630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie J, Yang X, Hu S, et al. Co-circulation of coxsackieviruses A-6, A-10, and A-16 causes hand, foot, and mouth disease in Guangzhou city, China. BMC Infect Dis. 2020;20(1):271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Yang Z, Di B, Wang M. Hand-foot-and-mouth disease and weather factors in Guangzhou, southern China. Epidemiol Infect. 2014;142(8):1741-1750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge S, Yan Q, He S, Zhuang S, Niu J, Xia N. Specific primer amplification of the VP1 region directed by 5' UTR sequence analysis: enterovirus testing and identification in clinical samples from hand-foot-and-mouth disease patients. J Virol Methods. 2013;193(2):463-469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrerizo M, Tarrago D, Munoz-Almagro C, et al. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71, coxsackievirus A16 and A6 associated with hand, foot and mouth disease in Spain. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2014;20(3):O150-O156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai FF, Yan Q, Ge SX, Tang X, Chen RJ, Xu HM. Epidemiologic and etiologic characteristics of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Chongqing, China between 2010 and 2013. J Med Virol. 2016;88(3):408-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Wang D, Yan D, et al. Molecular evidence of persistent epidemic and evolution of subgenotype B1 coxsackievirus A16-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in China. J Clin Microbiol. 2010;48:619-622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zong W, He Y, Yu S, et al. Molecular phylogeny of coxsackievirus A16 in Shenzhen, China, from 2005 to 2009. J Clin Microbiol. 2011;49:1659-1661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen XP, Tan XJ, Li J, et al. Molecular epidemiology of coxsackievirus A16: intratype and prevalent intertype recombination identified. PLoS One. 2013;8(12):e82861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan YF, Wee KL, Chiam CW, et al. Comparative genetic analysis of VP4, VP1 and 3D gene regions of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 circulating in Malaysia between 1997-2008. Trop Biomed. 2012;29(3):451-466.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>