<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">9738034</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>1998</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0095-1137</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>1998</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rapid shell vial culture technique for detection of enteroviruses and adenoviruses in fecal specimens: comparison with conventional virus isolation method.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2865</StartPage><EndPage>2868</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2865-8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Detection of enteroviruses and adenoviruses mainly in fecal specimens by rapid culture with inoculation onto cell monolayers in flat-bottom tubes by centrifugation and immunofluorescence staining with genus-specific monoclonal antibodies was compared with that by the conventional virus isolation procedure. For both conventional culture and shell vial culture human lung fibroblast cells and tertiary monkey kidney cells were used. For enterovirus detection, 979 clinical specimens (916 stool specimens, 56 cerebrospinal fluid specimens, and 7 nasopharyngeal swabs) were used. Conventional culture detected 74 enterovirus isolates. A cytopathic effect compatible with the presence of an enterovirus after 3 days of incubation occurred in 25 of the 74 (34%) specimens that eventually became positive. The detection rate for enteroviruses by rapid cell culture after 2 to 3 days of incubation was 42 of 74 (57%). The genus-specific enterovirus monoclonal antibody did not react with strains of echovirus types 22 and 23 or enterovirus type 71. Rapid cell culture for the detection of adenoviruses was performed with 567 clinical specimens (536 stool specimens, 25 cerebrospinal fluid specimens, and 6 miscellaneous specimens), in which 42 adenoviruses were found by conventional culture. Nine of the 42 (21%) adenovirus isolates were detected by conventional culture within 3 days after inoculation, whereas 21 (50%) were found by rapid cell culture within 2 to 3 days. Only two of the nine specimens found to be positive for the enteric adenovirus type 41 by conventional culture as well by a type-specific enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) tested positive by rapid cell culture. In conclusion, the rapid shell vial assay allows the early detection and identification of enteroviruses and adenoviruses in clinical specimens but is markedly less sensitive than the conventional isolation procedure according to the eventual results of the conventional isolation procedure. Conventional cell culture remains a prerequisite for serotyping of enteroviral isolates. On the basis of the results for adenovirus type 41, the rapid detection of adenoviruses was not considered to be useful for the detection of clinically relevant adenoviruses in fecal samples.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Doornum</LastName><ForeName>G J</ForeName><Initials>GJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Public Health, Municipal Health Service of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands. gvdoornum@gggd.amsterdam.nl</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Jong</LastName><ForeName>J C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505564</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0095-1137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000911">Antibodies, Monoclonal</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000260" MajorTopicYN="N">Adenoviruses, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000911" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Monoclonal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018929" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Culture Techniques</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000295" MajorTopicYN="N">instrumentation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002478" MajorTopicYN="N">Cells, Cultured</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005243" MajorTopicYN="N">Feces</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005347" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibroblasts</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008252" MajorTopicYN="N">Macaca fascicularis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017955" MajorTopicYN="N">Poliovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>1998</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>1998</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>1998</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>1998</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9738034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC105078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.36.10.2865-2868.1998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brandt C D, Kim H W, Rodriguez W J, Arrobio J O, Jeffries B C, Stallings E P, Lewis C, Miles A J, Gardner M K, Parrott M H. Adenoviruses and pediatric gastroenteritis. J Infect Dis. 1985;151:437&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2982960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brumback B G, Wade D. Simultaneous rapid culture for four respiratory viruses in the same cell monolayer using a differential multicolored fluorescent confirmatory stain. J Clin Microbiol. 1996;34:798&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC228895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8815086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Jong J C, Wigand R, Kidd A H, Wadell G, Kapsenberg Jacoba G, Muzerie C J, Wermenbol A G, Firtzlaff R-G. Candidate adenoviruses 40 and 41: fastidious adenoviruses from human infant stool. J Med Virol. 1983;11:215&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6306161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Jong J C, Bijlsma K, Wermenbol A G, Verweij-Uijterwaal M W, Van der Avoort H G A M, Wood D J, Bailey A S, Osterhaus A D M E. Detection, typing, and subtyping of enteric adenoviruses 40 and 41 from fecal samples and observation of changing incidences of infections with these types and subtypes. J Clin Microbiol. 1993;31:1562&#x2013;1569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC265578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8314997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger D, Pasamontes L, Ostermayer M, Bienz K. Reverse transcription multiplex PCR for differentiation between polio- and enteroviruses from clinical and environmental samples. J Clin Microbiol. 1995;33:1442&#x2013;1447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC228192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7650164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engler H D, Preuss J. Laboratory diagnosis of respiratory virus infections in 24 hours by utilizing shell vial cultures. J Clin Microbiol. 1997;35:2165&#x2013;2167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC229928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9230407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halonen P, Rocha E, Hierholzer J, Holloway B, Hyypi&#xe4; T, Hurskainen P, Pallansch M. Detection of enteroviruses and rhinoviruses in clinical specimens by PCR and liquid-phase hybridization. J Clin Microbiol. 1995;33:648&#x2013;653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC228007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7751371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huttunen P, Santti J, Pulli T, Hyypi&#xe4; T. The major echovirus group is genetically coherent and related to coxsackie B viruses. J Gen Virol. 1996;77:715&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8627260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyppi&#xe4; T, Hovi T, Knowles N J, Stanway G. Classification of enteroviruses based on molecular and biological properties. J Gen Virol. 1997;78:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9010279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapsenberg J G. Picornaviridae: the enteroviruses (polioviruses, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses. In: Balows A, Hausler W J, Lennette E H, editors. Laboratory diagnosis of infectious diseases, principles and practices. II. New York, N.Y: Springer-Verlag; 1988. pp. 692&#x2013;722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen M A, Shuck K M, Sambol A R, Flor S M, O&#x2019;Brien J, Cabrera B J. Isolation of seven respiratory viruses in shell vials: a practical and highly sensitive method. J Clin Microbiol. 1993;31:422&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC262779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8381816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabelais G P, Stout G G, Ladd K L, Cost K M. Rapid diagnosis of respiratory infections by using a shell vial assay and monoclonal antibody pool. J Clin Microbiol. 1992;30:1505&#x2013;1508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC265318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1624569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riding M H, Stewart J, Clements G, Galbraith D N. Enteroviral polymerase chain reaction in the investigation of aseptic meningitis. J Med Virol. 1996;50:204&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8915889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuelson A, Forsgren M, S&#xe4;llberg M. Characterization of the recognition site and diagnostic potential of an enterovirus group-reactive monoclonal antibody. J Clin Diagn Lab Immunol. 1995;2:385&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC170165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7545081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schirm J, Meulenberg J J M, Pastoor G W, Van Voorst Vader P C, Schr&#xf6;der F P. Rapid detection of varicella-zoster virus in clinical specimens using monoclonal antibodies on shell vials and smears. J Med Virol. 1989;28:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2542440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanway G, Kalkkinen N, Roivanen M, Ghazi F, Khan M, Smyth M, Meurman O, Hyypa&#xe4; T. Molecular and biological characteristics of echovirus 22, a representative of a new picornavirus group. J Clin Microbiol. 1994;68:8232&#x2013;8238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC237290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7966616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trabelsi A, Grattard F, Nejmeddine M, Aouni M, Bourlet T, Pozzetto B. Evaluation of an enterovirus group-specific anti-VP1 monoclonal antibody, 5-D8/1, in comparison with neutralization and PCR for rapid identification of enteroviruses in cell culture. J Clin Microbiol. 1995;33:2454&#x2013;2457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC228436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7494045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadell G. Adenoviridae: the adenoviruses. In: Balows A, Hausler W J, Lennette E H, editors. Laboratory diagnosis of infectious diseases, principles and practices. II. New York, N.Y: Springer-Verlag; 1988. pp. 285&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousef G E, Brown I N, Mowbray J F. Derivation and biochemical characterization of an enterovirus group-specific monoclonal antibody. Intervirology. 1987;28:163&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2836335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousef G E, Mann G F, Brown I N, Mowbray J F. Clinical and research application of an enterovirus group-reactive monoclonal antibody. Intervirology. 1987;28:199&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2835329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoll G J, Melchers W J G, Kopecka G, Jambroes G, Van der Poel H J A, Galama J M D. General primer-mediated polymerase chain reaction for the detection of enteroviruses: applications for diagnostic routine and persistent infections. J Clin Microbiol. 1992;30:160&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC265013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1370845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>