<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">22666293</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1741-4288</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2012</Volume><PubDate><Year>2012</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Evidence-based complementary and alternative medicine : eCAM</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Antiviral Ability of Kalanchoe gracilis Leaf Extract against Enterovirus 71 and Coxsackievirus A16.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>503165</StartPage><MedlinePgn>503165</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">503165</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2012/503165</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pandemic infection or reemergence of Enterovirus 71 (EV71) and coxsackievirus A16 (CVA16) occurs in tropical and subtropical regions, being associated with hand-foot-and-mouth disease, herpangina, aseptic meningitis, brain stem encephalitis, pulmonary edema, and paralysis. However, effective therapeutic drugs against EV71 and CVA16 are rare. Kalanchoe gracilis (L.) DC is used for the treatment of injuries, pain, and inflammation. This study investigated antiviral effects of K. gracilis leaf extract on EV71 and CVA16 replications. HPLC analysis with a C-18 reverse phase column showed fingerprint profiles of K. gracilis leaf extract had 15 chromatographic peaks. UV/vis absorption spectra revealed peaks 5, 12, and 15 as ferulic acid, quercetin, and kaempferol, respectively. K. gracilis leaf extract showed little cytotoxicity, but exhibited concentration-dependent antiviral activities including cytopathic effect, plaque, and virus yield reductions. K. gracilis leaf extract was shown to be more potent in antiviral activity than ferulic acid, quercetin, and kaempferol, significantly inhibiting in vitro replication of EV71 (IC(50) = 35.88&#x2009;&#x3bc;g/mL) and CVA16 (IC(50) = 42.91&#x2009;&#x3bc;g/mL). Moreover, K. gracilis leaf extract is a safe antienteroviral agent with the inactivation of viral 2A protease and reduction of IL-6 and RANTES expressions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ching-Ying</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chinese Pharmaceutical Sciences and Chinese Medicine Resources, China Medical University, Taichung 404, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Shun-Chueh</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yongjun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Zhen-Rung</ForeName><Initials>ZR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kung</LastName><ForeName>Szu-Hao</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Yuan-Shiun</ForeName><Initials>YS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Cheng-Wen</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2012</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101215021</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1741-427X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2012</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22666293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3361180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/503165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kao MC. Handbook of Taiwan Medicinal Plants. Taipei, Taiwan: Southern Materials Center; 1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai ZR, Peng WH, Ho YL, et al. Analgesic and anti-inflammatory activities of the methanol extract of Kalanchoe gracilis (L.) DC stem in mice. The American Journal of Chinese Medicine. 2010;38(3):529&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20503470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai ZR, Ho YL, Hung SC, et al. Antioxidant, anti-inflammatory and antiproliferative activities of Kalanchoe gracilis (L.) DC stem. The American Journal of Chinese Medicine. 2011;39(6):1275&#x2013;1290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22083996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karin CSL, Yang SL, Roberts MF, Phillipson JD. Eupafolin rhamnosides from Kalanchoe gracilis . Journal of Natural Products. 1989;52(5):970&#x2013;974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu PL, Hsu YL, Wu TS, Bastow KF, Lee KH. Kalanchosides A-C, new cytotoxic bufadienolides from the aerial parts of Kalanchoe gracilis . Organic Letters. 2006;8(23):5207&#x2013;5210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17078679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwu JR, Singha R, Hong SC, et al. Synthesis of new benzimidazole-coumarin conjugates as anti-hepatitis C virus agents. Antiviral Research. 2008;77(2):157&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17977606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang CC, Mouscadet JF, Tsai HJ, Liu CT, Hsu LY. Synthesis and HIV-1 integrase inhibition of novel bis- or tetra-coumarin analogues. Chemical and Pharmaceutical Bulletin. 2007;55(12):1740&#x2013;1743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18057750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, Cong XJ, Li P, Tan JJ, Chen WZ, Wang CX. Study on the inhibitory mechanism and binding mode of the hydroxycoumarin compound NSC158393 to HIV-1 integraseby molecular modeling. Biopolymers. 2009;91(9):700&#x2013;709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19382173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwu JR, Lin SY, Tsay SC, De Clercq E, Leyssen P, Neyts J. Coumarin-purine ribofuranoside conjugates as new agents against hepatitis c virus. Journal of Medicinal Chemistry. 2011;54(7):2114&#x2013;2126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21375337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong EBB, Watanabe N, Saito A, et al. Vipirinin, a coumarin-based HIV-1 Vpr inhibitor, interacts with a hydrophobic region of Vpr. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 2011;286(16):14049&#x2013;14056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3077605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21357691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conti C, Tomao P, Genovese D, Desideri N, Stein ML, Orsi N. Mechanism of action of the antirhinovirus flavanoid 4&#x2032;,6-dicyanoflavan. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy. 1992;36(1):95&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC189234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1317152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conti C, Genovese D, Santoro R, Stein ML, Orsi N, Fiore L. Activities and mechanisms of action of halogen-substituted flavanoids against poliovirus type 2 infection in vitro. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy. 1990;34(3):460&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC171615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2159258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genovese D, Conti C, Tomao P, et al. Effect of chloro-, cyano-, and amidino-substituted flavanoids on enterovirus infection in vitro. Antiviral Research. 1995;27(1-2):123&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7486950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvati AL, De Dominicis A, Tait S, Canitano A, Lahm A, Fiore L. Mechanism of action at the molecular level of the antiviral drug 3(2H)-isoflavene against type 2 poliovirus. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy. 2004;48(6):2233&#x2013;2243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC415587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15155227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mothana RA, Mentel R, Reiss C, Lindequist U. Phytochemical screening and antiviral activity of some medicinal plants from the island Soqotra. Phytotherapy Research. 2006;20(4):298&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16557613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supratman U, Fujita T, Akiyama K, et al. Anti-tumor promoting activity of bufadienolides from Kalanchoe pinnata and K. Daigremontiana &#xd7; tubiflora. Bioscience, Biotechnology and Biochemistry. 2001;65(4):947&#x2013;949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11388478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knipe DN, Howley PM, Griffin DE, et al. Enteroviruses: Polioviruses, Coxsackieviruses, Echoviruses, and Newer Enteroviruses. Fields Virology. (5th edition) 2007;1 Edited by Pallansch M. A. and Roos R. P.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Chow VT, Phoon MC, Chan KP, Poh CL. Direct detection of enterovirus 71 (EV71) in clinical specimens from a hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak in Singapore by reverse transcription-PCR with universal enterovirus and EV71-specific primers. Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 2002;40(8):2823&#x2013;2827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12149336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng H, Wen F, Gan Y, Huang W. MRI and associated clinical characteristics of EV71-induced brainstem encephalitis in children with hand-foot-mouth disease. Neuroradiology. In press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22200974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders SA, Herrero LJ, McPhie K, et al. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 over two decades in an Australian urban community. Archives of Virology. 2006;151(5):1003&#x2013;1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16369861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin KH, Hwang KP, Ke GM, et al. Evolution of EV71 genogroup in Taiwan from 1998 to 2005: an emerging of subgenogroup C4 of EV71. Journal of Medical Virology. 2006;78(2):254&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16372302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B, Chuang H, Yang KD. Sialylated glycans as receptor and inhibitor of enterovirus 71 infection to DLD-1 intestinal cells. Virology Journal. 2009;6:141&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2751754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19751532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Lin TY, Hsu KH, et al. Clinical features and risk factors of pulmonary oedema after enterovirus-71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease. The Lancet. 1999;354(9191):1682&#x2013;1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, et al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. The New England Journal of Medicine. 1999;341(13):929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CC, Liu CC, Chang YC, Chen CY, Wang ST, Yeh TF. Neurologic complications in children with enterovirus 71 infection. The New England Journal of Medicine. 1999;341(13):936&#x2013;942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Hsia SH, Huang YC, Wu CT, Chang LY. Proinflammatory cytokine reactions in enterovirus 71 infections of the central nervous system. Clinical Infectious Diseases. 2003;36(3):269&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12539066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podin Y, Gias EL, Ong F, et al. Sentinel surveillance for human enterovirus 71 in Sarawak, Malaysia: lessons from the first 7 years. BMC Public Health. 2006;6:180&#x2013;189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1543637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16827926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yen FB, Chang LY, Kao CL, et al. Coxsackieviruses infection in northern Taiwan&#x2014;epidemiology and clinical characteristics. Journal of Microbiology, Immunology and Infection. 2009;42(1):38&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19424557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai MT, Cheng YH, Liu YN, Liao NC, Lu WW, Kung SH. Real-time monitoring of human enterovirus (HEV)-infected cells and anti-HEV 3C protease potency by fluorescence resonance energy transfer. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy. 2009;53(2):748&#x2013;755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2630644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19015331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste MS, Pe&#xf1;aranda S, Rogers SL, Henderson E, Nix WA. Comparative evaluation of Taqman real-time PCR and semi-nested VP1 PCR for detection of enteroviruses in clinical specimens. Journal of Clinical Virology. 2010;49(1):73&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20667767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castell&#xf3; A, Alvarez E, Carrasco L. The multifaceted poliovirus 2A protease: regulation of gene expression by picornavirus proteases. Journal of Biomedicine and Biotechnology. 2011;2011:23 pages. Article ID 369648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3085340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21541224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo RL, Kung SH, Hsu YY, Liu WT. Infection with enterovirus 71 or expression of its 24 protease induces apoptotic cell death. Journal of General Virology. 2002;83(6):1367&#x2013;1376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12029152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim T, Cunha JM, Madi K, da Fonseca LM, Costa SS, Gon&#xe7;alves Koatz KVL. Immunomodulatory and anti-inflammatory effects of Kalanchoe brasiliensis . International Immunopharmacology. 2002;2(7):875&#x2013;883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12188029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi HJ, Song JH, Park KS, Baek SH. In vitro anti-enterovirus 71 activity of gallic acid from Woodfordia fruticosa flowers. Letters in Applied Microbiology. 2010;50(4):438&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20149083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Tsai KN, Li YS, Chueh CC, Chan EC. Inhibition of enterovirus 71-induced apoptosis by allophycocyanin isolated from a blue-green alga Spirulina platensis . Journal of Medical Virology. 2003;70(1):119&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12629652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu QC, Wang Y, Liu YP, et al. Inhibition of enterovirus 71 replication by chrysosplenetin and penduletin. European Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences. 2011;44(3):392&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CW, Wu CF, Hsiao NW, et al. Aloe-emodin is an interferon-inducing agent with antiviral activity against Japanese encephalitis virus and enterovirus 71. International Journal of Antimicrobial Agents. 2008;32(4):355&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7126984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18701259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Liu YC, Jheng JR, et al. Anti-enterovirus 71 activity screening of Chinese herbs with anti-infection and inflammation activities. American Journal of Chinese Medicine. 2009;37(1):143&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19222118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu BW, Pan TL, Leu YL, et al. Antiviral effects of Salvia miltiorrhiza (Danshen) against enterovirus 71. The American Journal of Chinese Medicine. 2007;35(1):153&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17265559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su FM, Chang JS, Wang KC, Tsai JJ, Chiang LC. A water extract of Pueraria lobata inhibited cytotoxicity of enterovirus 71 in a human foreskin fibroblast cell line. Kaohsiung Journal of Medical Sciences. 2008;24(10):523&#x2013;530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19181583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo KK, Chang JS, Wang KC, Chiang LC. Water extract of Glycyrrhiza uralensis inhibited enterovirus 71 in a human foreskin fibroblast cell line. The American Journal of Chinese Medicine. 2009;37(2):383&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19507280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Huang YC, Lin TY. Fulminant neurogenic pulmonary oedema with hand, foot, and mouth disease. The Lancet. 1998;352(9125):367&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9717926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Huang KJ, et al. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. The Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2003;188(4):564&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Su LY, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid cytokines in enterovirus 71 brain stem encephalitis and echovirus meningitis infections of varying severity. Clinical Microbiology and Infection. 2007;13(7):677&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17441979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Chang LY, Huang YC, Hsu KH, Chiu CH, Yang KD. Different proinflammatory reactions in fatal and non-fatal enterovirus 71 infections: implications for early recognition and therapy. Acta Paediatrica. 2002;91(6):632&#x2013;635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12162592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng KF, Chen LL, Huang PN, Shih SR. Neural pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 infection. Microbes and Infection. 2010;12(7):505&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20348010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khong WX, Foo DG, Trasti SL, Tan EL, Alonso S. Sustained high levels of interleukin-6 contribute to the pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 in a neonate mouse model. Journal of Virology. 2011;85(7):3067&#x2013;3076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3067852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21228224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>