<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16000779</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Potential regrowth and recolonization of salmonellae and indicators in biosolids and biosolid-amended soil.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3701</StartPage><EndPage>3708</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3701-8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>This study evaluated the potential for conversion of Class B to Class A biosolids with respect to salmonellae and fecal coliforms during solar drying in concrete lined drying beds. Anaerobically (8% solids) and aerobically (2% solids) digested Class B biosolids were pumped into field-scale drying beds, and microbial populations and environmental conditions were monitored. Numbers of fecal coliforms and salmonellae decreased as temperature and rate of desiccation increased. After 3 to 4 weeks, Class A requirements were achieved in both biosolids for the pathogens and the indicators. However, following rainfall events, significant increase in numbers was observed for both fecal coliforms and salmonellae. In laboratory studies, regrowth of fecal coliforms was observed in both biosolids and biosolid-amended soil, but the regrowth of salmonellae observed in the concrete-lined drying beds did not occur. These laboratory studies demonstrated that pathogens decreased in numbers when soil was amended with biosolids. Based on serotyping, the increased numbers of salmonellae seen in the concrete lined drying beds following rainfall events was most likely due to recolonization due to contamination from fecal matter introduced by animals and not from regrowth of salmonellae indigenous to biosolids. Overall, we conclude that the use of concrete-lined beds created a situation in which moisture added as rainfall accumulated in the beds, promoting the growth of fecal coliforms and salmonellae added from external sources.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaleski</LastName><ForeName>Kathleen J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Soil, Water, and Environmental Science, The University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona 85721, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Josephson</LastName><ForeName>Karen L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gerba</LastName><ForeName>Charles P</ForeName><Initials>CP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pepper</LastName><ForeName>Ian L</ForeName><Initials>IL</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012987">Soil</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001200" MajorTopicYN="N">Ascaris</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="Y">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004755" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterobacteriaceae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="Y">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="Y">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004784" MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental Monitoring</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005243" MajorTopicYN="N">Feces</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011891" MajorTopicYN="N">Rain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012475" MajorTopicYN="N">Salmonella</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="Y">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012987" MajorTopicYN="N">Soil</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000469" MajorTopicYN="N">parasitology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012988" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soil Microbiology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013696" MajorTopicYN="N">Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014865" MajorTopicYN="N">Waste Disposal, Fluid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16000779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1169032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.7.3701-3708.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">71/7/3701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American Public Health Association. 1998. Standard methods for the examination of water and wastewater, 20th ed. American Public Health Association, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandon, J. R., W. D. Burge, and N. K. Enkiri. 1977. Inactivation by ionizing radiation of Salmonella enteritidis serotype montevideo grown in composted sewage sludge. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 33:1011-1012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC170813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">326182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burge, W. D., N. K. Enkiri, and D. Hussong. 1987. Salmonella regrowth in compost as influenced by substrate (Salmonella regrowth in compost). Microb. Ecol. 14:243-253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24202718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferns, P. N., and G. P. Mudge. 2000. Abundance, diet, and Salmonella contamination of gulls feeding at sewage outfalls. Water Res. 34:2653-2660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geldreich, E. E., B. A. Kenner, and P. W. Kabler. 1964. Occurrence of coliforms, fecal coliforms, and streptococci on vegetation and insects. Appl. Microbiol. 12:63-69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1058066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14106942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geldreich, E. E., and N. A. Clarke. 1966. Bacterial pollution indicators in the intestinal tract of freshwater fish. Appl. Microbiol. 14:429-437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC546736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6008184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs, R. A., and G. E. Ho. 1993. Health risks from pathogens in untreated wastewater sludge: implications for Australian sludge management guidelines. Water 20:17-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs, R. A., C. J. Hu, G. E. Ho, and I. Unkovich. 1997. Regrowth of faecal coliforms and Salmonellae in stored biosolids and soil amended with biosolids. Water Sci. Technol. 35:269-275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs, R., C. J. Hu, G. E. Ho, I. Unkovich, and P. Phillips. 1994. Die-off of human pathogens in stored wastewater sludge and sludge applied to land. UWRAA Research Project no. [55-51 (91/58)]. Urban Water Research Association of Australia, Melbourne, Australia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussong, D., W. D. Burge, and N. K. Enkiri. 1985. Occurrence, growth, and suppression of Salmonellae in composted sewage sludge. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 50:887-893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC291765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3909966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang, N. L., S. R. Smith, D. M. Bellett-Travers, E. B. Pike, and C. L. Rowlands. 2003. Decay of Escherichi coli in soil following the application of biosolids to agricultural land. Water Environ. Management J. 17:23-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millner, P. D., K. E. Powers, N. K. Enkiri, and W. D. Burge. 1987. Microbially mediated growth suppression and death of Salmonella in composted sewage sludge. Microb. Ecol. 14:225-265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24202719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaghan, P., C. B. Shedden, K. Ensor, C. R. Fricker, and R. W. A. Girdwood. 1985. Salmonella carriage by herring gulls in the Clyde area of Scotland in relation to their feeding ecology. J. Appl. Ecol. 22:669-680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pepper, I. L., K. L. Josephson, R. L. Bailey, M. D. Burr, and C. P. Gerba. 1993. Survival of indicator organisms in Sonoran Desert soil amended with sewage sludge. J. Environ. Sci. Health A 28:1287-1302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietronave, S., L. Fracchia, and M. G. Martinotti. 2002. Researchers analyze how microorganisms suppress pathogen regrowth. BioCycle 43:57-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russ, C. F., and W. A. Yanko. 1981. Factors affecting salmonellae repopulation in composted sludges. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 41:597-602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7224626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidhu, J., R. A. Gibbs, G. E. Ho, and I. Unkovich. 1999. Selection of Salmonella typhimurium as an indicator for pathogen regrowth potential in composted biosolids. Lett. Appl. Microbiol. 29:303-307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10664970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidhu, J., R. A. Gibbs, G. E. Ho, and I. Unkovich. 2001. The role of indigenous microorganisms in suppression of Salmonella regrowth in composted biosolids. Water Res. 35:913-920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11235886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 1994. A plain English guide to the EPA part 503 biosolids rule. EPA/832/R-93-003, Office of Wastewater Management (4204), United States Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 1999. Biosolids generation, use, and disposal in the United States. EPA 530-R-99-099, Office of Solid Waste, United States Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 2000. A guide to field storage of biosolids and the organic by-products used in agriculture and for soil resource management. EPA/832-B-00-007, Office of Wastewater Management, United States Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 2003. Control of pathogens and vector attraction in sewage sludge. EPA/625/R-92/013, United States Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Donsel, D. J., E. E. Geldreich, and N. A. Clarke. 1967. Seasonal variations in survival of indicator bacteria in soil and their contribution to storm-water pollution. Appl. Microbiol. 15:1362-1370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC547201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16349746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward, R. L., J. G. Yeager, and C. S. Ashley. 1981. Response of bacteria in wastewater sludge to moisture loss by evaporation and effect of moisture content on bacterial inactivation by ionizing radiation. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 41:1123-1227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6789765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winfield, M. D., and E. A. Groisman. 2003. Role of nonhost environments in the lifestyles of Salmonella and Escherichia coli. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 69:3687-3694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC165204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12839733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanko, W. A. 1988. Occurrence of pathogens in distribution and marketing municipal sludge. EPA/600/1-37/014, United States Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeager, J. G., and R. L. Ward. 1981. Effects of moisture content on long-term survival and regrowth of bacteria in wastewater sludge. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 41:1117-1122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6789764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaleski, K. J., K. L. Josephson, C. P. Gerba, and I. L. Pepper. 2005. Survival, growth, and regrowth of enteric indicator and pathogenic bacteria in biosolids, compost, soil, and land applied biosolids. J. Residuals Sci. Technol. 2:49-63.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>