<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">17567704</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2007</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-538X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>81</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2007</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Retrograde axonal transport: a major transmission route of enterovirus 71 in mice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>8996</StartPage><EndPage>9003</EndPage><MedlinePgn>8996-9003</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Inoculation of enterovirus 71 (EV71) by the oral (p.o.), intramuscular (i.m.), or intracranial route resulted in brain infection, flaccid paralysis, pulmonary dysfunction, and death of 7-day-old mice. The lag time of disease progression indicated that neuroinvasion from the inoculation sites was a prerequisite for the development of the clinical signs. Although EV71 p.o. inoculation led to a persistent viremia and a transient increase in blood-brain barrier permeability at the early stage of the infection, only low levels of virus, which led to neither severe infection nor clinical illness, could be detected in the brain, suggesting that hematogenous transport might not represent a major transmission route. In the spinal cord, following both p.o. and hind limb i.m. inoculation, the virus first appeared and increased rapidly in the lower segments, especially at the anterior horn areas, and then spread to the upper segments and brain in the presence of viremia. A reverse pattern, with the virus being first detected in the upper segment, was observed when the virus was i.m. inoculated in the forelimb. Colchicine, a fast axonal transport inhibitor, but not sciatic nerve transection reduced EV71 neuroinvasion in a dose-dependent manner, indicating a neuronal transmission of the virus.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Che-Szu</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan 70101, Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Chuan</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Shin-Chao</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Yi-Ping</ForeName><Initials>YP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ya-Fang</ForeName><Initials>YF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jen-Ren</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Ching-Chuan</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lei</LastName><ForeName>Huan-Yao</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Chun-Keung</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2007</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>SML2Y3J35T</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003078">Colchicine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001370" MajorTopicYN="N">Axonal Transport</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001369" MajorTopicYN="N">Axons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003078" MajorTopicYN="N">Colchicine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008813" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred ICR</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016019" MajorTopicYN="N">Survival Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014766" MajorTopicYN="N">Viremia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2007</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2007</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2007</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2008</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17567704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.00236-07</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.00236-07</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bodian, D., T. Rivers, and F. Horsfall. 1959. Viral and rickettsial infections of man, p. 479-498. Lippincott, Philadelphia, PA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, C. Y., Y. C. Chang, C. C. Huang, C. C. Lui, K. W. Lee, and S. C. Huang. 2001. Acute flaccid paralysis in infants and young children with enterovirus 71 infection: MR imaging findings and clinical correlates. Am. J. Neuroradiol. 22:200-205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7975539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11158910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crotty, S., L. Hix, L. J. Sigal, and R. Andino. 2002. Poliovirus pathogenesis in a new poliovirus receptor transgenic mouse model: age-dependent paralysis and a mucosal route of infection. J. Gen. Virol. 83:1707-1720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12075090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douche-Aourik, F., W. Berlier, L. Feasson, T. Bourlet, R. Harrath, S. Omar, F. Grattard, C. Denis, and B. Pozzetto. 2003. Detection of enterovirus in human skeletal muscle from patients with chronic inflammatory muscle disease or fibromyalgia and healthy subjects. J. Med. Virol. 71:540-547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14556267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford, D. J., S. L. Ropka, G. H. Collins, and B. Jubelt. 2002. The neuropathology observed in wild-type mice inoculated with human poliovirus mirrors human paralytic poliomyelitis. Microb. Pathog. 33:97-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12220986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiung, G. D. 1994. Virus assay, neutralization test and antiviral assay, p. 46-55. In G. D. Hsiung, C. K. Y. Fong, and M. L. Landry (ed.), Hsiung's diagnostic virology. Yale University Press, New Haven, CT.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, C. C., M. J. Sun, H. Y. Lei, S. H. Chen, C. K. Yu, C. C. Liu, J. R. Wang, and T. M. Yeh. 2004. Human endothelial cell activation and apoptosis induced by enterovirus 71 infection. J. Med. Virol. 74:597-603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15484266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., L. Y. Chang, S. H. Hsia, Y. C. Huang, C. H. Chiu, C. Hsueh, S. R. Shih, C. C. Liu, and M. H. Wu. 2002. The 1998 enterovirus 71 outbreak in Taiwan: pathogenesis and management. Clin. Infect. Dis. 34(Suppl. 2):S52-S57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11938497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., L. Y. Chang, Y. C. Huang, K. H. Hsu, C. H. Chiu, and K. D. Yang. 2002. Different proinflammatory reactions in fatal and non-fatal enterovirus 71 infections: implications for early recognition and therapy. Acta Paediatr. 91:632-635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12162592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., S. H. Hsia, Y. C. Huang, C. T. Wu, and L. Y. Chang. 2003. Proinflammatory cytokine reactions in enterovirus 71 infections of the central nervous system. Clin. Infect. Dis. 36:269-274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12539066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P. C. 2002. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 26:91-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata, N., H. Shimizu, Y. Ami, Y. Tano, A. Harashima, Y. Suzaki, Y. Sato, T. Miyamura, T. Sata, and T. Iwasaki. 2002. Pyramidal and extrapyramidal involvement in experimental infection of cynomolgus monkeys with enterovirus 71. J. Med. Virol. 67:207-216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11992581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata, N., T. Iwasaki, Y. Ami, Y. Tano, A. Harashima, Y. Suzaki, Y. Sato, H. Hasegawa, T. Sata, T. Miyamura, and H. Shimizu. 2004. Differential localization of neurons susceptible to enterovirus 71 and poliovirus type 1 in the central nervous system of cynomolgus monkeys after intravenous inoculation. J. Gen. Virol. 85:2981-2989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15448361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohka, S., N. Matsuda, K. Tohyama, T. Oda, M. Morikawa, S. Kuge, and A. Nomoto. 2004. Receptor (CD155)-dependent endocytosis of poliovirus and retrograde axonal transport of the endosome. J. Virol. 78:7186-7198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC421661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15194795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohka, S., W. X. Yang, E. Terada, K. Iwasaki, and A. Nomoto. 1998. Retrograde transport of intact poliovirus through the axon via the fast transport system. Virology 250:67-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9770421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, R., and V. R. Racaniello. 1992. Poliovirus spreads from muscle to the central nervous system by neural pathways. J. Infect. Dis. 166:747-752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1326581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tam, P. E., and R. P. Messner. 1999. Molecular mechanisms of coxsackievirus persistence in chronic inflammatory myopathy: viral RNA persists through formation of a double-stranded complex without associated genomic mutations or evolution. J. Virol. 73:10113-10121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10559326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyler, K. L., D. A. McPhee, and B. N. Fields. 1986. Distinct pathways of viral spread in the host determined by reovirus S1 gene segment. Science 233:770-774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3016895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., H. Y. Lei, K. J. Huang, J. M. Wu, J. R. Wang, C. K. Yu, I. J. Su, and C. C. Liu. 2003. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J. Infect. Dis. 188:564-570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, T., T. Town, L. Alexopoulou, J. F. Anderson, E. Fikrig, and R. A. Flavell. 2004. Toll-like receptor 3 mediates West Nile virus entry into the brain causing lethal encephalitis. Nat. Med. 10:1366-1373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15558055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. F., C. T. Chou, H. Y. Lei, C. C. Liu, S. M. Wang, J. J. Yan, I. J. Su, J. R. Wang, T. M. Yeh, S. H. Chen, and C. K. Yu. 2004. A mouse-adapted enterovirus 71 strain causes neurological disease in mice after oral infection. J. Virol. 78:7916-7924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC446098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, J. J., I. J. Su, P. F. Chen, C. C. Liu, C. K. Yu, and J. R. Wang. 2001. Complete genome analysis of enterovirus 71 isolated from an outbreak in Taiwan and rapid identification of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 by RT-PCR. J. Med. Virol. 65:331-339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11536241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, W. X., T. Terasaki, K. Shiroki, S. Ohka, J. Aoki, S. Tanabe, T. Nomura, E. Terada, Y. Sugiyama, and A. Nomoto. 1997. Efficient delivery of circulating poliovirus to the central nervous system independently of poliovirus receptor. Virology 229:421-428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9126254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>