<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25356127</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1940-5901</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of clinical and experimental medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Clin Exp Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>MRI characteristics and follow-up findings in patients with neurological complications of enterovirus 71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2696</StartPage><EndPage>2704</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2696-704</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to investigate the magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) characteristics and clinical and MRI follow-up findings of patients with neurological complications of enterovirus 71-related hand, foot and mouth disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Data were collected from 12 patients who developed neurological complications of enterovirus 71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease during an enterovirus-71 outbreak in Hainan Province, China, from May 2008 to October 2011. Patients were followed up for 2 years.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In the six patients with brainstem encephalitis, MRI showed posterior brainstem abnormalities with hyperintense areas on T2-weighted images and hypointense areas on T1-weighted images. In the four patients with acute flaccid paralysis but no brainstem encephalitis, sagittal MRI images showed linear hyperintense areas in the anterior spinal cord, transverse T2-weighted images showed hyperintense areas in the spinal cord, and contrast-enhanced axial T1-weighted images showed strong enhancement of the anterior horns or nerve roots. In the two patients with aseptic meningitis, MRI showed widening of the subarachnoid space and ventricles. The MRI and clinical signs of aseptic meningitis resolved within 4 weeks in both patients. Patients with isolated pontine abnormalities recovered faster than those with multiple brainstem abnormalities, patients with isolated brainstem encephalitis recovered faster than those with associated acute flaccid paralysis, patients with paralysis of one limb recovered faster than those with paralysis of multiple limbs, and patients with isolated thoracolumbar cord abnormalities recovered faster than those with cervical cord abnormalities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">MRI is useful for assessment of the neurological complications of enterovirus 71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease. Patients who develop neurological complications characteristically have MRI abnormalities of the posterior brainstem or bilateral anterior horns of parts of the spinal cord. The MRI findings can help to predict prognosis.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, People's Hospital of Hainan Province Haikou 570311, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, People's Hospital of Hainan Province Haikou 570311, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jianjun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, People's Hospital of Hainan Province Haikou 570311, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xing</LastName><ForeName>Zengbao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, People's Hospital of Hainan Province Haikou 570311, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Shixiong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, People's Hospital of Hainan Province Haikou 570311, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wen</LastName><ForeName>Guoqiang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, People's Hospital of Hainan Province Haikou 570311, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Clin Exp Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101471010</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1940-5901</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EV71 infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foot and mouth disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurological complications</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25356127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4211777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chen F, Li J, Liu T, Wang L, Li Y. MRI characteristics of brainstem encephalitis in hand-foot-mouth disease induced by enterovirus type 71--will different MRI manifestations be helpful for prognosis? Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2013;17:486&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23561930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Chen F, Liu T, Wang L. MRI findings of neurological complications in hand-foot-mouth disease by enterovirus 71 infection. Int J Neurosci. 2012;122:338&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22248036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen WC, Chiu HH, Chow KC, Tsai CH. MR imaging findings of enteroviral encephaloymelitis: an outbreak in Taiwan. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 1999;20:1889&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7657785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10588115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CC, Liu CC, Chang YC, Chen CY, Wang ST, Yeh TF. Neurologic complications in children with enterovirus 71 infection. New Engl J Med. 1999;341:936&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Peng Y, Duan XM, Wang Xu, Zeng JJ, Sun GQ. MRI findings of spine: acute flaccid paralysis associated with enterovirus 71 infected hand-foot-mouth disease. Zhonghua Fang She Xue Za Zhi. 2008;42:1237&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Ma YX, Zhang CB, Chen YP, Ye XJ, Bai GH, Yu ZK, Yan ZH. Neurologic complications in children with enterovirus 71-infected hand-foot-mouth disease: clinical features, MRI findings and follow-up study. Zhonghua Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2012;92:1742&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22944180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang S, Suh SI, Ha SM, Byeon JH, Eun BL, Lee YH, Seo HS, Eun SH, Seol HY. Enterovirus 71-related encephalomyelitis: usual and unusual magnetic resonance imaging findings. Neuroradiology. 2012;54:239&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21861081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China. Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of hand, foot and mouth disease (2008 edition)  Available at:  http://www.chinacdc.net.cn/n272442/n272530/n275462/275477/n292888/23509.html. Accessed May 20, 2008. Chinese.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shieh WJ, Jung SM, Hsueh C, Kuo TT, Mounts A, Parashar U, Yang CF, Guarner J, Ksiazek TG, Dawson J, Goldsmith C, Chang GJ, Oberste SM, Pallansch MA, Anderson LJ, Zaki SR. Pathologic studies of fatal cases in outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease, Taiwan. Emerg Infect Dis. 2001;7:146&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2631691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11266307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Wang H, Gong E, Du J, Zhao X, McNutt MA, Wang S, Zhong Y, Gao Z, Zheng J. Neuropathology in 2 cases of fatal enterovirus type 71 infection from a recent epidemic in the People&#x2019;s Republic of China: a histopathologic, immunohistochemical, and reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction study. Hum Pathol. 2009;40:1288&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YF, Chou CT, Lei HY, Liu CC, Wang SM, Yan JJ, Su IJ, Wang JR, Yeh TM, Chen SH, Yu CK. A mouse-adapted enterovirus 71 strain causes neurological disease in mice after oral infection. J Virol. 2004;78:7916&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC446098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong KT, Munisamy B, Ong KC, Kojima H, Noriyo N, Chua KB, Ong BB, Nagashima K. The distribution of inflammation and virus in human enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis suggests possible viral spread by neural pathways. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2008;67:162&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18219253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng BW, Du ZH, Li XJ, Lin HS, Liu HS, Chen WX, Mai JN, Liang HC. Evolution and prognosis of the acute flaccid paralysis associated with enterovirus 71 infection evaluated through a clinical and magnetic resonance imaging follow-up study. Zhonghua Er Ke Za Zhi. 2012;50:255&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22801224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng H, Wen F, Gan Y, Huang W. MRI and associated clinical characteristics of EV71-induced brainstem encephalitis in children with hand-foot-mouth disease. Neuroradiology. 2012;54:623&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22200974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>