<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31966515</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1936-2625</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of clinical and experimental pathology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Clin Exp Pathol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identification of genes involved in enterovirus 71 infected SK-N-SH cells.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>11588</StartPage><EndPage>11595</EndPage><MedlinePgn>11588-11595</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The enterovirus 71 (EV71) is the major pathogen of hand-foot-and-mouth disease (HFMD) and has been associated with severe neurological disease in children under 5 years of age. The molecular mechanisms underlying the response of human neural cells to EV71 infection still remain unclear. In this study, the genome microarray was employed to perform transcriptome profiling analysis in human neuroblastoma SK-N-SH cells infected by EV71. The results indicated that EV71 infection lead to altered expression of 87 human mRNA. The up-regulated gene mainly include the cytokine and chemokine, ubiquitin mediated proteolysis, Toll-like receptor signaling pathway, p53 signaling pathway, apoptosis, leukocyte transendothelial migration, MAPK signaling pathway and Jak-STAT signaling pathway, etc. Finally, the microarray results were validated using real-time RT-PCR and ELISA in the RNA and protein level, respectively. Our results suggested that the high fatality rate of EV71 infection probably derived from a severe immune response caused by cytokines and chemokines. The findings will help to better understand the host responses to EV71 infection and provide the potential strategy for prevention and control of EV71 infection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>IJCEP Copyright &#xa9; 2017.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Fei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Basic Medical Sciences, Hubei University of Medicine Shiyan, Hubei Province.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Junjie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Basic Medical Sciences, Hubei University of Medicine Shiyan, Hubei Province.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xi</LastName><ForeName>Xueyan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Basic Medical Sciences, Hubei University of Medicine Shiyan, Hubei Province.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Clin Exp Pathol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101480565</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1936-2625</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EV71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HFMD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SK-N-SH</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemokine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gene microarray</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31966515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6966083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bohn-Wippert K, Tevonian EN, Megaridis MR, Dar RD. Similarity in viral and host promoters couples viral reactivation with host cell migration. Nat Commun. 2017;8:15006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5418578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28462923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan LG, Parashar UD, Lye MS, Ong FG, Zaki SR, Alexander JP, Ho KK, Han LL, Pallansch MA, Suleiman AB. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. For the outbreak study group. Clin Infect Dis. 2000;31:678&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong X, Zhou J, Zhu W, Liu N, Li J, Li L, Jin Y, Duan Z. Excessive proinflammatory cytokine and chemokine responses of human monocyte-derived macrophages to enterovirus 71 infection. BMC Infect Dis. 2012;12:224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3519709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22994237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han ZL, Li JA, Chen ZB. Genetic polymorphism of CCL2-2510 and susceptibility to enterovirus 71 encephalitis in a Chinese population. Arch Virol. 2014;5:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24788844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kudoh K, Ramanna M, Ravatn R, Elkahloun AG, Bittner ML, Meltzer PS, Trent JM, Dalton WS, Chin KV. Monitoring the expression profiles of doxorubicin induced and doxorubicinresistant cancer cells by cDNA microarray. Cancer Res. 2002;60:4161&#x2013;4166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10945624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YR, Liu MT, Lei HY, Liu CC, Wu JM, Tung YC, Lin YS, Yeh TM, Chen SH, Liu HS. A highly expressed chemokine in dengue haemorrhagic fever/dengue shock syndrome patients, may cause permeability change, possibly through reduced tight junctions of vascular endothelium cells. J Gen Virolo. 2006;87:3623&#x2013;3630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17098977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong WF, Chow VK. Transcriptomic and proteomic analyses of rhabdomyosarcoma cells reveal differential cellular gene expression in response to enterovirus 71 infection. Cell Microbiol. 2006;8:565&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7162300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16548883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Lin A, Yu C, Zhang Z, Xu D, Hu W, Liu L, Wang S, Nie X, Sun W, Gai Z, Chen Z. Association of enterovirus 71 encephalitis with the interleukin-8 gene region in Chinese children. Infect Dis. 2015;47:418&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25751776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JA, Chen ZB, Lv TG, Han ZL. Genetic polymorphism of CCL2-2518, CXCL10-201, IL8+781 and susceptibility to severity of enterovirus-71 infection in a Chinese population. Inflamm Res. 2014;63:549&#x2013;556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24609754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2002;26:91&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao P, Wu X, Li H, Wu Z, Yang Z, Yao H. Clinical significance of inflammatory cytokine and chemokine expression in hand, foot and mouth disease. Mol Med Rep. 2017;15:2859&#x2013;2866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28447721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang W, Qian S, Fang L, Han Y, Zheng C. Association study of inflammatory cytokine and chemokine expression in hand foot and mouth disease. Oncotarget. 2017;8:79425&#x2013;79432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5668054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29108321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Stollar V, Lin JY, Chang SC, Chen GW, Li ML. Identification of genes involved in the host response to enterovirus 71 infection. J Neurovirolo. 2004;10:293&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Liu CC. Cytokine immunopathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brain stem encephalitis. Clin Dev Immunol. 2012;2012:876241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3432373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22956971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Yu CK, Wang JR, Su IJ, Liu CC. Acute chemokine response in the blood and cerebrospinal fluid of children with enterovirus 71-associated brainstem encephalitis. J Infect Dis. 2008;198:1002&#x2013;1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18710325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Li W, Yang X, Zhang T, Wang Y, Zhong R, Jiao Y, Li T, Jiang T, Tian Y, Wu H. Interleukin-8 is elevated in severe hand, foot, and mouth disease. J Infect Dev Ctries. 2014;8:94&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24423718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Xie J, Jia L, Liu N, Liang Y, Wu F, Liang B, Li Y, Wang J, Sheng C, Li H, Liu H, Ma Q, Yang C, Du X, Qiu S, Song H. Analysis of miRNAs involved in mouse brain damage upon enterovirus 71 infection. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2017;7:133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5395563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28469998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye N, Gong X, Pang LL, Gao WJ, Zhang YT, Li XL, Liu N, Li DD, Jin Y, Duan ZJ. Cytokine responses and correlations thereof with clinical profiles in children with enterovirus 71 infections. BMC Infect Dis. 2015;15:225&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4461975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26058678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zamora Y, Rojas LJ, Sandoval EM, Porras JS, Contrera EY, Romero SS, Ramirez PD, Losada H, Rios C, Mahecha DA, Serrano KD, Monta&#xf1;a JC, Caicedo VL, Gutierrez FRS. Chagas disease immunogenetics: elusive markers of disease progression. Expert Rev Cardiovasc Ther. 2017;19:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28388241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Liu H, Wang L, Yang F, Hu Y, Ren X, Li G, Yang Y, Sun S, Li Y, Chen X, Li X, Jin Q. Comparative study of the cytokine/chemokine response in children with differing disease severity in enterovirus 71-induced hand, foot, and mouth disease. PLoS One. 2013;8:e67430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3696071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23840697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>