<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">17567701</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2007</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-538X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>81</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2007</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An attenuated strain of enterovirus 71 belonging to genotype a showed a broad spectrum of antigenicity with attenuated neurovirulence in cynomolgus monkeys.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9386</StartPage><EndPage>9395</EndPage><MedlinePgn>9386-95</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is a causative agent of hand, foot, and mouth disease and is also sometimes associated with serious neurological disorders. In this study, we characterized the antigenicity and tissue specificity of an attenuated strain of EV71 [EV71(S1-3')], which belongs to genotype A, in a monkey infection model. Three cynomolgus monkeys were inoculated with EV71(S1-3'), followed by lethal challenge with the parental virulent strain EV71(BrCr-TR) via an intravenous route on day 45 postinoculation of EV71(S1-3'). Monkeys inoculated with EV71(S1-3') showed a mild neurological symptom (tremor) but survived lethal challenge by virulent EV71(BrCr-TR) without exacerbation of the symptom. The immunized monkey sera showed a broad spectrum of neutralizing activity against different genotypes of EV71, including genotypes A, B1, B4, C2, and C4. For the strains examined, the sera showed the highest neutralization activity against the homotype (genotype A) and the lowest neutralization activity against genotype C2. The order of decreasing neutralization activity of sera was as follows: A &gt; B1 &gt; C4 &gt; B4 &gt; C2. To examine the tissue specificity of EV71(S1-3'), two monkeys were intravenously inoculated with EV71(S1-3'), followed by examination of virus distribution in the central nervous system (CNS) and extraneural tissues. In the CNS, EV71(S1-3') was isolated only from the spinal cord. These results indicate that EV71(S1-3') acts as an effective antigen, although this attenuated strain was still neurotropic when inoculated via the intravenous route.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arita</LastName><ForeName>Minetaro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology II, National Institute of Infectious Diseases, 4-7-1 Gakuen, Musashimurayama-shi, Tokyo 208-0011, Japan. minetaro@nih.go.jp</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagata</LastName><ForeName>Noriyo</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwata</LastName><ForeName>Naoko</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ami</LastName><ForeName>Yasushi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suzaki</LastName><ForeName>Yuriko</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mizuta</LastName><ForeName>Katsumi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwasaki</LastName><ForeName>Takuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sata</LastName><ForeName>Tetsutaro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wakita</LastName><ForeName>Takaji</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimizu</LastName><ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2007</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000914">Antibodies, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000956">Antigens, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014613">Vaccines, Attenuated</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014765">Viral Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000914" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000956" MajorTopicYN="N">Antigens, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002490" MajorTopicYN="N">Central Nervous System</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002522" MajorTopicYN="N">Chlorocebus aethiops</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003429" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross Reactions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008252" MajorTopicYN="N">Macaca fascicularis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009500" MajorTopicYN="N">Neutralization Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009928" MajorTopicYN="N">Organ Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016019" MajorTopicYN="N">Survival Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014202" MajorTopicYN="N">Tremor</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014613" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccines, Attenuated</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014709" MajorTopicYN="N">Vero Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014765" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Vaccines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2007</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2007</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2007</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2008</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17567701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.02856-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.02856-06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abubakar, S., H. Y. Chee, N. Shafee, K. B. Chua, and S. K. Lam. 1999. Molecular detection of enteroviruses from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Malaysia in 1997. Scand. J. Infect. Dis. 31:331-335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10528868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita, M., H. Horie, M. Arita, and A. Nomoto. 1999. Interaction of poliovirus with its receptor affords a high level of infectivity to the virion in poliovirus infections mediated by the Fc receptor. J. Virol. 73:1066-1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC103926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9882307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita, M., N. Nagata, T. Sata, T. Miyamura, and H. Shimizu. 2006. Quantitative analysis of poliomyelitis-like paralysis in mice induced by a poliovirus replicon. J. Gen. Virol. 87:3317-3327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17030866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita, M., H. Shimizu, and T. Miyamura. 2004. Characterization of in vitro and in vivo phenotypes of poliovirus type 1 mutants with reduced viral protein synthesis activity. J. Gen. Virol. 85:1933-1944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15218178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita, M., H. Shimizu, N. Nagata, Y. Ami, Y. Suzaki, T. Sata, T. Iwasaki, and T. Miyamura. 2005. Temperature-sensitive mutants of enterovirus 71 show attenuation in cynomolgus monkeys. J. Gen. Virol. 86:1391-1401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodian, D. 1954. Viremia in experimental poliomyelitis. I. General aspects of infection after intravascular inoculation with strains of high and of low invasiveness. Am. J. Hyg. 60:339-357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13207104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, B. A., M. S. Oberste, J. P. Alexander, Jr., M. L. Kennett, and M. A. Pallansch. 1999. Molecular epidemiology and evolution of enterovirus 71 strains isolated from 1970 to 1998. J. Virol. 73:9969-9975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10559310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, B. A., and M. A. Pallansch. 1995. Complete nucleotide sequence of enterovirus 71 is distinct from poliovirus. Virus Res. 39:195-205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8837884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns, C. C., J. Shaw, R. Campagnoli, J. Jorba, A. Vincent, J. Quay, and O. Kew. 2006. Modulation of poliovirus replicative fitness in HeLa cells by deoptimization of synonymous codon usage in the capsid region. J. Virol. 80:3259-3272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1440415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16537593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., T. Y. Lin, K. H. Hsu, Y. C. Huang, K. L. Lin, C. Hsueh, S. R. Shih, H. C. Ning, M. S. Hwang, H. S. Wang, and C. Y. Lee. 1999. Clinical features and risk factors of pulmonary oedema after enterovirus-71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet 354:1682-1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov, M., M. Voroshilova, L. Shindarov, I. Lavrova, L. Gracheva, G. Koroleva, S. Vasilenko, I. Brodvarova, M. Nikolova, S. Gyurova, M. Gacheva, G. Mitov, N. Ninov, E. Tsylka, I. Robinson, M. Frolova, V. Bashkirtsev, L. Martiyanova, and V. Rodin. 1979. Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch. Virol. 60:329-340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Jesus, N., D. Franco, A. Paul, E. Wimmer, and J. Cello. 2005. Mutation of a single conserved nucleotide between the cloverleaf and internal ribosome entry site attenuates poliovirus neurovirulence. J. Virol. 79:14235-14243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1280220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16254358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dufresne, A. T., and M. Gromeier. 2004. A nonpolio enterovirus with respiratory tropism causes poliomyelitis in intercellular adhesion molecule 1 transgenic mice. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 101:13636-13641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC518806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15353596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto, T., M. Chikahira, S. Yoshida, H. Ebira, A. Hasegawa, A. Totsuka, and O. Nishio. 2002. Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol. Immunol. 46:621-627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gromeier, M., B. Bossert, M. Arita, A. Nomoto, and E. Wimmer. 1999. Dual stem loops within the poliovirus internal ribosomal entry site control neurovirulence. J. Virol. 73:958-964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC103915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9882296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara, A., I. Tagaya, and T. Yoneyama. 1978. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Intervirology 9:60-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">202573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto, I., and A. Hagiwara. 1983. Comparative studies on the neurovirulence of temperature-sensitive and temperature-resistant viruses of enterovirus 71 in monkeys. Acta Neuropathol. (Berlin) 60:266-270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6310928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto, I., and A. Hagiwara. 1982. Pathogenicity of a poliomyelitis-like disease in monkeys infected orally with enterovirus 71: a model for human infection. Neuropathol. Appl. Neurobiol. 8:149-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7048123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hattori, M., M. Oseto, Y. Yamashita, M. Mori, H. Inouye, Y. Ishimaru, and S. Nakano. 1994. An epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with enterovirus 71 infection in Ehime in 1993. Annu. Rep. Ehime Prefectural Inst. Public Health Environ. Sci. 55:11-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M., E. R. Chen, K. H. Hsu, S. J. Twu, K. T. Chen, S. F. Tsai, J. R. Wang, and S. R. Shih. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929-935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C. C., C. C. Liu, Y. C. Chang, C. Y. Chen, S. T. Wang, and T. F. Yeh. 1999. Neurologic complications in children with enterovirus 71 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:936-942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iizuka, N., M. Kohara, K. Hagino-Yamagishi, S. Abe, T. Komatsu, K. Tago, M. Arita, and A. Nomoto. 1989. Construction of less neurovirulent polioviruses by introducing deletions into the 5&#x2032; noncoding sequence of the genome. J. Virol. 63:5354-5363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC251202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2555560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karber, G. 1931. Beitrag zur kollektiven Behandlung pharmakologischer Reihenversuche. Arch. Exp. Path. Pharm. 162:480.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamura, N., M. Kohara, S. Abe, T. Komatsu, K. Tago, M. Arita, and A. Nomoto. 1989. Determinants in the 5&#x2032; noncoding region of poliovirus Sabin 1 RNA that influence the attenuation phenotype. J. Virol. 63:1302-1309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC247827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2536835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu, H., Y. Shimizu, Y. Takeuchi, H. Ishiko, and H. Takada. 1999. Outbreak of severe neurologic involvement associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr. Neurol. 20:17-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L., Y. He, H. Yang, J. Zhu, X. Xu, J. Dong, Y. Zhu, and Q. Jin. 2005. Genetic characteristics of human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 circulating from 1999 to 2004 in Shenzhen, People's Republic of China. J. Clin. Microbiol. 43:3835-3839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1233905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, K. H., K. P. Hwang, G. M. Ke, C. F. Wang, L. Y. Ke, Y. T. Hsu, Y. C. Tung, P. Y. Chu, B. H. Chen, H. L. Chen, C. L. Kao, J. R. Wang, H. L. Eng, S. Y. Wang, L. C. Hsu, and H. Y. Chen. 2005. Evolution of EV71 genogroup in Taiwan from 1998 to 2005: an emerging of subgenogroup C4 of EV71. J. Med. Virol. 78:254-262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16372302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., S. J. Twu, M. S. Ho, L. Y. Chang, and C. Y. Lee. 2003. Enterovirus 71 outbreaks, Taiwan: occurrence and recognition. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:291-293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12643822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, C. Y., C. Y. Lee, C. L. Kao, W. Y. Shao, P. I. Lee, S. J. Twu, C. C. Yeh, S. C. Lin, W. Y. Shih, S. I. Wu, and L. M. Huang. 2002. Incidence and case-fatality rates resulting from the 1998 enterovirus 71 outbreak in Taiwan. J. Med. Virol. 67:217-223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11992582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, H. H., L. Alexander, and E. Wimmer. 1995. Construction and genetic analysis of dicistronic polioviruses containing open reading frames for epitopes of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 gp120. J. Virol. 69:4797-4806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC189292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7541843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum, L. C., K. T. Wong, S. K. Lam, K. B. Chua, A. Y. Goh, W. L. Lim, B. B. Ong, G. Paul, S. AbuBakar, and M. Lambert. 1998. Fatal enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. J. Pediatr. 133:795-798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macadam, A. J., G. Ferguson, D. M. Stone, J. Meredith, S. Knowlson, G. Auda, J. W. Almond, and P. D. Minor. 2006. Rational design of genetically stable, live-attenuated poliovirus vaccines of all three serotypes: relevance to poliomyelitis eradication. J. Virol. 80:8653-8663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1563845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16912313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., K. Lindsay, D. Perera, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, and M. J. Cardosa. 2001. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and western Australia. J. Virol. 75:7732-7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P. C. 2002. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 26:91-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minor, P. 1997. Poliovirus, p. 555-574. In N. Nathanson et al. (ed.), Viral pathogenesis. Lippincott-Raven Publishers, Philadelphia, PA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minor, P. D. 1992. The molecular biology of polio vaccines. J. Gen. Virol. 73:3065-3077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1335021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta, K., C. Abiko, T. Murata, Y. Matsuzaki, T. Itagaki, K. Sanjoh, M. Sakamoto, S. Hongo, S. Murayama, and K. Hayasaka. 2005. Frequent Importation of enterovirus 71 from surrounding countries into the local community of Yamagata, Japan, between 1998 and 2003. J. Clin. Microbiol. 43:6171-6175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16333123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller, S., D. Papamichail, J. R. Coleman, S. Skiena, and E. Wimmer. 2006. Reduction of the rate of poliovirus protein synthesis through large-scale codon deoptimization causes attenuation of viral virulence by lowering specific infectivity. J. Virol. 80:9687-9696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1617239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16973573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata, N., T. Iwasaki, Y. Ami, Y. Tano, A. Harashima, Y. Suzaki, Y. Sato, H. Hasegawa, T. Sata, T. Miyamura, and H. Shimizu. 2004. Differential localization of neurons susceptible to enterovirus 71 and poliovirus type 1 in the central nervous system of cynomolgus monkeys after intravenous inoculation. J. Gen. Virol. 85:2981-2989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15448361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata, N., H. Shimizu, Y. Ami, Y. Tano, A. Harashima, Y. Suzaki, Y. Sato, T. Miyamura, T. Sata, and T. Iwasaki. 2002. Pyramidal and extrapyramidal involvement in experimental infection of cynomolgus monkeys with enterovirus 71. J. Med. Virol. 67:207-216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11992581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathanson, N. 2005. Virus perpetuation in populations: biological variables that determine persistence or eradication. Arch. Virol. Suppl. 19:3-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7121194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16355865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathanson, N., and J. R. Martin. 1979. The epidemiology of poliomyelitis: enigmas surrounding its appearance, epidemicity, and disappearance. Am. J. Epidemiol. 110:672-692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">400274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omata, T., M. Kohara, S. Kuge, T. Komatsu, S. Abe, B. L. Semler, A. Kameda, H. Itoh, M. Arita, E. Wimmer, and A. Nomoto. 1986. Genetic analysis of the attenuation phenotype of poliovirus type 1. J. Virol. 58:348-358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC252919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3009852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulli, T., P. Koskimies, and T. Hyypia. 1995. Molecular comparison of coxsackie A virus serotypes. Virology 212:30-38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7676647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabin, A. B. 1965. Oral poliovirus vaccine. History of its development and prospects for eradication of poliomyelitis. JAMA 194:872-876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5321495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabin, A. B. 1956. Pathogenesis of poliomyelitis: reappraisal in the light of new data. Science 123:1151-1157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13337331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sambrook, J., and D. W. Russell. 2001. Molecular cloning: a laboratory manual, 3rd ed., p, 13.19-13.25. Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, Cold Spring Harbor, NY.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, N. J., E. H. Lennette, and H. H. Ho. 1974. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J. Infect. Dis. 129:304-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu, H., A. Utama, N. Onnimala, C. Li, Z. Li-Bi, M. Yu-Jie, Y. Pongsuwanna, and T. Miyamura. 2004. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection in the western Pacific region. Pediatr. Int. 46:231-235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu, H., A. Utama, K. Yoshii, H. Yoshida, T. Yoneyama, M. Sinniah, M. A. Yusof, Y. Okuno, N. Okabe, S. R. Shih, H. Y. Chen, G. R. Wang, C. L. Kao, K. S. Chang, T. Miyamura, and A. Hagiwara. 1999. Enterovirus 71 from fatal and nonfatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease epidemics in Malaysia, Japan and Taiwan in 1997-1998. Jpn. J. Infect. Dis. 52:12-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10808253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shindarov, L. M., M. P. Chumakov, M. K. Voroshilova, S. Bojinov, S. M. Vasilenko, I. Iordanov, I. D. Kirov, E. Kamenov, E. V. Leshchinskaya, G. Mitov, I. A. Robinson, S. Sivchev, and S. Staikov. 1979. Epidemiological, clinical, and pathomorphological characteristics of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease caused by enterovirus 71. J. Hyg. Epidemiol. Microbiol. Immunol. 23:284-295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">231067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tano, Y., H. Shimizu, M. Shiomi, T. Nakano, and T. Miyamura. 2002. Rapid serological diagnosis of enterovirus 71 infection by IgM ELISA. Jpn. J. Infect. Dis. 55:133-135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12403913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tardy-Panit, M., B. Blondel, A. Martin, F. Tekaia, F. Horaud, and F. Delpeyroux. 1993. A mutation in the RNA polymerase of poliovirus type 1 contributes to attenuation in mice. J. Virol. 67:4630-4638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC237848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8392604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallis, C., and J. L. Melnick. 1967. Virus aggregation as the cause of the non-neutralizable persistent fraction. J. Virol. 1:478-488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC375261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4318956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. R., Y. C. Tuan, H. P. Tsai, J. J. Yan, C. C. Liu, and I. J. Su. 2002. Change of major genotype of enterovirus 71 in outbreaks of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Taiwan between 1998 and 2000. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:10-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., H. Y. Lei, K. J. Huang, J. M. Wu, J. R. Wang, C. K. Yu, I. J. Su, and C. C. Liu. 2003. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J. Infect. Dis. 188:564-570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., C. C. Liu, H. W. Tseng, J. R. Wang, C. C. Huang, Y. J. Chen, Y. J. Yang, S. J. Lin, and T. F. Yeh. 1999. Clinical spectrum of enterovirus 71 infection in children in southern Taiwan, with an emphasis on neurological complications. Clin. Infect. Dis. 29:184-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10433583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenner, H. A., P. Harmon, A. M. Behbehani, H. Rouhandeh, and P. S. Kamitsuka. 1967. The antigenic heterogeneity of type 30 echoviruses. Am. J. Epidemiol. 85:240-249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6020795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>