<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">15870327</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Application of cation-coated filter method to detection of noroviruses, enteroviruses, adenoviruses, and torque teno viruses in the Tamagawa River in Japan.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2403</StartPage><EndPage>2411</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2403-11</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The occurrence of human enteric viruses in surface water in the Tamagawa River, Japan, was surveyed for 1 year, from April 2003 to March 2004. Sixty-four samples were collected from six sites along the river, and 500 ml of the sample was concentrated using the cation-coated filter method, which was developed in our previous study. This method showed recovery yields of 56% +/- 32% (n = 37) for surface water samples inoculated with polioviruses. More than one kind of tested virus was detected in 43 (67%) of 64 samples by TaqMan PCR. Noroviruses and adenoviruses were detected in a high positive ratio; 34 (53%), 28 (44%), and 29 (45%) of 64 samples were positive for norovirus genotype 1 and genotype 2 and adenoviruses, respectively. The mean concentrations of norovirus genotype 1 or genotype 2 determined by real-time PCR were 0.087 and 0.61 genome/ml, respectively, showing much higher values in winter (0.21 genome/ml for genotype 1 and 2.3 genomes/ml for genotype 2). Enteroviruses were detected by both direct PCR (6 of 64 samples; 9%) and cell culture PCR (2 of 64 samples; 3%). Torque teno viruses, emerging hepatitis viruses, were also isolated in three samples (5%). The concentration of total coliforms and the presence of F-specific phages showed a high correlation with the presence of viruses, which suggested that the simultaneous use of total coliforms and F-specific phages as indicators of surface water may work to monitor viral contamination.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haramoto</LastName><ForeName>Eiji</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urban Engineering, School of Engineering, University of Tokyo, Bunkyo-ku, Tokyo 113-8656, Japan. haramoto@env.t.u-tokyo.ac.jp</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katayama</LastName><ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oguma</LastName><ForeName>Kumiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohgaki</LastName><ForeName>Shinichiro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002412">Cations</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000256" MajorTopicYN="N">Adenoviridae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002412" MajorTopicYN="N">Cations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005374" MajorTopicYN="N">Filtration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029322" MajorTopicYN="N">Norovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045483" MajorTopicYN="N">Rivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D022783" MajorTopicYN="N">Torque teno virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014881" MajorTopicYN="N">Water Supply</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="Y">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15870327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1087541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.5.2403-2411.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">71/5/2403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbaszadegan, M., M. S. Huber, C. P. Gerba, and I. L. Pepper. 1993. Detection of enteroviruses in groundwater with the polymerase chain reaction. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 59:1318-1324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7685998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anonymous. 1995. Water quality. Detection and enumeration of bacteriophages&#x2014;part 1. Enumeration of F-specific RNA bacteriophages. ISO 10705-1. International Organization for Standardization, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anonymous. 1999. Food safety standards, costs and benefits, p. 1-154. Australia-New Zealand Food Authority, Commonwealth Government of Australia, Canberra.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapron, C. D., N. A. Ballester, J. H. Fontaine, C. N. Frades, and A. B. Margolin. 2000. Detection of astroviruses, enteroviruses, and adenovirus types 40 and 41 in surface waters collected and evaluated by the information collection rule and an integrated cell culture-nested PCR procedure. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 66:2520-2525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC110573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10831432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba, C. P., S. R. Farrah, S. M. Goyal, C. Wallis, and J. L. Melnik. 1978. Concentration of enteroviruses from large volumes of tap water, treated sewage, and seawater. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 35:540-548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC242876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">205175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilgen, M., D. Germann, J. L&#xfc;thy, and P. H&#xfc;bner. 1997. Three-step isolation method for sensitive detection of enterovirus, rotavirus, hepatitis A virus, and small round structured viruses in water samples. Int. J. Food Microbiol. 37:189-199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, D. H., and G. D. Lewis. 1999. Comparative detection of enteric viruses in wastewaters, sediments and oysters by reverse transcription-PCR and cell culture. Water Res. 33:1195-1200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guttman-Bass, N., and J. Catalano-Sherman. 1985. Effects of humic materials on virus recovery from water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 49:1260-1264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC238539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3159339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haramoto, E., H. Katayama, and S. Ohgaki. 2004. Detection of noroviruses in tap water in Japan by means of a new method for concentrating enteric viruses in large volumes of freshwater. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 70:2154-2160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC383138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15066808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havelaar, A. H., W. M. Hogeboom, and R. Pot. 1984. F-specific RNA bacteriophages in sewage: methodology and occurrence. Water Sci. Technol. 17:645-655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havelaar, A. H., M. Van Olphen, and Y. C. Drost. 1993. F-specific RNA bacteriophages are adequate model organisms for enteric viruses in freshwater. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 59:2956-2962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8215367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heim, A., C. Ebnet, G. Harste, and P. Pring-Akerblom. 2003. Rapid and quantitative detection of human adenovirus DNA by real-time PCR. J. Med. Virol. 70:228-239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12696109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IAWPRC Study Group on Health Related Microbiology. 1991. Bacteriophages as model viruses in water quality control. Water Sci. Technol. 25:529-545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irving, L. G., and F. A. Smith. 1981. One-year survey of enteroviruses, adenoviruses, and reoviruses isolated from effluent at an activated-sludge purification plant. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 41:51-59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6261687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johl, M., M. L. Kerkmann, U. Kramer, and R. Walter. 1991. Virological investigation of the River Elbe. Water Sci. Technol. 24:205-208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kageyama, T., S. Kojima, M. Shinohara, K. Uchida, S. Fukushi, F. B. Hoshino, N. Takeda, and K. Katayama. 2003. Broadly reactive and highly sensitive assay for Norwalk-like viruses based on real-time quantitative reverse transcription-PCR. J. Clin. Microbiol. 41:1548-1557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC153860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12682144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katayama, H., A. Shimasaki, and S. Ohgaki. 2002. Development of a virus concentration method and its application to detection of enterovirus and Norwalk virus from coastal seawater. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:1033-1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC123733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11872447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keswick, B. H., C. P. Gerba, S. L. Secor, and I. Cech. 1982. Survival of enteric viruses and indicator bacteria in groundwater. J. Environ. Sci. Health A 17:903-912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reference deleted.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohli, E., F. Bon, P. Pothier, R. Brachet, and A. Flahault. 1999. Investigation virologique du pic &#xe9;pid&#xe9;mique de gastro-ent&#xe9;rites de l'hiver 98-99. Virologie 3:156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limsawat, S., and S. Ohgaki. 1997. Fate of liberated viral RNA in wastewater determined by PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 63:2932-2933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1389215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16535660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lytle, C. D., and L. B. Routson. 1995. Minimized virus binding for tests of barrier materials. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 61:643-649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7574603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, J. F., J. Naranjo, and C. P. Gerba. 1994. Evaluation of MK filters for recovery of enteroviruses from tap water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 60:1974-1977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8031090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuura, K., S. Hasegawa, T. Nakayama, O. Morita, and H. Uetake. 1984. Viral pollution of the rivers in Toyama City. Microbiol. Immunol. 28:575-588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6088954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myrmel, M., E. M. M. Berg, E. Rimstad, and B. Grinde. 2004. Detection of enteric viruses in shellfish from the Norwegian coast. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 70:2678-2684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC404457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15128518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishizawa, T., H. Okamoto, K. Konishi, H. Yoshizawa, Y. Miyakawa, and M. Mayumi. 1997. A novel DNA virus (TTV) associated with elevated transaminase levels in posttransfusion hepatitis of unknown etiology. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 241:92-97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9405239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuanualsuwan, S., and D. O. Cliver. 2002. Pretreatment to avoid positive RT-PCR results with inactivated viruses. J. Virol. Methods 104:217-225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12088831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamoto, H., Y. Akahane, M. Ukita, M. Fukuda, F. Tsuda, Y. Miyakawa, and M. Mayumi. 1998. Fecal excretion of a nonenveloped DNA virus (TTV) associated with posttransfusion non-A-G hepatitis. J. Med. Virol. 56:128-132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9746068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pina, S., M. Puig, F. Lucena, J. Jofre, and R. Girones. 1998. Viral pollution in the environment and in shellfish: human adenovirus detection by PCR as an index of human viruses. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 64:3376-3382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC106735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9726885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shieh, Y. S. C., D. Wait, L. Tai, and M. D. Sobsey. 1995. Methods to remove inhibitors in sewage and other thermotolerant wastes for enterovirus detection by the polymerase chain reaction. J. Virol. Methods 54:51-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7559857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skraber, S., B. Gassilloud, and C. Gantzer. 2004. Comparison of coliforms and coliphages as tools for assessment of viral contamination in river water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 70:3644-3649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC427742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15184169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, M. B., N. Cox, M. A. Vrey, and W. O. K. Grabow. 2001. The occurrence of hepatitis A and astroviruses in selected river and dam waters in South Africa. Water Res. 35:2653-2660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11456164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokita, H., S. Murai, H. Kamitsukasa, M. Yagura, H. Harada, M. Takahashi, and H. Okamoto. 2002. High TT virus load as an independent factor associated with the occurrence of hepatocellular carcinoma among patients with hepatitis C virus-related chronic liver disease. J. Med. Virol. 67:501-509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12115995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai, Y. L., B. Tran, and C. J. Palmer. 1995. Analysis of viral RNA persistence in seawater by reverse transcriptase-PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 61:363-366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7887616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 1998. Announcement of the drinking water contaminant candidate list. Fed. Regist. 63:10273-10287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 2001. National primary drinking water standards. EPA816-F-01-007. Office of Water, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaidya, S. R., S. D. Chitambar, and V. A. Arankalle. 2002. Polymerase chain reaction-based prevalence of hepatitis A, hepatitis E and TT viruses in sewage from an endemic area. J. Hepatol. 37:131-136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12076872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinje, J., S. A. Altena, and M. Koopmans. 1997. The incidence and genetic variability of small round-structured viruses in outbreaks of gastroenteritis in The Netherlands. J. Infect. Dis. 176:1374-1378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9359742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadell, G. 1984. Molecular epidemiology of human adenoviruses. Curr. Top. Microbiol. Immunol. 110:191-220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6090058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward, R. L., D. I. Bernstein, E. C. Young, J. R. Sherwood, D. R. Knowlton, and G. M. Schiff. 1986. Human rotavirus studies in volunteers: determination of infectious dose and serological response to infection. J. Infect. Dis. 154:871-880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3021869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winona, L. J., A. W. Ommani, J. Olszewsky, J. B. Nuzzo, and K. H. Oshima. 2001. Efficient and predictable recovery of viruses from water by small scale ultrafiltration systems. Can. J. Microbiol. 47:1033-1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11766052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>