<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21980416</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characterization of an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Nanchang, China in 2010.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e25287</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e25287</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e25287</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0025287</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recent outbreaks of human enterovirus 71 (EV71) infection and EV71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) in China have affected millions and potentially lead to life-threatening complications in newborns. Furthermore, these outbreaks represent a significant global public health issue in the world. Understanding the epidemiology of HFMD and EV71 infection and their transmission patterns in China is essential for controlling outbreaks. However, no studies on the outbreaks of HFMD and EV71 infection in China during 2010 have been reported. In this report, we carried out an epidemiological analysis to study an outbreak of HFMD and EV71 infection in 2010 in the city of Nanchang in the Jiangxi province of People's Republic of China. From April 7 to May 11, 2010, a total of 109 HFMD cases were reported, and in this report the HFMD cases were studied by both epidemiological and laboratory analyses. The epidemiological study indicates that children aged younger than 8 years old represented more than 90% of the reported cases, with the age group of 1-3 years containing the highest number of cases. Laboratory studies detected a high prevalence of EV71 amongst the cases in our study, suggesting EV71 as a common enterovirus found in HFMD cases in Nanchang. Phylogenetic analysis of the sequence of the VP1 region of four EV71 isolates indicated that the Nanchang strains belong to the C4 subgenotype commonly found in China during outbreaks in 2008 but contain distinct variations from these strains. Our study for the first time characterizes the epidemiology of HFMD and EV71 infection in China in 2010 and furthermore, provides the first direct evidence of the genotype of EV71 circulating in Nanchang, China. Our study should facilitate the development of public health measures for the control and prevention of HFMD and EV71 infection in at-risk individuals in China.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Michelle Y</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Virology, College of Life Sciences, and Chinese-French Liver Disease Research Institute at Zhongnan Hospital, Wuhan University, Wuhan, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Weiyong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yingle</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berman</LastName><ForeName>Hillary</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Jianguo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Competing Interests: </b>Yang Zhu declares an affiliation to Jiangsu Affynigen Biotechnologies, Inc., Taizhou, Jiangsu, China. This does not alter the authors' adherence to all the PLoS ONE policies on sharing data and materials.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21980416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0025287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-11-09304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wong SS, Yip CC, Lau SK, Yuen KY. Human enterovirus 71 and hand, foot and mouth disease. Epidemiol Infect. 2010;138:1071&#x2013;1089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20056019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallansch M, Roos R. Enteroviruses: polioviruses, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses, and newer enteroviruses. In: Knipe DM, Howley PM, Griffin DE, Martin MA, Lamb RA, et al., editors. Fields Virology. Philadelphia, Pa.: Lippincott-William &amp; Wilkins; 2007. pp. 840&#x2013;893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, Cardosa MJ, McMinn P, et al. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect Dis. 2010;10:778&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Lin TY, Huang YC, Tsao KC, Shih SR, et al. Comparison of enterovirus 71 and coxsackie-virus A16 clinical illnesses during the Taiwan enterovirus epidemic, 1998. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1999;18:1092&#x2013;1096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10608631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong CY, Chan KP, Shah VA, Ng WY, Lau G, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore: a comparison of fatal and non-fatal cases. Acta Paediatr. 2003;92:1163&#x2013;1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14632332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CC, Liu CC, Chang YC, Chen CY, Wang ST, et al. Neurologic complications in children with enterovirus 71 infection. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:936&#x2013;942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, Twu SJ, Chen KT, et al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosoya M, Kawasaki Y, Sato M, Honzumi K, Kato A, et al. Genetic diversity of enterovirus 71 associated with hand, foot and mouth disease epidemics in Japan from 1983 to 2003. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2006;25:691&#x2013;694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16874167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta K, Abiko C, Murata T, Matsuzaki Y, Itagaki T, et al. Frequent importation of enterovirus 71 from surrounding countries into the local community of Yamagata, Japan, between 1998 and 2003. J Clin Microbiol. 2005;43:6171&#x2013;6175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16333123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podin Y, Gias EL, Ong F, Leong YW, Yee SF, et al. Sentinel surveillance for human enterovirus 71 in Sarawak, Malaysia: lessons from the first 7 years. BMC Public Health. 2006;6:180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1543637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16827926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhu Z, Yang W, Ren J, Tan X, et al. An emerging recombinant human enterovirus 71 responsible for the 2008 outbreak of hand foot and mouth disease in Fuyang city of China. Virol J. 2010;7:94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20459851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CH, Hsu BM, Wan MT. Molecular detection and prevalence of enterovirus within environmental water in Taiwan. J Appl Microbiol. 2008;104:817&#x2013;823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18201176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu BM, Chen CH, Wan MT. Prevalence of enteroviruses in hot spring recreation areas of Taiwan. FEMS Immunol Med Microbiol. 2008;52:253&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18218023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukashev AN, Lashkevich VA, Ivanova OE, Koroleva GA, Hinkkanen AE, et al. Recombination in circulating enteroviruses. J Virol. 2003;77:10423&#x2013;10431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC228507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12970427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste MS, Penaranda S, Pallansch MA. RNA recombination plays a major role in genomic change during circulation of coxsackie B viruses. J Virol. 2004;78:2948&#x2013;2955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC353746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14990713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oprisan G, Combiescu M, Guillot S, Caro V, Combiescu A, et al. Natural genetic recombination between co-circulating heterotypic enteroviruses. J Gen Virol. 2002;83:2193&#x2013;2200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12185273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santti J, Hyypia T, Kinnunen L, Salminen M. Evidence of recombination among enteroviruses. J Virol. 1999;73:8741&#x2013;8749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC112895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10482628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmonds P, Welch J. Frequency and dynamics of recombination within different species of human enteroviruses. J Virol. 2006;80:483&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16352572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bible JM, Iturriza-Gomara M, Megson B, Brown D, Pantelidis P, et al. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 in the United Kingdom from 1998 to 2006. J Clin Microbiol. 2008;46:3192&#x2013;3200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2566106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18650362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu H, Shimizu Y, Takeuchi Y, Ishiko H, Takada H. Outbreak of severe neurologic involvement associated with Enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr Neurol. 1999;20:17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Tseng HW, Wang SM, Wang JR, Su IJ. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998: epidemiologic and clinical manifestations. J Clin Virol. 2000;17:23&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma E, Chan KC, Cheng P, Wong C, Chuang SK. The enterovirus 71 epidemic in 2008&#x2013;public health implications for Hong Kong. Int J Infect Dis. 2010;14:e775&#x2013;780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20599410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortner B, Huang CW, Schmid D, Mutz I, Wewalka G, et al. Epidemiology of enterovirus types causing neurological disease in Austria 1999&#x2013;2007: detection of clusters of echovirus 30 and enterovirus 71 and analysis of prevalent genotypes. J Med Virol. 2009;81:317&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19107980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Velez CM, Anderson MS, Robinson CC, McFarland EJ, Nix WA, et al. Outbreak of neurologic enterovirus type 71 disease: a diagnostic challenge. Clin Infect Dis. 2007;45:950&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17879907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu H, Utama A, Onnimala N, Li C, Li-Bi Z, et al. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection in the Western Pacific Region. Pediatr Int. 2004;46:231&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu PV, Thao NT, Perera D, Huu TK, Tien NT, et al. Epidemiologic and virologic investigation of hand, foot, and mouth disease, southern Vietnam, 2005. Emerg Infect Dis. 2007;13:1733&#x2013;1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sanden S, Koopmans M, Uslu G, van der Avoort H. Epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in the Netherlands, 1963 to 2008. J Clin Microbiol. 2009;47:2826&#x2013;2833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2738086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witso E, Palacios G, Ronningen KS, Cinek O, Janowitz D, et al. Asymptomatic circulation of HEV71 in Norway. Virus Res. 2007;123:19&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16965832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao LX, Wu B, Bao WX, Han FA, Xu L, et al. Epidemiology of hand, foot, and mouth disease and genotype characterization of enterovirus 71 in Jiangsu, China. J Clin Virol. 2010 In press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20719557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Chen W, Chang H, Tang R, Zhao J, et al. Genetic analysis of the VP1 region of enterovirus 71 reveals the emergence of genotype A in central China in 2008. Virus Genes. 2010;41:1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20306124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Tan XJ, Wang HY, Yan DM, Zhu SL, et al. An outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with subgenotype C4 of human enterovirus 71 in Shandong, China. J Clin Virol. 2009;44:262&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19269888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chenna R, Sugawara H, Koike T, Lopez R, Gibson TJ, et al. Multiple sequence alignment with the Clustal series of programs. Nucleic Acids Res. 2003;31:3497&#x2013;3500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC168907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12824352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamura K, Dudley J, Nei M, Kumar S. MEGA4: molecular evolutionary genetics analysis (MEGA) software version 4.0. Mol Biol Evol. 2007:1596&#x2013;1599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17488738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, King CC, Hsu KH, Ning HC, Tsao KC, et al. Risk factors of enterovirus 71 infection and associated hand, foot, and mouth disease/herpangina in children during an epidemic in Taiwan. Pediatrics. 2002;109:e88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Tsao KC, Hsia SH, Shih SR, Huang CG, et al. Transmission and clinical features of enterovirus 71 infections in household contacts in Taiwan. JAMA. 2004;291:222&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14722149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>