<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23554831</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1741-427X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2013</Volume><PubDate><Year>2013</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Evidence-based complementary and alternative medicine : eCAM</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A laboratory evaluation of medicinal herbs used in china for the treatment of hand, foot, and mouth disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>504563</StartPage><MedlinePgn>504563</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">504563</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2013/504563</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) and coxsackievirus A16 (CVA16) are the causative agents of hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD). During recent epidemics of HFMD in China, medicinal herbals and preparations containing herbal extracts have demonstrated therapeutic efficacy with relative safety profiles. There have been no microbiological studies to validate their usefulness for HFMD. We selected 12 commonly used herbs for HFMD from government recommended guidelines as well as published reports and tested for their antiviral activity and anti-inflammatory activity. A water extract of Houttuynia cordata Thunb. (HCT) inhibited EV71 infection significantly and was marginally active against CVA16 infection. The IC50 (concentration to have 50% inhibitory effect) values of HCT against a Fuyang strain and a BrCr strain of EV71 were determined at 8.9&#x2009; &#x3bc; g/mL and 20.6&#x2009; &#x3bc; g/mL, respectively. Mentha haplocalyx Briq. (MHB) water extract was active against CVA16, with an IC50 value of 70.3&#x2009; &#x3bc; g/mL. The extract did not exhibit activity against EV71 infection. Although the majority of the extracts showed no activity against viral infection, several extracts demonstrated activity in blocking proinflammatory response by viral infection. This study therefore validates the effectiveness of Chinese herbs for HFMD since some formulations containing the correct combination of the herbs can block viral replication as well as proinflammatory response of HFMD.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoqing</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School and Jiangsu Key Laboratory of Molecular Medicine, Nanjing University, 22 Hankou Road, Nanjing 210093, China ; State Key Laboratory of Pharmaceutical Biotechnology and School of Life Sciences, Nanjing University, 22 Hankou Road, Nanjing 210093, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Chunyang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Lanfang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoshuang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Guang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Ren Xiang</ForeName><Initials>RX</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Erguang</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101215021</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1741-427X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2013</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2013</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23554831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3608275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/504563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Ren L, Xiong Z, et al. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in the People&#x2019;s Republic of China in 2008. Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 2009;47(7):2351&#x2013;2352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2708525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO.  Report on the Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease Outbreak in Fuyang City, Anhui Province and the Prevention and Control in China. 2008,  http://www2.wpro.who.int/NR/rdonlyres/591D6A7B-FB15-4E94-A1E9-1D3381847D60/0/HFMDCCDC20080515ENG.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian H, Yang QZ, Liang J, et al. Clinical features and management outcomes of severe hand, foot and mouth disease. Medical Principles and Practice. 2012;21(4):355&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22188681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Lewthwaite P, Cardosa MJ, Solomon T. Clinical features, diagnosis, and management of enterovirus 71. The Lancet Neurology. 2010;9(11):1097&#x2013;1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma E, Fung C, Yip SHL, Wong C, Chuang SK, Tsang T. Estimation of the basic reproduction number of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 in hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreaks. The Pediatric Infectious Disease Journal. 2011;30(8):675&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21326133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, Cardosa MJ, McMinn P, Ooi MH. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. The Lancet Infectious Diseases. 2010;10(11):778&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao HJ, Liu ZL, Steinmann P, et al. Chinese herbal medicines for treatment of hand, foot and mouth disease: a systematic review of randomized clinical trials. European Journal of Integrative Medicine. 2012;4(1):e85&#x2013;e111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang GL, Li ZG, Tong JB, et al. A review of Chinese traditional prescriptions used in treatment and prevention of hand, foot and mouth disease. Clinical Journal of Traditional Chinese Medicine. 2010;22(7):574&#x2013;582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue B, Yao Z, Yu R. Studies on anti-EV71 virus activity of traditional Chinese medicine and its clinical application in treatment of HFMD. Zhongguo Zhong Yao Za Zhi. 2011;36(23):3366&#x2013;3370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22393752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hozumi T, Matsumoto T, Ooyama H, et al. Antiviral agent containing crude drug. U.S. Patent 5,411,733, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhu Z, Yang W, et al. An emerging recombinant human enterovirus 71 responsible for the 2008 outbreak of hand foot and mouth disease in Fuyang city of China. Virology Journal. 2010;7(1, article 94)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20459851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed LJ, Muench H. A simple method of estimating fifty per cent endpoints. American Journal of Epidemiology. 1938;27(3):493&#x2013;497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Chou AH, Lien SP, et al. Identification and characterization of a cross-neutralization epitope of Enterovirus 71. Vaccine. 2011;29(26):4362&#x2013;4372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21501643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dulbecco R, Vogt M. Plaque formation and isolation of pure lines with poliomyelitis viruses. Journal of Experimental Medicine. 1954;99(2):167&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2180341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13130792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosmann T. Rapid colorimetric assay for cellular growth and survival: application to proliferation and cytotoxicity assays. Journal of Immunological Methods. 1983;65(1-2):55&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6606682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livak KJ, Schmittgen TD. Analysis of relative gene expression data using real-time quantitative PCR and the 2(-Delta Delta C(T)) Method. Methods. 2001;25(4):402&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11846609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CW, Tsai FJ, Tsai CH, et al. Anti-SARS coronavirus 3C-like protease effects of Isatis indigotica root and plant-derived phenolic compounds. Antiviral Research. 2005;68(1):36&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7114321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16115693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma SC, Du J, But PPH, et al. Antiviral Chinese medicinal herbs against respiratory syncytial virus. Journal of Ethnopharmacology. 2002;79(2):205&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11801383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cinatl J, Morgenstern B, Bauer G, Chandra P, Rabenau H, Doerr HW. Glycyrrhizin, an active component of liquorice roots, and replication of SARS-associated coronavirus. The Lancet. 2003;361(9374):2045&#x2013;2046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7112442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12814717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SJ, Chang YC, Lu KZ, et al. Antiviral activity of Isatis indigotica extract and its derived indirubin against Japanese encephalitis virus. Evidence-Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine. 2012;2012:7 pages.925830</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3405817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22911608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Liu YC, Jheng JR, et al. Anti-enterovirus 71 activity screening of Chinese herbs with anti-infection and inflammation activities. The American Journal of Chinese Medicine. 2009;37(1):143&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19222118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo KK, Chang JS, Wang KC, Chiang LC. Water extract of Glycyrrhiza uralensis inhibited enterovirus 71 in a human foreskin fibroblast cell line. The American Journal of Chinese Medicine. 2009;37(2):383&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19507280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai FJ, Lin CW, Lai CC, et al. Kaempferol inhibits enterovirus 71 replication and internal ribosome entry site (IRES) activity through FUBP and HNRP proteins. Food Chemistry. 2011;128(2):312&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25212137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu QC, Wang Y, Liu YP, et al. Inhibition of enterovirus 71 replication by chrysosplenetin and penduletin. European Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences. 2011;44(3):392&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Wang Z, Yang Z, et al. Houttuynia cordata blocks HSV infection through inhibition of NF-kappaB activation. Antiviral Research. 2011;92(2):341&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7114259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21951655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Hsia SH, Huang YC, Wu CT, Chang LY. Proinflammatory cytokine reactions in enterovirus 71 infections of the central nervous system. Clinical Infectious Diseases. 2003;36(3):269&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12539066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>