<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29109684</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1663-9812</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2017</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Antimicrobial, Anthelmintic, and Antiviral Activity of Plants Traditionally Used for Treating Infectious Disease in the Similipal Biosphere Reserve, Odisha, India.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>658</StartPage><MedlinePgn>658</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">658</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphar.2017.00658</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In the present study, we tested <i>in vitro</i> different parts of 35 plants used by tribals of the Similipal Biosphere Reserve (SBR, Mayurbhanj district, India) for the management of infections. From each plant, three extracts were prepared with different solvents (water, ethanol, and acetone) and tested for antimicrobial (<i>E. coli, S. aureus, C. albicans</i>); anthelmintic (<i>C. elegans</i>); and antiviral (<i>enterovirus 71</i>) bioactivity. In total, 35 plant species belonging to 21 families were recorded from tribes of the SBR and periphery. Of the 35 plants, eight plants (23%) showed broad-spectrum <i>in vitro</i> antimicrobial activity (inhibiting all three test strains), while 12 (34%) exhibited narrow spectrum activity against individual pathogens (seven as anti-staphylococcal and five as anti-candidal). Plants such as <i>Alangium salviifolium, Antidesma bunius, Bauhinia racemosa, Careya arborea, Caseria graveolens, Cleistanthus patulus, Colebrookea oppositifolia, Crotalaria pallida, Croton roxburghii, Holarrhena pubescens, Hypericum gaitii, Macaranga peltata, Protium serratum, Rubus ellipticus</i>, and <i>Suregada multiflora</i> showed strong antibacterial effects, whilst <i>Alstonia scholaris, Butea monosperma, C. arborea, C. pallida, Diospyros malbarica, Gmelina arborea, H. pubescens, M. peltata, P. serratum, Pterospermum acerifolium, R. ellipticus</i>, and <i>S. multiflora</i> demonstrated strong antifungal activity. Plants such as <i>A. salviifolium, A. bunius, Aporosa octandra, Barringtonia acutangula, C. graveolens, C. pallida, C. patulus, G. arborea, H. pubescens, H. gaitii, Lannea coromandelica, M. peltata, Melastoma malabathricum, Millettia extensa, Nyctanthes arbor-tristis, P. serratum, P. acerifolium, R. ellipticus, S. multiflora, Symplocos cochinchinensis, Ventilago maderaspatana</i>, and <i>Wrightia arborea</i> inhibit survival of <i>C. elegans</i> and could be a potential source for anthelmintic activity. Additionally, plants such as <i>A. bunius, C. graveolens, C. patulus, C. oppositifolia, H. gaitii, M. extensa, P. serratum, R. ellipticus</i>, and <i>V. maderaspatana</i> showed anti-enteroviral activity. Most of the plants, whose traditional use as anti-infective agents by the tribals was well supported, show <i>in vitro</i> inhibitory activity against an enterovirus, bacteria (<i>E. coil, S. aureus</i>), a fungus (<i>C. albicans</i>), or a nematode (<i>C. elegans</i>).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Panda</LastName><ForeName>Sujogya K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Zoology, North Orissa University, Baripada, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Padhi</LastName><ForeName>Laxmipriya</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Zoology, North Orissa University, Baripada, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leyssen</LastName><ForeName>Pieter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Rega Institute for Medical Research, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Maoxuan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neyts</LastName><ForeName>Johan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Rega Institute for Medical Research, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luyten</LastName><ForeName>Walter</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101548923</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1663-9812</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Similipal Biosphere Reserve</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anthelmintic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antibacterial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antifungal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antiviral</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ethnopharmacology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">traditional knowledge</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29109684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5660100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2017.00658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal S. G., Goyal S. (2013). Nyctanthes arbor&#x2013;tristis against pathogenic bacteria. J. Pharmacol. Phytochem. 2, 124&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwash M. S. A., Ibrahim N., Yaacob W. A., Din L. B. (2014). Antibacterial, antioxidant and cytotoxicity properties of traditionally used Melastoma malabathricum Linn. leaves. Adv. J. Food Sci. Technol. 6, 6&#x2013;12. 10.19026/ajfst.6.3022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19026/ajfst.6.3022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antony M., Mishra C. S., Thankamani V. (2014). Evaluation of active fraction from plant extracts of Alstonia scholaris for its in&#x2013;vitro and in&#x2013;vivo antiviral activity. Int. J. Pharm Pharma Sci. 6, 775&#x2013;781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijesh K., Sebastian D. (2013). Isolation and characterization of antibacterial compounds from Macaranga peltata against clinical isolates of Staphylococcus aureus. Int. J. Biol. Pharma Res. 4, 1196&#x2013;1203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner S. (1974). The genetics of Caenorhabditis elegans. Genetics 77, 71&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1213120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4366476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruu A.-L. (2002). Enteroviruses: polioviruses, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses and newer enteroviruses, in A Practical Guide to Clinical Virology, 2nd Edn., eds Haaheim L. R., Pattison J. R., Whitley R. J. (Chichester, UK: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd; ). 10.1002/0470857285.ch6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/0470857285.ch6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty A., Brantner A. H. (1999). Antibacterial steroid alkaloids from the stem bark of Holarrhena antidysenterica. J. Ethnopharmacol. 68, 339&#x2013;344. 10.1016/S0378-8741(99)00119-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0378-8741(99)00119-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10624899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox P. A., Balick M. J. (1994). The ethnobotanical approach to drug discovery. Sci. Am. 270, 82&#x2013;87. 10.1038/scientificamerican0694-82</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/scientificamerican0694-82</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8023119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desalermos A., Muhammed M., Glavis&#x2013;Bloom J., Mylonakis E. (2011). Using Caenorhabditis elegans for antimicrobial drug discovery. Expert Opin. Drug Discov. 6, 645&#x2013;652. 10.1517/17460441.2011.573781</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/17460441.2011.573781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3115622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21686092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desta B. (1993). Ethiopian traditional herbal drugs Part II. Antimicrobial activity of 63 medicinal plants. J. Ethnopharmacol. 39, 129&#x2013;139. 10.1016/0378-8741(93)90028-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0378-8741(93)90028-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8412246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El&#x2013;Mahmood A. M., Doughari J. H., Kiman H. S. (2010). In vitro antimicrobial activity of crude leaf and stem bark extracts of Gmelina arborea (Roxb) against some pathogenic species of Enterobacteriaceae. Afr. J. Pharma Pharmacol. 4, 355&#x2013;361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fabricant D. S., Farnsworth N. R. (2001). The value of plants used in traditional medicine for drug discovery. Environ. Health Perspect. 109, 69&#x2013;75. 10.1289/ehp.01109s169</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1289/ehp.01109s169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1240543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11250806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firn R. D. (2003). Bioprospecting &#x2013; why is it so unrewarding? Biodivers. Conserv. 12, 207&#x2013;216. 10.1023/A:1021928209813</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1021928209813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonzi W. A., Irwin M. Y. (1993). Isogenic strain construction and gene mapping in Candida albicans. Genetics 134, 717&#x2013;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1205510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8349105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyhrquist P. (2007). Traditional Medicinal Uses and Biological Activities of Some Plant Extracts of African Combretum Loefl., Terminalia L. and Pteleopsis Engl. Species (Combretaceae). Academic dissertation, University of Helsinki.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginsburg H., Deharo E. (2011). A call for using natural compounds in the development of new antimalarial treatments&#x2013;an introduction. Malar. J. 10:S1. 10.1186/1475-2875-10-S1-S1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-2875-10-S1-S1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3059457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21411010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girach R. D., Shaik A. A., Singh S. S., Ahmad M. (1999). The medicinal flora of Similipahar forests, Orissa State, India. J. Ethnopharmacol. 65, 165&#x2013;172. 10.1016/S0378-8741(98)00146-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0378-8741(98)00146-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10465657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govindarajan R., Vijayakumar M., Singh M., Rao C. V., Shirwaikar A., Rawat A. K. S., et al. . (2006). Antiulcer and antimicrobial activity of Anogeissus latifolia. J. Ethnophrmacol. 106, 57&#x2013;61. 10.1016/j.jep.2005.12.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2005.12.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16413714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurib&#x2013;Fakim A. (2005). Medicinal plants: traditions of yesterday and drugs of tomorrow. Mol. Aspects Med. 27, 1&#x2013;93. 10.1016/j.mam.2005.07.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mam.2005.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16105678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammer K. A., Carson C. F., Riley T. V. (1999). Antimicrobial activity of essential oils and other plant extracts. J. Appl. Microbiol. 86, 985&#x2013;990. 10.1046/j.1365-2672.1999.00780.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2672.1999.00780.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10438227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain A., Zaman M. K., Ramteke A. M. (2010). Antibacterial activity of trunk bark of Alstonia scholaris. Asian J. Pharmaceut. Clin. Res. 3, 46&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain V. C., Patel N. M., Shah D. P., Patel P. K., Joshi B. H. (2010). Antioxidant and antimicrobial activities of Alangium salvifolium (Lf) Wang root. Global J. Pharmacol. 4, 13&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawde A. B., Batra R. J., Weginwar R. G., Akkewar D. M., Gond G. S., Aparna Y. (2014). Preliminary phytochemical screening and bioevaluation studies of stem bark of Ventilago madersapatana Garten. Int. J. Res. Pharma Chem. 4, 74&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M. R., Omoloso A. D., Kihara M. (2003). Antibacterial activity of Alstonia scholaris and Leea tetramera. Fitoterapia 74, 736&#x2013;740. 10.1016/S0367-326X(03)00192-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0367-326X(03)00192-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14630186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R. S., Sivakumar T., Sundaram R. S., Sivakumar P., Nethaji R., Gupta M., et al. (2006). Antimicrobial and antioxidant activities of Careya arborea Roxb. stem bark. Iran J. Pharm. Ther. 5, 35&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar T., Alexander A., Dewangan A. D., Khan J., Sharma M. (2011). Investigation of in&#x2013;vitro anthelmintic activity of Bauhinia racemosa Linn. J. Appl. Pharm. Sci. 1, 73&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenaerts I., Walker G. A., Van Hoorebeke L., Gems D., Vanfleteren J. R. (2008). Dietary restriction of Caenorhabditis elegans by axenic culture reflects nutritional requirement for constituents provided by metabolically active microbes. J. Gerontol. A 63, 242&#x2013;252. 10.1093/gerona/63.3.242</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/63.3.242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4333221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18375873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lizardo R. C. M., Mabesa L. B., Dizon E. I., Aquino N. A. (2015). Functional and antimicrobial properties of bignay [Antidesma bunius (L.) Spreng.] extract and its potential as natural preservative in a baked product. Int. Food Res. J. 22, 88&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahapatra S. K., Mookerjee M., Roy D. S., Karak P., Das S., Dastidar S. G. (2013). Evaluation of antimicrobial potentiality of a flavonoid, isolated from the leaf of the plant Colebrookea Oppositifolia. Int. J. Biol. Pharm. Res. 4, 225&#x2013;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Gualda B., Sun L., Rivero-Buceta E., Flores A., Quesada E., Balzarini J., et al. . (2017). Structure-activity relationship studies on a Trp dendrimer with dual activities against HIV and enterovirus A71. Modifications on the amino acid. Antiviral Res. 139, 32&#x2013;40. 10.1016/j.antiviral.2016.12.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.antiviral.2016.12.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28017762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman D. J., Cragg G. M. (2016). Natural products as sources of new drugs from 1981 to 2014. J. Nat. Prod. 79, 629&#x2013;661. 10.1021/acs.jnatprod.5b01055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jnatprod.5b01055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26852623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padmavathi D., Bharathi R. V., Sarala A. (2011). In vitro anthelmintic activity of ethanolic extracts of Barringtonia acutangula (L.) Geartn. Int. J. Pharm Technol. Res. 3, 784&#x2013;786.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S. K. (2014). Ethno-medicinal uses and screening of plants for antibacterial activity from similipal biosphere reserve. Odisha, India. J. Ethnopharmacol. 151, 158&#x2013;175. 10.1016/j.jep.2013.10.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2013.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24177353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S. K., Dutta S. K. (2012). Antibacterial activity from bark extracts of Pterospermum acerifolium (L.) Willd. Int. J. Pharma Sci. Res. 2, 584&#x2013;595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S. K., Bastia A. K., Dutta S. K. (2010a). Anticandidal activity of Croton roxburghii Balak. Int. J. Curr. Pharma Res. 2, 55&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3255396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22247883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S. K., Das D., Tripthathy N. K. (2014). Phytochemical investigation and anthelmintic activity of various leaf extracts of Crotalaria pallida Aiton. World J. Pharma Pharmaceut. Sci. 4, 336&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S. K., Das D., Tripthathy N. K. (2015). Phytochemical investigation and anthelmintic activity of various root extracts of Gmelina arborea. Asian J. Plant Sci. Res. 5, 54&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S. K., Dutta S. K., Bastia A. K. (2010b). Antibacterial activity of Croton roxburghii Balak. against the enteric pathogens. J. Adv. Pharma Technol. Res. 1, 388&#x2013;391. 10.4103/0110-5558.76442</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0110-5558.76442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3255396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22247883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S. K., Mohanta Y. K., Padhi L., Park Y. H., Mohanta T. K., Bae H. (2016). Large scale screening of ethnomedicinal plants for identification of potential antibacterial compounds. Molecules 21, 1&#x2013;20. 10.3390/molecules21030293</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules21030293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6274442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26985889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda S. K., Patra N., Sahoo G., Bastia A. K., Dutta S. K. (2012). Anti&#x2013;diarrheal activities of medicinal plants of Similipal Biosphere Reserve, Odisha, India. Int. J. Med. Arom. Plants 2, 123&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey R. S. (2012). Anthelmintic activity of Alangium salviifolium bark. J. Nat. Prod. Plant Resour. 2, 717&#x2013;720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil U. H., Gaikwad D. K. (2010). Phytochemical profile and Antibacterial activity of stem bark of Anogeissus latifolia. Phrmacogn. J. 17, 70&#x2013;73. 10.1016/S0975-3575(10)80014-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0975-3575(10)80014-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pattnaik A., Sarkar R., Sharma A., Yadav K. K., Kumar A., Roy P., et al. (2013). Pharmacological studies on Buchanania lanzan Spreng.&#x2013;A focus on wound healing with particular reference to anti&#x2013;biofilm properties. Asian Pac. J. Trop. Biomed. 3, 967&#x2013;974. 10.1016/S2221-1691(13)60187-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2221-1691(13)60187-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3805096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24093788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patwardhan B. (2005). Ethnopharmacology and drug discovery. J. Ethnopharmacol. 100, 50&#x2013;52. 10.1016/j.jep.2005.06.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2005.06.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16023811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry B. D., Randolph T. F. (1999). Improving the assessment of the economic impact of parasitic diseases and of their control in production animals. Vet. Parasitol. 84, 145&#x2013;168. 10.1016/S0304-4017(99)00040-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0304-4017(99)00040-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10456413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prashanth D., Asha M. K., Amit A., Padmaja R. (2001). Anthelmintic activity of Butea monosperma. Fitoterapia 72, 421&#x2013;422. 10.1016/S0367-326X(00)00333-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0367-326X(00)00333-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11395269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prichard R. (1994). Anthelmintic resistance. Vet. Parasitol. 54, 259&#x2013;268. 10.1016/0304-4017(94)90094-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0304-4017(94)90094-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7846855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashed K., Butnariu M. (2014). Antimicrobial and antioxidant activities of Bauhinia racemosa Lam. and chemical content. Iran J. Pharm. Res. 13, 1073&#x2013;1080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4177630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25276210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahoo S., Panda P. K., Behera P. S., Mishra S. R., Ellaiah P. (2008). Antifungal activity of Barringtonia acutangula against selected human pathogenic fungi. Ind. Drugs 45, 26&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahu M. C., Padhy R. N. (2013). In vitro antibacterial potency of Butea monosperma Lam. against 12 clinically isolated multidrug resistant bacteria. Asian Pac. J. Trop. Dis. 3, 217&#x2013;226. 10.1016/S2222-1808(13)60044-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2222-1808(13)60044-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sant A., Ingole A., Dhabarde D., Kamble M. (2014). Evaluation of anthelmintic activity of flower extract of Butea monosperma var. lutea. J. Pharmacogn. Phytochem. 2, 152&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saslis&#x2013;Lagoudakis C. H., Savolainen V., Williamson E. M., Forest F., Wagstaff S. J., Baral S. R., et al. . (2012). Phylogenies reveal predictive power of traditional medicine in bioprospecting. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 109, 15835&#x2013;15840. 10.1073/pnas.1202242109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1202242109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3465383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22984175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satpute K., Bodas K., Shende V., Chaus W., Atul D., Amar G. (2014). Anthelmintic activity of extracts of Holarrhena antidysenterica Wall. World J. Pharma Pharmaceut. Sci. 3, 561&#x2013;567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena H. O., Brahmam M. (1994-1996). The Flora of Orissa, Vol. 1&#x2013;4 Bhubaneswar: RRL; CSIR.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shruti S., Goyal S., Shrivastva K., Singh P. M., Dave K., Singh N. (2009). In&#x2013;vitro anthelmintic activity of hydro alcoholic extract of leaves of Nyctanthes arbortristis Linn. J. Global Pharma Technol. 1, 101&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddiqui B. S., Ali S. T., Rizwani G. H., Begum S., Tauseef S., Ahmad A. (2012). Antimicrobial activity of the methanolic bark extract of Holarrhena pubescens (Buch. Ham), its fractions and the pure compound conessine. Nat. Prod. Res. 26, 987&#x2013;992. 10.1080/14786419.2010.537268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14786419.2010.537268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21834632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silhavy T. J., Kahne D., Walker S. (2010). The bacterial cell envelope. Cold Spring Harb. Perspect Biol. 2:a000414. 10.1101/cshperspect.a000414</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/cshperspect.a000414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2857177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20452953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R. K., Singh K. P., Turner N. J. (2013). A special note on Prior Informed Consent (PIC). Why are you asking our gyan (knowledge) and padhati (practice)?: Ethics and prior informed consent for research on traditional knowledge systems. Indian J. Tradit. Knowl. 12, 547&#x2013;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S. S., Sharma S. K. (2013). Anthelmintic potential of stem bark and roots of Alstonia scholaris (L.) R.Br. World J. Pharma Pharmaceut. Sci. 2, 3807&#x2013;3817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soejarto D. D., Fong H. H. S., Tan G. T., Zhang H. J., Ma C. Y., Franzblau S. J., et al. . (2005). Ethnobotany/ethnopharmacology and mass bioprospecting: issues on intellectual property and benefit&#x2013;sharing. J. Ethnopharmacol. 100, 15&#x2013;22. 10.1016/j.jep.2005.05.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2005.05.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15993554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suteky T., Dwatmadji (2011). Anthelmintic activity of Melastoma malabatricum extract on Haemonchus contortus activity in vitro. Asian J. Pharm. Clin. Res. 4, 68&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thatoi H. N., Panda S. K., Rath S. K., Dutta S. K. (2008). Antimicrobial activity and ethnomedicinal uses of some medicinal plants from Similipal Biosphere Reserve, Orissa. Asian J. Plant Sci. 7, 260&#x2013;267. 10.3923/ajps.2008.260.267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3923/ajps.2008.260.267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari P., Jain R., Kumar K., Mishra R., Chandy A. (2012). Antibacterial activity and physicochemical evaluation of roots of Butea monosperma. Asian Pacific J. Trop. Biomed. 2, S881&#x2013;S883. 10.1016/S2221-1691(12)60328-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2221-1691(12)60328-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ukil S., Laskar S., Roy R. N. (2016). Physicochemical characterization and antibacterial activity of the leaf oil of Crotalaria pallida Aiton. J. Taibah Univ. Sci. 10, 490&#x2013;496. 10.1016/j.jtusci.2015.07.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtusci.2015.07.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verpoorte R. (2000). Pharmacognosy in the new millennium: lead finding and biotechnology. J. Pharma Pharmacol. 52, 253&#x2013;262. 10.1211/0022357001773931</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1211/0022357001773931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10757412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner H., Ulrich&#x2013;Merzenich G. (2009). Synergy research: approaching a new generation of phytopharmaceuticals. Phytomedicine 16, 97&#x2013;110. 10.1016/j.phymed.2008.12.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phymed.2008.12.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19211237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan H., Moens M.-F., Luyten W., Zhou X., Mei Q., Liu L., et al. . (2016). Extracting relations from traditional Chinese medicine literature via heterogeneous entity networks. J. Am. Med. Informat. Assoc. 23, 356&#x2013;365. 10.1093/jamia/ocv092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamia/ocv092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7784314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26224335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson E., Okpako D. T., Evans F. J. (1996). Selection, Preparation and Pharmacological Evaluation of Plant Material. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood&#x2013;Sheldon J., Balick M. J., Laird S. A. (1997). Medicinal Plants: Can Utilization and Conservation Coexist? Bronx, NY: The New York Botanical Garden.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadava R. N., Tiwari L. (2005). A potential antiviral flavone glycoside from the seeds of Butea monosperma O. Kuntze. J. Asian Nat. Prod. Res. 7, 185&#x2013;188. 10.1080/1028602042000204054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1028602042000204054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15621625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F., Qin C., Tao L., Liu X., Shi Z., Ma X., et al. . (2011). Clustered patterns of species origins of nature&#x2013;derived drugs and clues for future bioprospecting. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 108, 12943&#x2013;12948. 10.1073/pnas.1107336108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1107336108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3150889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21768386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>