<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">19864378</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2010</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>84</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Formaldehyde-inactivated whole-virus vaccine protects a murine model of enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis against disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>661</StartPage><EndPage>665</EndPage><MedlinePgn>661-5</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.00999-09</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) causes childhood hand, foot, and mouth disease and neurological complications, and no vaccines or therapeutic drugs are currently available. Formaldehyde-inactivated whole-virus vaccines derived from EV71 clinical isolates and a mouse-adapted virus (MAV) were tested in a mouse model of EV71 encephalomyelitis. After only two immunizations, given to mice at 1 and 7 days of age, the MAV vaccine protected mice at 14 days of age from disease. Tissues from immunized mice were negative for virus by viral culture, reverse transcriptase PCR, immunohistochemistry analysis, and in situ hybridization. Cross-neutralizing EV71 antibodies to strains with genotypes B3, B4, and C1 to C5 generated in immunized adult mice were able to passively protect 14-day-old mice from disease.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ong</LastName><ForeName>Kien Chai</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, University of Malaya, 50603 Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Devi</LastName><ForeName>Shamala</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cardosa</LastName><ForeName>Mary Jane</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Kum Thong</ForeName><Initials>KT</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D057134">Antibodies, Neutralizing</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015164">Vaccines, Inactivated</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>1HG84L3525</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005557">Formaldehyde</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057134" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Neutralizing</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056738" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross Protection</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004679" MajorTopicYN="N">Encephalomyelitis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005557" MajorTopicYN="N">Formaldehyde</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007114" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015164" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccines, Inactivated</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2798416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.00999-09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.00999-09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alexander, J. P., L. Baden, M. A. Pallansch, and G. Anderson. 1994. Enterovirus 71 infections and neurologic disease&#x2014;United States, 1977-1991. J. Infect. Dis. 169:905-908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8133108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., D. Perera, B. A. Brown, D. Cheon, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, H. Cho, and P. McMinn. 2003. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 strains and recent outbreaks in the Asia-Pacific region: comparative analysis of the VP1 and VP4 genes. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:461-468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12702227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K. P., K. T. Goh, C. Y. Chong, E. S. Teo, G. Lau, and A. E. Ling. 2003. Epidemic hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:78-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, L. G., U. D. Parashar, M. S. Lye, F. G. L. Ong, S. R. Zaki, J. P. Alexander, K. K. Ho, L. L. Han, M. A. Pallansch, A. B. Suleiman, M. Jegathesan, and L. J. Anderson. 2000. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristic of the disease. Clin. Infect. Dis. 31:678-683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H. L., J. Y. Huang, T. W. Chu, T. C. Tsai, C. M. Hung, C. C. Lin, F. C. Liu, L. F. Wang, Y. J. Chen, M. F. Lin, and C. M. Chen. 2008. Expression of VP1 protein in the milk of transgenic mice: a potential oral vaccine protects against enterovirus 71 infection. Vaccine 26:2882-2889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18450335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong, C. Y., K. P. Chan, V. A. Shah, W. Y. M. Ng, G. Lau, T. S. Teo, S. H. Lai, and A. E. Ling. 2003. Hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore: a comparison of fatal and non-fatal cases. Acta Paediatr. 92:1163-1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14632332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung, Y. C., M. S. Ho, J. C. Wu, W. J. Chen, J. H. Huang, S. T. Chou, and Y. C. Hu. 2008. Immunization with virus-like particles of enterovirus 71 elicits potent immune responses and protects mice against lethal challenge. Vaccine 26:1855-1862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18329759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto, T., M. Chikahira, S. Yoshida, H. Ebira, A. Hasegawa, A. Totsuka, and O. Nishio. 2002. Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol. Immunol. 46:621-627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara, A., I. Tagaya, and T. Yoneyama. 1978. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Intervirology 9:60-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">202573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson, R. R. 1988. Case of paralytic illness associated with enterovirus 71 infection. JAMA 259:1621-1622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3343765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrero, L. J., C. S. Lee, R. J. Hurrelbrink, B. H. Chua, K. B. Chua, and P. C. McMinn. 2003. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in peninsular Malaysia, 1997-2000. Arch. Virol. 148:1369-1385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12827466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C. C., C. C. Liu, Y. C. Chang, C. Y. Chen, S. T. Wang, and T. F. Yeh. 1999. Neurologic complication in children with enterovirus 71 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929-935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishimaru, Y., S. Nakano, K. Yamaoka, and S. Takami. 1980. Outbreaks of hand, foot, and mouth disease by enterovirus 71. High incidence of complication disorders of central nervous system. Arch. Dis. Child. 55:583-588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1627055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6254449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennett, M. L., C. J. Birch, F. A. Lewis, A. P. Yung, S. A. Locarnini, and L. D. Gust. 1974. Enterovirus type 71 infection in Melbourne. Bull. World Health Organ. 51:609-614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2366271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4377551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu, K., Y. Shimizu, Y. Takeuchi, H. Ishiko, and H. Takada. 1999. Outbreak of severe neurologic involvement associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr. Neurol. 20:17-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum, L. C. S., K. T. Wong, S. K. Lam, K. B. Chua, A. Y. T. Goh, W. L. Lim, B. B. Ong, G. Paul, S. AbuBakar, and M. Lamber. 1998. Fatal enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. J. Pediatr. 133:795-798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n, J., G. Crossland, D. J. Wood, and P. D. Minor. 2003. Characterization of formaldehyde-inactivated poliovirus preparations made from live-attenuated strains. J. Gen. Virol. 84:1781-1788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12810872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick, J. L. 1984. Enterovirus 71 infections: a varied clinical pattern sometimes mimicking poliomyelitis. Rev. Infect. Dis. 6(Suppl. 2):S387-S390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy, G., S. Tak&#xe1;tsy, E. Kuk&#xe1;n, L. Mihaly, and I. D&#xf6;m&#xf6;k. 1982. Virological diagnosis of enterovirus type 71 infections: experiences gained during epidemic of acute CNS diseases in Hungary in 1978. Arch. Virol. 71:217-227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6285858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, D. K. K., A. K. W. Law, S. W. W. Cherk, and L. L. Mak. 2001. First fatal case of enterovirus 71 infection in Hong Kong. Hong Kong Med. J. 7:193-196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11514756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong, K. C., B. Munisamy, S. Devi, M. J. Cardosa, and K. T. Wong. 2008. Pathologic characterization of a murine model of human enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol. 67:532-542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18520772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallansch, M. A., and R. P. Roos. 2001. Enteroviruses: poliovirus, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses, and newer enteroviruses, p. 723-775. In D. M. Knipe, P. M. Howley, D. E. Griffin, M. A. Martin, R. A. Lamb, and B. Roizman (ed.), Fields virology, 4th ed., vol. 1. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, Philadelphia, PA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podin, Y., E. L. Gias, F. Ong, Y. W. Leong, S. F. Yee, M. A. Yusof, D. Perera, B. Teo, T. Y. Wee, S. C. Yao, S. K. Tao, A. Kiyu, M. T. Arif, and M. J. Cardosa. 2006. Sentinel surveillance for human enterovirus 71 in Sarawak, Malaysia: lessons from the first 7 years. BMC Public Health 6:180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1543637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16827926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shindarov, L. M., M. P. Chumakov, M. K. Voroshilova, S. Bojinov, S. M. Vasilenko, I. Iordanov, I. D. Kirov, E. Kamenov, E. V. Leshchinskaya, G. Mitov, I. A. Robinson, S. Sivchev, and S. Staikov. 1979. Epidemiological, clinical, and pathomorphological characteristics of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease caused by enterovirus 71. J. Hyg. Epidemiol. Microbiol. Immunol. 23:284-295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">231067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu, P. V., N. T. T. Thao, D. Perera, T. H. Huu, N. T. K. Tien, T. C. Thuong, O. M. How, M. J. Cardosa, and P. C. McMinn. 2007. Epidemiological and virologic investigation of hand, foot, and mouth disease, Southern Vietnam, 2005. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 13:1733-1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. F., C. T. Chou, H. Y. Lei, C. C. Liu, S. M. Wang, J. J. Yan, I. J. Su, J. R. Wang, T. M. Yeh, S. H. Chen, and C. K. Yu. 2004. A mouse-adapted enterovirus 71 strain causes neurological disease in mice after oral infection. J. Virol. 78:7916-7924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC446098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, K. T., M. Badmanathan, K. C. Ong, H. Kojima, N. Nagata, K. B. Chua, B. B. Ong, and K. Nagashima. 2008. The distribution of inflammation and virus in human enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis suggests possible viral spread by neural pathways. J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol. 67:162-169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18219253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, C. N., Y. C. Lin, C. Fann, N. S. Liao, S. R. Shih, and M. S. Ho. 2002. Protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by passive immunization with subunit VP1 vaccines and inactivated virus. Vaccine 20:895-904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>