<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">33031627</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1865-1682</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>68</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Transboundary and emerging diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Transbound Emerg Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The nasal viromes of cattle on arrival at western Canadian feedlots and their relationship to development of bovine respiratory disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2209</StartPage><EndPage>2218</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2209-2218</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/tbed.13873</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Bovine respiratory disease (BRD) has a complex pathogenesis and aetiology, being the costliest disease affecting the cattle industry in North America. In this study, we applied Nanopore-based viral metagenomic sequencing to explore the nasal virome of cattle upon arrival at feedlot and related the findings to the development of BRD. Deep nasal swabs (DNS) from 310 cattle for which BRD outcomes were known (155 cattle developed BRD within 40&#xa0;days and 155 remained healthy) were included. The most prevalent virus in on-arrival samples was bovine coronavirus (BCV) (45.2%, 140/310), followed by bovine rhinitis virus B (BRBV) (21.9%, 68/310), enterovirus E (EVE) (19.6%, 60/310), bovine parainfluenza virus 3 (BPIV3) (10.3%, 32/310), ungulate tetraparvovirus 1 (UTPV1) (9.7%, 30/310) and influenza D virus (7.1%, 22/310). No relationship was found between BRD development and the number of viruses detected, the presence of any specific individual virus or combination of viruses. Bovine kobuvirus (BKV) was detected in 2.6% of animals (8/310), being the first report of this virus in Canada. Results of this study demonstrate the diversity of viruses in bovine DNS collected upon arrival at feedlot and highlights the need for further research into prediction of BRD development in the context of mixed infections.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Maodong</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9565-3017</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Pathology, Western College of Veterinary Medicine, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hill</LastName><ForeName>Janet E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2187-6277</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Microbiology, Western College of Veterinary Medicine, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alexander</LastName><ForeName>Trevor W</ForeName><Initials>TW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada, Lethbridge Research and Development Centre, Lethbridge, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Yanyun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Pathology, Western College of Veterinary Medicine, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prairie Diagnostic Services Inc, Saskatoon, SK, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>China Scholarship Council</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SBIF2015-109</GrantID><Agency>Saskatchewan Cattlemen's Association</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ADF20160092</GrantID><Agency>Agriculture Development Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>AMR.10.17</GrantID><Agency>Beef Cattle Research Council</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Transbound Emerg Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101319538</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1865-1674</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002170" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Canada</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002417" MajorTopicYN="N">Cattle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002418" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cattle Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017938" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coronavirus, Bovine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012140" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Tract Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="Y">veterinary</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000083422" MajorTopicYN="N">Virome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014780" MajorTopicYN="N">Viruses</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bovine coronavirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bovine kobuvirus (BKV)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bovine respiratory disease (BRD)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">influenza D virus (IDV)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nanopore sequencing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nasal virome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tbed.13873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Allander, T., Tammi, M. T., Eriksson, M., Bjerkner, A., Tiveljung-Lindell, A., &amp; Andersson, B. (2005). Cloning of a human parvovirus by molecular screening of respiratory tract samples. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 102, 12891-12896. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0504666102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blas-Machado, U., Saliki, J. T., Boileau, M. J., Goens, S. D., Caseltine, S. L., Duffy, J. C., &amp; Welsh, R. D. (2007). Fatal ulcerative and hemorrhagic typhlocolitis in a pregnant heifer associated with natural bovine enterovirus type-1 infection. Veterinary Pathology, 44, 110-115. https://doi.org/10.1354/vp.44-1-110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blas-Machado, U., Saliki, J. T., S&#xe1;nchez, S., Brown, C. C., Zhang, J., Keys, D., Woolums, A., &amp; Harvey, S. B. (2011). Pathogenesis of a bovine enterovirus-1 isolate in experimentally infected calves. Veterinary Pathology, 48, 1075-1084. https://doi.org/10.1177/0300985810395728</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowland, S. L., &amp; Shewen, P. E. (2000). Bovine respiratory disease: Commercial vaccines currently available in Canada. Canadian Veterinary Journal, 41, 33-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buermans, H. P., &amp; den Dunnen, J. T. (2014). Next generation sequencing technology: Advances and applications. Biochimica Et Biophysica Acta, 1842, 1932-1941. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbadis.2014.06.015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis, J. (2019). What is the evidence that bovine coronavirus is a biologically significant respiratory pathogen in cattle? Canadian Veterinary Journal, 60, 147-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson, L., Olivier, A. K., Genova, S., Epperson, W. B., Smith, D. R., Schneider, L., Barton, K., McCuan, K., Webby, R. J., &amp; Wan, X. F. (2016). Pathogenesis of influenza D virus in cattle. Journal of Virology, 90, 5636-5642. https://doi.org/10.1128/JVI.03122-15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulton, R. W. (2009). Bovine respiratory disease research (1983-2009). Animal Health Research Reviews, 10, 131-139. https://doi.org/10.1017/S146625230999017X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulton, R. W., Ridpath, J. F., &amp; Burge, L. J. (2013). Bovine coronaviruses from the respiratory tract: Antigenic and genetic diversity. Vaccine, 31, 886-892. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vaccine.2012.12.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graf, E. H., Simmon, K. E., Tardif, K. D., Hymas, W., Flygare, S., Eilbeck, K., Yandell, M., &amp; Schlaberg, R. (2016). Unbiased detection of respiratory viruses by use of RNA sequencing-based metagenomics: A systematic comparison to a commercial PCR panel. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 54, 1000-1007. https://doi.org/10.1128/jcm.03060-15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin, D. (1997). Economic impact associated with respiratory disease in beef cattle. Veterinary Clinics of North America: Food Animal Practice, 13, 367-377. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0749-0720(15)30302-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin, D., Chengappa, M. M., Kuszak, J., &amp; McVey, D. S. (2010). Bacterial pathogens of the bovine respiratory disease complex. The Veterinary Clinics of North America. Food Animal Practice, 26, 381-394. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cvfa.2010.04.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas, B. J., Papanicolaou, A., Yassour, M., Grabherr, M., Blood, P. D., Bowden, J., Couger, M. B., Eccles, D., Li, B., Lieber, M., MacManes, M. D., Ott, M., Orvis, J., Pochet, N., Strozzi, F., Weeks, N., Westerman, R., William, T., Dewey, C. N., &#x2026; Regev, A. (2013). De novo transcript sequence reconstruction from RNA-seq using the Trinity platform for reference generation and analysis. Nature Protocols, 8, 1494-1512. https://doi.org/10.1038/nprot.2013.084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hause, B. M., Collin, E. A., Anderson, J., Hesse, R. A., &amp; Anderson, G. (2015). Bovine rhinitis viruses are common in U.S. cattle with bovine respiratory disease. PLoS ONE, 10, e0121998. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0121998</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hause, B. M., Collin, E. A., Liu, R., Huang, B., Sheng, Z., Lu, W., Wang, D., Nelson, E. A., &amp; Li, F. (2014). Characterization of a novel influenza virus in cattle and Swine: Proposal for a new genus in the Orthomyxoviridae family. Mbio, 5, e00031-e14. https://doi.org/10.1128/mBio.00031-14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hause, B. M., Ducatez, M., Collin, E. A., Ran, Z., Liu, R., Sheng, Z., Armien, A., Kaplan, B., Chakravarty, S., Hoppe, A. D., Webby, R. J., Simonson, R. R., &amp; Li, F. (2013). Isolation of a novel swine influenza virus from Oklahoma in 2011 which is distantly related to human influenza C viruses. PLoS Pathogens, 9, e1003176. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.ppat.1003176</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilton, W. M. (2014). BRD in 2014: Where have we been, where are we now, and where do we want to go? Animal Health Research Reviews, 15, 120-122. https://doi.org/10.1017/s1466252314000115</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoet, A. E., &amp; Saif, L. J. (2004). Bovine torovirus (Breda virus) revisited. Animal Health Research Reviews, 5, 157-171. https://doi.org/10.1079/ahr200498</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain, A., &amp; Mohanty, S. B. (1979). Cell mediated immunity to bovine rhinovirus type 1 in calves. Archives of Virology, 59, 17-24. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF01317890</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamrin, P., Maneekarn, N., Okitsu, S., &amp; Ushijima, H. (2014). Epidemiology of human and animal kobuviruses. Virusdisease, 25, 195-200. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13337-014-0200-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, S., Stecher, G., Li, M., Knyaz, C., &amp; Tamura, K. (2018). MEGA X: Molecular evolutionary genetics analysis across computing platforms. Molecular Biology and Evolution, 35, 1547-1549. https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msy096</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ley, V., Higgins, J., &amp; Fayer, R. (2002). Bovine enteroviruses as indicators of fecal contamination. Applied and Environment Microbiology, 68, 3455-3461. https://doi.org/10.1128/aem.68.7.3455-3461.2002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. (2018). Minimap2: Pairwise alignment for nucleotide sequences. Bioinformatics, 34, 3094-3100. https://doi.org/10.1093/bioinformatics/bty191</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loose, M., Malla, S., &amp; Stout, M. (2016). Real-time selective sequencing using nanopore technology. Nature Methods, 13, 751-754. https://doi.org/10.1038/nmeth.3930</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMullen, C., Orsel, K., Alexander, T. W., van der Meer, F., Plastow, G., &amp; Timsit, E. (2019). Comparison of the nasopharyngeal bacterial microbiota of beef calves raised without the use of antimicrobials between healthy calves and those diagnosed with bovine respiratory disease. Veterinary Microbiology, 231, 56-62. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vetmic.2019.02.030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McVey, D. S. (2009). BRD research needs in the next 10-20 years. Animal Health Research Reviews, 10, 165-167. https://doi.org/10.1017/s1466252309990247</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitra, N., Cernicchiaro, N., Torres, S., Li, F., &amp; Hause, B. M. (2016). Metagenomic characterization of the virome associated with bovine respiratory disease in feedlot cattle identified novel viruses and suggests an etiologic role for influenza D virus. Journal of General Virology, 97, 1771-1784. https://doi.org/10.1099/jgv.0.000492</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosier, D. (2014). Review of BRD pathogenesis: The old and the new. Animal Health Research Reviews, 15, 166-168. https://doi.org/10.1017/s1466252314000176</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray, G. M., O'Neill, R. G., More, S. J., McElroy, M. C., Earley, B., &amp; Cassidy, J. P. (2016). Evolving views on bovine respiratory disease: An appraisal of selected key pathogens - Part 1. The Veterinary Journal, 217, 95-102. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tvjl.2016.09.012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, T. F., Kondov, N. O., Deng, X., Van Eenennaam, A., Neibergs, H. L., &amp; Delwart, E. (2015). A metagenomics and case-control study to identify viruses associated with bovine respiratory disease. Journal of Virology, 89, 5340-5349. https://doi.org/10.1128/JVI.00064-15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olfert, E. D., Cross, B. M., &amp; McWilliam, A. A. (1993). Guide to the care and use of experimental animals. : Canadian Council on Animal Care.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, S. J., Jeong, C., Yoon, S. S., Choy, H. E., Saif, L. J., Park, S. H., Kim, Y. J., Jeong, J. H., Park, S. I., Kim, H. H., Lee, B. J., Cho, H. S., Kim, S. K., Kang, M. I., &amp; Cho, K. O. (2006). Detection and characterization of bovine coronaviruses in fecal specimens of adult cattle with diarrhea during the warmer seasons. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 44, 3178-3188. https://doi.org/10.1128/jcm.02667-05</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portis, E., Lindeman, C., Johansen, L., &amp; Stoltman, G. (2012). A ten-year (2000-2009) study of antimicrobial susceptibility of bacteria that cause bovine respiratory disease complex-Mannheimia haemolytica, Pasteurella multocida, and Histophilus somni-in the United States and Canada. Journal of Veterinary Diagnostic Investigation, 24, 932-944. https://doi.org/10.1177/1040638712457559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quick, J., Grubaugh, N. D., Pullan, S. T., Claro, I. M., Smith, A. D., Gangavarapu, K., Oliveira, G., Robles-Sikisaka, R., Rogers, T. F., Beutler, N. A., Burton, D. R., Lewis-Ximenez, L. L., de Jesus, J. G., Giovanetti, M., Hill, S. C., Black, A., Bedford, T., Carroll, M. W., Nunes, M., &#x2026; Loman, N. J. (2017). Multiplex PCR method for MinION and Illumina sequencing of Zika and other virus genomes directly from clinical samples. Nature Protocols, 12, 1261. https://doi.org/10.1038/nprot.2017.066</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quick, J., Loman, N. J., Duraffour, S., Simpson, J. T., Severi, E., Cowley, L., Bore, J. A., Koundouno, R., Dudas, G., Mikhail, A., Ou&#xe9;draogo, N., Afrough, B., Bah, A., Baum, J. H. J., Becker-Ziaja, B., Boettcher, J. P., Cabeza-Cabrerizo, M., Camino-S&#xe1;nchez, &#xc1;., Carter, L. L., &#x2026; Carroll, M. W. (2016). Real-time, portable genome sequencing for Ebola surveillance. Nature, 530, 228-232. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature16996</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuter, G., Boros, A., &amp; Pankovics, P. (2011). Kobuviruses - A comprehensive review. Reviews in Medical Virology, 21, 32-41. https://doi.org/10.1002/rmv.677</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saif, L. J. (2010). Bovine respiratory coronavirus. The Veterinary Clinics of North America. Food Animal Practice, 26, 349-364. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cvfa.2010.04.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storz, J., Stine, L., Liem, A., &amp; Anderson, G. A. (1996). Coronavirus isolation from nasal swab samples in cattle with signs of respiratory tract disease after shipping. Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 208, 1452-1455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, S., Fu, X., Li, G., Kerlin, F., &amp; Veit, M. (2017). Novel influenza D virus: Epidemiology, pathology, evolution and biological characteristics. Virulence, 8, 1580-1591. https://doi.org/10.1080/21505594.2017.1365216</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki, T., Otake, Y., Uchimoto, S., Hasebe, A., &amp; Goto, Y. (2020). Genomic characterization and phylogenetic classification of bovine coronaviruses through whole genome sequence analysis. Viruses, 12, https://doi.org/10.3390/v12020183</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White, S. K., Ma, W., McDaniel, C. J., Gray, G. C., &amp; Lednicky, J. A. (2016). Serologic evidence of exposure to influenza D virus among persons with occupational contact with cattle. Journal of Clinical Virology, 81, 31-33. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcv.2016.05.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, J. R., Yang, R., Clifford, J. L., Watson, D., Campbell, R., Getnet, D., Kumar, R., Hammamieh, R., &amp; Jett, M. (2019). Functional Heatmap: An automated and interactive pattern recognition tool to integrate time with multi-omics assays. BMC Bioinformatics, 20, 81. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859-019-2657-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M., Hill, J. E., Fernando, C., Alexander, T. W., Timsit, E., van der Meer, F., &amp; Huang, Y. (2019). Respiratory viruses identified in western Canadian beef cattle by metagenomic sequencing and their association with bovine respiratory disease. Transboundary and Emerging Diseases, 66, 1379-1386. https://doi.org/10.1111/tbed.13172</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M., Hill, J. E., Godson, D. L., Ngeleka, M., Fernando, C., &amp; Huang, Y. (2020). The pulmonary virome, bacteriological and histopathological findings in bovine respiratory disease from western Canada. Transboundary and Emerging Diseases, 67, 924-934. https://doi.org/10.1111/tbed.13419</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M., Huang, Y., Godson, D. L., Fernando, C., Alexander, T. W., &amp; Hill, J. E. (2020). Assessment of metagenomic sequencing and qPCR for detection of influenza D virus in bovine respiratory tract samples. Viruses, 12, https://doi.org/10.3390/v12080814</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. M., Herbst, W., Kousoulas, K. G., &amp; Storz, J. (1994). Biological and genetic characterization of a hemagglutinating coronavirus isolated from a diarrhoeic child. Journal of Medical Virology, 44, 152-161. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmv.1890440207</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, L., Xing, Z., Gai, X., Li, S., San, Z., &amp; Wang, X. (2014). Identification of a novel enterovirus E isolates HY12 from cattle with severe respiratory and enteric diseases. PLoS ONE, 9, e97730. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0097730</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, N., Zhang, D., Wang, W., Li, X., Yang, B., Song, J., Zhao, X., Huang, B., Shi, W., Lu, R., Niu, P., Zhan, F., Ma, X., Wang, D., Xu, W., Wu, G., Gao, G. F., &amp; Tan, W. (2020). A novel coronavirus from patients with pneumonia in China, 2019. New England Journal of Medicine, 382, 727-733. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2001017</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>