<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">12788711</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2003</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>69</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2003</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A multiplex reverse transcription-PCR method for detection of human enteric viruses in groundwater.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3158</StartPage><EndPage>3164</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3158-64</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Untreated groundwater is responsible for about half of the waterborne disease outbreaks in the United States. Human enteric viruses are thought to be leading etiological agents of many of these outbreaks, but there is relatively little information on the types and levels of viruses found in groundwater. To address this problem, monthly samples from 29 groundwater sites were analyzed for 1 year for enteroviruses, hepatitis A virus, Norwalk virus, reoviruses, and rotaviruses by multiplex reverse transcription-PCR (RT-PCR). A procedure with which to remove environmental RT-PCR inhibitors from groundwater samples was developed. The procedure allowed an average of 71 liters of the original groundwater to be assayed per RT-PCR, with an average virus recovery rate of 74%, based on seeded samples. Human enteric viruses were detected in 16% of the groundwater samples analyzed, with reoviruses being the most frequently detected virus group.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fout</LastName><ForeName>G Shay</ForeName><Initials>GS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Exposure Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Cincinnati, Ohio 45268, USA. fout.shay@epa.gov</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martinson</LastName><ForeName>Beth C</ForeName><Initials>BC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moyer</LastName><ForeName>Michael W N</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dahling</LastName><ForeName>Daniel R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D023362">Evaluation Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005618" MajorTopicYN="N">Fresh Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D030041" MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatitis A virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009663" MajorTopicYN="N">Norwalk virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018165" MajorTopicYN="N">Orthoreovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012328" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA Viruses</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012401" MajorTopicYN="N">Rotavirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2003</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2003</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2003</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2003</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12788711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC161478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.69.6.3158-3164.2003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbaszadegan, M., M. S. Huber, C. P. Gerba, and I. L. Pepper. 1993. Detection of enteroviruses in groundwater with the polymerase chain reaction. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 59:1318-1324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7685998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbaszadegan, M., P. Stewart, and M. LeChevallier. 1999. A strategy for detection of viruses in groundwater by PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 65:444-449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC91045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9925566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beller, M., A. Ellis, S. H. Lee, M. A. Drebot, S. A. Jenkerson, E. Funk, M. D. Sobsey, O. D. Simmons III, S. S. Monroe, T. Ando, J. Noel, M. Petric, J. P. Middaugh, and J. S. Spika. 1997. Outbreak of viral gastroenteritis due to a contaminated well: international consequences. JAMA 278:563-568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9268277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control. 1983. Water-related disease surveillance annual summary 1982. HHS publication no. (CDC)83-8385. Centers for Disease Control, Atlanta, Ga.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craun, G. F. 1990. Review of the causes of waterborne outbreaks, p. 1-22. In G. F. Craun (ed.), Methods for the investigation and prevention of waterborne disease outbreaks. EPA/600/1-90/005a. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Cincinnati, Ohio.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cukor, G., and N. R. Blacklow. 1984. Human viral gastroenteritis. Microbiol. Rev. 48:157-179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC373217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahling, D. R. 2002. An improved filter elution and cell culture assay procedure for evaluating public groundwater systems for cultural enteroviruses. Water Environ. Res. 74:564-568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12540097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahling, D. R., and B. A. Wright. 1986. Recovery of viruses from water by a modified flocculation procedure for second-step concentration. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 51:1326-1331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC239066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3015024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Leon, R., Y. S. C. Shieh, R. S. Baric, and M. D. Sobsey. 1990. Detection of enteroviruses and hepatitis A virus in environmental samples by gene probes and polymerase chain reaction. Am. Water Works Assoc. Proc. 1989:833-853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Serres, G., T. L. Cromeans, B. Levesque, N. Brassard, C. Barthe, M. Dionne, H. Prud'homme, D. Paradis, C. N. Shapiro, O. V. Nainan, and H. S. Margolis. 1999. Molecular confirmation of hepatitis A virus from well water: epidemiology and public health implications. J. Infect. Dis. 179:37-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9841820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Environmental Protection Agency. 1984. USEPA manual of methods for virology. Publication no. EPA-600/4-84-013. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Cincinnati, Ohio. [Online.] www.epa.gov/microbes.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fout, G. S., F. W. Schaefer III, J. W. Messer, D. R. Dahling, and R. E. Stetler. 1996. ICR microbial laboratory manual. Publication no. EPA/600/R-95/178. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C. [Online.] www.epa.gov/microbes.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal, S. M. 1984. Viral pollution of the marine environment. CRC Crit. Rev. Environ. Cont. 14:1-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris, J. R., M. L. Cohen, and E. C. Lippy. 1983. Water-related disease outbreaks in the United States. J. Infect. Dis. 148:759-762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6313817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ijzerman, M. M., D. R. Dahling, and G. S. Fout. 1997. A method to remove environmental inhibitors prior to the detection of waterborne enteric viruses by reverse-transcription polymerase chain reaction. J. Virol. Methods 63:145-153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9015285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreader, C. A. 1996. Relief of amplification inhibition in PCR with bovine serum albumin or T4 gene 32 protein. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 62:1102-1106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8975603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson, H. W., M. M. Braun, R. I. Glass, S. E. Stine, S. S. Monroe, H. K. Atrash, L. E. Lee, and S. J. Englender. 1991. Waterborne outbreak of Norwalk virus gastroenteritis at a southwest US resort: role of geological formations in contamination of well water. Lancet 337:1200-1204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1673747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeBaron, C. W., N. P. Furutan, J. F. Lew, J. R. Allen, V. Gouvea, C. Moe, and S. S. Monroe. 1990. Viral agents of gastroenteritis. Public health importance and outbreak management. Morb. Mortal. Wkly. Rep. Recomm. Rep. 39(RR-5):1-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2157945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieberman, R. J., L. C. Shadix, B. S. Newport, S. R. Crout, S. E. Buescher, R. S. Safferman, R. E. Stetler, D. Lye, G. S. Fout, and D. R. Dahling. 1995. Source water microbial quality of some vulnerable public ground water supplies, p. 1425-1436. In Proceedings of the 1994 Water Quality Technology Conference, part II. American Water Works Association, Denver, Colo.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurer, A. M., and D. Sturchler. 2000. A waterborne outbreak of small round structured virus, campylobacter and shigella co-infections in La Neuveville, Switzerland, 1998. Epidemiol. Infect. 125:325-332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2869605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11117956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick, J. L. 1984. Enteric viruses in water. Monogr. Virol. 15:1-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez I. I., L. L. Hermann, P. R. Hazelton, and K. M. Coombs. 2000. A comparative analysis of Freon substitutes in the purification of reovirus and calicivirus. J. Virol. Methods 90:59-67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11011081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds, K. A., C. P. Gerba, and I. L. Pepper. 1996. Detection of infectious enteroviruses by an integrated cell culture-PCR procedure. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 62:1424-1427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8919804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson, J. B., and S. C. Edberg. 1997. Natural protection of spring and well drinking water against surface microbial contamination. I. Hydrogeological parameters. Crit. Rev. Microbiol. 23:143-178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9226112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rueckert, R. R., and M. A. Pallansch. 1981. Preparation and characterization of EMC virus. Methods Enzymol. 78:315-325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6276658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab, K. J., M. K. Estes, F. H. Neill, and R. L. Atmar. 1997. Use of heat release and an internal RNA standard control in reverse transcription-PCR detection of Norwalk virus from stool samples. J. Clin. Microbiol. 35:511-514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC229614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9003630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shieh, Y. S. C., D. Wait, L. Tai, and M. D. Sobsey. 1995. Methods to remove inhibitors in sewage and other fecal wastes for enterovirus detection by the polymerase chain reaction. J. Virol. Methods 54:51-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7559857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey, M. D. 1994. Molecular methods to detect viruses in environmental samples, p. 387-400. In R. C. Spencer, E. P. Wright, and S. W. B. Newsom (ed.), Rapid methods and automation in microbiology and immunology. Intercept Limited, Hampshire, United Kingdom.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey, M. D., and J. S. Glass. 1980. Poliovirus concentration from tap water with electropositive adsorbent filters. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 40:201-210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC291553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6258472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stetler, R. E., and F. P. Williams, Jr. 1996. Pretreatment to reduce somatic salmonella phage interference with FRNA coliphage assays: successful use in a one-year survey of vulnerable groundwaters. Lett. Appl. Microbiol. 23:49-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8679143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>