<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21900167</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>85</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Annexin II binds to capsid protein VP1 of enterovirus 71 and enhances viral infectivity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>11809</StartPage><EndPage>11820</EndPage><MedlinePgn>11809-20</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.00297-11</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus type 71 (EV71) causes hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD), which is mostly self-limited but may be complicated with a severe to fatal neurological syndrome in some children. Understanding the molecular basis of virus-host interactions might help clarify the largely unknown neuropathogenic mechanisms of EV71. In this study, we showed that human annexin II (Anx2) protein could bind to the EV71 virion via the capsid protein VP1. Either pretreatment of EV71 with soluble recombinant Anx2 or pretreatment of host cells with an anti-Anx2 antibody could result in reduced viral attachment to the cell surface and a reduction of the subsequent virus yield in vitro. HepG2 cells, which do not express Anx2, remained permissive to EV71 infection, though the virus yield was lower than that for a cognate lineage expressing Anx2. Stable transfection of plasmids expressing Anx2 protein into HepG2 cells (HepG2-Anx2 cells) could enhance EV71 infectivity, with an increased virus yield, especially at a low infective dose, and the enhanced infectivity could be reversed by pretreating HepG2-Anx2 cells with an anti-Anx2 antibody. The Anx2-interacting domain was mapped by yeast two-hybrid analysis to VP1 amino acids 40 to 100, a region different from the known receptor binding domain on the surface of the picornavirus virion. Our data suggest that binding of EV71 to Anx2 on the cell surface can enhance viral entry and infectivity, especially at a low infective dose.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Su-Lin</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Life Sciences, Taiwan Centers for Disease Control, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chou</LastName><ForeName>Ying-Ting</ForeName><Initials>YT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Cheng-Nan</ForeName><Initials>CN</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ho</LastName><ForeName>Mei-Shang</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017306">Annexin A2</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D036022">Capsid Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017306" MajorTopicYN="N">Annexin A2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036022" MajorTopicYN="N">Capsid Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054884" MajorTopicYN="Y">Host-Pathogen Interactions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054730" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Interaction Domains and Motifs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D025941" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Interaction Mapping</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020798" MajorTopicYN="N">Two-Hybrid System Techniques</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053585" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Attachment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21900167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3209289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.00297-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.00297-11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alexander J. P., Jr., Baden L., Pallansch M. A., Anderson L. J. 1994. Enterovirus 71 infections and neurologic disease&#x2014;United States, 1977&#x2013;1991. J. Infect. Dis. 169: 905&#x2013;908</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8133108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backes P., et al. 2010. Role of annexin A2 in the production of infectious hepatitis C virus particles. J. Virol. 84: 5775&#x2013;5789</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2876593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20335258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown B. A., Pallansch M. A. 1995. Complete nucleotide sequence of enterovirus 71 is distinct from poliovirus. Virus Res. 39: 195&#x2013;205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8837884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgoyne R. D., Cambray-Deakin M. A., Norman K. M. 1989. Developmental regulation of tyrosine kinase substrate p36 (calpactin heavy chain) in rat cerebellum. J. Mol. Neurosci. 1: 47&#x2013;54</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2534968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan L. G., et al. 2000. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. Clin. Infect. Dis. 31: 678&#x2013;683</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang L. Y., Huang Y. C., Lin T. Y. 1998. Fulminant neurogenic pulmonary oedema with hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet 352: 367&#x2013;368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9717926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang L. Y., et al. 1999. Clinical features and risk factors of pulmonary oedema after enterovirus-71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet 354: 1682&#x2013;1686</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H. F., Chang M. H., Chiang B. L., Jeng S. T. 2006. Oral immunization of mice using transgenic tomato fruit expressing VP1 protein from enterovirus 71. Vaccine 24: 2944&#x2013;2951</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16448730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colston E. M., Racaniello V. R. 1995. Poliovirus variants selected on mutant receptor-expressing cells identify capsid residues that expand receptor recognition. J. Virol. 69: 4823&#x2013;4829</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC189295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7609049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donato R., Russo-Marie F. 1999. The annexins: structure and functions. Cell Calcium 26: 85&#x2013;89</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10598271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreier R., Schmid K. W., Gerke V., Riehemann K. 1998. Differential expression of annexins I, II and IV in human tissues: an immunohistochemical study. Histochem. Cell Biol. 110: 137&#x2013;148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9720986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frohlich M., et al. 1990. Enhanced expression of the protein kinase substrate p36 in human hepatocellular carcinoma. Mol. Cell. Biol. 10: 3216&#x2013;3223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC360686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2160596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerke V., Moss S. E. 2002. Annexins: from structure to function. Physiol. Rev. 82: 331&#x2013;371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11917092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara A., Tagaya I., Yoneyama T. 1978. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Intervirology 9: 60&#x2013;63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">202573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang M. L., Chiang P. S., Luo S. T., Liou G. Y., Lee M. S. 2010. Development of a high-throughput assay for measuring serum neutralizing antibody against enterovirus 71. J. Virol. Methods 165: 42&#x2013;45</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20036286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishimaru Y., Nakano S., Yamaoka K., Takami S. 1980. Outbreaks of hand, foot, and mouth disease by enterovirus 71. High incidence of complication disorders of central nervous system. Arch. Dis. Child. 55: 583&#x2013;588</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1627055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6254449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J., Hajjar K. A. 2002. Annexin II: a plasminogen-plasminogen activator co-receptor. Front. Biosci. 7: d341&#x2013;d348</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11815288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeBouder F., Lina B., Rimmelzwaan G. F., Riteau B. 2010. Plasminogen promotes influenza A virus replication through an annexin 2-dependent pathway in the absence of neuraminidase. J. Gen. Virol. 91: 2753&#x2013;2761</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20702651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao S., Racaniello V. 1997. Allele-specific adaptation of poliovirus VP1 B-C loop variants to mutant cell receptors. J. Virol. 71: 9770&#x2013;9777</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC230287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9371643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y. C., Wu C. N., Shih S. R., Ho M. S. 2002. Characterization of a Vero cell-adapted virulent strain of enterovirus 71 suitable for use as a vaccine candidate. Vaccine 20: 2485&#x2013;2493</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12057603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum L. C., et al. 1998. Fatal enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. J. Pediatr. 133: 795&#x2013;798</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma G., et al. 2004. Secretory leukocyte protease inhibitor binds to annexin II, a cofactor for macrophage HIV-1 infection. J. Exp. Med. 200: 1337&#x2013;1346</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2211913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15545357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhotra R., et al. 2003. Isolation and characterisation of potential respiratory syncytial virus receptor(s) on epithelial cells. Microbes Infect. 5: 123&#x2013;133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12650770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao L. X., et al. 2010. Epidemiology of hand, foot, and mouth disease and genotype characterization of enterovirus 71 in Jiangsu, China. J. Clin. Virol. 49: 100&#x2013;104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20719557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minor P. D., Ferguson M., Evans D. M., Almond J. W., Icenogle J. P. 1986. Antigenic structure of polioviruses of serotypes 1, 2 and 3. J. Gen. Virol. 67(Pt. 7): 1283&#x2013;1291</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2425046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray M. G., et al. 1988. Poliovirus host range is determined by a short amino acid sequence in neutralization antigenic site I. Science 241: 213&#x2013;215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3908517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2838906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y., et al. 2009. Human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15: 794&#x2013;797</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong K. C., Devi S., Cardosa M. J., Wong K. T. 2010. Formaldehyde-inactivated whole-virus vaccine protects a murine model of enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis against disease. J. Virol. 84: 661&#x2013;665</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2798416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortner B., et al. 2009. Epidemiology of enterovirus types causing neurological disease in Austria 1999&#x2013;2007: detection of clusters of echovirus 30 and enterovirus 71 and analysis of prevalent genotypes. J. Med. Virol. 81: 317&#x2013;324</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19107980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pena-Alonso E., et al. 2008. Annexin A2 localizes to the basal epithelial layer and is down-regulated in dysplasia and head and neck squamous cell carcinoma. Cancer Lett. 263: 89&#x2013;98</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18262347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietropaolo R., Compton T. 1999. Interference with annexin II has no effect on entry of human cytomegalovirus into fibroblast cells. J. Gen. Virol. 80(Pt. 7): 1807&#x2013;1816</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10423150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plevka P., et al. 2010. Interaction of decay-accelerating factor with echovirus 7. J. Virol. 84: 12665&#x2013;12674</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3004353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20881044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puisieux A., Ji J., Ozturk M. 1996. Annexin II up-regulates cellular levels of p11 protein by a post-translational mechanism. Biochem. J. 313(Pt. 1): 51&#x2013;55</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1216908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8546709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racaniello V. R. 1996. Early events in poliovirus infection: virus-receptor interactions. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 93: 11378&#x2013;11381</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC38065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8876143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racaniello V. R. 2007. Picornaviridae: the viruses and their replication, p. 795&#x2013;838 In Knipe D. M., et al. (ed.), Fields virology, 5th ed. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, Philadelphia, PA</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai T., Mosoian A., Resh M. D. 2010. Annexin 2 is not required for human immunodeficiency virus type 1 particle production but plays a cell type-dependent role in regulating infectivity. J. Virol. 84: 9783&#x2013;9792</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2937750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20631122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raynor C. M., Wright J. F., Waisman D. M., Pryzdial E. L. 1999. Annexin II enhances cytomegalovirus binding and fusion to phospholipid membranes. Biochemistry 38: 5089&#x2013;5095</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10213612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves S. A., Chavez-Kappel C., Davis R., Rosenblum M., Israel M. A. 1992. Developmental regulation of annexin II (lipocortin 2) in human brain and expression in high grade glioma. Cancer Res. 52: 6871&#x2013;6876</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1333884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rintala-Dempsey A. C., Rezvanpour A., Shaw G. S. 2008. S100-annexin complexes&#x2014;structural insights. FEBS J. 275: 4956&#x2013;4966</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18795951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryzhova E. V., et al. 2006. Annexin 2: a novel human immunodeficiency virus type 1 Gag binding protein involved in replication in monocyte-derived macrophages. J. Virol. 80: 2694&#x2013;2704</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1395445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16501079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih S. R., et al. 2000. Genetic analysis of enterovirus 71 isolated from fatal and non-fatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease during an epidemic in Taiwan, 1998. Virus Res. 68: 127&#x2013;136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10958984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih S. R., et al. 2004. Mutation in enterovirus 71 capsid protein VP1 confers resistance to the inhibitory effects of pyridyl imidazolidinone. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 48: 3523&#x2013;3529</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC514779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15328120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan C. S., Cardosa M. J. 2007. High-titred neutralizing antibodies to human enterovirus 71 preferentially bind to the N-terminal portion of the capsid protein VP1. Arch. Virol. 152: 1069&#x2013;1073</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17318736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung W. S., Bakar S. A., Sekawi Z., Rosli R. 2007. DNA vaccine constructs against enterovirus 71 elicit immune response in mice. Genet. Vaccines Ther. 5: 6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3225814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17445254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuthill T. J., Groppelli E., Hogle J. M., Rowlands D. J. 2010. Picornaviruses. Curr. Top. Microbiol. Immunol. 343: 43&#x2013;89</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3018333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20397067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sanden S., Koopmans M., Uslu G., van der Avoort H. 2009. Epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in the Netherlands, 1963 to 2008. J. Clin. Microbiol. 47: 2826&#x2013;2833</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2738086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J. R., et al. 2000. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998. II. Laboratory diagnosis and genetic analysis. J. Clin. Virol. 17: 91&#x2013;99</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10942089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng T. Y., et al. 2005. Lactoferrin inhibits enterovirus 71 infection by binding to VP1 protein and host cells. Antiviral Res. 67: 31&#x2013;37</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15916817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright J. F., Kurosky A., Wasi S. 1994. An endothelial cell-surface form of annexin II binds human cytomegalovirus. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 198: 983&#x2013;989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8117306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C. N., et al. 2001. Protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by passive immunization with subunit VP1 vaccines and inactivated virus. Vaccine 20: 895&#x2013;904</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S., et al. 2009. Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15: 798&#x2013;801</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J. J., Wang J. R., Liu C. C., Yang H. B., Su I. J. 2000. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan 1998: a comprehensive pathological, virological, and molecular study on a case of fulminant encephalitis. J. Clin. Virol. 17: 13&#x2013;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H., et al. 2010. Genetic analysis of the VP1 region of enterovirus 71 reveals the emergence of genotype A in central China in 2008. Virus Genes 41: 1&#x2013;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20306124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>