<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35504535</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1995-820X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Virologica Sinica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Virol Sin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A microfluidic cell chip for virus isolation via rapid screening for permissive cells.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>547</StartPage><EndPage>557</EndPage><MedlinePgn>547-557</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.virs.2022.04.011</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1995-820X(22)00075-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Virus identification is a prerequisite not only for the early diagnosis of viral infectious diseases but also for the effective prevention of epidemics. Successful cultivation is the gold standard for identifying a virus, according to the Koch postulates. However, this requires screening for a permissive cell line, which is traditionally time-, reagent- and labor-intensive. Here, a simple and easy-to-operate microfluidic chip, formed by seeding a variety of cell lines and culturing them in parallel, is reported for use in virus cultivation and virus-permissive host-cell screening. The chip was tested by infection with two known viruses, enterovirus 71 (EV71) and influenza virus H1N1. Infection with EV71 and H1N1 caused significant cytopathic effects (CPE) in RD and MDCK cells, respectively, demonstrating that virus cultivation based on this microfluidic cell chip can be used as a substitute for the traditional plate-based culture method and reproduce the typical CPE caused by virus infection. Using this microfluidic cell chip method for virus cultivation could make it possible to identify an emerging virus in a high-throughput, automatic, and unprecedentedly fast way.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Publishing services by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Weide</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Virology, Wuhan Institute of Virology, Center for Biosafety Mega-Science, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Wuhan, 430071, China; University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100049, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qiu</LastName><ForeName>Jingjiang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanics and Safety Engineering, Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, 450001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mei</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Virology, Wuhan Institute of Virology, Center for Biosafety Mega-Science, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Wuhan, 430071, China; Current address: Wuhan Institute of Biological Products Co., Ltd., Wuhan, 430070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xian-En</ForeName><Initials>XE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Synthetic Biology, Shenzhen Institute of Advanced Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shenzhen, 518055, China; National Laboratory of Biomacromolecules, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100101, China; University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100049, China. Electronic address: zhangxe@ibp.ac.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Fluid Power and Mechatronic Systems, School of Mechanical Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, 310027, China. Electronic address: yongqin@zju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Virology, Wuhan Institute of Virology, Center for Biosafety Mega-Science, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Wuhan, 430071, China; University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, 100049, China. Electronic address: fli@wh.iov.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Virol Sin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101514185</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1995-820X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053118" MajorTopicYN="Y">Influenza A Virus, H1N1 Subtype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044085" MajorTopicYN="N">Microfluidics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014776" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Cultivation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus 71 (EV71)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Influenza virus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microfluidic cell chip</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Permissive cell</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virus cultivation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35504535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9437619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.virs.2022.04.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1995-820X(22)00075-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alonso F.V., Compans R.W. Differential effect of monensin on enveloped viruses that form at distinct plasma membrane domains. J.&#xa0;Cell Biol. 1981;89:700&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2111791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6265471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatia S.N., Ingber D.E. Microfluidic organs-on-chips. Nat. Biotechnol. 2014;32:760&#x2013;772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25093883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryan W.R. Interpretation of host response in quantitative studies on animal viruses. Ann. N. Y. Acad. Sci. 1957;69:698&#x2013;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13488325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drews K., Calgi M.P., Harrison W.C., Drews C.M., Costa-Pinheiro P., Shaw J.J.P., Jobe K.A., Nelson E.A., Han J.D., Fox T., White J.M., Kester M. Glucosylceramidase maintains influenza virus infection by regulating endocytosis. J.&#xa0;Virol. 2019;93:e00017&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6613767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30918081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudas G., Carvalho L.M., Bedford T., Tatem A.J., Baele G., Faria N.R., Park D.J., Ladner J.T., Arias A., Asogun D., Bielejec F., Caddy S.L., Cotten M., D'Ambrozio J., Dellicour S., Di Caro A., Diclaro J.W., Duraffour S., Elmore M.J., Fakoli L.S., Faye O., Gilbert M.L., Gevao S.M., Gire S., Gladden-Young A., Gnirke A., Goba A., Grant D.S., Haagmans B.L., Hiscox J.A., Jah U., Kugelman J.R., Liu D., Lu J., Malboeuf C.M., Mate S., Matthews D.A., Matranga C.B., Meredith L.W., Qu J., Quick J., Pas S.D., Phan M.V.T., Pollakis G., Reusken C.B., Sanchez-Lockhart M., Schaffner S.F., Schieffelin J.S., Sealfon R.S., Simon-Loriere E., Smits S.L., Stoecker K., Thorne L., Tobin E.A., Vandi M.A., Watson S.J., West K., Whitmer S., Wiley M.R., Winnicki S.M., Wohl S., Wolfel R., Yozwiak N.L., Andersen K.G., Blyden S.O., Bolay F., Carroll M.W., Dahn B., Diallo B., Formenty P., Fraser C., Gao G.F., Garry R.F., Goodfellow I., Gunther S., Happi C.T., Holmes E.C., Kargbo B., Keita S., Kellam P., Koopmans M.P.G., Kuhn J.H., Loman N.J., Magassouba N., Naidoo D., Nichol S.T., Nyenswah T., Palacios G., Pybus O.G., Sabeti P.C., Sall A., Stroher U., Wurie I., Suchard M.A., Lemey P., Rambaut A. Virus genomes reveal factors that spread and sustained the Ebola epidemic. Nature. 2017;544:309&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5712493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28405027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farokhzad N., Tao W. Materials chemistry-enabled platforms in detecting sexually transmitted infections: progress towards point-of-care tests. Trends in Chemistry. 2021;3:589&#x2013;602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisch H., Gifford G.E. A&#xa0;photometric and plaque assay for macrophage mediated tumor cell cytotoxicity. J.&#xa0;Immunol. Methods. 1983;57:311&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6827109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganzenmueller T., Kluba J., Hilfrich B., Puppe W., Verhagen W., Heim A., Schulz T., Henke-Gendo C. Comparison of the performance of direct fluorescent antibody staining, a point-of-care rapid antigen test and virus isolation with that of RT-PCR for the detection of novel 2009 influenza A (H1N1) virus in respiratory specimens. J.&#xa0;Med. Microbiol. 2010;59:713&#x2013;717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20203216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo F., Li S., Caglar M.U., Mao Z., Liu W., Woodman A., Arnold J.J., Wilke C.O., Huang T.J., Cameron C.E. Single-cell Virology: on-chip investigation of viral infection dynamics. Cell Rep. 2017;21:1692&#x2013;1704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5689460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29117571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hierholzer J.C., Suggs M.T., Hall E.C. Standardized viral hemagglutination and hemagglutination-inhibition tests. II. Description and statistical evaluation. Appl. Microbiol. 1969;18:824&#x2013;833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC378095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4984203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann M., Kleine-Weber H., Schroeder S., Kruger N., Herrler T., Erichsen S., Schiergens T.S., Herrler G., Wu N.H., Nitsche A., Muller M.A., Drosten C., Pohlmann S. SARS-CoV-2 cell entry depends on ACE2 and TMPRSS2 and is blocked by a clinically proven protease inhibitor. Cell. 2020;181:271&#x2013;280. e278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7102627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32142651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S.B., Wang S.S., Hsieh C.H., Lin Y.C., Lai C.S., Wu M.H. An integrated microfluidic cell culture system for high-throughput perfusion three-dimensional cell culture-based assays: effect of cell culture model on the results of chemosensitivity assays. Lab Chip. 2013;13:1133&#x2013;1143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23353927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imai M., Ninomiya A., Minekawa H., Notomi T., Ishizaki T., Tashiro M., Odagiri T. Development of H5-RT-LAMP (loop-mediated isothermal amplification) system for rapid diagnosis of H5 avian influenza virus infection. Vaccine. 2006;24:6679&#x2013;6682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16797110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan F., Tare R.S., Kanczler J.M., Oreffo R.O., Bradley M. Strategies for cell manipulation and skeletal tissue engineering using high-throughput polymer blend formulation and microarray techniques. Biomaterials. 2010;31:2216&#x2013;2228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20056271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku Z., Shi J., Liu Q., Huang Z. Development of murine monoclonal antibodies with potent neutralization effects on enterovirus 71. J.&#xa0;Virol Methods. 2012;186:193&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22771741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee W.C., Fuller A.O. Herpes simplex virus type 1 and pseudorabies virus bind to a common saturable receptor on Vero cells that is not heparan sulfate. J.&#xa0;Virol. 1993;67:5088&#x2013;5097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC237906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8394437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonardi G.P., Mitrache I., Pigal A., Freedman L. Public hospital-based laboratory experience during an outbreak of pandemic influenza A (H1N1) virus infections. J.&#xa0;Clin. Microbiol. 2010;48:1189&#x2013;1194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2849614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20147645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong P.W., Liew K., Lim W., Chow V.T. Differential display RT-PCR analysis of enterovirus-71-infected rhabdomyosarcoma cells reveals mRNA expression responses of multiple human genes with known and novel functions. Virology. 2002;295:147&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12033773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W., Moore M.J., Vasilieva N., Sui J., Wong S.K., Berne M.A., Somasundaran M., Sullivan J.L., Luzuriaga K., Greenough T.C., Choe H., Farzan M. Angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 is a functional receptor for the SARS coronavirus. Nature. 2003;426:450&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14647384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Feng J., Zhang Q., Guo D., Zhang L., Suo T., Hu W., Guo M., Wang X., Huang Z., Xiong Y., Chen G., Chen Y., Lan K. Analytical comparisons of SARS-COV-2 detection by qRT-PCR and ddPCR with multiple primer/probe sets. Emerg. Microb. Infect. 2020;9:1175&#x2013;1179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7448863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32448084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum L.C., Chua K.B., McMinn P.C., Goh A.Y., Muridan R., Sarji S.A., Hooi P.S., Chua B.H., Lam S.K. Echovirus 7 associated encephalomyelitis. J.&#xa0;Clin. Virol. 2002;23:153&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11595594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehling M., Tay S. Microfluidic cell culture. Curr. Opin. Biotechnol. 2014;25:95&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24484886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrill S., Gilbert N.M., Lewis A.L. Gardnerella vaginalis as a cause of bacterial vaginosis: appraisal of the evidence from in vivo models. Front. Cell. Infect. Microbiol. 2020;10:168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7193744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32391287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakauchi M., Takayama I., Takahashi H., Tashiro M., Kageyama T. Development of a reverse transcription loop-mediated isothermal amplification assay for the rapid diagnosis of avian influenza A (H7N9) virus infection. J.&#xa0;Virol Methods. 2014;204:101&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24747008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phanthanawiboon S., An A., Panngarm N., Limkittikul K., Ikuta K., Anantapreecha S., Kurosu T. Isolation and propagation of Dengue virus in Vero and BHK-21 cells expressing human DC-SIGN stably. J.&#xa0;Virol Methods. 2014;209:55&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25205264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puhl A.C., Fritch E.J., Lane T.R., Tse L.V., Yount B.L., Sacramento C.Q., Fintelman-Rodrigues N., Tavella T.A., Maranhao Costa F.T., Weston S., Logue J., Frieman M., Premkumar L., Pearce K.H., Hurst B.L., Andrade C.H., Levi J.A., Johnson N.J., Kisthardt S.C., Scholle F., Souza T.M.L., Moorman N.J., Baric R.S., Madrid P.B., Ekins S. Repurposing the Ebola and marburg virus inhibitors tilorone, quinacrine, and pyronaridine: in vitro activity against SARS-CoV-2 and potential mechanisms. ACS Omega. 2021;6:7454&#x2013;7468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7992063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33778258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren X., Yang F., Hu Y., Zhang T., Liu L., Dong J., Sun L., Zhu Y., Xiao Y., Li L., Yang J., Wang J., Jin Q. Full genome of influenza A (H7N9) virus derived by direct sequencing without culture. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 2013;19:1881&#x2013;1884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3837655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24206919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivers T.M. Viruses and koch's postulates. J.&#xa0;Bacteriol. 1937;33:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC545348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16559982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen C.F., Guilbault C., Li X., Elahi S.M., Ansorge S., Kamen A., Gilbert R. Development of suspension adapted Vero cell culture process technology for production of viral vaccines. Vaccine. 2019;37:6996&#x2013;7002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31288997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen L., Wang C., Zhao J., Tang X., Shen Y., Lu M., Ding Z., Huang C., Zhang J., Li S., Lan J., Wong G., Zhu Y. Delayed specific IgM antibody responses observed among COVID-19 patients with severe progression. Emerg. Microb. Infect. 2020;9:1096&#x2013;1101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8284968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32476607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Z., Kong N., Zhang X., Liu Y., Hu P., Mou S., Liljestrom P., Shi J., Tan W., Kim J.S., Cao Y., Langer R., Leong K.W., Farokhzad O.C., Tao W. A&#xa0;materials-science perspective on tackling COVID-19. Nat. Rev. Mater. 2020;5:847&#x2013;860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7556605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33078077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobias-Altura M.C., Ngelangel C.A. In vitro anti-viral activity of hexetidine (Bactidol&#xae;) oral mouthwash against human coronavirus OC43 and influenza A (H1N1) virus. Philippine Journal of Health Research and Development. 2022;26:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong Y.G., Shi W.F., Liu D., Qian J., Liang L., Bo X.C., Liu J., Ren H.G., Fan H., Ni M., Sun Y., Jin Y., Teng Y., Li Z., Kargbo D., Dafae F., Kanu A., Chen C.C., Lan Z.H., Jiang H., Luo Y., Lu H.J., Zhang X.G., Yang F., Hu Y., Cao Y.X., Deng Y.Q., Su H.X., Sun Y., Liu W.S., Wang Z., Wang C.Y., Bu Z.Y., Guo Z.D., Zhang L.B., Nie W.M., Bai C.Q., Sun C.H., An X.P., Xu P.S., Zhang X.L., Huang Y., Mi Z.Q., Yu D., Yao H.W., Feng Y., Xia Z.P., Zheng X.X., Yang S.T., Lu B., Jiang J.F., Kargbo B., He F.C., Gao G.F., Cao W.C., China Mobile Laboratory Testing Team in Sierra L Genetic diversity and evolutionary dynamics of Ebola virus in Sierra Leone. Nature. 2015;524:93&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10601608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25970247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G., Zhang J., Li W., Xin G., Su Y., Gao Y., Zhang H., Lin G., Jiao X., Li K. Apoptosis and proinflammatory cytokine responses of primary mouse microglia and astrocytes induced by human H1N1 and avian H5N1 influenza viruses. Cell. Mol. Immunol. 2008;5:113&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4651245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18445341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warrick J.W., Timm A., Swick A., Yin J. Tools for single-cell kinetic analysis of virus-host interactions. PLoS One. 2016;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4713429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26752057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Y., Zhang X., Yang S.T. Microplate-reader compatible perfusion microbioreactor array for modular tissue culture and cytotoxicity assays. Biotechnol. Prog. 2010;26:1135&#x2013;1144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20730768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu F., Zhao S., Yu B., Chen Y.M., Wang W., Song Z.G., Hu Y., Tao Z.W., Tian J.H., Pei Y.Y., Yuan M.L., Zhang Y.L., Dai F.H., Liu Y., Wang Q.M., Zheng J.J., Xu L., Holmes E.C., Zhang Y.Z. A&#xa0;new coronavirus associated with human respiratory disease in China. Nature. 2020;579:265&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao J., Zhang Y., Hong M., Han Z., Zhang M., Song Y., Yan D., Zhu S., Xu W. Phylogenetic characteristics and molecular epidemiological analysis of novel enterovirus EV-B83 isolated from Tibet, China. Sci. Rep. 2020;10:6630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7171079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32313119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi L., He Y., Chen Y., Kung H.F., He M.L. Potent inhibition of human enterovirus 71 replication by type I interferon subtypes. Antivir. Ther. 2011;16:51&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y., Wang Q., Wang C., Shang L. Living materials for regenerative medicine. Engineered Regeneration. 2021;2:96&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D., Bian F., Cai L., Wang T., Kong T., Zhao Y. Bioinspired photonic barcodes for multiplexed target cycling and hybridization chain reaction. Biosens. Bioelectron. 2019;143:111629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31470170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Chen G., Yu Y., Guo J., Tan Q., Zhao Y. Microfluidic printing of slippery textiles for medical drainage around wounds. Adv. Sci. 2020;7:2000789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7435260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32832352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P., Yang X.L., Wang X.G., Hu B., Zhang L., Zhang W., Si H.R., Zhu Y., Li B., Huang C.L., Chen H.D., Chen J., Luo Y., Guo H., Jiang R.D., Liu M.Q., Chen Y., Shen X.R., Wang X., Zheng X.S., Zhao K., Chen Q.J., Deng F., Liu L.L., Yan B., Zhan F.X., Wang Y.Y., Xiao G.F., Shi Z.L. A&#xa0;pneumonia outbreak associated with a new coronavirus of probable bat origin. Nature. 2020;579:270&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Zhao J., Zheng D., Yu Y., Liu L. Agent-based simulation of virus testing in certain-exposure time through community health service centers' evaluation-A case study of wuhan. Healthcare (Basel) 2021;9:1519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8617634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34828565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>