<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36308803</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-7103</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>630</Volume><Issue>Pt B</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of colloid and interface science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Colloid Interface Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Employing functionalized graphene quantum dots to combat coronavirus and enterovirus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>10</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-10</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jcis.2022.10.082</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0021-9797(22)01844-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The ongoing COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus) pandemic continues to adversely affect the human life, economy, and the world's ecosystem. Although significant progress has been made in developing antiviral materials for the coronavirus, much more work is still needed. In this work, N-functionalized graphene quantum dots (GQDs) were designed and synthesized as the antiviral nanomaterial for Feline Coronavirus NTU156 (FCoV NTU156) and Enterovirus 71 (EV71)) with ultra-high inhibition (&gt;99.9%). To prepare the GQD samples, a unique solid-phase microwave-assisted technique was developed and the cell toxicity was established on the H171 and H184 cell lines after 72&#xa0;h incubation, indicating superior biocompatibility. The surface functionality of GQDs (i.e., the phenolic and amino groups) plays a vital role in interacting with the receptor-binding-domain of the spike protein. It was also found that the addition of polyethylene glycol is advantageous for the dispersion and the adsorption of functionalized GQDs onto the virus surface, leading to an enhanced virus inhibition. The functionality of as-prepared GQD nanomaterials was further confirmed where a functionalized GQD-coated glass was shown to be extremely effective in hindering the virus spread for a relatively long period (&gt;20&#xa0;h).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsieh</LastName><ForeName>Chien-Te</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering and Materials Science, Yuan Ze University, Taoyuan 32003, Taiwan; Department of Mechanical, Aerospace, and Biomedical Engineering, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, TN 37996, United States. Electronic address: cthsieh@saturn.yzu.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gu</LastName><ForeName>Siyong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian Provincial Key Laboratory of Functional Materials and Applications, School of Materials Science and Engineering, Xiamen University of Technology, Xiamen 361024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gandomi</LastName><ForeName>Yasser Ashraf</ForeName><Initials>YA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA 02142, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Chun-Chieh</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Materials Engineering, Chang Gung University, Guishan, Taoyuan 33302, Taiwan; Research and Development Division, Gold Carbon Co., Ltd., Taoyuan 320675, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sung</LastName><ForeName>Po-Yu</ForeName><Initials>PY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering and Materials Science, Yuan Ze University, Taoyuan 32003, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Juang</LastName><ForeName>Ruey-Shin</ForeName><Initials>RS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Materials Engineering, Chang Gung University, Guishan, Taoyuan 33302, Taiwan; Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Chang Gung Memorial Hospital, Linkou, Taiwan; Department of Safety, Health and Environmental Engineering, Ming Chi University of Technology, Taishan, New Taipei City 24301, Taiwan. Electronic address: rsjuang@mail.cgu.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Cheng-Cheung</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Preventive Medicine, National Defense Medical Center, New Taipei City 23742, Taiwan; Graduate Institute of Medical Science, National Defense Medical Center, Taipei City 11490, Taiwan. Electronic address: chengcheung_chen@gapps.ndmctsgh.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Colloid Interface Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0043125</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0021-9797</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7782-42-5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006108">Graphite</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000998">Antiviral Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045663" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quantum Dots</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006108" MajorTopicYN="Y">Graphite</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017753" MajorTopicYN="N">Ecosystem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000998" MajorTopicYN="N">Antiviral Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus deactivation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Graphene quantum dots</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Solid-phase microwave-assisted method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surface functionality</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36308803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9580242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2022.10.082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0021-9797(22)01844-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>&#x141;oczechin A., S&#xe9;ron K., Barras A., Giovanelli E., Belouzard S., Chen Y.-T., et al. Functional carbon quantum dots as medical countermeasures to human coronavirus. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2019;11:42964&#x2013;42974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7075527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31633330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jindal S., Gopinath P. Nanotechnology based approaches for combatting COVID-19 viral infection. Nano Express. 2020;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri V., Papi M. Can graphene take part in the fight against COVID-19? Nano Today. 2020;33</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7203038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32382315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manivannan S., Ponnuchamy K. Quantum dots as a promising agent to combat COVID-19. Appl. Organomet. Chem. 2020;e5887:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7361141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32836625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udugama B., Kadhiresan P., Kozlowski H.N., Malekjahani A., Osborne M., Li V.Y.C., et al. Diagnosing COVID-19: the disease and tools for detection. ACS Nano. 2020;14:3822&#x2013;3835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32223179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosales-Mendoza S., M&#xe1;rquez-Escobar V.A., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Ortega O., Nieto-G&#xf3;mez R., Ar&#xe9;valo-Villalobos J.I. What does plant-based vaccine technology offer to the fight against COVID-19? Vaccine. 2020;8:183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32295153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss C., Carriere M., Fusco L., Capua I., Regla-Nava J.A., Pasquali M., et al. Toward nanotechnology-enabled approaches against the COVID-19 pandemicm. ACS Nano. 2020;14:6383&#x2013;6406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32519842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang S., Hillyer C., Du L. Neutralizing antibodies against SARS-CoV-2 and other human coronaviruses. Trends Immunol. 2020;41:355&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7129017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32249063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magrone T., Magrone M., Jirillo E. Focus on receptors for coronaviruses with special reference to angiotensin converting enzyme 2 as a potential drug target-a perspective, Endocr. Metab. Immune. Disord. Drug. Targets. 2020;20:807&#x2013;811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32338224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galabov A.S. Virucidal agents in the eve of manorapid synergy. GMS Krankenhhyg Interdiszip. 2007;2:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2831485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20200679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones S.T. How materials can beat a virus. J. Mater. Sci. 2020;55:9148&#x2013;9151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7216856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zare M., Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; M., Ramakrishna S. Essential role of quantum science and nanoscience in antiviral strategies for COVID. Adv. Mater. 2021;2:2188&#x2013;2199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovic Z.M., Ristic B.Z., Arsikin K.M., Klisic D.G., Harhaji-Trajkovic L.M., Todorovic-Markovic B.M., Kepic D.P., Kravic-Stevovic T.K., Jovanovic S.P., Milenkovic M.M., Milivojevic D.D., Bumbasirevic V.Z., Dramicanin M.D., Trajkovic V.S. Graphene quantum dots as autophagy-inducing photodynamic agents. Biomaterials. 2021;33:7084&#x2013;7092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22795854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ristic B.Z., Milenkovic M.M., Dakic I.R., Todorovic-Markovic B.M., Milosavljevic M.S., Budimir M.D., Paunovic V.G., Dramicanin M.D., Markovic Z.M., Trajkovic V.S. Photodynamic antibacterial effect of graphene quantum dots. Biomaterials. 2014;35:4428&#x2013;4435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24612819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovi&#x107; Z.M., Jovanovi&#x107; S.P., Ma&#x161;kovi&#x107; P.Z., Danko M., Mi&#x10d;u&#x161;&#xed;k M., Pavlovi&#x107; V.B., Milivojevi&#x107; D.D., Kleinov&#xe1; A., &#x160;pitalsk&#xfd; Z., Markovi&#x107; B.M.T. Photo-induced antibacterial activity of four graphene based nanomaterials on a wide range of bacteria. RSC Adv. 2018;8:31337&#x2013;31347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9085601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35548242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Z., Yang D., Yang C., Wu X., Hu Y., Zhang Y., Yuwen L., Yeow E.K.L., Weng L., Huang W., Wang L. Graphene quantum dots modified with adenine for efficient two-photon bioimaging and white light-activated antibacterial. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2018;434:155&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Yang C., Yang D., Shao Z., Hu Y., Chen J., Yuwen L., Weng L., Luo Z., Wang L. Reduction of graphene oxide quantum dots to enhance the yield of reactive oxygen species for photodynamic therapy. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2018;20:17262&#x2013;17267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29901057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volarevic V., Paunovic V., Markovic Z., Markovic B.S., Misirkic-Marjanovic M., Todorovi-Markovi B., Bojic S., Vucicevic L., Jovanovic S., Arsenijevic N., Holclajtner-Antunovi I., Milosavljevic M., Dramicanin M., Kravic-Stevovic T., Ciric D., Lukic M.L., Trajkovic V. Large graphene quantum dots alleviate immune-mediated liver damage. ACS Nano. 2014;8:12098&#x2013;12109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25415137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markovi&#x107; Z.M., Jovanovi&#x107; S.P., Ma&#x161;kovi&#x107; P.Z., Mojsin M.M., Stevanovi&#x107; M.J., Danko M., Mi&#x10d;u&#x161;&#xed;k M., Jovanovi&#x107; D.J., Kleinov&#xe1; A., &#x160;pitalsk&#xfd; Z., Pavlovi&#x107; V.B., Markovi&#x107; B.M.T. Graphene oxide size and structure pro-oxidant and antioxidant activity and photoinduced cytotoxicity relation on three cancer cell lines. J. Photochem. Photobiol. B: Biol. 2019;200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31648133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H., Wu L., Wei W., Qu X. Recent advances in graphene quantum dots for sensing. Mater. Today. 2013;16:433&#x2013;442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juang R.-S., Hsieh C.-T., Kao C.-P., Ashraf Gandomi Y., Fu C.-C., Liu S.-H., et al. Highly fluorescent green and red emissions from boron-doped graphene quantum dots under blue light illumination. 2021;176:61&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves H.M.R., Duarte A.J., Esteves Da Silva J.C.G. Optical fiber sensor for Hg(II) based on carbon dots. Biosens. Bioelectron. 2010;26:1302&#x2013;1306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20675118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu S., Hsieh C.-T., Tsai Y.-Y., Ashraf Gandomi Y., Yeom S., Kihm K.D., et al. Sulfur and nitrogen co-doped graphene quantum dots as a fluorescent quenching probe for highly sensitive detection toward mercury ions. ACS Appl. Nano Mater. 2019;2:790&#x2013;798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S., Cao L., Luo P.G., Lu F., Wang X., Wang H., et al. Carbon dots for optical imaging in vivo. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2009;131:11308&#x2013;11309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2739123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19722643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu C.-C., Wu C.-Y., Chien C.-C., Hsu T.-H., Ou S.-F., Chen S.-T., et al. Polyethylene glycol6000/carbon nanodots as fluorescent bioimaging agents. Nanomaterials. 2020;10:677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7222009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32260230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu S., Hsieh C.-T., Mallick B.C., Fu C.-C., Juang R.-S., Ashraf Gandomif Y., et al. Novel electrochemical sensor based on highly amidized graphene quantum dots to electrochemically detect hydrogen peroxide. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2020;528</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu S., Hsieh C.-T., Mallick B.C., Ashraf Gandomi Y. Infrared-assisted synthesis of highly amidized graphene quantum dots as metal-free electrochemical catalysts. Electrochim. Acta. 2020;360</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao D., Zhu C., Xia X., Liu J., Zhang X., Wang J., et al. Graphene quantum dots coated VO2 arrays for highly durable electrodes for Li and Na ion batteries. Nano Lett. 2015;15:565&#x2013;573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25531798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiyi L., Yuanyuan J., Xiaoyan Z., Zaijun L., Zhiguo G., Guangli W., et al. significantly enhanced electrochemical performance of lithium titanate anode for lithium ion battery by the hybrid of nitrogen and sulfur co-doped graphene quantum dots. Electrochim. Acta. 2015;178:303&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu S., Christensen T., Hsieh C.-T., Mallick B.C., Ashraf Gandomi Y., Li J., et al. Improved lithium storage capacity and high rate capability of nitrogen-doped graphite-like electrode materials prepared from thermal pyrolysis of graphene quantum dots. Electrochim. Acta. 2020;354</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daugherty M.C., Gu S., Aaron D.S., Mallick B.C., Ashraf Gandomi Y., Hsieh C.-T. Decorating sulfur and nitrogen co-doped graphene quantum dots on graphite felt as high-performance electrodes for vanadium redox flow batteries. J. Power Sources. 2020;477</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Hu A. Carbon quantum dots: synthesis, properties and applications. J. Mater. Chem. C. 2014;2:6921&#x2013;6939.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao S., Liang K., Zhu J., Yang B., Zhao D., Kong B. Hetero-atom-doped carbon dots: doping strategies, properties and applications. Nano Today. 2020;33</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garga P., Sangama S., Kochhar D., Paharic S., Kar C., Mukherjee M. Exploring the role of triazole functionalized heteroatom co-doped carbon quantum dots against human coronaviruses. Nano Today. 2020;35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33052202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu S., Hsieh C.-T., Ashraf Gandomi Y., Chang J.-K., Li J., Li J., et al. Microwave growth and tunable photoluminescence of nitrogen-doped graphene and carbon nitride quantum dots. J. Mater. Chem. C. 2019;7:5468&#x2013;5476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu S., Hsieh C.-T., Ashraf Gandomi Y., Li J., Yue X.X., Chang J.-K. Tailoring fluorescence emissions, quantum yields, and white light emitting from nitrogen-doped graphene and carbon nitride quantum dots. Nanoscale. 2019;11:16553&#x2013;16561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31455955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y.-N., Hsueh Y.-H., Hsieh C.-T., Tzou D.-Y., Chang P.-L. Antiviral activity of graphene-silver nanocomposites against non-enveloped and enveloped viruses. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2016;13:430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4847092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27104546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J.-R., Tuan Y.-C., Tsai H.-P., Yan J.-J., Liu C.-C., Su I.-J. Change of major genotype of entrovirus 71 in outbreaks of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Taiwan between 1998 and 2000. J. Clin. Microbiol. 2002;40:10&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen N.C., Black J.W., Boyle J.F., Evermann J.F., McKeirnan A.J., Ott R.L. Pathogenic differences between various feline coronavirus isolates. Adv. Exp. Med. Biol. 1984;173:365&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6331125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J., He Y.-Q., Yi L.-N., Zan H., Kung H.-F., He M.-L. Viral kinetics of enterovirus 71 in human abdomyosarcoma cells. World J. Gastroenterol. 2011;17:4135&#x2013;4142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3203367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22039330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed L.J., Muench H. A simple method of estimating fifty percent endpoints. Am. J. Epidemiol. 1938;27:493&#x2013;497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S., Hwang S.W., Kim M.K., Dong Y.S., Dong H.S., Chang O.K., Yang S.B., Park J.H., Hwang E., Choi S.H. Anomalous behaviors of visible luminescence from graphene quantum dots: interplay between size and shape. ACS Nano. 2012;6:8203&#x2013;8208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22881035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Y.T., Kim N.S., Park J., Han J.B., Choi Y.S., Ryu H., Lee H.J. Temperature-dependent growth of carbon nanotubes by pyrolysis of ferrocene and acetylene in the range between 700 and 1000&#xb0;C. Chem. Phys. Lett. 2003;372:853&#x2013;859.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim K., Kim K., Jung W.S., Bae S.Y., Park J., Choi J., Choo J. Investigation on the temperature-dependent growth rate of carbon nanotubes using chemical vapor deposition of ferrocene and acetylene. Chem. Phys. Lett. 2005;401:459&#x2013;464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni L., Kuroda K., Zhou L., Kizuka T., Ohta K., Matsuishi K., Nakamura J. Kinetic study of carbon nanotube synthesis over Mo/Co/MgO catalysts. Carbon. 2006;44:2265&#x2013;2272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng J., Gao W., Gupta B.K., Liu Z., Romero-Aburto R., Ge L., et al. Graphene quantum dots derived from carbon fibers. Nano Lett. 2012;12:844&#x2013;849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22216895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu T., Yin K., Xie X., He L., Wang B., Sun L. Size-dependent evolution of graphene nanopores under thermal excitation. Small. 2012;8:3422&#x2013;3426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22903811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia X., Hofmann M., Meunier V., Sumpter B.G., Campos-Delgado J., Romo-Herrera J.M. Controlled formation of sharp zigzag and armchair edges in graphitic nanoribbons. Science. 2009;323:1701&#x2013;1705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19325109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Y., Long H., Wang X., Wang Y., Gu Q., Jiang W., et al. Doping: versatile graphene quantum dots with tunable nitrogen doping. Part. Part. Syst. Char. 2014;31:597&#x2013;604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barman S., Sadhukhan M. Facile bulk production of highly blue fluorescent graphitic carbon nitride quantum dots and their application as highly selective and sensitive sensors for the detection of mercuric and iodide ions in aqueous media. J. Mater. Chem. 2012;22:21832&#x2013;21837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K., Chai Z., Li C., Shi L., Liu M., Xie Q., et al. Catalyst-free growth of three-dimensional graphene flakes and graphene/g-C3N4 composite for hydrocarbon oxidation. ACS Nano. 2016;10:3665&#x2013;3673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26918323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A., Wang C., Fu L., Wong-Ng W., Lan Y. Recent advances of graphitic carbon nitride-based structures and applications in catalyst, sensing, imaging, and LEDs. Nano-Micro Lett. 2017;9:47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6199047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30393742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar G.S., Roy R., Sen D., Ghorai U.K., Thapa R., Mazumder N., et al. Amino-functionalized graphene quantum dots: origin of tunable heterogeneous photoluminescence. Nanoscale. 2014;6:3384&#x2013;3391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24531861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh C.T., Lin C.Y., Chen Y.F., Lin J.S., Teng H. Silver nanorods attached to graphene sheets as anode materials for lithium-ion batteries. Carbon. 2013;62:109&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezani Z., Dayer M.R., Noorizadeh S., Thompson M. Deactivation of SARS-CoV-2 via shielding of spike glycoprotein using carbon quantum dots: bioinformatic perspective. COVID. 2021;1:120&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barras A., Pagneux Q., Sane F., Wang Q., Boukherroub R., Hober D., et al. High efficiency of functional carbon nanodots as entry inhibitors of herpes simplex virus type 1. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2016;8:9004&#x2013;9013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27015417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du T., Liang J., Dong N., Liu L., Fang L., Xiao S., et al. Carbon dots as inhibitors of virus by activation of type I interferon response. Carbon. 2016;110:278&#x2013;285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ting D., Dong N., Fang L., Lu J., Bi J., Xiao S., et al. Multisite inhibitors for enteric coronavirus: antiviral cationic carbon dots based on curcumin. ACS Appl. Nano Mater. 2018;1:5451&#x2013;5459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35286056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong X., Moyer M.M., Yang F., Sun Y.P., Yang L. Carbon dots&#x2019; antiviral functions against noroviruses. Sci. Rep. 2017;7:519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5428842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28364126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L., Liang J. An overview of functional nanoparticles as novel emerging antiviral therapeutic agents. Mater. Sci. Eng. C. 2020;112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32409074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong T., Hu H., Zhou J., Deng S., Zhang X., Tang W., Fang L., Xiao S. Glycyrrhizic-acid-based carbon dots with high antiviral activity by multisite inhibition mechanisms. Small. 2020;16:1906206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32077621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Zeng T.H., Hofmann M., Burcombe E., Wei J., Jiang R., Kong J., Chen Y. Antibacterial activity of graphite, graphite oxide, graphene oxide, and reduced graphene oxide: membrane and oxidative stress. ACS Nano. 2011;5:6971&#x2013;6980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21851105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Kong W., Wang L., Zhang J.Z., Li Y., Liu X., Li Y. Optimizing oxygen functional groups in graphene quantum dots for improved antioxidant mechanism. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2019;21:1336&#x2013;1343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30574959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travlou N.A., Giannakoudakis D.A., Algarra M., Labella A.M., Rodr&#xed;guez-Castell&#xf3;n E., Bandosz T.J. S- and N-doped carbon quantum dots: Surface chemistry dependent antibacterial activity. Carbon. 2018;135:104&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34996200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juang R.-S., Fu C.-C., Hsieh C.-T., Gu S., Ashraf Gandomi Y., Liu S.-H. Highly luminescent aggregate-induced emission from polyethylene glycol-coated carbon quantum dot clusters under blue light illumination. J. Mater. Chem. C. 2020;8:16569&#x2013;16576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Kotta, H.M. Aldawsari, S.M. Badr-Eldin, N.A. Alhakamy, S. Md, A.B. Nair, et al., Exploring the potential of carbon dots to combat COVID-19, Front. Mol. Biosci. 7 (2020) 616575 (1-11).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7793735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33425995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>