<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34997684</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1654</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Reviews in medical virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rev Med Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Does enterovirus 71 urge for effective vaccine control strategies? Challenges and current opinion.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2322</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2322</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/rmv.2322</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is an infectious virus affecting all age groups of people around the world. It is one of the major aetiologic agents for HFMD (hand, foot and mouth disease) identified globally. It has led to many outbreaks and epidemics in Asian countries. Infection caused by this virus that can lead to serious psychological problems, heart diseases and respiratory issues in children younger than 10&#xa0;years of age. Many studies are being carried out on the pathogenesis of the virus, but little is known. The host immune response and other molecular responses against the virus are also not clearly determined. This review deals with the interaction between the host and the EV71 virus. We discuss how the virus makes use of its proteins to affect the host's immunity and how the viral proteins help their replication. Additionally, we describe other useful resources that enable the virus to evade the host's immune responses. The knowledge of the viral structure and its interactions with host cells has led to the discovery of various drug targets for the treatment of the virus. Additionally, this review focusses on the antiviral drugs and vaccines developed by targeting various viral surface molecules during their infectious period. Furthermore, it is asserted that the improvement of prevailing vaccines will be the simplest method to manage EV71 infection swiftly. Therefore, we summarise numerous vaccines candidate for the EV71, such as the use of an inactivated complete virus, recombinant VP1 protein, artificial peptides, VLPs (viral-like particles) and live attenuated vaccines for combating the viral outbreaks promptly.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swain</LastName><ForeName>Subrat Kumar</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9173-1727</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Genomics and Biomedical Informatics, IMS and SUM Hospital, Siksha 'O' Anusandhan (Deemed to be University), Bhubaneswar, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gadnayak</LastName><ForeName>Ayushman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Genomics and Biomedical Informatics, IMS and SUM Hospital, Siksha 'O' Anusandhan (Deemed to be University), Bhubaneswar, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohanty</LastName><ForeName>Jatindra Nath</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Genomics and Biomedical Informatics, IMS and SUM Hospital, Siksha 'O' Anusandhan (Deemed to be University), Bhubaneswar, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarangi</LastName><ForeName>Rachita</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, IMS and SUM Hospital, Siksha 'O' Anusandhan University (Deemed to be University), Bhubaneswar, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Das</LastName><ForeName>Jayashankar</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Genomics and Biomedical Informatics, IMS and SUM Hospital, Siksha 'O' Anusandhan (Deemed to be University), Bhubaneswar, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rev Med Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1052-9276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D057134">Antibodies, Neutralizing</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000914">Antibodies, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014613">Vaccines, Attenuated</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014765">Viral Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057134" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Neutralizing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000914" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Viral</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014613" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccines, Attenuated</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014765" MajorTopicYN="Y">Viral Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HFMD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus-71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand, foot and mouth disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">replication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vaccines</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34997684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rmv.2322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kumar KB, Kiran AG, Kumar BU. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in children: a clinical epidemiological study. Indian J Paediatr Dermatol. 2016;17:1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh WM, Bogich T, Siegel K, et&#xa0;al. The epidemiology of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Asia: a systematic review and analysis. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2016;35(10):e285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang ZC, Kou ZQ, Bai YJ, et&#xa0;al. Epidemiological research on hand, foot, and mouth disease in mainland China. Viruses. 2015;7(12):6400-6411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Podin Y, Akin W, Delsel S, Mohan A. Human enterovirus 71 diseases in Sarawak, Malaysia: a prospective clinical, virological, and molecular epidemiological study. Clin Infect Dis. 2007;44:646-656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Liu CC. Enterovirus 71: epidemiology, pathogenesis, and management. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2009;7:735-742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Chang LY, Huang YC, Hsu KH, Chiu CH, Yang KD. Different proinflammatory reactions in fatal and non-fatal enterovirus 71 infections: implications for early recognition and therapy. Acta Paediatr 2002;91:632-635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang HI, Shih SR. Neurotropic enter virus infections in the central nervous system. Viruses. 2015;7:6051-6066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G, Wildsen G, Knowles NJ, McCauley JW. Complete nucleotide sequence of a coxsackie B5 virus and its relationships to swine vesicular disease virus. J Gen Virol. 1993;74:845-853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta K, Aoki Y, Suto A, Ootani K, Katsushima N, Itagaki T. Cross-antigenicity among EV71 strains from different genogroups isolated in Yamagata, Japan, between 1990 and 2007. Vaccine. 2009;27:3153-3158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang ML, Chiang PS, Chia MY, Luo ST, Chang LY, Lin TY. Cross-reactive neutralizing antibody responses to enterovirus 71 infections in young children: implications for vaccine development. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2013;7:e2067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, An D, Liu W, Mao Q, Jin J, Xu L. Analysis of cross-reactive neutralizing antibodies in human HFMD serum with an EV71 pseudovirus-based assay. PLOS ONE. 2014;9:e100545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar S, Chee HY, Al-Kobaisi MF, Xiaoshan J, Bing Chua K, Kit Lam S. Identification of enterovirus 71 isolates from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) with fatal cases of encephalomyelitis in Malaysia. Virus Res. 1999;61:1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tee KK, Lam TT, Chan YF, et&#xa0;al. Evolutionary genetics of human enterovirus 71: origin, population dynamics, natural selection, and seasonal periodicity of the VP1 gene. J Virol. 2010;84:3339-3350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang ZC, Kou ZQ, Bai YJ, Cong X, Wang LH, Li C. Epidemiological research on hand, foot, and mouth disease in Mainland China. Viruses. 2015;7:6400-6411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flewett TH, Warin RP, Clarke SKR. &#x2018;Hand, foot, and mouth disease&#x2019; associated with Coxsackie A5 virus. J Clin Pathol. 1963;16:53-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes RO, Roberts C. Hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with Coxsackie A9 virus. Lancet. 1972;2:751-752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindenbaum JE, Van Dyck PC, Allen RG. Hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with Coxsackievirus group B. Scand J Infect Dis. 1975;7:161-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang LW, Koh BK, Chan KP, Chua LT, James L, Goh KT. Epidemiology and control of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Singapore. Ann Acad Med Singap. 2009;38(2):106-112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YF, Yang F, Du J, Dong J, Zhang T, Wu ZQ. Complete genome analysis of Coxsackievirus A2, A4, A5, and A10 strains isolated from hand, foot, and mouth disease patients in China revealing frequent recombination of human enterovirus a. J Clin Microbiol. 2011;49:2426-2434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flett K, Youngster I, Huang J, McAdam A, Sandora TJ, Rennick M. Hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by Coxsackievirus A6. Emerg Infect Dis. 2012;18:1702-1704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreoni AR, Colton AS. Coxsackievirus B5 associated with hand-foot-mouth disease in a healthy adult. JAAD Case Rep. 2017;3:165-168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu H, Shimizu Y, Takeuchi Y, Ishiko H, Takada H. Outbreak of severe neurologic involvement associated with Enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr Neurol. 1999;20:17-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P, Stratov I, Nagarajan L, Davis S. Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin Infect Dis. 2001;32:236-242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt NJ, Lennette EH, Ho HH. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J&#xa0;Infect Dis. 1974;129:304-309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov M, Voroshilova M, Shindarov L, Lavrova I, Gracheva L, Koroleva G. Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch Virol. 1979;60:329-340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy G, Takatsy S, Kukan E, Mihaly I, Domok I. Virological diagnosis of enterovirus type 71 infections: experiences gained during an epidemic of acute CNS diseases in Hungary in 1978. Arch Virol. 1982;71:217-227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta K, Aoki Y, Suto A, et&#xa0;al. Cross-antigenicity among EV71 strains from different genogroups isolated in Yamagata, Japan, between 1990 and 2007. Vaccine. 2009;27(24):3153-3158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang ML, Chiang PS, Chia MY, et&#xa0;al. Cross-reactive neutralizing antibody responses to enterovirus 71 infections in young children: implications for vaccine development. PLOS Negl Trop Dis. 2013;7(2):e2067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, An D, Liu W, et&#xa0;al. Analysis of cross-reactive neutralizing antibodies in human HFMD serum with an EV71 pseudovirus-based assay. PLOS ONE. 2014;9(6):e100545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HO M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, et&#xa0;al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan enterovirus epidemic working group. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:929-935. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM199909233411301</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in Western Australia associated with acute flaccid paralysis. Preliminary report. Commun Dis Intell. 1999;23:199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto T, Chikahira M, Yoshida S, Ebira H, Hasegawa A, Totsuka A. Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol Immunol. 2002;46:621-627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin JY, Shih SR, Pan M, Li C, Lue CF, Stollar V. hnRNP A1 interacts with the 50 untranslated regions of enterovirus 71 and Sindbis virus RNA and is required for viral replication. J Virol. 2009;83:6106-6114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu PV, Thao NT, Perera D, Huu TK, Tien NT, Thuong TC. Epidemiologic and virologic investigation of hand, foot, and mouth disease, southern Vietnam, 2005. Emerg Infect Dis. 2007;13:1733-1741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sazaly A, Sam IC, Jaliha Y, Meng Keang L, Suzana M, Poh-Sim H. Enterovirus 71 outbreak, Brunei. Emerg Infect Dis J. 2009;15:79-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KH. Enterovirus 71 infection: an experience in Korea. Korean J. Pediatr. 2010;53:616-622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallansch MA. Enteroviruses: polioviruses, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses, and newer enteroviruses. Fields Virol. 2007:839-893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, et&#xa0;al. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect Dis. 2010;10:778-790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MS, Chiang PS, Luo ST, Huang ML, Liou GY, Tsao KC. Incidence rates of enterovirus 71 infections in young children during a nationwide epidemic in Taiwan, 2008-09. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2012;6:e1476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CS, Yao YC, Lin SC, Lee YP, Wang YF, Wang JR. Retrograde axonal transport: a major transmission route of enterovirus 71 in mice. J Virol. 2007;81:8996-9003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Wakita T, Shimizu H. Tyrosine sulfation of the amino terminus of PSGL-1 is critical for enterovirus 71 Infection. PLOS Pathog. 2010;6:e1001174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SC, Lin JY, Lo LY, Li ML, Shih SR. Diverse apoptotic pathways in enterovirus 71-infected cells. J Neurovirol. 2004;10:338-349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng HY, Huang YC, Yen TY, et&#xa0;al. The correlation between the presence of viremia and clinical severity in patients with enterovirus 71 infection: a multi-center cohort study. BMC Infect Dis. 2014;14(1):417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Hsia SH, Huang YC, Wu CT, Chang LY. Pro inflammatory cytokine reactions in Enterovirus 71 infections of the central nervous system. Clin Infect Dis. 2003;36:269-274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths MJ, Ooi MH, Wong SC, Mohan A, Podin Y, Perera D. In enterovirus 71 encephalitis with cardio-respiratory compromise, elevated interleukin 1beta, interleukin 1 receptor antagonist, and granulocyte colony-stimulating factor levels are markers of poor prognosis. J Infect Dis. 2012;206:881-892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye N, Gong X, Pang LL, Gao WJ, Zhang YT, Li XL. Cytokine responses and correlations thereof with clinical profiles in children with enterovirus 71 infections. BMC Infect Dis. 2015;15:225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Huang KJ, Wu JM, Wang JR, Yu CK. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J Infect Dis. 2003;188:564-570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao SJ, Yang FL, Hsu YH, et&#xa0;al. Mechanism of fulminant pulmonary edema caused by enterovirus 71. Clin Infect Dis. 2004;38:1784-1788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown BA, Pallansch MA. Complete nucleotide sequence of enterovirus 71 is distinct from poliovirus. Virus Res 1995;39:195-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plevka P, Lim PY, Perera R, Cardosa J, Suksatu A, Kuhn RJ. Neutralizing antibodies can initiate genome release from human enterovirus 71. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2014;111:2134-2139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2002;26:91-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tee KK, Lam TT, Chan YF, Bible JM, Kamarulzaman A, Tong CY. Evolutionary genetics of human enterovirus 71: origin, population dynamics, natural selection, and seasonal periodicity of the VP1 gene. J Virol. 2010;84:3339-3350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin JY, Li ML, Shih SR. Far upstream element binding protein 2 interacts with enterovirus 71 internal ribosomal entry site and negatively regulates viral translation. Nucleic Acids Res. 2009;37:47-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bessaud M, Razafindratsimandresy R, Nougairede A, Joffret ML, Deshpande JM, Dubot-Peres A. Molecular comparison and evolutionary analyses of VP1 nucleotide sequences of new African human enterovirus 71 isolates reveal a wide genetic diversity. PLoS One. 2014;9:e90624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JX, Mao QY, Liang ZL, Ji H, Zhu FC. Development of enterovirus 71 vaccines: from the lab bench to phase 3 clinical trials. Expert Rev Vaccines. 2014;13:609-618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YJ, Meng FY, Mao QY. Clinical evaluation for batch consistency of an inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in a large-scale phase 3 clinical trial. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2014;10:1366-1372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong P, Guo MS, Lin FH. Immunological and biochemical characterization of Coxsackievirus A16 viral particles. PLOS ONE. 2012;7:e49973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ida-Hosonuma M, Iwasaki T, Yoshikawa T, et&#xa0;al. The &#x3b1;/&#x3b2; interferon response controls tissue tropism and pathogenicity of poliovirus. J Virol. 2005;79:4460-4469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YF, Yu CK. Animal models of enterovirus 71 infection: applications and limitations. J Biomed Sci. 2014;21:31-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Meng FY, Li JX. Efficacy, safety, and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2013;38:2024-2032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YW, Yu SL, Shao HY. Human SCARB2 transgenic mice as an infectious animal model for enterovirus 71. PLOS ONE. 2013;8:e57591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujii K, Nagata N, Sato Y. Transgenic mouse model for the study of enterovirus 71 neuropathogenesis. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2013;110:14753-14758.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsson EC, Jamshidi F, Johansson SM, Oberste MS, Arnberg N. Sialic acid is a cellular receptor for Coxsackievirus A24 variant, an emerging virus with pandemic potential. J Virol. 2008;82(6):3061-3068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Q, Cheng T, Zhu F. The cross-neutralizing activity of enterovirus 71 subgenotype C4 vaccines in healthy Chinese infants and children. PLoS One. 2013;8:e79599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staring J, van den Hengel LG, Raaben M, Blomen VA, Carette JE, Brummelkamp TR. KREMEN1 is a host entry receptor for a major group of enteroviruses. Cell Host Microbe. 2018;23(5):636-643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang HW, Lin YW, Ho HM, et&#xa0;al. Protective efficacy of VP1-specific neutralizing antibody associated with a reduction of viral load and pro-inflammatory cytokines in human SCARB2-transgenic mice. PLoS One. 2013;8(7):e69858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao B, Wu W, Davidson G, et&#xa0;al. Kremen proteins are Dickkopf receptors that regulate Wnt/b-catenin signalling. Nature. 2002;417:664-667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin JY, Shih SR, Pan M, et&#xa0;al. hnRNP A1 interacts with the 5&#x2032; untranslated regions of enterovirus 71 and Sindbis virus RNA and is required for viral replication. J Virol. 2009;83(12):6106-6114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Stollar V, Li ML. Host factors in enterovirus 71 replication. J Virol. 2011;85(19):9658-9666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergelson JM, Mohanty JG, Crowell RL, St John NF, Lublin DM, Finberg RW. Coxsackievirus B3 adapted to grow in RD cells binds to decay-accelerating factor (CD 55). J Virol. 1995;69:1903-1906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafren DS, Bates RC, Agrez MV, Herd RL, Burns GF, Barry RD. Coxsackieviruses B1, B3, and B5 use decay accelerating factor as a receptor for cell attachment. J Virol. 1995;69:3873-3877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colonno RJ. Cell surface receptors for picornaviruses. Bioessays. 1987;5:270-274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulli T, Koskimies P, Hyypi&#xe4; T. Molecular comparison of coxsackie A virus serotypes. Virology. 1995;212:30-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greve JM, Davis G, Meyer AM, et&#xa0;al. The major human rhinovirus receptor is ICAM-1. Cell. 1989;56(5):839-847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khandia R, Singhal S, Kumar U, et&#xa0;al. Analysis of Nipah virus codon usage and adaptation to hosts. Front Microbiol. 2019;10:886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staunton DE, Merluzzi VJ, Rothlein R, Barton R, Marlin SD, Springer TA. A cell adhesion molecule, ICAM-1, is the major surface receptor for rhinoviruses. Cell. 1989;56:849-853.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar H, Kawai T, Akira S. Pathogen recognition by the innate immune system. Int Rev Immunol. 2011;30(1):16-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathinayake PS, Hsu AC, Wark PA. Innate immunity and immune evasion by enterovirus 71. Viruses. 2015;7:6613-6630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald KA, Rowe DC, Barnes BJ, et&#xa0;al. LPS-TLR4 signaling to IRF-3/7 and NF-&#x3ba;B involves the toll adapters TRAM and TRIF. J&#xa0;Exp Med. 2003;198(7):1043-1055.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Xi X, Lei X, et&#xa0;al. Enterovirus 71 protease 2Apro targets MAVS to inhibit anti-viral type I interferon responses. PLoS Pathog. 2013;9:e1003231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X, Sun Z, Liu X, Jin Q, He B, Wang J. Cleavage of the adaptor protein TRIF by enterovirus 71b 3C inhibits antiviral responses mediated by Toll-like receptor 3. J Virol. 2011;85:8811-8818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter JA, Randall RE, Taylor GL. Crystal structure of human IPS-1/MAVS/VISA/Cardifcaspase activation recruitment domain. BMC Struct Biol. 2008;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid E, Charleston B. Type I and III interferon production in response to RNA viruses. J Interferon Cytokine Res. 2014;34(9):649-658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin JY, Chen TC, Weng KF, Chang SC, Chen LL, Shih SR. Viral and host proteins involved in picornavirus life cycle. J Biomed Sci. 2009;16(1):1-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Stollar V, Li ML. Host factors in enterovirus 71 replication. J Virol. 2011;85:9658-9666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Q, Langereis MA, Lork M, Nguyen M, Hato SV, Lanke K. Enterovirus 2Apro targets MDA5 and MAVS in infected cells. J&#xa0;Virol. 2014;88:3369-3378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J, Yi L, Zhao J, Yu J, Chen Y, Lin MC. Enterovirus 71 disrupts interferon signaling by reducing the level of interferon receptor 1. J&#xa0;Virol. 2012;86:3767-3776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X, Liu X, Ma Y, Sun Z, Yang Y, Jin Q. The 3C protein of enterovirus 71 inhibits retinoid acid-inducible gene I-mediated interferon regulatory factor 3 activation and type I interferon responses. J Virol. 2010;84:8051-8061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang PN, Lin JY, Locker N, Kung YA, Hung CT, Lin JY. Far upstream element binding protein 1 binds the internal ribosomal entry site of enterovirus 71 and enhances viral translation and viral growth. Nucleic Acids Res. 2011;39:9633-9648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X, Xiao X, Xue Q, Jin Q, He B, Wang J. Cleavage of interferon regulatory factor 7 by enterovirus 71 3C suppresses cellular responses. J Virol. 2013;87:1690-1698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan K, Bowie AG. Activation of host pattern recognition receptors by viruses. Curr Opin Microbiol. 2010;13:503-507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanarek N, Grivennikov SI, Leshets M, et&#xa0;al. Critical role for IL-1&#x3b2; in DNA damage-induced mucositis. Proc Natl Acad Sci Unit States Am. 2014;111(6):E702-E711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versteeg GA, Garcia-Sastre A. Viral tricks to grid-lock the type I interferon system. Curr Opin Microbiol. 2010;13:508-516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson MR, Kaminski JJ, Kurt-Jones EA, Fitzgerald KA. Pattern recognition receptors and the innate immune response to viral infection. Viruses. 2011;3:920-940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oudshoorn D, Versteeg GA, Kikkert M. Regulation of the innate immune system by ubiquitin and ubiquitin-like modifiers. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2012;23:273-282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Yang L, Liang X, Zhu G. MicroRNA-155 promotes atherosclerosis inflammation via targeting SOCS1. Cell Physiol Biochem. 2015;36:1371-1381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y, Qiu J, Li C, et&#xa0;al. Fortunellin-induced modulation of phosphatase and tensin homolog by MicroRNA-374a decreases inflammation and maintains intestinal barrier function in colitis. Front Immunol. 2018;9:83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu W, Zhan H, Zhou XY, et&#xa0;al. MicroRNA-22 regulates inflammation and angiogenesis via targeting VE-cadherin. FEBS Lett. 2017;591:513-526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsen TA, de Souza GA, Odegaard B, Engebretsen L, Brinchmann JE. microRNA-140 inhibits inflammation and stimulates chondrogenesis in a model of interleukin 1beta-induced osteoarthritis. Mol Ther Nucleic Acids. 2016;5:e373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Song J, Liu L, et&#xa0;al. Different microRNA alterations contribute to diverse outcomes following EV71 and CA16 infections: insights from high throughput sequencing in rhesus monkey peripheral blood mononuclear cells. Int J Biochem Cell Biol. 2016;81:20-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lui YL, Tan TL, Woo WH, et&#xa0;al. Enterovirus 71 (EV71) utilise host microRNAs to mediate host immune system enhancing survival during infection. PLoS One. 2014;9:e102997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho BC, Yu SL, Chen JJ, et&#xa0;al. Enterovirus-induced miR-141 contributes to shutoff of host protein translation by targeting the translation initiation factor eIF4E. Cell Host Microbe. 2011;9:58-69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukhatme VP, Cao XM, Chang LC, et&#xa0;al. A zinc finger-encoding gene coregulated with c-fos during growth and differentiation, and after cellular depolarization. Cell. 1988;53:37-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho BC, Yu IS, Lu LF, et&#xa0;al. Inhibition of miR-146a prevents enterovirus-induced death by restoring the production of type I interferon. Nat Commun. 2014;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Zheng J. MicroR-9-5p suppresses EV71 replication through targeting NF&#x3ba;B of the RIG-I-mediated innate immune response. FEBS Open Bio. 2018;8(9):1457-1470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong P, Hsieh SY, Liu CC. Production of EV71 vaccine candidates. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2012;8:1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kung YA, Hung CT, Liu YC, Shih SR. Update on the development of enterovirus 71 vaccines. Expert Opin Biol Ther. 2014;14:1455-1464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng A, Fung CP, Liu CC. A phase 1, randomized, open-label study to evaluate the safety and immunogenicity of enterovirus 71 vaccine. Vaccine. 2013;31:2471-2476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou AH, Liu CC, Chang JY. Formalin-inactivated EV71 vaccine candidate induced cross-neutralizing antibody responses against subgenotypes B1, B4, B5 and C4A in adult volunteers. PLoS One. 2013;8:e79783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JX, Mao QY, Liang ZL, Ji H, Zhu FC. Development of enterovirus 71 vaccines: from the lab bench to phase 3 clinical trials. Expert Rev Vaccines. 2014;13:609-618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Q, Cheng T, Zhu F. The cross-neutralizing activity of enterovirus 71 subgenotype C4 vaccines in healthy Chinese infants and children. PLoS One. 2013;8:e79599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M, Ami Y, Wakita T, Shimizu H. Cooperative effect of the attenuation determinants derived from poliovirus Sabin 1 strain is essential for attenuation of enterovirus 71 in the NOD/SCID mouse infection model. J Virol. 2008;82:1787-1797.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M, Nagata N, Iwata N, Ami Y, Suzaki Y, Mizuta K. An attenuated strain of enterovirus 71 belonging to genotype A showed a broad spectrum of antigenicity with attenuated neurovirulence in cynomolgus monkeys. J Virol. 2007;81:9386-9395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung WS, Bakar SA, Sekawi Z, Rosli R. DNA vaccine constructs against enterovirus 71 elicit immune response in mice. Genet Vaccines Ther. 2007;5:6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenland JR, Letvin NL. Chemical adjuvants for plasmid DNA vaccines. Vaccine. 2007;25:3731-3741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards EA, Grant CC, Huang QS, Powell KF, Croxson MC. A case of vaccine-associated paralytic poliomyelitis. J Paediatr Child Health. 2000;36:408-411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YC, Hsu JT, Huang JH, Ho MS, Ho YC. Formation of enterovirus-like particle aggregates by recombinant baculoviruses co-expressing P1 and 3CD in insect cells. Biotechnol Lett. 2003;25:919-925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung YC, Huang JH, Lai CW, et&#xa0;al. Expression, purification and characterization of enterovirus-71 virus-like particles. World J Gastroenterol. 2006;12:921-927.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung YC, Ho MS, Wu JC, et&#xa0;al. Immunization with virus-like particles of enterovirus 71 elicits potent immune responses and protects mice against lethal challenge. Vaccine. 2008;26:1855-1862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Supplementary Information on Vaccine Safety. Part 2: Background Rates of Adverse Events Following Immunization. WHO; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung WS, Bakar SA, Sekawi Z, Rosli R. DNA vaccine constructs against enterovirus 71 elicit immune response in mice. Genet Vaccines Ther. 2007;5:6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu CH, Chu C, He CC, Lin TY. Protection of neonatal mice from lethal enterovirus 71 infection by maternal immunization with attenuated Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium expressing VP1 of enterovirus 71. Microbes Infect. 2006;8:1671-1678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsou YL, Lin YW, Shao HY, et&#xa0;al. Recombinant adeno-vaccine expressing enterovirus 71-like particles against hand, foot, and mouth disease. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2015;9(4):e0003692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HF, Chang MH, Chiang BL, et&#xa0;al. Oral immunization of mice using transgenic tomato fruit expressing VP1 protein from enterovirus 71. Vaccine. 2006;24:2944-2951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo DG, Alonso S, Chow VT, Poh CL. Passive protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by neutralizing antibodies elicited by a synthetic peptide. Microbes Infect. 2007;9(11):1299-1306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JN, Wang W, Duo JY, et&#xa0;al. Combined peptides of human enterovirus 71 protect against virus infection in mice. Vaccine. 2010;28(46):7444-7451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Chou AH, Lien SP, et&#xa0;al. Identification and characterization of a cross neutralization epitope of enterovirus 71. Vaccine. 2011;29(26):4362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CN, Lin YC, Fann C, Liao NS, Shih SR, Ho MS. Protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by passive immunization with subunit VP1 vaccines and inactivated virus. Vaccine. 2001;20:895-904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, He D, Li Z, et&#xa0;al. Protection against lethal enterovirus 71 challenge in mice by a recombinant vaccine candidate containing a broadly cross-neutralizing epitope within the VP2 EF loop. Theranostics. 2014;4(5):498-513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo C, Yang J, Lei L, Qiao L, Xin J, Pan Z. Hepatitis B virus core particles containing multiple epitopes confer protection against enterovirus 71 and Coxsackievirus A16 infection in mice. Vaccine. 2017;35(52):7322-7330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aw-Yong KL, Sam IC, Koh MT, Chan YF. Immunodominant IgM and IgG epitopes recognized by antibodies induced in enterovirus A71-associated hand, foot and mouth disease patients. PLOS ONE. 2016;11(11):e0165659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lata KS, Kumar S, Vaghasia V, et&#xa0;al. Exploring leptospiral proteomes to identify potential candidates for vaccine design against leptospirosis using an immunoinformatics approach. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):1-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lata KS, Vaghasia V, Bhairappanvar S, Patel S, Das J. Vaccine design against leptospirosis using an immunoinformatic approach. Methods Mol Biol 2020;2131:173-184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L, Fan R, Sun S, et&#xa0;al. A new EV71 VP3 epitope in norovirus P particle vector displays neutralizing activity and protection in vivo in mice. Vaccine. 2015;33(48):6596-6603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Country Hub. Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance. Accessed January 21, 2021. http://www.gavi.org/country/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadhav S, Gautam M, Gairola S. Role of vaccine manufacturers in developing countries towards global healthcare by providing quality vaccines at affordable prices. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2014;20(Suppl 5):37-44.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>