<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33607859</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>100</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence of recessive infection of pathogens of hand, foot, and mouth disease in healthy people in China: A meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e24855</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e24855</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e24855</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000024855</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">To analyze the prevalence of latent infection of pathogens of hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) in Chinese healthy population and its influencing factors, so as to provide reference for the prevention and control of HFMD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic literature searching about the incidence of latent infection of HFMD was conducted in Chinese and English databases. The inclusion and exclusion criteria of the retrieved literature were established. The qualified literatures were screened and the data were extracted. The pooled rate and its 95% confidence interval was used to assess the latent infection rate of HFMD pathogens in healthy Chinese population, and subgroup analysis was conducted based on gender and age. All statistical analyses were performed using the STATA version 12.0 software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 31 literatures were included in this meta-analysis. The recessive infection rate of HFMD pathogens reported in the literature of Chinese healthy people ranged from 4.59% to 44.12%. The results of meta-analysis showed that the latent infection rate of human enteroviruses (HEVs) in healthy Chinese population was 17.5% (14.9-20.1%), among which, the latent infection rates of EV-A71, CV-A16, and other HEVs were 3.3% (2.2-4.4%), 1.7% (1.0-2.5%), and 15.1% (11.1-17.1%), respectively. The latent infection rates of HEVs in healthy men and women in China were 16.7% (12.9-20.4%) and 14.4% (10.8-18.0%), respectively. The latent infection rates of HEVs in the healthy population aged 0 to 5&#x200a;years and over 5&#x200a;years were 24.4% (20.4-28.5%) and 9.4% (6.5-12.2%), respectively. Meta regression showed that the factors affecting the latent infection rate of HEVs in Chinese healthy population included sampling period, sampling area, and study population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The latent infection rate of HEVs is high in healthy people in China, but it is mainly caused by other enteroviruses. The latent infection rate of HEVs in male was higher than that of female and was greater in people aged 0 to 5 than that of aged over 5&#x200a;years. Limited by the quantity and quality of the included studies, more high-quality studies are needed for further verification in the future.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Jie</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nantong Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Nantong Hospital Affiliated to Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Jianshe Road, Chongchuan district, Nantong.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Niu</LastName><ForeName>Xiu-De</ForeName><Initials>XD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuxi Huishan District People's Hospital, Wuxi, Jiangsu Province.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Ya-Qing</ForeName><Initials>YQ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LongHua Hospital of Shanghai University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shanghai.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qian</LastName><ForeName>Zheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nantong Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Nantong Hospital Affiliated to Nanjing University of Chinese Medicine, Jianshe Road, Chongchuan district, Nantong.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Bao-Lin</ForeName><Initials>BL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">1234-4566-6667-7888</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NanJing Pukou Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, No. 18 GongYuan North Road, Jiangpu Street, Pukou District, Nanjing, 211800, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058345" MajorTopicYN="N">Asymptomatic Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016022" MajorTopicYN="N">Case-Control Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000079803" MajorTopicYN="N">Data Management</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064368" MajorTopicYN="N">Healthy Volunteers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000085343" MajorTopicYN="N">Latent Infection</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33607859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7899851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000024855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202102190-00098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xing W, Liao Q, Viboud C, et al. . Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China, 2008&#x2013;12: an epidemiological study. Lancet Infect Dis 2014;14:308&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24485991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, et al. . Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect Dis 2010;10:778&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Wei H, Wu S, et al. . Epidemiological and etiological characteristics of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Henan, China, 2008&#x2013;2013. Sci Rep 2015;5:8904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4354091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25754970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CC, Jiang DS, Wu HM, et al. . A dynamic model for the outbreaks of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Taiwan. Epidemiol Infect 2016;144:1500&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4823833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26567705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng H, Lu J, Zheng H, et al. . The epidemiological study of Coxsackievirus A6 revealing hand, foot and mouth disease epidemic patterns in Guangdong, China. Sci Rep 2015;5:10550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4440203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25993899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang JC, Ding R, Du YG, et al. . Research on the aetiology of suspected enterovirus infected patients in Xuzhou district in 2009. Zhonghua Shi Yan He Lin Chuang Bing Du Xue Za Zhi 2011;25:106&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21863630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Z, Lawrence WR, Zhang W, et al. . Bayesian spatiotemporal analysis for association of environmental factors with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Guangdong, China. Sci Rep 2018;8:15147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6181968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30310172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y, Wang S, Zhang L, et al. . Risk factors of severe hand, foot and mouth disease: a meta-analysis. Scand J Infect Dis 2014;46:515&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musuuza JS, Guru PK, O&#x2019;Horo JC, et al. . The impact of chlorhexidine bathing on hospital-acquired bloodstream infections: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Infect Dis 2019;19:416&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6518712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31088521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begg CB, Berlin JA. Publication bias and dissemination of clinical research. J Natl Cancer Inst 1989;81:107&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2642556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Davey Smith G, Schneider M, et al. . Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ 1997;315:629&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang HK, Yuan DK, Huang Y, et al. . Survey on epidemic situation of recessive infection of HFMD in healthy adults and children in Dongguan. Chin J Health Lab Technol 2010;20:1519&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang N, Tan Y, Bi FY, et al. . In apparent infection of enteroviruses in 50 children in Nanning. Dis Surveillance 2010;25:682&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin FQ, Shi ZB. The infection of entericvirus in healthy population and the population in intimate contact with the cases of HFMD in Lanshan District. J Shandong Med Coll 2011;33:430&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CH. Investigation and analysis on the rate of poisoning among healthy people and close contacts of HFMD in Jining city. J Prev Rehabil 2011;13:377&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng HL, Wang XY, Ma CF, et al. . Pathogenic and epidemiological analysis of 1020 cases of hand foot and mouth disease and 207 healthy children. Shaanxi Med J 2011;40:1226&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang WG, Ding SJ, Gao ZJ, et al. . Investigation of the prevalence of enterovirus carriers among healthy children and their guardians during HFMD outbreaks. J Pathog Biol 2011;6:857&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo LF, Wang L, Ren Y, et al. . Investigation of latent infection of hand foot and mouth disease in healthy population in Spring and Autumn in Shenzhen. J Mod Med Health 2012;28:1916&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Y, Wang DL, Zeng YL, et al. . Investigation of the HFMD carrier status of healthy adults and children in a district of Shenzhen, 2011. J Trop Med 2012;12:1025&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceng HR, Zhang YH, Sun LM, et al. . Investigation on the carrying rate of enterovirus in healthy population and close contacts of HFMD cases. Chin J Health Lab Technol 2012;22:1158&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Lu H, Tian HF, et al. . Analysis of enterovirus-carrying situation in healthy children in Zanhuang county of Shijiazhuang. J Chin Matern Child Health 2012;27:1661&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang DL, Yao W, Feng B, et al. . Investigation on in-apparent infection situation of HFMD in nursery schools in a district of Shenzhen, 2010. Chin J Health Lab Technol 2012;22: 885&#x2013;857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y, Zeng JR, Wei HZ, et al. . Investigation and research on the carrying rate of EV71 and CoxA16 of kindergarten children. China Foreign Med Treat 2012;17:1&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu WD, Dai L, Shi J. Survey on epidemic situation of recessive infection of HFMD in healthy children and adults in Zhengzhou. Chin J Health Lab Technol 2012;22:2209&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi QH, Zhang X, Tang FY, et al. . Epidemical analysis of hand-foot-mouth disease among healthy children in kindergartens of Taizhou. J Prev Med Inf 2013;29:533&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen FY. Comparison of enterovirus type between common cases of HFMD and healthy children HFMD in Xingtai City. Hebei Med J 2013;35:2190&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang XA, Wang HY, Ding SJ, et al. . Prevalence of enteroviruses in children with and without hand, foot, and mouth disease in China. BMC Infect Dis 2013;13:606.doi: 10. 1186/1471-2334-13-606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3890605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24370001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W, Xu WB, Chen L, et al. . Molecular identification and analysis of human enteroviruses isolated from healthy children in Shenzhen, China from 2010 to 2011. PLoS One 2013;8:e64889.doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0064889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3675095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23762262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Zhang XP, Bao XB. Investigation and analysis on the inapparent infection of HFMD pathogens in healthy population in Anyang in 2010 and 2011. Chin J Health Lab Technol 2013;23:2173&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai MS, Ren Y. Investigation on latent infection of Hand foot and mouth disease in healthy population in Shenzhen in 2012. Chin J Health Inspect 2013;23:2355&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu FR, Liu Q, Wang X, et al. . Sub-clinical infection investigation and its risk factors analysis of hand&#x2013;foot&#x2013;mouth disease on healthy kindergarten children. J Trop Med 2014;14:246&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun BC, Gao J, Chen D, et al. . Study on the recessive infection of HFMD virus in children. Pract Prev Med 2014;21:914&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou ZY, Niu XY. Investigation of latent infection of Hand foot and mouth disease in healthy preschool children and analysis of risk factors. J China Prescription Drug 2015;14:117&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X, You S, Qiu Q, et al. . Analysis on epidemic situation of recessive infection of HFMD in healthy population in Pingxiang. Mod Prev Med 2015;42:4178&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L. Analysis of detection results of Hand foot and mouth disease in Linyi city and research on prevention and control counter measures. Shandong Univ 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao W, Yang M, Xiang D, et al. . Study on the status of the recessive infection of hand-foot-mouth disease virus in healthy children and the family aggregation of parent and children. J Med Pest Control 2016;32:754&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HQ, Wu B, Lang ZK, et al. . Investigation on the carrying status of hand-foot-mouth disease pathogens among children in kindergartens in Wanzhou district of Chongqing. Chin J Health Lab Technol 2016;26:582&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Fu X, Jiang L, et al. . Prevalence of enteroviruses in healthy populations and excretion of pathogens in patients with hand, foot, and mouth disease in a highly endemic area of southwest China. PLoS One 2017;12:e0181234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5509318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28704524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan W, Cheng XW, Liu YQ, et al. . Subclinical infection of hand-foot-mouth disease in healthy kindergarten children and influencing factors. J Prev Med Inf 2018;34:1063&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y, Xia L, Yuan J. Investigation on inapparent infection status of hand&#x2013;foot&#x2013;mouth disease in Xi&#x2019;an City of Shaanxi province. J Clin Med Pract 2019;23:45&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh WM, Bogich T, Siegel K, et al. . The epidemiology of hand, foot and mouth disease in Asia: a systematic review and analysis. Pediatr Infect Dis J 2016;35:e285&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5130063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27273688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson SG, Higgins JP. How should meta-regression analyses be undertaken and interpreted? Stat Med 2002;21:1559&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>