<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">15691948</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Adhesion-aggregation and inactivation of poliovirus 1 in groundwater stored in a hydrophobic container.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>912</StartPage><EndPage>920</EndPage><MedlinePgn>912-20</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Viral inactivation and adhesion-aggregation in water are often studied as separate phenomena. When the focus is placed on viral adhesion-aggregation, inactivation is neglected because the phenomena under investigation occur over a short period measured in days. When viral inactivation is studied, adhesion-aggregation phenomena are considered to be negligible because viral survival is traced over several days or months. In the present work, we took a global approach, examining the relative contributions of each of these processes in a complex system composed of groundwater, Poliovirus 1, and a hydrophobic container (polypropylene) maintained in a dark environment at 20 degrees C. We demonstrated that infectious viral load fell off 2.8 log(10) during the first 20 days. During this time, adhesion was far from negligible because it accounted for most of the decline, 1.5 log(10). Adhesion was undoubtedly favored by the presence of divalent ions in the groundwater. After 20 days, aggregation may also have been the cause of 0.66 to 0.92 log(10) of viral loss. Finally, viral inactivation was quantitatively the lowest phenomena because it only explained 0.38 to 0.64 log(10) of the viral loss. This study thus clearly demonstrated that estimates of viral survival in a given system must always take into account adhesion-aggregation phenomena which may be responsible for the majority of viral loss in the aqueous phase. Adhesion and aggregation are reversible processes which may lead to an underestimation of viral load in certain studies.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gassilloud</LastName><ForeName>Beno&#xee;t</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire de Chimie Physique et Microbiologie pour l'Environnement, UMR 7564 CNRS/Universit&#xe9; Henri Poincar&#xe9;-Nancy I, Facult&#xe9; de pharmacie, 5 rue Albert Lebrun, 54001 Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gantzer</LastName><ForeName>Christophe</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011126">Polypropylenes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002448" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Adhesion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005618" MajorTopicYN="N">Fresh Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057927" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrophobic and Hydrophilic Interactions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017955" MajorTopicYN="N">Poliovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="Y">growth &amp; development</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011126" MajorTopicYN="N">Polypropylenes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013499" MajorTopicYN="N">Surface Properties</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D038301" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Inactivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15691948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC546705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.2.912-920.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">71/2/912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alvarez, M. E., M. Aguilar, A. Fountain, N. Gonzalez, O. Rascon, and D. Saenz. 2000. Inactivation of MS-2 and poliovirus in groundwater. Can. J. Microbiol. 46:159-165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10721484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babich, H. B., and G. Stotzky. 1980. Reduction in inactivation rates of bacteriophages by clay minerals in lake water. Water Res. 14:185-187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bales, R. C., S. R. Hinkle, T. W. Kroeger, K. Stocking, and C. P. Gerba. 1991. Bacteriophage adsorption during transport through porous media: chemical perturbations and reversibility. Environ. Sci. Technol. 25:2088-2095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bixby, R. L., and D. J. O'Brien. 1979. Influence of fulvic acid on bacteriophage adsorption and complexation in soil. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 38:840-845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">396884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biziagos, E., J. Passagot, J.-M. Crance, and R. Deloince. 1988. Long-term survival of hepatitis A virus and poliovirus type 1 in mineral water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 54:2705-2710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC204359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2850763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borrego, J. J., R. Cornax, D. R. Preston, S. R. Farrah, B. McElhaney, and G. Bitton. 1991. Development and application of new positively charged filters for recovery of bacteriophages from water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 57:1218-1222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2059044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chattopadhyay, D., S. Chattopadhyay, W. G. Lyon, and J. T. Wilson. 2002. Effect of surfactants on the survival and sorption of viruses. Environ. Sci. Technol. 36:4017-4024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12380069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowd, S. E., S. D. Pillai, S. Wang, and M. Y. Corapcioglu. 1998. Delineating the specific influence of virus isoelectric point and size on virus adsorption and transport through sandy soils. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 64:405-410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC106058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9464373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enriquez, C. E., C. J. Hurst, and C. P. Gerba. 1995. Survival of the enteric adenoviruses 40 and 41 in tap, sea, and waste water. Water Res. 29:2548-2553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floyd, R., and D. G. Sharp. 1977. Aggregation of poliovirus and reovirus by dilution in water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 33:159-167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC170617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floyd, R., and D. G. Sharp. 1978. Viral aggregation: effects of salts on the aggregation of poliovirus and reovirus at low pH. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 35:1084-1094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC242989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floyd, R., and D. G. Sharp. 1979. Viral aggregation: buffer effects in the aggregation of poliovirus and reovirus at low and high pH. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 38:395-401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">43706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujioka, R. S., P. C. Loh, and L. S. Lau. 1980. Survival of human enteroviruses in the Hawaiian ocean environment: evidence for virus-inactivating microorganisms. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 39:1105-1110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC291490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6250472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujioka, R. S., and B. S. Yoneyama. 2002. Sunlight inactivation of human enteric viruses and fecal bacteria. Water Sci. Technol. 46:291-295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12523768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gantzer, C., A. Maul, Y. Levi, and L. Schwartzbrod. 1998. Fate of the genome and infectious units of coxsackie B3 virus in phosphate buffered saline. Water Res. 32:1329-1333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gassilloud, B., L. Schwartzbrod, and C. Gantzer. 2003. Presence of viral genomes in mineral water: a sufficient condition to assume infectious risk? Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 69:3965-3969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC165182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12839768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba, C. P. 1984. Applied and theoretical aspects of virus adsorption to surfaces. Adv. Appl. Microbiol. 30:133-168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6099689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst, C. J., W. H. Benton, and K. A. McClellan. 1989. Thermal and water source effects upon the stability of enteroviruses in surface freshwater. Can. J. Microbiol. 35:474-480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2545321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, C. R., M. R. Adams, P. A. Zhdan, and A. H. L. Chamberlain. 1999. The role of surface physicochemical properties in determining the distribution of the autochthonous microflora in mineral water bottles. J. Appl. Microbiol. 86:917-927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10389242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutz, S. M., and C. P. Gerba. 1988. Comparison of virus survival in freshwater sources. Water Sci. Technol. 20:467-471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaBelle, R. L., and C. P. Gerba. 1979. Influence of pH, salinity, and organic matter on the adsorption of enteric viruses to estuarine sediments. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 38:93-101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaBelle, R. L., and C. P. Gerba. 1982. Investigations into the protective effect of estuarine sediment on virus survival. Water Res. 16:469-478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lance, J. C., and C. P. Gerba. 1984. Effect of ionic composition of suspending solution on virus adsorption by a soil column. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 47:484-488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC239707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16346487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipson, S. M., and G. Stotzky. 1984. Effect of proteins on reovirus adsorption to clay minerals. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 48:525-530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC241560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6497370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loveland, J. P., J. N. Ryan, G. L. Amy, and R. W. Harvey. 1996. The reversibility of virus attachment to mineral surfaces. Colloids Surf. 107:205-221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukasik, J., T. M. Scott, D. Andryshak, and S. R. Farrah. 2000. Influence of salts on virus adsorption to microporous filters. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 66:2914-2920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lytle, D. C., and L. B. Routson. 1995. Minimized virus binding for tests of barrier materials. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 61:643-649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7574603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maul, A. 1991. Aspects statistiques des methodes de quantification en virologie, p. 143-171. In L. Schwartzbrod (ed.), Virologie des milieux hydriques. Lavoisier, Paris, France.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore, R. S., D. H. Taylor, L. S. Sturman, M. M. Reddy, and G. W. Fuhs. 1981. Poliovirus adsorption by 34 minerals and soils. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 42:963-975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC244141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6274259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuanualsuwan, S., and D. O. Cliver. 2002. Pretreatment to avoid positive RT-PCR results with inactivated viruses. J. Virol. Methods 104:217-225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12088831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Official Journal of the European Communities. 1980. Council directive 80/777/EEC of 15 July 1980 on the approximation of the laws of the member states relating to the exploitation and marketing of natural mineral waters. Annex III. Indications and criteria laid down in article 9. Off. J. Eur. Commun. 229:1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pancorbo, O. C., B. G. Evanshen, W. F. Campbell, S. Lambert, S. K. Curtis, and T. W. Woolley. 1987. Infectivity and antigenicity reduction rates of human rotavirus strain Wa in fresh waters. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 53:1803-1811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC204004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2821902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powelson, D. K., J. R. Simpson, and C. P. Gerba. 1991. Effects of organic matter on virus transport in unsaturated flow. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 57:2192-2196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC183549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1768089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preston, D. R., T. V. Vasudevan, G. Bitton, S. R. Farrah, and J.-L. Morel. 1988. Novel approach for modifying micoporous filters for virus concentration from water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 54:1325-1329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC202657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2843091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quignon, F., and L. Schwartzbrod. 1995. Influence of salts and montmorillonite upon heat inactivation of poliovirus in sterile water. Water Sci. Technol. 31:177-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman, J. A., S. B. Grant, T. M. Olson, J. M. Adkins, J. L. Jackson, M. S. Castillo, and W. A. Yanko. 1999. Physicochemical mechanisms responsible for the filtration and mobilization of a filamentous bacteriophage in quartz sand. Water Res. 33:43-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp, D. G., R. Floyd, and J. D. Johnson. 1975. Nature of the surviving plaque-forming unit of reovirus in water containing bromine. Appl. Microbiol. 29:94-101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC186917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1167388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey, M. D., and A. R. Hickey. 1985. Effects of humic and fulvic acids on poliovirus concentration from water by microporous filtration. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 49:259-264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC238390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2984989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey, M. D., D. A. Battigelli, G. A. Shin, and S. Newland. 1998. RT-PCR amplification detects inactivated viruses in water and wastewater. Water Sci. Technol. 38:91-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, D. H., R. S. Moore, and L. S. Sturman. 1981. Influence of pH and electrolyte composition on adsorption of poliovirus by soils and minerals. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 42:976-984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC244142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6274260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, S. S., M. Flury, M. V. Yates, and W. A. Jury. 1998. Role of the air-water-solid interface in bacteriophage sorption experiments. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 64:304-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC124709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9435082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, S. S., and M. V. Yates. 1999. Bacteriophage inactivation at the air-water-solid interface in dynamic batch systems. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 65:1186-1190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC91162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10049881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Totsuka, A., K. Ohtaki, and I. Tagaya. 1978. Aggregation of enterovirus small plaque variants and polioviruses under low ionic strength conditions. J. Gen. Virol. 38:519-533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">204734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voorthuizen, E. M., N. J. Ashbolt, and A. I. Sch&#xe4;fer. 2001. Role of hydrophobic and electrostatic interactions for initial enteric virus retention by MF membranes. J. Membr. Sci. 194:69-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward, R. L., and P. E. Winston. 1985. Development of methods to measure virus inactivation in fresh waters. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 50:1144-1148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC238714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3004328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward, R. L., D. R. Knowlton, and P. E. Winston. 1986. Mechanism of inactivation of enteric viruses in fresh water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 52:450-459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC203555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3021056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yates, M. V., C. P. Gerba, and L. M. Kelley. 1985. Virus persistence in groundwater. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 49:778-781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC238444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4004211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang, J., and Y. Jin. 2003. Virus retention and transport through Al-oxide coated sand columns: effects of ionic strength and composition. J. Contam. Hydrol. 60:193-209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12504359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>