<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">17445254</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2007</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1479-0556</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><PubDate><Year>2007</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Genetic vaccines and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Genet Vaccines Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>DNA vaccine constructs against enterovirus 71 elicit immune response in mice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6</StartPage><MedlinePgn>6</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is a major causative viral agent responsible for large outbreaks of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD), a common rash illness in children and infants. There is no effective antiviral treatment for severe EV71 infections and no vaccine is available. The objectives of this study were to design and construct a DNA vaccine against Enterovirus 71 using the viral capsid protein (VP1) gene of EV71 and to verify the functionality of the DNA vaccine in vitro and in vivo.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The VP1 gene of EV71 from two local outbreak isolates were amplified using PCR and then inserted into a eukaryotic expression vector, pVAX1. The 3.9 kb recombinant constructs were transformed into competent E. coli cells and the positive clones were screened and selected using PCR analysis, restriction digestion analysis and DNA sequencing. The constructs were then tested for protein expression in Vero cells. Subsequently, in the in vivo studies, female Balb/c mice were immunized with the DNA vaccine constructs. Enzyme Linked Immunosorbent Assay (ELISA) and virus neutralizing assay were performed to detect the presence of anti-VP1 IgG in mice and its neutralizing effect against the EV71.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The pVAX1 vector was successfully cloned with the VP1 gene from each of the isolate (S2/86/1 and 410/4) in the correct orientation and in-frame. The DNA vaccine constructs with the VP1 gene were shown to be expressed in a cell-free in vitro expression system. The VP1 protein was successfully expressed in the mammalian cell line and was detected using RT-PCR, Indirect Immunofluorescence Assay (IFA) and western blotting. The anti-VP1 IgG levels in mice immunized with the DNA vaccine constructs increased after the first booster but declined following the second booster. The anti-VP1 IgG in the mice immunized with the DNA vaccine constructs exhibited neutralising activity against EV71.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The promising results obtained in the present study have prompted further testing to improve the expression and immunogenicity of this potential EV71 DNA vaccine.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tung</LastName><ForeName>Wong Siew</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept of Human Growth and Development, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Universiti Putra Malaysia, 43400 Serdang, Selangor, Malaysia. siewtung77@hotmail.com</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bakar</LastName><ForeName>Sazaly Abu</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sekawi</LastName><ForeName>Zamberi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosli</LastName><ForeName>Rozita</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2007</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Genet Vaccines Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101178414</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1479-0556</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2006</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2007</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2007</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2007</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2007</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2007</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17445254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3225814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1479-0556-5-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1479-0556-5-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Muir P, Kammerer U, Korn K, Mulders MN, Poyry T, Weissbrich B, Kandolf R, Cleator GM, van Loon AM. Molecular typing of enteroviruses: current status and future requirements. Clin Microbiol Rev. 1998;11:202&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC121380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9457433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rueckert RR. In: Virology. Fields BN, Knipe DM, editor. Lippincott-Raven, New York; 1990. Picornaviruses and their replication; pp. 507&#x2013;548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander JP, Baden L, Pallansch MA, Anderson LJ. Enterovirus infections and neurologic disease &#x2013; United States, 1977&#x2013;91. J Infect Dis. 1994;169:905&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8133108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick JL. Enterovirus type 71 infections: a variedclinical pattern sometimes mimicking paralytic poliomyelitis. Rev Infect Dis. 1984;6(Suppl):S387&#x2013;S390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt NJ, Lennette EH, Ho HH. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J Infect Dis. 1974;129:304&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov M, Voroshilova M, Shindarov L, Lavrova L, Gracheva L, Koroleva G, Vasilenko S, Brodvarova I, Nikolova M, Gyurova S, Gacheva M, Mitov G, Ninov N, Tsylka E, Robinson I, Frolova M, Bashkirtsev V, Martiyanova L, Rodin V. Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch Virol. 1979;60:329&#x2013;340. doi: 10.1007/BF01317504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01317504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg J, Lycke E, Ahlfors K, Johnsson T, Wolontis S, von Zeipel G. New enterovirus type associated with aseptic meningitis and/or hand, foot and mouth disease. Lancet. 1974;2:112. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(74)91684-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(74)91684-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4136956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert GL, Dickson KE, Waters MJ, Kennett ML, Land SA, Sneddon M. Outbreak of enterovirus 71 in Victoria, Australia, with a high incidence of neurologic involvement. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1988;7:484&#x2013;488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2841639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy G, Takatsy S, Kukan E, Mihaly I, Domok I. Virological diagnosis of enterovirus 71 infections: Experiences gained during an epidemic of acute CNS diseases in Hungary in 1978. Arch Virol. 1982;71:217&#x2013;227. doi: 10.1007/BF01314873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01314873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6285858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuda GM, Chang WK, Yeung CY, Tang PS. Monoplegiacaused by enterovirus 71 infection: an outbreak in Hong Kong. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1987;6:206&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3562141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum LCS, Wong KT, Lam SK, Chua KB, Goh AYT. Neurogenic pulmonary oedema and enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. Lancet. 1998;352:1391. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(05)60789-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(05)60789-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9802304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar S, Chee HY, Al-Kobaisi MF, Xiaoshan J, Chua KB, Lam SK. Identification of enterovirus 71 isolates from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease with fatal cases of encephalomyelitis in Malaysia. Virus Res. 1999;61:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/S0168-1702(99)00019-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0168-1702(99)00019-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10426204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Huang YC, Lin TY. Fulminant neurogenic pulmonary oedema with hand, foot and mouth disease. Lancet. 1998;352:367&#x2013;368. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(98)24031-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(98)24031-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9717926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. An Overview of the evolution of enterovirus71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2002;26:91&#x2013;107. doi: 10.1111/j.1574-6976.2002.tb00601.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1574-6976.2002.tb00601.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shindarov LM, Chumakov MP, Voroshilova MK, Bojinov S, Vasilenko SM, Kirov ID, Kamenov E, Leshchinskaya EV, Mitov G, Robinson IA, Sivchev S, Staikov S. Epidemiological, clinical and pathomorphological characteristics of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease caused by enterovirus 71. J Hyg Epidemiol Microbiol Immunol. 1979;23:284&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">231067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CN, Lin YC, Cathy Y, Liao NS, Shih SR, Ho MS. Protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by passive immunization with subunit VP1 vaccines and inactivated virus. Vaccine. 2002;20:895&#x2013;904. doi: 10.1016/S0264-410X(01)00385-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0264-410X(01)00385-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao HT, Hung KL. Neurologic involvement in an outbreakof enterovirus 71 infection: A hospital-based study. Acta Paediatr Taiwan. 2001;42:27&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11270182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu CK, Chen CC, Chen CL, Wang JR, Liu CC, Yan JJ, Su IJ. Neutralizing antibody provided protection against Enterovirus type 71 lethal challenge in neonatal mice. J Biomed Sci. 2000;7:523&#x2013;528. doi: 10.1007/BF02253368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02253368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11060501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan YF, AbuBakar S. Enterovirus 71 infection induces apoptosis in Vero cells. Malaysian J Pathol. 2003;25(1):29&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16196375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ertl PF, Thomsen LL. Technical issues in construction of nucleic acid vaccines. Methods. 2003;31:199&#x2013;206. doi: 10.1016/S1046-2023(03)00134-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1046-2023(03)00134-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14511952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery DL, Ulmer JB, Donnely JJ, Liu MA. DNAVaccines. Pharmacol Ther. 1997;74(2):195&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1016/S0163-7258(97)82003-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0163-7258(97)82003-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9336022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babiuk LA, Pontarollo R, Babiuk S, Loehr B, van Drunen Littel-vanden Hurk S. Induction of immune responses by DNA vaccines in large animals. Vaccine. 2003;21:649&#x2013;658. doi: 10.1016/S0264-410X(02)00574-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0264-410X(02)00574-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12531334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts GBS, Boyd JF. The histopathology of enterovirus infections in new-born mice. J Infect. 1987;15:45&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1016/S0163-4453(87)91426-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0163-4453(87)91426-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2822811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manthorpe M, Comefert-Jensen F, Hartikka J, Felgner J, Rundell A, Margalith M, Dwarki V. Gene therapy by intramuscular injection of plasmid DNA: studies on firefly luciferase gene expression in mice. Hum Gene Ther. 1993;4:419&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8399489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanghe A, Denis O, Lamvrecht B, Motte V, van den Berg T, Huygen K. Tuberculosis DNA vaccine encoding Ag85A is immunogenic and protective when administered by intramuscular needle injection but not by epidermal gene gun bombardment. Infect Immun. 2000;68:3854&#x2013;3860. doi: 10.1128/IAI.68.7.3854-3860.2000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.68.7.3854-3860.2000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC101658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10858194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur R, Sachdeva G, Vrati S. Plasmid DNA immunizationagainst Japanese Encephalitis Virus: Immunogenicity of membrane-anchored and secretory envelope protein. J Infect Dis. 2002;185:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1086/338015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/338015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11756975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caselli E, Boni M, Di Luca D, Salvatori D, Vita A, Cassai E. A combined bovine herpesvirus 1 gB-gD DNA vaccine induces immune response in mice. Comp Immunol Microbiol Infect Dis. 2005;28:155&#x2013;166. doi: 10.1016/j.cimid.2004.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cimid.2004.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15582691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H, Liu Z, Sun S, Bao H, Chen Y, Liu X, Xie Q. Immune response in guinea pigs vaccinated with DNA vaccine of foot-and-mouth disease virus O/China99. Vaccine. 2005;23:3236&#x2013;3242. doi: 10.1016/j.vaccine.2004.03.074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2004.03.074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15837227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodmell DL, Parnell MJ, Weyhrich JT, Ewalt LC. Canine rabies DNA vaccination: a single-dose intradermal injection into ear pinnae elicits elevated and persistent levels of neutralizing antibody. Vaccine. 2003;21:3998&#x2013;4002. doi: 10.1016/S0264-410X(03)00297-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0264-410X(03)00297-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12922136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horie H, Koike S, Kurata T, Sato-Yoshida Y, Ise I, Ota Y, Abe S, Hioke K, Kato H, Taya C, Nomura T, Hashizume S, Yonekawa H, Nomoto A. Transgenic mice carrying the human poliovirus receptor: new animal model for the study of poliovirus neurovirulence. J Virol. 1994;68:681&#x2013;688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC236503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8289371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>