<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25356130</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1940-5901</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of clinical and experimental medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Clin Exp Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>IL-6, IL-10 and IL-13 are associated with pathogenesis in children with Enterovirus 71 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2718</StartPage><EndPage>2723</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2718-23</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>In the present study, the aim was to reveal the relationship of serum IL-6, IL-10 and IL-13 levels in patient with Enterovirus 71 (EV71) infection. To elucidate the role of immune mechanisms in the pathogenesis of Hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD), we analyzed the cytokine of 112 EV71-infected patients. A significant elevation of serum (interleukin) IL-6, IL-10 and IL-13 levels in patients with EV71 infection compare with Un-EV71 infection HFMD patient and Healthy individuals. The production of inflammatory cytokines was increased with disease clinical stage. In addition, the immunological consequences of these cytokine in patient with EV71 infection showed a downward trend after cure. These data suggested that EV71 infection significantly increased the release of circulating IL-6, IL-10 and IL-13. The systemic inflammatory response may play an important role in the pathogenesis of HFMD. Moreover, this study may be designed to evaluate the potential therapeutic of medicine in the treatment of patients with EV71 infection.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zhifeng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Dongguan People's Hospital Dongguan 523059, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ruiqin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Dongguan People's Hospital Dongguan 523059, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Zhichao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Dongguan People's Hospital Dongguan 523059, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Guoqiang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Dongguan People's Hospital Dongguan 523059, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Qingchun</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Dongguan People's Hospital Dongguan 523059, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Jincheng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Medical Molecular Diagnostics, Guandong Medical College Dongguan 523808, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Clin Exp Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101471010</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1940-5901</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hand food mouth disease (HFMD)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurologic pulmonary edema</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pro-inflammatory</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25356130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4211780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Robinson CR, Doane FW, Rhodes AJ. Report of an outbreak of febrile illness with pharyngeal lesions and exanthem: Toronto, summer 1957; isolation of group A Coxsackie virus. Can Med Assoc J. 1958;79:615&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1830188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13585281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, Zhu S, Guo X, Wang J, Wang D, Yan D, Tan X, Tang L, Zhu H, Yang Z, Jiang X, Ji Y, Zhang Y, Xu W. Retrospective seroepidemiology indicated that human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 circulated wildly in central and southern China before large-scale outbreaks from 2008. Virol J. 2010;7:300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2989968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21050463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Lin TY, Huang YC, Tsao KC, Shih SR, Kuo ML, Ning HC, Chung PW, Kang CM. Comparison of enterovirus 71 and coxsackie-virus A16 clinical illnesses during the Taiwan enterovirus epidemic, 1998. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1999;18:1092&#x2013;1096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10608631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong CY, Chan KP, Shah VA, Ng WY, Lau G, Teo TE, Lai SH, Ling AE. Hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore: a comparison of fatal and non-fatal cases. Acta Paediatr. 2003;92:1163&#x2013;1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14632332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2002;26:91&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SW, Lee YP, Hung YT, Lin CH, Chuang JI, Lei HY, Su IJ, Yu CK. Exogenous interleukin-6, interleukin-13, and interferon-&#x3b3; provoke pulmonary abnormality with mild edema in enterovirus 71-infected mice. Respir Res. 2011;12:147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3223501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22054060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khong WX, Foo DG, Trasti SL, Tan EL, Alonso S. Sustained high levels of interleukin-6 contribute to the pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 in a neonate mouse model. J Virol. 2011;85:3067&#x2013;3076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3067852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21228224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolan MA, Craig ME, Lahra MM, Rawlinson WD, Prager PC, Williams GD, Bye AM, Andrews PI. Survival after pulmonary edema due to enterovirus 71 encephalitis. Neurology. 2003;60:1651&#x2013;1656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12771257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Liu H, Wang L, Yang F, Hu Y, Ren X, Li G, Yang Y, Sun S, Li Y, Chen X, Li X, Jin Q. Comparative study of the cytokine/chemokine response in children with differing disease severity in enterovirus 71-induced hand, foot, and mouth disease. PLoS One. 2013;8:e67430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3696071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23840697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J, Wang Y, Gan X, Song J, Sun P, Dong XP. Serum cytokine profiles of children with human enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease. J Med Virol. 2014;86:1377&#x2013;1385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24619468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enk AH, Angeloni VL, Udey MC, Katz SI. Inhibition of Langerhans cell antigen-presenting function by IL-10: a role for IL-10 in induction of tolerance. J Immunol. 1993;151:2390&#x2013;2398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8103065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Huang KJ, Wu JM, Wang JR, Yu CK, Su IJ, Liu CC. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J Infect Dis. 2003;188:564&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackburn SD, Wherry EJ. IL-10, T cell exhaustion and viral persistence. Trends Microbiol. 2007;15:143&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17336072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassatella MA, Meda L, Bonora S, Ceska M, Constantin G. Interleukin-10 (IL-10) inhibits the release of proinflammatory cytokines from human polymorphonuclear leukocytes: evidence for an autocrine role of tumor necrosis factor and IL-1 beta in mediating the production of IL-8 triggered by lipopolysaccharide. J Exp Med. 1993;178:2207&#x2013;2211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2191270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8245792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minty A, Chalon P, Derocq JM, Dumont X, Guillemot JC, Kaghad M, Labit C, Leplatois P, Liauzun P, Miloux B. Interleukin-13 is a new human lymphokine regulating inflammatory and immune responses. Nature. 1993;362:248&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8096327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Vries JE. The role of IL-13 and its receptor in allergy and inflammatory responses. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 1998;102:165&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9723655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuperman DA, Huang X, Koth LL, Chang GH, Dolganov GM, Zhu Z, Elias JA, Sheppard D, Erle DJ. Direct effects of interleukin-13 on epithelial cells cause airway hyperreactivity and mucus overproduction in asthma. Nat Med. 2002;8:885&#x2013;889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12091879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>