<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16521221</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2006</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1007-9327</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2006</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of gastroenterology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Expression, purification and characterization of enterovirus-71 virus-like particles.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>921</StartPage><EndPage>927</EndPage><MedlinePgn>921-7</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Enterovirus 71 (EV71) has been implicated as the etiological agent responsible for the recent outbreaks of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with severe neurological diseases in the Asia-Pacific region.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The assembly process was hypothesized to occur via an orchestrated proteolytic processing of the P1 precursor by the viral protease 3CD. To test this hypothesis, we constructed 3 recombinant baculoviruses: Bac-P1 expressing P1; Bac-3CD expressing 3CD; and Bac-P1-3CD co-expressing P1 and 3CD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Both single infection by Bac-P1-3CD and co-infection by Bac-P1 and Bac-3CD resulted in correct cleavage of P1 to yield individual proteins VP0, VP1 and VP3, while the former approach yielded higher VLP production. In the cells, the structural proteins self-assembled into clusters of virus-like particles (VLP) resembling the authentic EV71 particle aggregates. After ultracentrifugation purification, the dispersed VLPs were indistinguishable from the authentic virus in size, appearance, composition and surface epitopes, as determined by SDS-PAGE, Western blot, transmission electron microscopy and immunogold labeling.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our data, for the first time, suggest that in insect cells EV71 structural proteins adopt a processing and assembly pathway similar to poliovirus assembly. The preservation of particle morphology and composition suggest that the VLP may be a valuable vaccine candidate to prevent EV71 epidemics.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chung</LastName><ForeName>Yao-Chi</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, National Tsing Hua University, Hsinchu 300, Taiwan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Jen-Huang</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Chia-Wei</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheng</LastName><ForeName>Heng-Chun</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shih</LastName><ForeName>Shin-Ru</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ho</LastName><ForeName>Mei-Shang</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Chen</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Gastroenterol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1007-9327</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014764">Viral Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004196" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Outbreaks</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="Y">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018411" MajorTopicYN="N">Spodoptera</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014764" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2006</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2006</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2006</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2006</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16521221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4066158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v12.i6.921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2002;26:91&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov M, Voroshilova M, Shindarov L, Lavrova I, Gracheva L, Koroleva G, Vasilenko S, Brodvarova I, Nikolova M, Gyurova S, et al. Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch Virol. 1979;60:329&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg J, Lycke E, Ahlfors K, Johnsson T, Wolontis S, von Zeipel G. Letter: New enterovirus type associated with epidemic of aseptic meningitis and-or hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet. 1974;2:112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4136956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert GL, Dickson KE, Waters MJ, Kennett ML, Land SA, Sneddon M. Outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Victoria, Australia, with a high incidence of neurologic involvement. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1988;7:484&#x2013;488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2841639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy G, Tak&#xe1;tsy S, Kuk&#xe1;n E, Mih&#xe1;ly I, D&#xf6;m&#xf6;k I. Virological diagnosis of enterovirus type 71 infections: experiences gained during an epidemic of acute CNS diseases in Hungary in 1978. Arch Virol. 1982;71:217&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6285858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuda GM, Chang WK, Yeung CY, Tang PS. Monoplegia caused by Enterovirus 71: an outbreak in Hong Kong. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1987;6:206&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3562141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, Twu SJ, Chen KT, Tsai SF, Wang JR, Shih SR. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto T, Chikahira M, Yoshida S, Ebira H, Hasegawa A, Totsuka A, Nishio O. Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol Immunol. 2002;46:621&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Chow VT, Phoon MC, Chan KP, Poh CL. Direct detection of enterovirus 71 (EV71) in clinical specimens from a hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak in Singapore by reverse transcription-PCR with universal enterovirus and EV71-specific primers. J Clin Microbiol. 2002;40:2823&#x2013;2827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12149336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown BA, Pallansch MA. Complete nucleotide sequence of enterovirus 71 is distinct from poliovirus. Virus Res. 1995;39:195&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8837884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toyoda H, Nicklin MJ, Murray MG, Anderson CW, Dunn JJ, Studier FW, Wimmer E. A second virus-encoded proteinase involved in proteolytic processing of poliovirus polyprotein. Cell. 1986;45:761&#x2013;770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3011278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ypma-Wong MF, Dewalt PG, Johnson VH, Lamb JG, Semler BL. Protein 3CD is the major poliovirus proteinase responsible for cleavage of the P1 capsid precursor. Virology. 1988;166:265&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2842953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putnak JR, Phillips BA. Picornaviral structure and assembly. Microbiol Rev. 1981;45:287&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC281510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7022155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hummeler K, Anderson TF, Brown RA. Identification of poliovirus particles of different antigenicity by specific agglutination as seen in the electron microscope. Virology. 1962;16:84&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14449962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casal JI. Use of parvovirus-like particles for vaccination and induction of multiple immune responses. Biotechnol Appl Biochem. 1999;29(Pt 2):141&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10075910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenz P, Day PM, Pang YY, Frye SA, Jensen PN, Lowy DR, Schiller JT. Papillomavirus-like particles induce acute activation of dendritic cells. J Immunol. 2001;166:5346&#x2013;5355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11313370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy P. Genetically engineered particulate virus-like structures and their use as vaccine delivery systems. Intervirology. 1996;39:62&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8957671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert SC. Virus-like particles as vaccine adjuvants. Mol Biotechnol. 2001;19:169&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11725486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiller JT, Lowy DR. Papillomavirus-like particle based vaccines: cervical cancer and beyond. Expert Opin Biol Ther. 2001;1:571&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11727495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo L, Li Y, Cannon PM, Kim S, Kang CY. Chimeric gag-V3 virus-like particles of human immunodeficiency virus induce virus-neutralizing antibodies. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1992;89:10527&#x2013;10531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC50372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1438241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho Y, Lin PH, Liu CY, Lee SP, Chao YC. Assembly of human severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-like particles. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2004;318:833&#x2013;838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7111196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15147946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang KC, Wu JC, Chung YC, Ho YC, Chang MD, Hu YC. Baculovirus as a highly efficient gene delivery vector for the expression of hepatitis delta virus antigens in mammalian cells. Biotechnol Bioeng. 2005;89:464&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15609271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansardi DC, Porter DC, Morrow CD. Coinfection with recombinant vaccinia viruses expressing poliovirus P1 and P3 proteins results in polyprotein processing and formation of empty capsid structures. J Virol. 1991;65:2088&#x2013;2092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC240068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1848318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe4;utigam S, Snezhkov E, Bishop DH. Formation of poliovirus-like particles by recombinant baculoviruses expressing the individual VP0, VP3, and VP1 proteins by comparison to particles derived from the expressed poliovirus polyprotein. Virology. 1993;192:512&#x2013;524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8380663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urakawa T, Ferguson M, Minor PD, Cooper J, Sullivan M, Almond JW, Bishop DH. Synthesis of immunogenic, but non-infectious, poliovirus particles in insect cells by a baculovirus expression vector. J Gen Virol. 1989;70(Pt 6):1453&#x2013;1463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2543785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YC, Hsu JT, Huang JH, Ho MS, Ho YC. Formation of enterovirus-like particle aggregates by recombinant baculoviruses co-expressing P1 and 3CD in insect cells. Biotechnol Lett. 2003;25:919&#x2013;925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12889824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung YC, Liu HJ, Hu YC. Facile monitoring of avian reovirus sB expression and purification processes by tagged green fluorescent protein. Enzyme Microb. Technol. 2004;35:494&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YC, Wu CN, Shih SR, Ho MS. Characterization of a Vero cell-adapted virulent strain of enterovirus 71 suitable for use as a vaccine candidate. Vaccine. 2002;20:2485&#x2013;2493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12057603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YC, Tsai CT, Chung YC, Lu JT, Hsu JTA. Generation of chimeric baculovirus with histidine-tags displayed on the envelope and its purification using immobilized metal affinity chromatography. Enzyme Microb Technol. 2003;33:445&#x2013;452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YC, Liu HJ, Chung YC. High level expression of the key antigenic protein, sC, from avian reovirus into insect cells and its purification by immobilized metal affinity chromatography. Biotechnol Lett. 2002;24:1017&#x2013;1022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YC, Bentley WE. Effect of MOI ratio on the composition and yield of chimeric infectious bursal disease virus-like particles by baculovirus co-infection: deterministic predictions and experimental results. Biotechnol Bioeng. 2001;75:104&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11536133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbustini E, Grasso M, Porcu E, Bellini O, Diegoli M, Fasani R, Banchieri N, Pilotto A, Morbini P, Dal Bello B, et al. Enteroviral RNA and virus-like particles in the skeletal muscle of patients with idiopathic dilated cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 1997;80:1188&#x2013;1193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9359548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaghan P, Cook H, Jackson T, Ryan M, Wileman T. The ultrastructure of the developing replication site in foot-and-mouth disease virus-infected BHK-38 cells. J Gen Virol. 2004;85:933&#x2013;946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15039536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold E, Luo M, Vriend G, Rossmann MG, Palmenberg AC, Parks GD, Nicklin MJ, Wimmer E. Implications of the picornavirus capsid structure for polyprotein processing. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1987;84:21&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC304133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3467351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateu MG. Antibody recognition of picornaviruses and escape from neutralization: a structural view. Virus Res. 1995;38:1&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8546007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minor PD, Ferguson M, Evans DM, Almond JW, Icenogle JP. Antigenic structure of polioviruses of serotypes 1, 2 and 3. J Gen Virol. 1986;67(Pt 7):1283&#x2013;1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2425046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breitburd F, Kirnbauer R, Hubbert NL, Nonnenmacher B, Trin-Dinh-Desmarquet C, Orth G, Schiller JT, Lowy DR. Immunization with viruslike particles from cottontail rabbit papillomavirus (CRPV) can protect against experimental CRPV infection. J Virol. 1995;69:3959&#x2013;3963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC189126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7745754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzich JA, Ghim SJ, Palmer-Hill FJ, White WI, Tamura JK, Bell JA, Newsome JA, Jenson AB, Schlegel R. Systemic immunization with papillomavirus L1 protein completely prevents the development of viral mucosal papillomas. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1995;92:11553&#x2013;11557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC40440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8524802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao Q, Bu Z, Vzorov A, Yang C, Compans RW. Virus-like particle and DNA-based candidate AIDS vaccines. Vaccine. 2003;21:638&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12531332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcea RL, Gissmann L. Virus-like particles as vaccines and vessels for the delivery of small molecules. Curr Opin Biotechnol. 2004;15:513&#x2013;517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15560977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tacket CO, Sztein MB, Losonsky GA, Wasserman SS, Estes MK. Humoral, mucosal, and cellular immune responses to oral Norwalk virus-like particles in volunteers. Clin Immunol. 2003;108:241&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14499247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutsky LA, Ault KA, Wheeler CM, Brown DR, Barr E, Alvarez FB, Chiacchierini LM, Jansen KU. A controlled trial of a human papillomavirus type 16 vaccine. N Engl J Med. 2002;347:1645&#x2013;1651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12444178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CN, Lin YC, Fann C, Liao NS, Shih SR, Ho MS. Protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by passive immunization with subunit VP1 vaccines and inactivated virus. Vaccine. 2001;20:895&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rombaut B, Vrijsen R, Boeye A. New evidence for the precursor role of 14S subunits in poliovirus morphogenesis. Virology. 1990;177:411&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2162113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rombaut B, Andries K, Boey&#xe9; A. A comparison of WIN 51711 and R 78206 as stabilizers of poliovirus virions and procapsids. J Gen Virol. 1991;72(Pt 9):2153&#x2013;2157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1716654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rombaut B, Foriers A, Boeye A. In vitro assembly of poliovirus 14 S subunits: identification of the assembly promoting activity of infected cell extracts. Virology. 1991;180:781&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1846498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>