<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">19625480</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2009</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-660X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>47</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2009</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in the Netherlands, 1963 to 2008.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2826</StartPage><EndPage>2833</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2826-33</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JCM.00507-09</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The incidence of enterovirus 71 (EV71) infection has greatly increased in the Asian Pacific region since 1997. Several large outbreaks, caused by different subgenogroups of EV71, occurred with high rates of morbidity and a substantial number of deaths. In 2007, 58 cases of EV71 infection requiring hospitalization were reported in The Netherlands after a period of low endemicity of 21 years. These events triggered a study on the epidemiology of EV71 in The Netherlands. Genetic analysis of the VP1 capsid region of 199 EV71 isolates collected from 1963 to 2008 as part of enterovirus surveillance activities revealed a change in the prevailing subgenogroups over time. From 1963 to 1986 infections were caused by three different and successive lineages belonging to subgenogroup B (the novel lineage designated B0, as well as B1 and B2). In 1987, following a major epidemic the previous year, the B genogroup was replaced by genogroup C strains of lineages C1 and, later, C2. Analyses of the clinical data suggested that there were differences between infection with genogroup B and with genogroup C strains in terms of the age groups affected and the severity of illness. From comparative analysis with genomic data available in the public domain, we concluded that EV71 strain evolution shows a global pattern, which leads to the question of whether the recently emerged C4 lineage strains will also spread outside of Asia.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Sanden</LastName><ForeName>Sabine</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Public Health and the Environment, RIVM, P.O. Box 1, 3720 BA Bilthoven, The Netherlands. sabine.van.der.sanden@rivm.nl</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koopmans</LastName><ForeName>Marion</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uslu</LastName><ForeName>G&#xf6;khan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Avoort</LastName><ForeName>Harrie</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Dutch Working Group for Clinical Virology</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>GENBANK</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>AB491212</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AB491213</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AB491214</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AB491215</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AB491216</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AB491217</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AB491218</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AB491219</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>AB491220</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2009</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505564</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0095-1137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D036022">Capsid Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036022" MajorTopicYN="N">Capsid Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016000" MajorTopicYN="N">Cluster Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008969" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Sequence Data</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009426" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Netherlands</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017422" MajorTopicYN="N">Sequence Analysis, DNA</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017385" MajorTopicYN="N">Sequence Homology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2738086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00507-09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JCM.00507-09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar, S., I. C. Sam, J. Yusof, M. K. Lim, S. Misbah, N. MatRahim, and P. S. Hooi. 2009. Enterovirus 71 outbreak, Brunei. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 1579-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19116058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bible, J. M., M. Iturriza-Gomara, B. Megson, D. Brown, P. Pantelidis, P. Earl, J. Bendig, and C. Y. Tong. 2008. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 in the United Kingdom from 1998 to 2006. J. Clin. Microbiol. 463192-3200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2566106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18650362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bible, J. M., P. Pantelidis, P. K. Chan, and C. Y. Tong. 2007. Genetic evolution of enterovirus 71: epidemiological and pathological implications. Rev. Med. Virol. 1 7371-379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17487831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, B. A., M. S. Oberste, J. P. Alexander, Jr., M. L. Kennett, and M. A. Pallansch. 1999. Molecular epidemiology and evolution of enterovirus 71 strains isolated from 1970 to 1998. J. Virol. 739969-9975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10559310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., S. Krishnan, P. H. Tio, D. Perera, and S. C. Wong. 1999. Isolation of subgenus B adenovirus during a fatal outbreak of enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sibu, Sarawak. Lancet 354987-991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10501361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., D. Perera, B. A. Brown, D. Cheon, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, H. Cho, and P. McMinn. 2003. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 strains and recent outbreaks in the Asia-Pacific region: comparative analysis of the VP1 and VP4 genes. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9461-468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12702227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro, C. M., A. C. Cruz, E. E. Silva, and L. Gomes Mde. 2005. Molecular and seroepidemiologic studies of enterovirus 71 infection in the State of Para, Brazil. Rev. Inst. Med. Trop. Sao Paulo 4765-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15880216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K. P., K. T. Goh, C. Y. Chong, E. S. Teo, G. Lau, and A. E. Ling. 2003. Epidemic hand, foot and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 978-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y. 2008. Enterovirus 71 in Taiwan. Pediatr. Neonatol. 49103-112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19054914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, K. T., H. L. Chang, S. T. Wang, Y. T. Cheng, and J. Y. Yang. 2007. Epidemiologic features of hand-foot-mouth disease and herpangina caused by enterovirus 71 in Taiwan, 1998-2005. Pediatrics 120e244-e252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention and the World Health Organization. 2008. Report on the hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in Fuyang City, Anhui Province, and the prevention and control in china. World Health Organization in China, Beijing, China.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu, P. Y., K. H. Lin, K. P. Hwang, L. C. Chou, C. F. Wang, S. R. Shih, J. R. Wang, Y. Shimada, and H. Ishiko. 2001. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in Taiwan. Arch. Virol. 146589-600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11338392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua, K. B., B. H. Chua, C. S. Lee, Y. K. Chem, N. Ismail, A. Kiyu, and V. Kumarasamy. 2007. Genetic diversity of enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of hand, foot and mouth disease in the 1997, 2000 and 2005 outbreaks, Peninsular Malaysia. Malays. J. Pathol. 2969-78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19108398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov, M., M. Voroshilova, L. Shindarov, I. Lavrova, L. Gracheva, G. Koroleva, S. Vasilenko, I. Brodvarova, M. Nikolova, S. Gyurova, M. Gacheva, G. Mitov, N. Ninov, E. Tsylka, I. Robinson, M. Frolova, V. Bashkirtsev, L. Martiyanova, and V. Rodin. 1979. Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch. Virol. 60329-340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deshpande, J. M., S. S. Nadkarni, and P. P. Francis. 2003. Enterovirus 71 isolated from a case of acute flaccid paralysis in India represents a new genotype. Curr. Sci. 841350-1353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert, G. L., K. E. Dickson, M. J. Waters, M. L. Kennett, S. A. Land, and M. Sneddon. 1988. Outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Victoria, Australia, with a high incidence of neurologic involvement. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 7484-488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2841639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong, L. M., Q. Ge, J. Y. Yan, Y. Y. Lu, Y. Feng, H. Y. Mao, M. H. Li, and M. Zhou. 2005. Isolation and sequencing of VP1 region of enterovirus 71 strains in Zhejiang, China. Zhonghua Liu Xing Bing Xue Za Zhi 26971-974. [In Chinese.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16676593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y. Q., H. Yang, L. L. Li, J. Tan, L. Zhou, L. S. Mao, F. Yang, J. J. Liu, and X. Lv. 2008. Genotype analysis of enterovirus type 71 detected from patients with hand-foot-mouth disease in Shenzhen. Zhonghua Liu Xing Bing Xue Za Zhi. 29790-793. [In Chinese.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19103116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrero, L. J., C. S. Lee, R. J. Hurrelbrink, B. H. Chua, K. B. Chua, and P. C. McMinn. 2003. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in peninsular Malaysia, 1997-2000. Arch. Virol. 1481369-1385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12827466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M. 2000. Enterovirus 71: the virus, its infections and outbreaks. J. Microbiol. Immunol. Infect. 33205-216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11269363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M., E. R. Chen, K. H. Hsu, S. J. Twu, K. T. Chen, S. F. Tsai, J. R. Wang, and S. R. Shih for the Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. N. Engl. J. Med. 341929-935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, K. Y., X. Zhang, P. H. Chung, K. C. Tsao, T. Y. Lin, L. H. Su, and C. H. Chiu. 2008. Enterovirus 71 in Taiwan, 2004-2006: epidemiological and virological features. Scand. J. Infect. Dis. 40571-574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18584550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y. P., T. L. Lin, C. Y. Kuo, M. W. Lin, C. Y. Yao, H. W. Liao, L. C. Hsu, C. F. Yang, J. Y. Yang, P. J. Chen, and H. S. Wu. 2008. The circulation of subgenogroups B5 and C5 of enterovirus 71 in Taiwan from 2006 to 2007. Virus Res. 137206-212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18706461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapsenberg, J. G. 1991. Non-polio enterovirussen Infectieziekten Bull. 108-13. [In Dutch.]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kung, S. H., S. F. Wang, C. W. Huang, C. C. Hsu, H. F. Liu, and J. Y. Yang. 2007. Genetic and antigenic analyses of enterovirus 71 isolates in Taiwan during 1998-2005. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. 13782-787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17488328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L., Y. He, H. Yang, J. Zhu, X. Xu, J. Dong, Y. Zhu, and Q. Jin. 2005. Genetic characteristics of human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 circulating from 1999 to 2004 in Shenzhen, People's Republic of China. J. Clin. Microbiol. 433835-3839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1233905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., S. J. Twu, M. S. Ho, L. Y. Chang, and C. Y. Lee. 2003. Enterovirus 71 outbreaks, Taiwan: occurrence and recognition. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9291-293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12643822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie, J. S., K. B. Chua, P. W. Daniels, B. T. Eaton, H. E. Field, R. A. Hall, K. Halpin, C. A. Johansen, P. D. Kirkland, S. K. Lam, P. McMinn, D. J. Nisbet, R. Paru, A. T. Pyke, S. A. Ritchie, P. Siba, D. W. Smith, G. A. Smith, A. F. van den Hurk, L. F. Wang, and D. T. Williams. 2001. Emerging viral diseases of Southeast Asia and the Western Pacific. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 7497-504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2631848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11485641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., K. Lindsay, D. Perera, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, and M. J. Cardosa. 2001. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J. Virol. 757732-7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P. C. 2002. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 2691-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta, K., C. Abiko, T. Murata, Y. Matsuzaki, T. Itagaki, K. Sanjoh, M. Sakamoto, S. Hongo, S. Murayama, and K. Hayasaka. 2005. Frequent importation of enterovirus 71 from surrounding countries into the local community of Yamagata, Japan, between 1998 and 2003. J. Clin. Microbiol. 436171-6175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16333123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nix, W. A., M. S. Oberste, and M. A. Pallansch. 2006. Sensitive, seminested PCR amplification of VP1 sequences for direct identification of all enterovirus serotypes from original clinical specimens. J. Clin. Microbiol. 442698-2704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1594621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16891480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste, M. S., K. Maher, D. R. Kilpatrick, M. R. Flemister, B. A. Brown, and M. A. Pallansch. 1999. Typing of human enteroviruses by partial sequencing of VP1. J. Clin. Microbiol. 371288-1293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC84754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10203472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi, M. H., S. C. Wong, Y. Podin, W. Akin, S. del Sel, A. Mohan, C. H. Chieng, D. Perera, D. Clear, D. Wong, E. Blake, J. Cardosa, and T. Solomon. 2007. Human enterovirus 71 disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: a prospective clinical, virological, and molecular epidemiological study. Clin. Infect. Dis. 44646-656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17278054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortner, B., C. W. Huang, D. Schmid, I. Mutz, G. Wewalka, F. Allerberger, J. Y. Yang, and H. P. Huemer. 2009. Epidemiology of enterovirus types causing neurological disease in Austria 1999-2007: detection of clusters of echovirus 30 and enterovirus 71 and analysis of prevalent genotypes. J. Med. Virol. 81317-324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19107980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Velez, C. M., M. S. Anderson, C. C. Robinson, E. J. McFarland, W. A. Nix, M. A. Pallansch, M. S. Oberste, and M. P. Glode. 2007. Outbreak of neurologic enterovirus type 71 disease: a diagnostic challenge. Clin. Infect. Dis. 45950-957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17879907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders, S. A., L. J. Herrero, K. McPhie, S. S. Chow, M. E. Craig, D. E. Dwyer, W. Rawlinson, and P. C. McMinn. 2006. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 over two decades in an Australian urban community. Arch. Virol. 1511003-1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16369861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, N. J., E. H. Lennette, and H. H. Ho. 1974. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J. Infect. Dis. 129304-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu, H., A. Utama, N. Onnimala, C. Li, Z. Li-Bi, M. Yu-Jie, Y. Pongsuwanna, and T. Miyamura. 2004. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection in the Western Pacific Region. Pediatr. Int. 46231-235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S., C. L. Poh, and V. T. Chow. 2002. Complete sequence analyses of enterovirus 71 strains from fatal and non-fatal cases of the hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in Singapore (2000). Microbiol. Immunol. 46801-808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12516778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trabelsi, A., F. Grattard, M. Nejmeddine, M. Aouni, T. Bourlet, and B. Pozzetto. 1995. Evaluation of an enterovirus group-specific anti-VP1 monoclonal antibody, 5-D8/1, in comparison with neutralization and PCR for rapid identification of enteroviruses in cell culture. J. Clin. Microbiol. 332454-2457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC228436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7494045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu, P. V., N. T. Thao, D. Perera, T. K. Huu, N. T. Tien, T. C. Thuong, O. M. How, M. J. Cardosa, and P. C. McMinn. 2007. Epidemiologic and virologic investigation of hand, foot, and mouth disease, southern Vietnam, 2005. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 131733-1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van de Peer, Y., and R. De Wachter. 1994. TREECON for Windows: a software package for the construction and drawing of evolutionary trees for the Microsoft Windows environment. Comput. Appl. Biosci. 10569-570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7828077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. R., Y. C. Tuan, H. P. Tsai, J. J. Yan, C. C. Liu, and I. J. Su. 2002. Change of major genotype of enterovirus 71 in outbreaks of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Taiwan between 1998 and 2000. J. Clin. Microbiol. 4010-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witso, E., G. Palacios, K. S. Ronningen, O. Cinek, D. Janowitz, M. Rewers, B. Grinde, and W. I. Lipkin. 2007. Asymptomatic circulation of HEV71 in Norway. Virus Res. 12319-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16965832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 2004. Polio laboratory manual, 4 ed. World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousef, G. E., G. F. Mann, I. N. Brown, and J. F. Mowbray. 1987. Clinical and research application of an enterovirus group-reactive monoclonal antibody. Intervirology 28199-205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2835329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>