<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23302872</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>87</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Functional comparison of SCARB2 and PSGL1 as receptors for enterovirus 71.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3335</StartPage><EndPage>3347</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3335-47</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.02070-12</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Human scavenger receptor class B, member 2 (SCARB2), and P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 (PSGL1) have been identified to be the cellular receptors for enterovirus 71 (EV71). We compared the EV71 infection efficiencies of mouse L cells that expressed SCARB2 (L-SCARB2) and PSGL1 (L-PSGL1) and the abilities of SCARB2 and PSGL1 to bind to the virus. L-SCARB2 cells bound a reduced amount of EV71 compared to L-PSGL1 cells. However, EV71 could infect L-SCARB2 cells more efficiently than L-PSGL1 cells. The results suggested that the difference in the binding capacities of the two receptors was not the sole determinant of the infection efficiency and that SCARB2 plays an essential role after attaching to virions. Therefore, we examined the viral entry into L-SCARB2 cells and L-PSGL1 cells by immunofluorescence microscopy. In both cells, we detected internalized EV71 virions that colocalized with an early endosome marker. We then performed a sucrose density gradient centrifugation analysis to evaluate viral uncoating. After incubating the EV71 virion with L-SCARB2 cells or soluble SCARB2 under acidic conditions below pH 6.0, we observed that part of the native virion was converted into an empty capsid that lacked both genomic RNA and VP4 capsid proteins. The results suggested that the uncoating of EV71 requires both SCARB2 and an acidic environment and occurs after the internalization of the virus-receptor complex into endosomes. However, the empty capsid formation was not observed after incubation with L-PSGL1 cells or soluble PSGL1 under any of the tested pH conditions. These results indicated that SCARB2 is capable of viral binding, viral internalization, and viral uncoating and that the low infection efficiency of L-PSGL1 cells is due to the inability of PSGL1 to induce viral uncoating. The characterization of SCARB2 as an uncoating receptor greatly contributes to the understanding of the early steps of EV71 infection.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamayoshi</LastName><ForeName>Seiya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurovirology Project, Tokyo Metropolitan Institute of Medical Science, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohka</LastName><ForeName>Seii</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujii</LastName><ForeName>Ken</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koike</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D051907">Lysosomal Membrane Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008562">Membrane Glycoproteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C084882">P-selectin ligand protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D051116">Receptors, Scavenger</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011991">Receptors, Virus</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C074299">SCARB2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051907" MajorTopicYN="N">Lysosomal Membrane Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008562" MajorTopicYN="N">Membrane Glycoproteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008856" MajorTopicYN="N">Microscopy, Fluorescence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051116" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Scavenger</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011991" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053586" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Internalization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057646" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Uncoating</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23302872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3592140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.02070-12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.02070-12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Racaniello V. 2007. Picornaviridae: the viruses and their replication, p 795&#x2013;838 In Knipe DM, Howley PM, Griffin DE, Lamb RA, Martin MA, Roizman B, Straus SE. (ed), Fields virology, 5th ed Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, Philadelphia, PA</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossmann MG, Johnson JE. 1989. Icosahedral RNA virus structure. Annu. Rev. Biochem. 58:533&#x2013;573</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2673017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Peng W, Ren J, Hu Z, Xu J, Lou Z, Li X, Yin W, Shen X, Porta C, Walter TS, Evans G, Axford D, Owen R, Rowlands DJ, Wang J, Stuart DI, Fry EE, Rao Z. 2012. A sensor-adaptor mechanism for enterovirus uncoating from structures of EV71. Nat. Struct. Mol. Biol. 19:424&#x2013;429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3378640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22388738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plevka P, Perera R, Cardosa J, Kuhn RJ, Rossmann MG. 2012. Crystal structure of human enterovirus 71. Science 336:1274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3448362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22383808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossmann MG, He Y, Kuhn RJ. 2002. Picornavirus-receptor interactions. Trends Microbiol. 10:324&#x2013;331</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12110211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt NJ, Lennette EH, Ho HH. 1974. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J. Infect. Dis. 129:304&#x2013;309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg J, Lycke E, Ahlfors K, Johnsson T, Wolontis S, von Zeipel G. 1974. New enterovirus type associated with epidemic of aseptic meningitis and-or hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet ii:112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4136956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara A, Tagaya I, Yoneyama T. 1978. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Intervirology 9:60&#x2013;63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">202573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. 2002. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 26:91&#x2013;107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto T, Chikahira M, Yoshida S, Ebira H, Hasegawa A, Totsuka A, Nishio O. 2002. Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol. Immunol. 46:621&#x2013;627</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan LG, Parashar UD, Lye MS, Ong FG, Zaki SR, Alexander JP, Ho KK, Han LL, Pallansch MA, Suleiman AB, Jegathesan M, Anderson LJ. 2000. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. For the Outbreak Study Group. Clin. Infect. Dis. 31:678&#x2013;683</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, Twu SJ, Chen KT, Tsai SF, Wang JR, Shih SR. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929&#x2013;935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad K. 2000. Hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak reported in Singapore. Lancet 356:1338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11073035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu J. 2008. Enterovirus 71 infection: a new threat to global public health? Lancet Neurol. 7:868&#x2013;869</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18848307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan JJ, Wang JR, Liu CC, Yang HB, Su IJ. 2000. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan 1998: a comprehensive pathological, virological, and molecular study on a case of fulminant encephalitis. J. Clin. Virol. 17:13&#x2013;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Ren L, Xiong Z, Li J, Xiao Y, Zhao R, He Y, Bu G, Zhou S, Wang J, Qi J. 2009. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in the People's Republic of China in 2008. J. Clin. Microbiol. 47:2351&#x2013;2352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2708525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Yamashita Y, Li J, Hanagata N, Minowa T, Takemura T, Koike S. 2009. Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15:798&#x2013;801</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Shimojima M, Tano Y, Miyamura T, Wakita T, Shimizu H. 2009. Human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15:794&#x2013;797</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskelinen EL, Tanaka Y, Saftig P. 2003. At the acidic edge: emerging functions for lysosomal membrane proteins. Trends Cell Biol. 13:137&#x2013;145</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12628346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reczek D, Schwake M, Schroder J, Hughes H, Blanz J, Jin X, Brondyk W, Van Patten S, Edmunds T, Saftig P. 2007. LIMP-2 is a receptor for lysosomal mannose-6-phosphate-independent targeting of beta-glucocerebrosidase. Cell 131:770&#x2013;783</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18022370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanz J, Groth J, Zachos C, Wehling C, Saftig P, Schwake M. 2010. Disease-causing mutations within the lysosomal integral membrane protein type 2 (LIMP-2) reveal the nature of binding to its ligand beta-glucocerebrosidase. Hum. Mol. Genet. 19:563&#x2013;572</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19933215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Iizuka S, Yamashita T, Minagawa H, Mizuta K, Okamoto M, Nishimura H, Sanjoh K, Katsushima N, Itagaki T, Nagai Y, Fujii K, Koike S. 2012. Human SCARB2-dependent infection by coxsackievirus A7, A14, and A16 and enterovirus 71. J. Virol. 86:5686&#x2013;5696</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3347270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22438546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Koike S. 2011. Identification of a human SCARB2 region that is important for enterovirus 71 binding and infection. J. Virol. 85:4937&#x2013;4946</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3126200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21389126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Song Z, Qi Y, Feng X, Xu N, Sun Y, Wu X, Yao X, Mao Q, Li X, Dong W, Wan X, Huang N, Shen X, Liang Z, Li W. 2012. Molecular determinants of enterovirus 71 viral entry: cleft around GLN-172 on VP1 protein interacts with variable region on scavenge receptor B 2. J. Biol. Chem. 287:6406&#x2013;6420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3307280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22219187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain KM, Leong KL, Ng MM, Chu JJ. 2011. The essential role of clathrin-mediated endocytosis in the infectious entry of human enterovirus 71. J. Biol. Chem. 286:309&#x2013;321</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3012988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20956521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Lin YW, Lin HY, Tsou YL, Chitra E, Hsiao KN, Shao HY, Liu CC, Sia C, Chong P, Chow YH.
2012. 
Human SCARB2-mediated entry and endocytosis of EV71. PLoS One
7:e30507
doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0030507</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0030507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3260287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22272359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sako D, Chang XJ, Barone KM, Vachino G, White HM, Shaw G, Veldman GM, Bean KM, Ahern TJ, Furie B, Cumming DA, Larsen GR. 1993. Expression cloning of a functional glycoprotein ligand for P-selectin. Cell 75:1179&#x2013;1186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7505206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laszik Z, Jansen PJ, Cummings RD, Tedder TF, McEver RP, Moore KL. 1996. P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is broadly expressed in cells of myeloid, lymphoid, and dendritic lineage and in some nonhematopoietic cells. Blood 88:3010&#x2013;3021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8874199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somers WS, Tang J, Shaw GD, Camphausen RT. 2000. Insights into the molecular basis of leukocyte tethering and rolling revealed by structures of P- and E-selectin bound to SLe(X) and PSGL-1. Cell 103:467&#x2013;479</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11081633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ley K, Kansas GS. 2004. Selectins in T-cell recruitment to non-lymphoid tissues and sites of inflammation. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 4:325&#x2013;335</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15122198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Nishimura Y, Wakita T, Shimizu H.
2010. 
Tyrosine sulfation of the amino terminus of PSGL-1 is critical for enterovirus 71 infection. PLoS Pathog.
6:e1001174
doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1001174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1001174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2973824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21079683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Dong W, Quan X, Ma C, Qin C, Zhang L. 2012. Transgenic expression of human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is not sufficient for enterovirus 71 infection in mice. Arch. Virol. 157:539&#x2013;543</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22187102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergelson JM. 2010. Receptors, p 73&#x2013;86 In Ehrenfeld E, Domingo E, Roos RP. (ed), The picornaviruses. ASM Press, Washington, DC</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuthill TJ, Groppelli E, Hogle JM, Rowlands DJ. 2010. Picornaviruses. Curr. Top. Microbiol. Immunol. 343:43&#x2013;89</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3018333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20397067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendelsohn CL, Wimmer E, Racaniello VR. 1989. Cellular receptor for poliovirus: molecular cloning, nucleotide sequence, and expression of a new member of the immunoglobulin superfamily. Cell 56:855&#x2013;865</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2538245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koike S, Horie H, Ise I, Okitsu A, Yoshida M, Iizuka N, Takeuchi K, Takegami T, Nomoto A. 1990. The poliovirus receptor protein is produced both as membrane-bound and secreted forms. EMBO J. 9:3217&#x2013;3224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC552052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2170108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staunton DE, Merluzzi VJ, Rothlein R, Barton R, Marlin SD, Springer TA. 1989. A cell adhesion molecule, ICAM-1, is the major surface receptor for rhinoviruses. Cell 56:849&#x2013;853</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2538244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomassini JE, Graham D, DeWitt CM, Lineberger DW, Rodkey JA, Colonno RJ. 1989. cDNA cloning reveals that the major group rhinovirus receptor on HeLa cells is intercellular adhesion molecule 1. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 86:4907&#x2013;4911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC297524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2544880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greve JM, Davis G, Meyer AM, Forte CP, Yost SC, Marlor CW, Kamarck ME, McClelland A. 1989. The major human rhinovirus receptor is ICAM-1. Cell 56:839&#x2013;847</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2538243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duque H, Baxt B. 2003. Foot-and-mouth disease virus receptors: comparison of bovine alpha(V) integrin utilization by type A and O viruses. J. Virol. 77:2500&#x2013;2511</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC141088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12551988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofer F, Gruenberger M, Kowalski H, Machat H, Huettinger M, Kuechler E, Blaas D. 1994. Members of the low density lipoprotein receptor family mediate cell entry of a minor-group common cold virus. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 91:1839&#x2013;1842</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC43259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8127891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergelson JM, Cunningham JA, Droguett G, Kurt-Jones EA, Krithivas A, Hong JS, Horwitz MS, Crowell RL, Finberg RW. 1997. Isolation of a common receptor for coxsackie B viruses and adenoviruses 2 and 5. Science 275:1320&#x2013;1323</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9036860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomko RP, Xu R, Philipson L. 1997. HCAR and MCAR: the human and mouse cellular receptors for subgroup C adenoviruses and group B coxsackieviruses. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 94:3352&#x2013;3356</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC20373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9096397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafren DR, Bates RC, Agrez MV, Herd RL, Burns GF, Barry RD. 1995. Coxsackieviruses B1, B3, and B5 use decay accelerating factor as a receptor for cell attachment. J. Virol. 69:3873&#x2013;3877</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC189108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7538177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafren DR, Williams DT, Barry RD. 1997. A decay-accelerating factor-binding strain of coxsackievirus B3 requires the coxsackievirus-adenovirus receptor protein to mediate lytic infection of rhabdomyosarcoma cells. J. Virol. 71:9844&#x2013;9848</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC230302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9371658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milstone AM, Petrella J, Sanchez MD, Mahmud M, Whitbeck JC, Bergelson JM. 2005. Interaction with coxsackievirus and adenovirus receptor, but not with decay-accelerating factor (DAF), induces A-particle formation in a DAF-binding coxsackievirus B3 isolate. J. Virol. 79:655&#x2013;660</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC538729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15596863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coyne CB, Bergelson JM. 2006. Virus-induced Abl and Fyn kinase signals permit coxsackievirus entry through epithelial tight junctions. Cell 124:119&#x2013;131</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16413486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M, Koike S, Aoki J, Horie H, Nomoto A. 1998. Interaction of poliovirus with its purified receptor and conformational alteration in the virion. J. Virol. 72:3578&#x2013;3586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC109578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9557638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fricks CE, Hogle JM. 1990. Cell-induced conformational change in poliovirus: externalization of the amino terminus of VP1 is responsible for liposome binding. J. Virol. 64:1934&#x2013;1945</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC249347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2157861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prchla E, Kuechler E, Blaas D, Fuchs R. 1994. Uncoating of human rhinovirus serotype 2 from late endosomes. J. Virol. 68:3713&#x2013;3723</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC236876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8189509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curry S, Abrams CC, Fry E, Crowther JC, Belsham GJ, Stuart DI, King AM. 1995. Viral RNA modulates the acid sensitivity of foot-and-mouth disease virus capsids. J. Virol. 69:430&#x2013;438</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC188591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7983739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Tuthill TJ, Harlos K, Walter TS, Knowles NJ, Groppelli E, Rowlands DJ, Stuart DI, Fry EE.
2009. 
Equine rhinitis A virus and its low pH empty particle: clues towards an aphthovirus entry mechanism? PLoS Pathog.
5:e1000620
doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1000620</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1000620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2752993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19816570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurani G, Lindqvist B, Casasnovas JM. 2003. Receptor priming of major group human rhinoviruses for uncoating and entry at mild low-pH environments. J. Virol. 77:11985&#x2013;11991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC254263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14581535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata N, Shimizu H, Ami Y, Tano Y, Harashima A, Suzaki Y, Sato Y, Miyamura T, Sata T, Iwasaki T. 2002. Pyramidal and extrapyramidal involvement in experimental infection of cynomolgus monkeys with enterovirus 71. J. Med. Virol. 67:207&#x2013;216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11992581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiroki K, Kato H, Koike S, Odaka T, Nomoto A. 1993. Temperature-sensitive mouse cell factors for strand-specific initiation of poliovirus RNA synthesis. J. Virol. 67:3989&#x2013;3996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC237766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8389915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatakeyama S, Sakai-Tagawa Y, Kiso M, Goto H, Kawakami C, Mitamura K, Sugaya N, Suzuki Y, Kawaoka Y. 2005. Enhanced expression of an alpha2,6-linked sialic acid on MDCK cells improves isolation of human influenza viruses and evaluation of their sensitivity to a neuraminidase inhibitor. J. Clin. Microbiol. 43:4139&#x2013;4146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1233980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Noda T, Ebihara H, Goto H, Morikawa Y, Lukashevich IS, Neumann G, Feldmann H, Kawaoka Y. 2008. Ebola virus matrix protein VP40 uses the COPII transport system for its intracellular transport. Cell Host Microbe 3:168&#x2013;177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2330329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18329616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed LJ, Muench H. 1938. A simple method of estimating fifty per cent endpoints. Am. J. Hyg. 27:493&#x2013;499</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M, Takebe Y, Wakita T, Shimizu H. 2010. A bifunctional anti-enterovirus compound that inhibits replication and the early stage of enterovirus 71 infection. J. Gen. Virol. 91:2734&#x2013;2744</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20660150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dierssen U, Rehren F, Henke-Gendo C, Harste G, Heim A. 2008. Rapid routine detection of enterovirus RNA in cerebrospinal fluid by a one-step real-time RT-PCR assay. J. Clin. Virol. 42:58&#x2013;64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18164234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan G, Freistadt MS, Racaniello VR. 1990. Neutralization of poliovirus by cell receptors expressed in insect cells. J. Virol. 64:4697&#x2013;4702</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC247955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2168959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Liu CC, Guo MS, Lin FH, Hsiao KN, Chang KH, Chou AH, Wang YC, Chen YC, Yang CS, Chong PC.
2011. 
Purification and characterization of enterovirus 71 viral particles produced from Vero cells grown in a serum-free microcarrier bioreactor system. PLoS One
6:e20005
doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0020005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0020005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3094384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamura K, Nishimura Y, Abo M, Wakita T, Shimizu H. 2011. Adaptive mutations in the genomes of enterovirus 71 strains following infection of mouse cells expressing human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1. J. Gen. Virol. 92:287&#x2013;291</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20943886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Garriga D, Pickl-Herk A, Luque D, Wruss J, Caston JR, Blaas D, Verdaguer N.
2012. 
Insights into minor group rhinovirus uncoating: the X-ray structure of the HRV2 empty capsid. PLoS Pathog.
8:e1002473
doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1002473</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1002473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3252380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22241997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostina M, Levy H, Filman DJ, Hogle JM. 2011. Poliovirus RNA is released from the capsid near a twofold symmetry axis. J. Virol. 85:776&#x2013;783</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3020038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20980499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Hsia SH, Huang YC, Wu CT, Chang LY. 2003. Proinflammatory cytokine reactions in enterovirus 71 infections of the central nervous system. Clin. Infect. Dis. 36:269&#x2013;274</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12539066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Huang KJ, Wu JM, Wang JR, Yu CK, Su IJ, Liu CC. 2003. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J. Infect. Dis. 188:564&#x2013;570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>