<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33643772</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2196-5226</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>GMS hygiene and infection control</Title><ISOAbbreviation>GMS Hyg Infect Control</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative in vitro evaluation of the antimicrobial activities of povidone-iodine and other commercially available antiseptics against clinically relevant pathogens.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>Doc05</StartPage><MedlinePgn>Doc05</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">Doc05</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3205/dgkh000376</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Aims:</b> Antiseptics, such as povidone-iodine (PVP-I), play an important role in infection control across a wide range of clinical settings. This study aimed to evaluate the comparative <i>in vitro</i> efficacy and rate of onset of action of a range of formulations of PVP-I and other commonly used antiseptics. <b>Methods:</b> The antimicrobial efficacy of a range of antiseptics and antimicrobial agents used for skin, wound, vagina and oral antisepsis was evaluated according to the EU Standards DIN EN1276 and EN14476. The panel of organisms tested included bacterial and fungal pathogens and two enteroviruses (Coxsackievirus A16 [CA16] and Enterovirus 71 [EV71]). <b>Results:</b> All PVP-I products tested were highly efficacious <i>in vitro</i> (&gt;99.99% kill rate) against a range of clinically relevant bacterial and fungal pathogens with rapid onset of action (30-60 seconds), at both high and low concentrations. By comparison, the efficacy of other antiseptics tested was generally reduced upon dilution. PVP-I products used in wound and oral care were found to be more effective <i>in vitro</i> against CA16 and EV71, and had a faster onset of action than most other agents tested. <b>Conclusion:</b> This study provides valuable insights into the <i>in vitro</i> efficacy of a range of commonly used antiseptics and may help inform the selection of appropriate antiseptics by healthcare professionals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Tan et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Eng Lee</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Singapore Polytechnic, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johari</LastName><ForeName>Nur Humaira</ForeName><Initials>NH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Singapore Polytechnic, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>GMS Hyg Infect Control</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101609519</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2196-5226</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger"><AbstractText><b>Zielsetzung:</b> Antiseptika wie Povidon-Iod (PVP-I) spielen eine wichtige Rolle in der Infektionskontrolle in einem breiten klinischen Anwendungsbereich. In der Studie sollte die <i>in vitro</i>-Wirksamkeit einer Reihe von Formulierungen auf Basis von PVP-I mit anderen h&#xe4;ufig verwendeten Antiseptika verglichen werden.<b>Methode:</b> Gem&#xe4;&#xdf; DIN EN1276 und EN14476 wurde die antimikrobielle Wirksamkeit einer Reihe von Antiseptika und antimikrobiellen Wirkstoffen, die in Pr&#xe4;paraten zur Anwendung auf Haut, Wunden, sowie zur Intim- und Mundpflege eingesetzt werden, gepr&#xfc;ft. Das Panel der Pr&#xfc;forganismen umfasste bakterielle und pilzliche Erreger sowie zwei Enteroviren (Coxsackievirus A16 [CA16] und Enterovirus 71 [EV71]). <b>Ergebnisse:</b> Alle getesteten PVP-I-Produkte waren <i>in vitro</i> hochwirksam (&gt;99,99% Abt&#xf6;tungsrate) gegen eine Reihe klinisch relevanter bakterieller und pilzlicher Erreger mit schnellem Wirkungseintritt (30&#x2013;60 s) sowohl bei hohen als auch bei niedrigen Konzentrationen. Im Vergleich dazu war die Wirksamkeit anderer getesteter Antiseptika bei Verd&#xfc;nnung im Allgemeinen geringer. Zur Wund- und Mundh&#xf6;hlenantiseptik eingesetzte PVP-I-Produkte erwiesen sich <i>in vitro</i> als wirksamer gegen CA16 und EV71 und hatten einen schnelleren Wirkungseintritt als die meisten anderen getesteten Mittel.<b>Diskussion:</b> Durch die Kenntnis der <i>In-vitro</i>-Wirksamkeit einer Reihe h&#xe4;ufig verwendeter Antiseptika wird die Auswahl geeigneter Antiseptika durch medizinisches Fachpersonal erleichtert.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Tan et al.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PVP-I</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antimicrobial resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antiseptics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">in vitro antimicrobial activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">povidone-iodine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Eng Lee Tan and Nur Humaira Johari received service contracts from Mundipharma for the study and have done consultancy and speaker engagements for Mundipharma.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7894193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3205/dgkh000376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">dgkh000376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Roberts CD, Leaper DJ, Assadian O. The Role of Topical Antiseptic Agents Within Antimicrobial Stewardship Strategies for Prevention and Treatment of Surgical Site and Chronic Open Wound Infection. Adv Wound Care (New Rochelle) 2017 Feb;6(2):63&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1089/wound.2016.0701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/wound.2016.0701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5286547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28224049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slaviero L, Avruscio G, Vindigni V, Tocco-Tussardi I. Antiseptics for burns: a review of the evidence. Ann Burns Fire Disasters. 2018 Sep;31(3):198&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6367858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30863253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer A, Eggers M. Pr&#xe4;vention respiratorischer Virusinfektionen durch viruzide Schleimhautantiseptik bei medizinischem Personal und in der Bev&#xf6;lkerung. [Prevention of respiratory viral infections by virucidal mucosal antisepsis among medical staff and in the community]. HygMed;45(9):D118&#x2013;24. (Ger).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ripa S, Bruno N, Reder RF, Casillis R, Roth RI. Clinical applications of povidone-iodine as a topical antimicrobial. In: Paulson DS, editor. Handbook of topical antimicrobials: Industrial applications in consumer products and pharmaceuticals. New York, NY: Marcel Dekker, Inc.; 2002. pp. 78&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1201/9780203909256.ch4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLure AR, Gordon J. In-vitro evaluation of povidone-iodine and chlorhexidine against methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus. J Hosp Infect. 1992 Aug;21(4):291&#x2013;299. doi: 10.1016/0195-6701(92)90139-d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0195-6701(92)90139-d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1355784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traor&#xe9; O, Fayard SF, Laveran H. An in-vitro evaluation of the activity of povidone-iodine against nosocomial bacterial strains. J Hosp Infect. 1996 Nov;34(3):217&#x2013;222. doi: 10.1016/s0195-6701(96)90069-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0195-6701(96)90069-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8923277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu M, Okuzumi K, Yoneyama A, Kunisada T, Araake M, Ogawa H, Kimura S. In vitro antiseptic susceptibility of clinical isolates from nosocomial infections. Dermatology. 2002;204(Suppl 1):21&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1159/000057720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000057720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12011516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorman SP, Scott EM, Hutchinson EP. Effects of aqueous and alcoholic povidone-iodine on spores of Bacillus subtilis. J Appl Bacteriol. 1985 Jul;59(1):99&#x2013;105. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2672.1985.tb01780.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2672.1985.tb01780.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3928572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rikimaru T, Kondo M, Kondo S, Oizumi K. Bactericidal activities of povidone-iodine against Mycobacterium. Dermatology. 1997;195(Suppl 2):104&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1159/000246041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000246041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9403266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wutzler P, Sauerbrei A, Kl&#xf6;cking R, Br&#xf6;gmann B, Reimer K. Virucidal activity and cytotoxicity of the liposomal formulation of povidone-iodine. Antiviral Res. 2002 May;54(2):89&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1016/s0166-3542(01)00213-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0166-3542(01)00213-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12062394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawana R, Kitamura T, Nakagomi O, Matsumoto I, Arita M, Yoshihara N, Yanagi K, Yamada A, Morita O, Yoshida Y, Furuya Y, Chiba S. Inactivation of human viruses by povidone-iodine in comparison with other antiseptics. Dermatology. 1997;195(Suppl 2):29&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1159/000246027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000246027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9403252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haley CE, Marling-Cason M, Smith JW, Luby JP, Mackowiak PA. Bactericidal activity of antiseptics against methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus. J Clin Microbiol. 1985 Jun;21(6):991&#x2013;992. doi: 10.1128/JCM.21.6.991-992.1985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.21.6.991-992.1985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC271835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4008627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenheim PD. In vitro efficacy of povidone-iodine solution and cream against methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus. Postgrad Med J. 1993;69(Suppl 3):S62&#x2013;S65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8290460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson MJ, David ML, Scholz M, Bull SJ, Morse D, Hulse-Stevens M, Peterson ML. Efficacy of skin and nasal povidone-iodine preparation against mupirocin-resistant methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus and S. aureus within the anterior nares. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2015 May;59(5):2765&#x2013;2773. doi: 10.1128/AAC.04624-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.04624-14</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4394816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25733504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdolrasouli A, Armstrong-James D, Ryan L, Schelenz S. In vitro efficacy of disinfectants utilised for skin decolonisation and environmental decontamination during a hospital outbreak with Candida auris. Mycoses. 2017 Nov;60(11):758&#x2013;763. doi: 10.1111/myc.12699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/myc.12699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28872735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Tracking Candida auris. 2019.  [accessed Sep 2020].  Available from:  https://www.cdc.gov/fungal/candida-auris/tracking-c-auris.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kean R, McKloud E, Townsend EM, Sherry L, Delaney C, Jones BL, Williams C, Ramage G. The comparative efficacy of antiseptics against Candida auris biofilms. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2018 Nov;52(5):673&#x2013;677. doi: 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2018.05.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2018.05.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29775686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore G, Schelenz S, Borman AM, Johnson EM, Brown CS. Yeasticidal activity of chemical disinfectants and antiseptics against Candida auris. J Hosp Infect. 2017 Dec;97(4):371&#x2013;375. doi: 10.1016/j.jhin.2017.08.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhin.2017.08.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28865738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunisada T, Yamada K, Oda S, Hara O. Investigation on the efficacy of povidone-iodine against antiseptic-resistant species. Dermatology. 1997;195(Suppl 2):14&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1159/000246025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000246025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9403250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoekstra MJ, Westgate SJ, Mueller S. Povidone-iodine ointment demonstrates in vitro efficacy against biofilm formation. Int Wound J. 2017 Feb;14(1):172&#x2013;179. doi: 10.1111/iwj.12578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iwj.12578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7949843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26968574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capriotti K, Pelletier J, Barone S, Capriotti J. Efficacy of dilute povidone-iodine against multi-drug resistant bacterial biofilms, fungal biofilms and fungal spores. Clinical Res Dermatol Open Access. 2018;5:1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.15226/2378-1726/5/1/00174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15226/2378-1726/5/1/00174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill KE, Malic S, McKee R, Rennison T, Harding KG, Williams DW, Thomas DW. An in vitro model of chronic wound biofilms to test wound dressings and assess antimicrobial susceptibilities. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2010 Jun;65(6):1195&#x2013;1206. doi: 10.1093/jac/dkq105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20378671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleischer W, Reimer K. Povidone-iodine in antisepsis--state of the art. Dermatology. 1997;195(Suppl 2):3&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1159/000246022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000246022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9403248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer A, Dissemond J, Kim S, Willy C, Mayer D, Papke R, Tuchmann F, Assadian O. Consensus on Wound Antisepsis: Update 2018. Skin Pharmacol Physiol. 2018;31(1):28&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1159/000481545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000481545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29262416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigliardi PL, Alsagoff SAL, El-Kafrawi HY, Pyon JK, Wa CTC, Villa MA. Povidone iodine in wound healing: a review of current concepts and practices. Int J Surg. 2017 Aug;44:260&#x2013;268. doi: 10.1016/j.ijsu.2017.06.073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijsu.2017.06.073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28648795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jonge SW, Boldingh QJJ, Solomkin JS, Allegranzi B, Egger M, Dellinger EP, Boermeester MA. Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials Evaluating Prophylactic Intra-Operative Wound Irrigation for the Prevention of Surgical Site Infections. Surg Infect (Larchmt) 2017 May-Jun;18(4):508&#x2013;519. doi: 10.1089/sur.2016.272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/sur.2016.272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28448203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan F, Zhao Z, Zhao X, Ma Q, Li K, Fu W, Jia Z. Reduction of Ocular Surface Damage and Bacterial Survival Using 0.05% Povidone-Iodine Ocular Surface Irrigation before Cataract Surgery. Ophthalmic Res. 2019;62(3):166&#x2013;172. doi: 10.1159/000501373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000501373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31352456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown NM, Cipriano CA, Moric M, Sporer SM, Della Valle CJ. Dilute betadine lavage before closure for the prevention of acute postoperative deep periprosthetic joint infection. J Arthroplasty. 2012 Jan;27(1):27&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2011.03.034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2011.03.034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21550765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng A, Sun HY, Tsai YT, Wu UI, Chuang YC, Wang JT, Sheng WH, Hsueh PR, Chen YC, Chang SC. Evaluation of Povidone-Iodine and Chlorhexidine against Outbreak and Nonoutbreak Strains of Mycobacterium abscessus Using Standard Quantitative Suspension and Carrier Testing. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2018 Jan;62(1):e01364&#x2013;e01317. doi: 10.1128/AAC.01364-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01364-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5740345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29061748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng MT, Chang MC, Wang ST, Yu WK, Liu CL, Chen TH. Efficacy of dilute betadine solution irrigation in the prevention of postoperative infection of spinal surgery. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2005 Aug;30(15):1689&#x2013;1693. doi: 10.1097/01.brs.0000171907.60775.85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.brs.0000171907.60775.85</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16094267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt PM, Hauser J, Rossbach O, Bosse B, Fleischer W, Steinau HU, Reimer K. Polyvinyl pyrrolidone-iodine liposome hydrogel improves epithelialization by combining moisture and antisepis. A new concept in wound therapy. Wound Repair Regen. 2001 Mar-Apr;9(2):116&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1046/j.1524-475x.2001.00116.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1524-475x.2001.00116.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11350649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EN1276 chemical disinfectants and antiseptics - quantitative suspension test for the evaluation of bactericidal activity of chemical disinfectants and antiseptics used in food, industrial, domestic and institutional areas - test method and requirements (phase 2, step 1) 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonnell G, Russell AD. Antiseptics and disinfectants: activity, action, and resistance. Clin Microbiol Rev. 1999 Jan;12(1):147&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9880479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EN14476 chemical disinfectants and antiseptics - quantitative suspension test for the evaluation of virucidal activity in the medical area - test method and requirements (phase 2/step 1) 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardona AF, Wilson SE. Skin and soft-tissue infections: a critical review and the role of telavancin in their treatment. Clin Infect Dis. 2015 Sep;61(Suppl 2):S69&#x2013;S78. doi: 10.1093/cid/civ528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/civ528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26316560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negut I, Grumezescu V, Grumezescu AM. Treatment Strategies for Infected Wounds. Molecules. 2018 Sep;23(9):2392. doi: 10.3390/molecules23092392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules23092392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6225154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30231567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan EL, Chua JX, M&#xfc;ller S. Comparative testing of betadine&#xae; and other commercially available antiseptics, based on current european suspension assay [Poster]. International Wound and Biotherapy Conference; 2015; 16-18 October 2015, Malaysia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonowitz A, Schaller M, Laude J, Reimer K, Korting HC. Comparative therapeutic and toxic effects of different povidone iodine (PVP-I) formulations in a model of oral candidosis based on in vitro reconstituted epithelium. J Drug Target. 2001;9(1):75&#x2013;83. doi: 10.3109/10611860108995634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10611860108995634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11378525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eggers M, Koburger-Janssen T, Eickmann M, Zorn J. In Vitro Bactericidal and Virucidal Efficacy of Povidone-Iodine Gargle/Mouthwash Against Respiratory and Oral Tract Pathogens. Infect Dis Ther. 2018 Jun;7(2):249&#x2013;259. doi: 10.1007/s40121-018-0200-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40121-018-0200-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5986684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29633177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanagalingam J, Feliciano R, Hah JH, Labib H, Le TA, Lin JC. Practical use of povidone-iodine antiseptic in the maintenance of oral health and in the prevention and treatment of common oropharyngeal infections. Int J Clin Pract. 2015 Nov;69(11):1247&#x2013;1256. doi: 10.1111/ijcp.12707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijcp.12707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6767541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26249761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoneyama A, Shimizu M, Tabata M, Yashiro J, Takata T, Hikida M. In vitro short-time killing activity of povidone-iodine (Isodine Gargle) in the presence of oral organic matter. Dermatology. 2006;212(Suppl 1):103&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1159/000089207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000089207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16490985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmermann P, Curtis N. Antimicrobial Effects of Antipyretics. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2017 Apr;61(4):e02268&#x2013;e02216. doi: 10.1128/AAC.02268-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.02268-16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5365702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28137805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slukin PV, Fursova NK, Briko NI. Antibacterial activity of benzydamine hydrochloride against clinical isolates of bacteria, isolated from people in Russia and Spain. Epidemiology and Vaccine Prevention. 2019;17:11&#x2013;18. doi: 10.31631/2073-3046-2018-17-11-18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31631/2073-3046-2018-17-11-18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera D, Santos S, Ferr&#xfa;s J, Barbieri G, Trombelli L, Sanz M. Efficacy of a 0.15% benzydamine hydrochloride and 0.05% cetylpyridinium chloride mouth rinse on 4-day de novo plaque formation. J Clin Periodontol. 2005 Jun;32(6):595&#x2013;603. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-051X.2005.00718.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-051X.2005.00718.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15882217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyski S, Bocian E, Mikucka A, Grzybowska W. Antibacterial activity of selected commercial products for mouth washing and disinfection, assessed in accordance with PN-EN 1040. Med Sci Monit. 2013 Jun;19:458&#x2013;466. doi: 10.12659/MSM.883952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.883952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3692377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23764523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiraishi T, Nakagawa Y. Evaluation of the bactericidal activity of povidone-iodine and commercially available gargle preparations. Dermatology. 2002;204(Suppl 1):37&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1159/000057723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000057723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12011519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaewiad K, Nakpheng T, Srichana T. Dental floss impregnated with povidone-iodine coated with Eudragit L-100 as an antimicrobial delivery system against periodontal-associated pathogens. J Med Microbiol. 2020 Feb;69(2):298&#x2013;308. doi: 10.1099/jmm.0.001126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jmm.0.001126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31976854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulu W, Yimer M, Zenebe Y, Abera B. Common causes of vaginal infections and antibiotic susceptibility of aerobic bacterial isolates in women of reproductive age attending at Felegehiwot Referral Hospital, Ethiopia: a cross sectional study. BMC Womens Health. 2015 May;15:42. doi: 10.1186/s12905-015-0197-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-015-0197-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4438529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25968607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turovskiy Y, Sutyak Noll K, Chikindas ML. The aetiology of bacterial vaginosis. J Appl Microbiol. 2011 May;110(5):1105&#x2013;1128. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2672.2011.04977.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2672.2011.04977.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3072448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21332897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaambo E, Africa C, Chambuso R, Passmore JS. Vaginal Microbiomes Associated With Aerobic Vaginitis and Bacterial Vaginosis. Front Public Health. 2018;6:78. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2018.00078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2018.00078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5879096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29632854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razzak MS, Al-Charrakh AH, Al-Greitty BH. Relationship between lactobacilli and opportunistic bacterial pathogens associated with vaginitis. N Am J Med Sci. 2011 Apr;3(4):185&#x2013;192. doi: 10.4297/najms.2011.3185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4297/najms.2011.3185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3336910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22540089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aly R.  Medical Microbiology. 4th edition. Galveston (TX): University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston; 1996. Microbial infections of skin and nails. Available from:  https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK8301/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21413322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cogen AL, Nizet V, Gallo RL. Skin microbiota: a source of disease or defence? Br J Dermatol. 2008 Mar;158(3):442&#x2013;455. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2133.2008.08437.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2133.2008.08437.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2746716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18275522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichel M, Heisig P, Kohlmann T, Kampf G. Alcohols for skin antisepsis at clinically relevant skin sites. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2009 Nov;53(11):4778&#x2013;4782. doi: 10.1128/AAC.00582-09.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00582-09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19738017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura C. Comparison of the antimicrobial efficacy of povidone-iodine, povidone-iodine-ethanol and chlorhexidine gluconate-ethanol surgical scrubs. Dermatology. 2006;212(Suppl 1):21&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1159/000089195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000089195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16490971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. A guide to clinical management and public health response for hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) 2011.  [accessed Sep 2020].  Available from:  https://iris.wpro.who.int/bitstream/handle/10665.1/5521/9789290615255_eng.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain Khan MA, Anwar KS, Muraduzzaman AKM, Hossain Mollah MA, Akhter-Ul-Alam SM, Munisul Islam K, Hoque SA, Nazrul Islam M, Ali MA. Emerging Hand Foot Mouth Disease in Bangladeshi Children- First Report of Rapid Appraisal on Pocket Outbreak: Clinico-epidemiological Perspective Implicating Public Health Emergency. F1000Res. 2018;7:1156. doi: 10.12688/f1000research.15170.3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/f1000research.15170.3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6662677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31372207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eggers M, Eickmann M, Kowalski K, Zorn J, Reimer K. Povidone-iodine hand wash and hand rub products demonstrated excellent in vitro virucidal efficacy against Ebola virus and modified vaccinia virus Ankara, the new European test virus for enveloped viruses. BMC Infect Dis. 2015 Sep;15:375. doi: 10.1186/s12879-015-1111-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-015-1111-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4574578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26381737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Li Z, Zhang W, Guo P, Ma Z, Chen Q, Du S, Peng J, Deng Y, Hao Y. Hand-Washing: The Main Strategy for Avoiding Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2016 Jun;13(6):610. doi: 10.3390/ijerph13060610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph13060610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4924067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27322307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson DE, Sivalingam V, Kang AEZ, Ananthanarayanan A, Arumugam H, Jenkins TM, Hadjiat Y, Eggers M. Povidone-Iodine Demonstrates Rapid In Vitro Virucidal Activity Against SARS-CoV-2, The Virus Causing COVID-19 Disease. Infect Dis Ther. 2020 Sep;9(3):669&#x2013;675. doi: 10.1007/s40121-020-00316-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40121-020-00316-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7341475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32643111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eggers M, Eickmann M, Zorn J. Rapid and Effective Virucidal Activity of Povidone-Iodine Products Against Middle East Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus (MERS-CoV) and Modified Vaccinia Virus Ankara (MVA) Infect Dis Ther. 2015 Dec;4(4):491&#x2013;501. doi: 10.1007/s40121-015-0091-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40121-015-0091-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4675768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26416214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito H, Ito T, Hikida M, Yashiro J, Otsuka A, Kida H, Otsuki K. Outbreak of highly pathogenic avian influenza in Japan and anti-influenza virus activity of povidone-iodine products. Dermatology. 2006;212(Suppl 1):115&#x2013;118. doi: 10.1159/000089210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000089210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16490988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sriwilaijaroen N, Wilairat P, Hiramatsu H, Takahashi T, Suzuki T, Ito M, Ito Y, Tashiro M, Suzuki Y. Mechanisms of the action of povidone-iodine against human and avian influenza A viruses: its effects on hemagglutination and sialidase activities. Virol J. 2009 Aug;6:124. doi: 10.1186/1743-422X-6-124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-422X-6-124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2739848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19678928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eggers M. Infectious Disease Management and Control with Povidone Iodine. Infect Dis Ther. 2019 Dec;8(4):581&#x2013;593. doi: 10.1007/s40121-019-00260-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40121-019-00260-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6856232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31414403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne DN, Gibson SA, Lewis R. Antiseptics: a forgotten weapon in the control of antibiotic resistant bacteria in hospital and community settings? J R Soc Health. 1998 Feb;118(1):18&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1177/146642409811800105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/146642409811800105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9724934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wewalka G, Kurz C, Enzelsberger H. Genital antisepsis &#x2013; test methodology and efficacy of povidone-iodine. Postgrad Med J. 1993;69(Suppl 3):S43&#x2013;S48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8290457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato-Boku A, Nagano K, Hasegawa Y, Kamimura Y, Sento Y, So M, Kako E, Okuda M, Tachi N, Ito H, Adachi Y, Sobue K. Comparison of disinfection effect between benzalkonium chloride and povidone iodine in nasotracheal intubation: a randomized trial. BMC Anesthesiol. 2019 Aug;19(1):168. doi: 10.1186/s12871-019-0839-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12871-019-0839-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6717375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31470798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinmann J, Paulmann D, Becker B, Bischoff B, Steinmann E, Steinmann J. Comparison of virucidal activity of alcohol-based hand sanitizers versus antimicrobial hand soaps in vitro and in vivo. J Hosp Infect. 2012 Dec;82(4):277&#x2013;280. doi: 10.1016/j.jhin.2012.08.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhin.2012.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23009803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>