<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36609748</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-8798</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>168</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archives of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arch Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Seroprevalence of coxsackievirus A6 and enterovirus A71 infection in humans: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>37</StartPage><MedlinePgn>37</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">37</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00705-022-05642-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) is a common infectious disease in children. Enterovirus A71 (EV-A71) is one of the main pathogens, and coxsackievirus A6 (CVA6) has gradually become the dominant pathogen of HFMD in recent years. This study was conducted mainly to assess the serological prevalence of EV-A71 and CVA6 antibodies in people of different ages, sexes, and regions through a systematic review and meta-analysis. A comprehensive study was performed based on the EV-A71 and CVA6 serological literature published before May 2022. Heterogeneity analysis (Cochrane's Q test and the I<sup>2</sup> statistic) and random effect models were adopted. Subgroup and meta-regression analyses were used to identify potential sources of heterogeneity in the data, and all analysis was performed using STATA version 16.0. This study included 71 studies involving 55,176 people from 13 countries that met the inclusion criteria. The serological prevalence of EV-A71 antibody in different studies was 4.31-88.8%, and that of CVA6 antibody was 40.8-80.9%. Meta-analysis results showed that the serum positive rate for EV-A71 antibody was 45.9% (95% CI: 37.6-54.1%). The rate in the Chinese population was 47.8% (95% CI: 42.4-53.2%), and in the other countries, it was 38% (95% CI: 23-55%). The serum positive rate for CVA6 antibody was 58.3% (95% CI: 46.5-70.2%). The rate in the Chinese population was 49.1% (95% CI: 38.3-59.9%), and in the other countries, it was 68% (95% CI: 51-83%). Subgroup analysis was also conducted. The seroprevalence of EV-A71 and CVA6 antibodies is related to age rather than gender or region. The rates of EV-A71 and CVA6 seropositivity are considerably lower in children younger than five years of age. However, the rates gradually increase with age. The findings of this study suggest that children under five years of age may be susceptible to EV-A71 and CVA6. Thus, safety education and vaccination should be strengthened accordingly. This study provides a basis for understanding the risk factors for EV-A71 and CVA6 infection in China and for deciding how to formulate standard preventive measures to prevent the spread of the virus.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Austria, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Yingying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Jianghan University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Peiqing</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Jianghan University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bai</LastName><ForeName>Yijing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Jianghan University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Xuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Jianghan University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yongjuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8836-5327</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Central Laboratory, The Affiliated Lianyungang Hospital of Xuzhou Medical University, Lianyungang, 222000, Jiangsu, China. lyjquanzhiyuan_09@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2018CFB254</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Hubei Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>BK20180269</GrantID><Agency>Government of Jiangsu Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Austria</Country><MedlineTA>Arch Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7506870</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0304-8608</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000914">Antibodies, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016036" MajorTopicYN="N">Seroepidemiologic Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000914" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Viral</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest relevant to this study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36609748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9825098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00705-022-05642-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00705-022-05642-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xing W, Liao Q, Viboud C, Zhang J, Sun J, Wu JT, Chang Z, Liu F, Fang VJ, Zheng Y, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in china, 2008&#x2013;12: an epidemiological study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2014;14(4):308&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24485991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox B, Levent F. Hand, foot, and mouth disease. JAMA. 2018;320(23):2492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30561482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez G, Carr MJ, Kobayashi M, Hanaoka N, Fujimoto T. Enterovirus-associated hand-foot and mouth disease and neurological complications in japan and the rest of the world. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20(20):5201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6834195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31635198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi Z, Pei S, Suo W, Wang X, Huang Z, Yi A, Wang B, He Z, Wang R, Li Y, et al. Epidemiological characteristics, routine laboratory diagnosis, clinical signs and risk factors for hand, -foot -and -mouth disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2022;17(4):e267716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9049560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35482791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Ren M, Chen S, Nie T, Cui J, Ran L, Li Z. Chang Z (2020) Pathogen spectrum of hand, foot, and mouth disease based on laboratory surveillance - China. China CDC Wkly. 2018;2(11):167&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8393163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34594617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Bae KS, Kim JH, Kang JH, Choi UY. Seroprevalence of neutralizing antibodies against candidate serotypes of enterovirus vaccines among Korean children. Viral Immunol. 2021;34(2):62&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33030408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diarimalala RO, Hu M, Wei Y, Hu K. Recent advances of enterovirus 71 formula: see text] targeting inhibitors. Virol J. 2020;17(1):173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7657364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33176821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamau E, Nguyen D, Celma C, Blomqvist S, Horby P, Simmonds P, Harvala H. Seroprevalence and virologic surveillance of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus a6, United Kingdom, 2006&#x2013;2017. Emerg Infect Dis. 2021;27(9):2261&#x2013;2268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8386771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34423767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Teng Z, Cui X, Li C, Pan H, Zheng Y, Mao S, Yang Y, Wu L, Guo X, et al. Epidemiological and serological surveillance of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Shanghai, China, 2012&#x2013;2016. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2018;7(1):8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5837173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29362406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian L, Wang Y, Yao X, Mao Q, Xu M, Liang Z. Coxsackievirus a6: a new emerging pathogen causing hand, foot and mouth disease outbreaks worldwide. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2015;13(9):1061&#x2013;1071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimmis BD, Downing C, Tyring S. Hand-foot-and-mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus a6 on the rise. Cutis. 2018;102(5):353&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30566537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao M, Apostol LN, de Quiroz-Castro M, Jee Y, Roque VJ, Mapue MN, Navarro FM, Tabada CF, Tandoc AR. Non-polio enteroviruses among healthy children in the Philippines. BMC Public Health. 2020;20(1):167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6998086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32013921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, Shamseer L, Tetzlaff JM, Akl EA, Brennan SE, et al. The prisma 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;10:372n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai MS, Ren Y. Investigation on hfmd recessive infection in healthy population in some community of Shenzhen in 2012. Zhongguo Wei Sheng Jian Yan. 2013;23(10):2355&#x2013;2357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Yi L, Su J, Lu J, Zeng H, Guan D, Ma C, Zhang W, Xiao H, Li H, et al. Seroepidemiology of human enterovirus71 and coxsackievirusa16 among children in Guangdong province China. Bmc Infect Dis. 2013;13:13322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3717138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23855481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Yi L, Su J, Lu J, Ke C, Zeng H, Guan D, Ma C, Zhang W, Xiao H, et al. Seroprevalence of human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus a16 in Guangdong, China, in pre- and post-2010 hfmd epidemic period. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(12):e80515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3850913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24324604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Wang Y. Seroepidemiological study of enterovirus 71 infection in children aged 1 through 6 years in Changzhou in 2006. Pract Prev Med. 2013;20:179&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen XQ, Zhang ZY, Pang HY. Monitoring and analysis of the levels of neutralizing antibody against enterovirus 71 in individuals under the age of 15 in Donghai county. Xian Dai Yu Fang Yi Xue. 2013;40(20):3875&#x2013;3877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y, Gong T, Shi Y, Zhou J, Liu LP, Zeng YW. Seroepidemiology investigation on hev71 in the population in Nanchang in early 2010. Xian Dai Yu Fang Yi Xue. 2013;40(1):7&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W, Ju L, Jiang L, Shen H, Wang Q, Jiang Q. Serum levels of antibody against enterovirus 71 in healthy children at Shanghai in 2011. Chin J Infect Dis. 2013;34:650&#x2013;653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linsuwanon P, Puenpa J, Huang SW, Wang YF, Mauleekoonphairoj J, Wang JR, Poovorawan Y. Epidemiology and seroepidemiology of human enterovirus 71 among Thai populations. J Biomed Sci. 2014;21:2116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3937078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24548776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Xing M, Zhang C, Yang Y, Chi Y, Tang X, Zhang H, Xiong S, Yu L, Zhou D. Neutralizing antibody responses to enterovirus and adenovirus in healthy adults in China. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2014;3(5):e30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4051363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26038738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhmadishina LV, Eremeeva TP, Trotsenko OE, Ivanova OE, Mikhailov MI, Lukashev AN. Seroepidemiology and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in Russia. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(5):e97404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4018281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24819617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>XU Yu-ling YLQJ Seroepidemiological study of enterovirus 71 among healthy children during 2010 to 2012 in Henan province of China. Chin J Viral Dis. 2014;2(4):141&#x2013;143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Wang M, Chang H, Lu J, Lu B, Li J, Chen W, Tang R, Gan L, Zhao J, et al. Prevalence of antibodies against enterovirus 71 in children from Lu'an city in central China. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2011;64(6):528&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22116336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang LW, Phoon MC, Wu Y, Cutter J, James L, Chow VT. The changing seroepidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection among children and adolescents in Singapore. Bmc Infect Dis. 2011;11:11270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21988931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran CB, Nguyen HT, Phan HT, Tran NV, Wills B, Farrar J, Santangelo JD, Simmons CP. The seroprevalence and seroincidence of enterovirus71 infection in infants and children in ho Chi Minh city, Viet nam. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(7):e21116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3134465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21765891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Q, Zhu F, Li L, Li D, Liu Y. Serum epidemiology survey of hev 71 among children in Ganyu county. Jiangsu J Prev Med. 2011;22:224&#x2013;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu KWCLZ. Investigation on enterovirus 71 antibody levels among children in Guangzhou area. Chin J Evid Based Pediatr. 2011;3(6):211&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo R, Deng J, Li Y, Ma Y. Serum epidemiological study of hfmd in handan, 2009. J Pathog Biol. 2011;6:848&#x2013;850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang DX, Yang F, Wang B, Yue LJ, He YX, Song P. Subclinical infection of hand-foot-mouth disease in Shenzhen city. Zhongguo Re Dai Yi Xue. 2011;11(11):1332&#x2013;1333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng-cang Z, Shi-jie Z, Jian-ning Y. Seroepidemiologic investigation of hev 71 among children in Xi&#x2019;ning city. Chin J Public Healt. 2011;27(3):361&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Zhang Y, Gao L, Liu H, Li L, L&#xfc; LK, Yang D. Seroepidemiology investigation of neutralizing antibody against enterovirus 71 among healthy people in Tianjin. Zhonghua Liu Xing Bing Xue Za Zhi. 2011;32(6):568&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21781473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Liang ZL, Meng FY, Zeng Y, Mao QY, Chu K, Song XF, Yao X, Li JX, Ji H, et al. Retrospective study of the incidence of hfmd and seroepidemiology of antibodies against ev71 and coxa16 in prenatal women and their infants. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(5):e37206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3360679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22662137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng M, El KN, Tu S, Ren P, Xu S, Zhu Q, Mo X, Pu D, Wang X, Altmeyer R. Seroepidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection prior to the 2011 season in children in Shanghai. J Clin Virol. 2012;53(4):285&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22265829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji H, Li L, Liu Y, Ge H, Wang X, Hu J, Wu B, Fu J, Zhang Z, Chen X, et al. Seroepidemiology of human enterovirus71 and coxsackievirusa16 in Jiangsu province, China. Virol J. 2012;9:9248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3545860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23102275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang WC, Huang LM, Kao CL, Lu CY, Shao PL, Cheng AL, Fan TY, Chi H, Chang LY. Seroprevalence of enterovirus 71 and no evidence of crossprotection of enterovirus 71 antibody against the other enteroviruses in kindergarten children in Taipei city. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2012;45(2):96&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22154997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HongBin H, HaiTao Z, HuaShu Z, RunLi C. Igg antibody levels in healthy people of Futian district of Shenzhen city. Occupation and Health. 2012;28(24):3107&#x2013;3108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JM, Xu YJ, Wang QY. Investigation of enterovirus 71 antibody levels among children in the Longgang district, city of Shenzhen. Zhongguo Bing Yuan Sheng Wu Xue Za Zhi. 2012;7(12):924&#x2013;926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng HL, Ma SW, Mi B, Wu R, Wang J, Li JB. Survey on enterovirus subclinical infection of healthy children in Xi'an. Yi Xue Lin Chuang Yan Jiu. 2012;29(2):204&#x2013;208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni H, Yi B, Yin J, Fang T, He T, Du Y, Wang J, Zhang H, Xie L, Ding Y, et al. Epidemiological and etiological characteristics of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Ningbo, China, 2008&#x2013;2011. J Clin Virol. 2012;54(4):342&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22652041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu MH. Pathogen composition causing hand foot and mouth disease (hfmd) and seroepidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection in shanghai, china. Fudan University; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi EE, Phoon MC, Ishak B, Chan SH. Seroepidemiology of human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg Infect Dis. 2002;8(9):995&#x2013;997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2732542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12194783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu CY, Lee CY, Kao CL, Shao WY, Lee PI, Twu SJ, Yeh CC, Lin SC, Shih WY, Wu SI, et al. Incidence and case-fatality rates resulting from the 1998 enterovirus 71 outbreak in Taiwan. J Med Virol. 2002;67(2):217&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11992582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, King CC, Hsu KH, Ning HC, Tsao KC, Li CC, Huang YC, Shih SR, Chiou ST, Chen PY, et al. Risk factors of enterovirus 71 infection and associated hand, foot, and mouth disease/herpangina in children during an epidemic in Taiwan. Pediatrics. 2002;109(6):e88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro CM, Cruz AC, Silva EE, Gomes ML. Molecular and seroepidemiologic studies of enterovirus 71 infection in the state of para, Brazil. Rev Inst Med Trop Sao Paulo. 2005;47(2):65&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15880216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou SL, Li LL, He YQ. Serological epidemiology investigation of enterovirus type 71 infection in Shenzhen. J Trop Med. 2007;7(1):66&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo X, Zhu S, Wang D. Seroepidemiology investigation of hev71 in healthy children of 1&#x2013;6 years old in three counties of China in 2005. Zhongguo Yi Miao He Mian Yi. 2009;15(2):141&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20077660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo ST, Chiang PS, Chao AS, Liou GY, Lin R, Lin TY, Lee MS. Enterovirus 71 maternal antibodies in infants, Taiwan. Emerg Infect Dis. 2009;15(4):581&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19331737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diedrich S, Weinbrecht A, Schreier E. Seroprevalence and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in Germany. Arch Virol. 2009;154(7):1139&#x2013;1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19506798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao QY, Yang ZW, Yu X, Jing Q, He P. Epidemic tendency of neutralizing antibody against enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus a 16 in infants in rural area of Kaifeng city, Henan province, China. Chin J Biol. 2009;22(9):911&#x2013;913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao QY, Liao XY, Yu X, Li N, Zhu FC, Zeng Y, Liang ZL, Li FX, Wang JZ, Lu FM, et al. Dynamic change of mother-source neutralizing antibodies against enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus a16 in infants. Chin Med J (Engl) 2010;123(13):1679&#x2013;1684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20819628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabenau HF, Richter M, Doerr HW. Hand, foot and mouth disease: seroprevalence of coxsackie a16 and enterovirus 71 in Germany. Med Microbiol Immunol. 2010;199(1):45&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19941005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, Zhu S, Guo X, Wang J, Wang D, Yan D, Tan X, Tang L, Zhu H, Yang Z, et al. Retrospective seroepidemiology indicated that human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus a16 circulated wildly in central and southern china before large-scale outbreaks from 2008. Virol J. 2010;7:7300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2989968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21050463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gui J, Liu Z, Zhang T, Hua Q, Jiang Z, Chen B, Gu H, Lv H, Dong C. Epidemiological characteristics and spatial-temporal clusters of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Zhejiang province, China, 2008&#x2013;2012. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(9):e139109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4589370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26422015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang LW, Tay J, Phoon MC, Hsu JP, Cutter J, James L, Goh KT, Chow VT. Seroepidemiology of coxsackievirus a6, coxsackievirus a16, and enterovirus 71 infections among children and adolescents in Singapore, 2008&#x2013;2010. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(5):e127999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4444285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26011735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu X, Wang Y, Zhu F, Chen F. Two models for changes of ev71 immunity in infants and young children. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2015;11(6):1429&#x2013;1433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4514399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25906390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NikNadia N, Sam IC, Rampal S, WanNorAmalina W, NurAtifah G, Verasahib K, Ong CC, MohdAdib M, Chan YF. Cyclical patterns of hand, foot and mouth disease caused by enterovirus a71 in Malaysia. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2016;10(3):e4562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4806993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27010319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sanden SM, Koen G, van Eijk H, Koekkoek SM, de Jong MD, Wolthers KC. Prediction of protection against asian enterovirus 71 outbreak strains by cross-neutralizing capacity of serum from Dutch donors, the Netherlands. Emerg Infect Dis. 2016;22(9):1562&#x2013;1569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4994357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27533024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian X, Jiang Z, Ma Q, Liu Q, Lu X, Liu W, Liao X, Zhou R, Su X, Luo Q. Prevalence of neutralizing antibodies to common respiratory viruses in intravenous immunoglobulin and in healthy donors in southern China. J Thorac Dis. 2016;8(5):803&#x2013;812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4842828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27162653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao F, Mao QY, Chen P, Bian LL, Yao X, Li JX, Zhu FC, Liang ZL. Seroepidemiology of coxsackievirus a6, coxsackievirus a16, and enterovirus 71 infections in infants and children: a prospective cohort study in Jiangsu, China. J Infect. 2016;73(5):509&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27546063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horwood PF, Andronico A, Tarantola A, Salje H, Duong V, Mey C, Ly S, Dussart P, Cauchemez S, Buchy P. Seroepidemiology of human enterovirus 71 infection among children, Cambodia. Emerg Infect Dis. 2016;22(1):92&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4696711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26690000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JX, Zhu SL, Wang J, Lin Y, Pei YW, Sun DP, Zhang Y, Wang XJ, Xu WB, Ding SJ. Seroprevalence of enterovirus a71 and coxsackievirus a16 in healthy people in Shandong province, China. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(9):e162373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5017641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27611441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerra JA, Waters A, Kelly A, Morley U, O'Reilly P, O'Kelly E, Dean J, Cunney R, O'Lorcain P, Cotter S, et al. Seroepidemiological and phylogenetic characterization of neurotropic enteroviruses in ireland, 2005&#x2013;2014. J Med Virol. 2017;89(9):1550&#x2013;1558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28071799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Chen Y, Chen X, He Z, Zhu X, Hao Y. Enterovirus 71 neutralizing antibodies seroepidemiological research among children in Guangzhou, China between 2014 and 2015: a cross-sectional study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2017;14(3):319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5369155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28335535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu R, Cheng T, Yin Z, Liu D, Xu L, Li Y, Wang W, Liu J, Que Y, Ye X, et al. Serological survey of neutralizing antibodies to eight major enteroviruses among healthy population. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2018;7(1):2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5837151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29323107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerdsamran H, Prasertsopon J, Mungaomklang A, Klinmalai C, Noisumdaeng P, Sangsiriwut K, Tassaneetrithep B, Guntapong R, Iamsirithaworn S, Puthavathana P. Seroprevalence of antibodies to enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus a16 among people of various age groups in a northeast province of Thailand. Virol J. 2018;15(1):158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6192276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30326914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Yang Z, Wang Z, Xu Y, Luo S, Yu X, Liu J, Zhou Y, Tong W, Zeng P. The surveillance of the epidemiological and serotype characteristics of hand, foot, mouth disease in Neijiang city, China, 2010&#x2013;2017: a retrospective study. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(6):e217474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6553746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31170178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang CQ, Nguyen HD, Ho NX, Vu T, Pham T, Nguyen KT, Nguyen HT, Hoang LT, Clapham H, Nguyen T, et al. Incidence of infection of enterovirus 71 and coxsackieviruses a6 and a16 among household contacts of index cases in dong Thap province, southern Vietnam. Biomed Res Int. 2020 doi: 10.1155/2020/9850351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/9850351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7695493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33274234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puenpa J, Chansaenroj J, Auphimai C, Srimuan D, Thatsanathorn T, Poovorawan Y, Wanlapakorn N. Neutralizing antibody against enterovirus-a71 in thai children: a longitudinal study from birth to age 4 years. Vaccine. 2020;38(48):7638&#x2013;7644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33067033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo FL, Khanh TH, Chung WY, Hung NT, Luo ST, Chang WC, Nhan L, Thinh LQ, Lee MS. Seroprevalence of ev-a71 neutralizing antibodies following the 2011 epidemic in hcmc, vietnam. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2020;14(3):e8124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7077839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32126083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao F, Bian LL, Chen L, Zhou YP, Li GF, Mao QY, He Q, Wu X, Yao SS, Yang XM, et al. A cross-sectional seroepidemiology study of seven major enteroviruses causing hfmd in guangdong, china. J Infect. 2021;83(1):119&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33872666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javadi M, Nejati A, Yousefi M, Mahmoodi M, Shoja Z, Shahmahmoodi S. First seroepidemiological investigation of human enterovirus 71 in iran. Iran J Microbiol. 2021;13(4):502&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8421584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34557279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Boeckel TP, Takahashi S, Liao Q, Xing W, Lai S, Hsiao V, Liu F, Zheng Y, Chang Z, Yuan C, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in china: critical community size and spatial vaccination strategies. Sci Rep. 2016 doi: 10.1038/srep25248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep25248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4850478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27125917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Jiang L, Zhang C, He W, Tan Y, Ning C. The changes in the epidemiology of hand, foot, and mouth disease after the introduction of the ev-a71 vaccine. Vaccine. 2021;39(25):3319&#x2013;3323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33994239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honkanen H, Oikarinen S, Pakkanen O, Ruokoranta T, Pulkki MM, Laitinen OH, Tauriainen S, Korpela S, Lappalainen M, Vuorinen T, et al. Human enterovirus 71 strains in the background population and in hospital patients in finland. J Clin Virol. 2013;56(4):348&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23261080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witso E, Palacios G, Ronningen KS, Cinek O, Janowitz D, Rewers M, Grinde B, Lipkin WI. Asymptomatic circulation of hev71 in norway. Virus Res. 2007;123(1):19&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16965832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P, Chen Y, Tang A, Gao F, Yan JB. Seroprevalence of coxsackievirus a16 antibody among people of various age groups: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Public Health. 2021;79(1):166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8447778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34535186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>