<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16204506</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Concentrations of pathogens and indicators in animal feces in the Sydney watershed.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5929</StartPage><EndPage>5934</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5929-34</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>A fecal analysis survey was undertaken to quantify animal inputs of pathogenic and indicator microorganisms in the temperate watersheds of Sydney, Australia. The feces from a range of domestic animals and wildlife were analyzed for the indicator bacteria fecal coliforms and Clostridium perfringens spores, the pathogenic protozoa Cryptosporidium and Giardia, and the enteric viruses adenovirus, enterovirus, and reovirus. Pathogen and fecal indicator concentrations were generally higher in domestic animal feces than in wildlife feces. Future studies to quantify potential pathogen risks in drinking-water watersheds should thus focus on quantifying pathogen loads from domestic animals and livestock rather than wildlife.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cox</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ecowise Environmental, P.O. Box 1834, Fyshwick, ACT 2609, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Griffith</LastName><ForeName>Merran</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Angles</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deere</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferguson</LastName><ForeName>Christobel</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000829" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals, Domestic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000835" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals, Wild</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001315" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Australia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002415" MajorTopicYN="N">Cats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002417" MajorTopicYN="N">Cattle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003016" MajorTopicYN="N">Clostridium perfringens</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003458" MajorTopicYN="N">Cryptosporidium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004285" MajorTopicYN="N">Dogs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004755" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterobacteriaceae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005243" MajorTopicYN="N">Feces</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005618" MajorTopicYN="N">Fresh Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005872" MajorTopicYN="N">Giardia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013171" MajorTopicYN="N">Spores, Bacterial</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014780" MajorTopicYN="N">Viruses</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014881" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water Supply</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16204506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1265995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.10.5929-5934.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">71/10/5929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>APHA. 1998. Standard methods for the examination of water and wastewater, 20th ed. American Public Health Association, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aramini, J. J., C. Stephen, J. P. Dubey, C. Engelstoft, H. Schwanthje, and C. S. Ribble. 1999. Potential contamination of drinking water with Toxoplasma gondii oocysts. Epidemiol. Infect. 122:305-315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2809621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10355797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atwill, E. R., S. M. Camargo, R. Phillips, L. H. Alonso, K. W. Tate, W. A. Jensen, J. Bennet, S. Little, and T. P. Salmon. 2001. Quantitative shedding of two genotypes of Cryptosporidium parvum in California ground squirrels (Spermophilus beecheyi). Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 67:2840-2843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11375204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atwill, E. R., J. A. Harp, T. Jones, P. W. Jardon, S. Checel, and M. Zylstra. 1998. Evaluation of periparturient dairy cows and contact surfaces as a reservoir of Cryptosporidium parvum for calfhood infection. Am. J. Vet. Res. 59:1116-1121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9736387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atwill, E. R., B. Hoar, M. das Gracas Cabral Pereira, K. W. Tate, F. Rulofson, and G. Nader. 2003. Improved quantitative estimates of low environmental loading and sporadic periparturient shedding of Cryptosporidium parvum in adult beef cattle. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 69:4604-4610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC169081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12902248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atwill, E. R., E. M. Johnson, and M. das Gracas Cabral Pereira. 1999. Association of herd composition, stocking rate, and duration of calving season with fecal shedding of Cryptosporidium parvum oocysts in beef herds. J. Am. Vet. Med. Assoc. 215:1833-1838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10613218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atwill, E. R., N. K. McDougald, and L. Perea. 2000. Cross-sectional study of faecal shedding of Giardia duodenalis and Cryptosporidium parvum among packstock in the Sierra Nevada Range. Equine Vet. J. 32:247-252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10836481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalmers, R. M., A. P. Sturdee, S. A. Bull, A. Miller, and S. E. Wright. 1997. The prevalence of Cryptosporidium parvum and C. muris in Mus domesticus, Apodemus sylvaticus and Clethrionomys glareolus in an agricultural system. Parasitol. Res. 83:478-482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9197396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies, C. M., C. Kaucner, D. D. Deere, and N. J. Ashbolt. 2003. Recovery and enumeration of Cryptosporidium parvum from animal fecal matrices. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 69:2842-2847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC154511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12732556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies, C. M., J. A. H. Long, M. Donald, and N. J. Ashbolt. 1995. Survival of fecal microorganisms in marine and freshwater sediments. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 61:1888-1896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7646026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emerson, D. J., and V. J. Cabelli. 1982. Extraction of Clostridium perfringens spores from bottom sediment samples. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 44:1144-1149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC242160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6295278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enemark, H. L., P. Ahrens, C. J. Lowery, S. M. Thamsborg, J. M. D. Enemark, V. Bille-Hansen, and P. Lind. 2002. Cryptosporidium andersoni from a Danish cattle herd: identification and preliminary characterisation. Vet. Parasitol. 107:37-49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12072212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayer, R., J. M. Trout, T. K. Graczyk, and E. J. Lewis. 2000. Prevalence of Cryptosporidium, Giardia and Eimeria infections in post-weaned and adult cattle on three Maryland farms. Vet. Parasitol. 93:103-112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11035228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson, C. M. 1994. Faecal indicators and pathogens in water and sediment of the Georges River, Sydney. M.S. thesis. University of Technology, Sydney, Australia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson, C. M., N. J. Ashbolt, and D. A. Deere. 2004. Prioritisation of catchment management in the Sydney catchment&#x2014;construction of a pathogen budget. Water Sci. Technol. Water Supply 4:35-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser, R. H., P. K. Barten, and D. A. K. Pinney. 1998. Predicting stream pathogen loading from livestock using a geographical information system-based delivery model. J. Environ. Qual. 27:935-945.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginsberg, H. S. 1980. Reoviruses and epidemic acute gastroenteritis, p. 1205-1216. In B. D. Davis, R. Dulbecco, H. N. Eisen, and H. S. Ginsberg (ed.), Microbiology, 3rd ed. Harper and Row, Philadelphia, Pa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graczyk, T. K., B. M. Evans, C. J. Shiff, H. J. Karreman, and J. A. Patz. 2000. Environmental and geographical factors contributing to watershed contamination with Cryptosporidium parvum oocysts. Environ. Res. 82:263-271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10702335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graczyk, T. K., R. Fayer, J. M. Trout, E. J. Lewis, C. A. Farley, I. Sulaiman, and A. A. Lal. 1998. Giardia sp. cysts and infectious Cryptosporidium parvum oocysts in the feces of migratory Canada geese (Branta canadensis). Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 64:2736-2738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC106456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9647860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heitman, T. L., L. M. Frederick, J. R. Viste, N. J. Guselle, U. M. Morgan, R. C. A. Thompson, and M. E. Olson. 2002. Prevalence of Giardia and Cryptosporidium and characterization of Cryptosporidium spp. isolated from wildlife, human, and agricultural sources in the North Saskatchewan River Basin in Alberta, Canada. Can. J. Microbiol. 48:530-541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12166680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helsel, D. R., and R. M. Hirsch. 1992. Statistical methods in water resources. Elsevier, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan, U. M., J. R. Buddle, A. Armson, A. Elliot, and R. C. A. Thompson. 1999. Molecular and biological characterisation of Cryptosporidium in pigs. Aust. Vet. J. 77:44-47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10028394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan, U. M., L. Xiao, R. Fayer, A. A. Lal, and R. C. A. Thompson. 1999. Variation in Cryptosporidium: towards a taxonomic revision of the genus. Int. J. Parasitol. 29:1733-1751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10616920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson, M. E., J. Goh, M. Phillips, N. Guselle, and T. A. McAllister. 1999. Giardia cyst and Cryptosporidium oocyst survival in water, soil, and cattle feces. J. Environ. Qual. 28:1991-1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson, M. E., N. J. Guselle, R. M. O'Handley, M. L. Swift, T. A. McAllister, M. D. Jelinski, and D. W. Morck. 1997. Giardia and Cryptosporidium in dairy calves in British Columbia. Can. Vet. J. 38:703-706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1576818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9360789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson, M. E., C. L. Thorlakson, L. Deselliers, D. W. Morck, and T. A. McAllister. 1997. Giardia and Cryptosporidium in Canadian farm animals. Vet. Parasitol. 68:375-381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9106959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega-Mora, L. N., J. A. Requejo-Fernandez, M. Pilar-Izquierdo, and J. Pereira-Bueno. 1999. Role of adult sheep in transmission of infection by Cryptosporidium parvum to lambs: confirmation of periparturient rise. Int. J. Parasitol. 29:1261-1268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10576577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Power, M. L., M. B. Slade, S. R. Shanker, N. C. Sangster, and D. A. Veal. 2004. Cryptosporidium in Eastern grey kangaroos Macropus giganteus, p. 207-209. In R. C. A. Thompson (ed.), Cryptosporidium: from molecules to disease. Elsevier, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston, B. J., T. A. McAllister, and M. E. Olson. 2003. Prevalence and infection pattern of naturally acquired giardiasis and cryptosporidiosis in range beef calves and their dams. Vet. Parasitol. 114:113-122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12781473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standards Australia. 2000. Water microbiology&#x2014;spores of sulfite reducing anaerobes (clostridia) including Clostridium perfringens: membrane filtration method. Standards Australia, Sydney, Australia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturdee, A. P., A. T. Bodley-Tickell, A. Archer, and R. M. Chalmers. 2003. Long-term study of Cryptosporidium prevalence on a lowland farm in the United Kingdom. Vet. Parasitol. 116:97-113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14519315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, Y. Q., P. Gong, J. D. Radke, and J. Scarborough. 2002. Spatial and temporal modeling of microbial contaminants on grazing farmlands. J. Environ. Qual. 31:860-869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12026089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environment Protection Agency. 1999. Method 1623: Cryptosporidium and Giardia in water by filtration. IMS/IFA EPA-821-R99-006. Office of Water, U.S. Environment Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warnecke, M., C. Weir, and G. Vesey. 2003. Evaluation of an internal positive control for Cryptosporidium and Giardia testing in water samples. Lett. Appl. Microbiol. 37:244-248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12904227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, L. H., R. P. Herd, and G. L. Bowman. 1994. Prevalence of Cryptosporidium and Giardia infections on two Ohio pig farms with different management systems. Vet. Parasitol. 52:331-336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8073616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>