<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">22039330</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2219-2840</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>36</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of gastroenterology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Viral kinetics of enterovirus 71 in human abdomyosarcoma cells.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4135</StartPage><EndPage>4142</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4135-42</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3748/wjg.v17.i36.4135</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To characterise the viral kinetics of enterovirus 71 (EV71).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this study, human rhabdomyosarcoma (RD) cells were infected with EV71 at different multiplicity of infection (MOI). After infection, the cytopathic effect (CPE) was monitored and recorded using a phase contrast microscope associated with a CCD camera at different time points post viral infection (0, 6, 12, 24 h post infection). Cell growth and viability were measured by 3-(4,5-dimethylthiazol-2-yl)-2,5-diphenyltetrazolium bromide (MTT) assay in both EV71 infected and mock infected cells at each time point. EV71 replication kinetics in RD cells was determined by measuring the total intracellular viral RNA with real-time reverse-transcription polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR). Also, the intracellular and extracellular virion RNA was isolated and quantified at different time points to analyze the viral package and secretion. The expression of viral protein was determined by analyze the levels of viral structure protein VP1 with Western blotting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">EV71 infection induced a significant CPE as early as 6 h post infection (p.i.) in both RD cells infected with high ratio of virus (MOI 10) and low ratio of virus (MOI 1). In EV71 infected cells, the cell growth was inhibited and the number of viable cells was rapidly decreased in the later phase of infection. EV71 virions were uncoated immediately after entry. The intracellular viral RNA began to increase at as early as 3 h p.i. and the exponential increase was found between 3 h to 6 h p.i. in both infected groups. For viral structure protein synthesis, results from western-blot showed that intracellular viral protein VP1 could not be detected until 6 h p.i. in the cells infected at either MOI 1 or MOI 10; and reached the peak at 9 h p.i. in the cells infected with EV71 at both MOI 1 and MOI 10. Simultaneously, the viral package and secretion were also actively processed as the virus underwent rapid replication. The viral package kinetics was comparable for both MOI 1 and MOI 10 infected groups. It was observed that at 3 h p.i, the intracellular virions obviously decreased, thereafter, the intracellular virions began to increase and enter into the exponential phase until 12 h p.i. The total amounts of intracellular virons were decreased from 12 to 24 h p.i. Consistent with this result, the increase of virus secretion occurred during 6 to 12 h p.i.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The viral kinetics of EV71 were established by analyzing viral replication, package and secretion in RD cells.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stanley Ho Center for Emerging Infectious Diseases, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Ya-Qing</ForeName><Initials>YQ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yi</LastName><ForeName>Li-Na</ForeName><Initials>LN</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zan</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kung</LastName><ForeName>Hsiang-Fu</ForeName><Initials>HF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Ming-Liang</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Gastroenterol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1007-9327</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014764">Viral Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002470" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Survival</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012208" MajorTopicYN="N">Rhabdomyosarcoma</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014407" MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor Cells, Cultured</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014764" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000096" MajorTopicYN="N">biosynthesis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014779" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Replication</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quantitative reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Viral kinetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Western blotting</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2011</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22039330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3203367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v17.i36.4135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fowlkes AL, Honarmand S, Glaser C, Yagi S, Schnurr D, Oberste MS, Anderson L, Pallansch MA, Khetsuriani N. Enterovirus-associated encephalitis in the California encephalitis project, 1998-2005. J Infect Dis. 2008;198:1685&#x2013;1691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18959496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamaguchi T, Fujisawa H, Sakai K, Okino S, Kurosaki N, Nishimura Y, Shimizu H, Yamada M. Acute encephalitis caused by intrafamilial transmission of enterovirus 71 in adult. Emerg Infect Dis. 2008;14:828&#x2013;830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2600258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18439374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishimaru Y, Nakano S, Yamaoka K, Takami S. Outbreaks of hand, foot, and mouth disease by enterovirus 71. High incidence of complication disorders of central nervous system. Arch Dis Child. 1980;55:583&#x2013;588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1627055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6254449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2002;26:91&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SW, Hsu YW, Smith DJ, Kiang D, Tsai HP, Lin KH, Wang SM, Liu CC, Su IJ, Wang JR. Reemergence of enterovirus 71 in 2008 in taiwan: dynamics of genetic and antigenic evolution from 1998 to 2008. J Clin Microbiol. 2009;47:3653&#x2013;3662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19776232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Ren L, Xiong Z, Li J, Xiao Y, Zhao R, He Y, Bu G, Zhou S, Wang J, et al. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in the People&#x2019;s Republic of China in 2008. J Clin Microbiol. 2009;47:2351&#x2013;2352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2708525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar S, Chee HY, Al-Kobaisi MF, Xiaoshan J, Chua KB, Lam SK. Identification of enterovirus 71 isolates from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) with fatal cases of encephalomyelitis in Malaysia. Virus Res. 1999;61:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10426204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P, Lindsay K, Perera D, Chan HM, Chan KP, Cardosa MJ. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J Virol. 2001;75:7732&#x2013;7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bible JM, Iturriza-Gomara M, Megson B, Brown D, Pantelidis P, Earl P, Bendig J, Tong CY. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 in the United Kingdom from 1998 to 2006. J Clin Microbiol. 2008;46:3192&#x2013;3200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2566106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18650362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Chow VT, Phoon MC, Chan KP, Poh CL. Direct detection of enterovirus 71 (EV71) in clinical specimens from a hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak in Singapore by reverse transcription-PCR with universal enterovirus and EV71-specific primers. J Clin Microbiol. 2002;40:2823&#x2013;2827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12149336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muir P, K&#xe4;mmerer U, Korn K, Mulders MN, P&#xf6;yry T, Weissbrich B, Kandolf R, Cleator GM, van Loon AM. Molecular typing of enteroviruses: current status and future requirements. The European Union Concerted Action on Virus Meningitis and Encephalitis. Clin Microbiol Rev. 1998;11:202&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC121380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9457433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Yamashita Y, Li J, Hanagata N, Minowa T, Takemura T, Koike S. Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat Med. 2009;15:798&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoll J, Heus HA, van Kuppeveld FJ, Melchers WJ. The structure-function relationship of the enterovirus 3&#x2019;-UTR. Virus Res. 2009;139:209&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18706945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrmann E, Lee JH, Marinos G, Modi M, Zeuzem S. Effect of ribavirin on hepatitis C viral kinetics in patients treated with pegylated interferon. Hepatology. 2003;37:1351&#x2013;1358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12774014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layden-Almer JE, Ribeiro RM, Wiley T, Perelson AS, Layden TJ. Viral dynamics and response differences in HCV-infected African American and white patients treated with IFN and ribavirin. Hepatology. 2003;37:1343&#x2013;1350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12774013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeuzem S, Herrmann E, Lee JH, Fricke J, Neumann AU, Modi M, Colucci G, Roth WK. Viral kinetics in patients with chronic hepatitis C treated with standard or peginterferon alpha2a. Gastroenterology. 2001;120:1438&#x2013;1447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11313314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belsham GJ, Normann P. Dynamics of picornavirus RNA replication within infected cells. J Gen Virol. 2008;89:485&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18198379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger D, Bienz K. Intracellular location and translocation of silent and active poliovirus replication complexes. J Gen Virol. 2005;86:707&#x2013;718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15722531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen BJ, Audet S, Andrews N, Beeler J. Plaque reduction neutralization test for measles antibodies: Description of a standardised laboratory method for use in immunogenicity studies of aerosol vaccination. Vaccine. 2007;26:59&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18063236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi L, He Y, Chen Y, Kung HF, He ML. Potent inhibition of human enterovirus 71 replication by type I interferon subtypes. Antivir Ther. 2011;16:51&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21311108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong WF, Chow VT. Transcriptomic and proteomic analyses of rhabdomyosarcoma cells reveal differential cellular gene expression in response to enterovirus 71 infection. Cell Microbiol. 2006;8:565&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7162300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16548883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Stollar V, Lin JY, Chang SC, Chen GW, Li ML. Identification of genes involved in the host response to enterovirus 71 infection. J Neurovirol. 2004;10:293&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kok TW, Pryor T, Payne L. Comparison of rhabdomyosarcoma, buffalo green monkey kidney epithelial, A549 (human lung epithelial) cells and human embryonic lung fibroblasts for isolation of enteroviruses from clinical samples. J Clin Virol. 1998;11:61&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9784144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>She RC, Crist G, Billetdeaux E, Langer J, Petti CA. Comparison of multiple shell vial cell lines for isolation of enteroviruses: a national perspective. J Clin Virol. 2006;37:151&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16884950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson ES, Xing L, Cheng RH, Shafren DR. Enhanced cellular receptor usage by a bioselected variant of coxsackievirus a21. J Virol. 2004;78:12603&#x2013;12612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC525059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15507647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Ruiz M, Navarro-Mar&#xed; JM, Palacios del Valle E, Rosa-Fraile M. Human rhabdomyosarcoma cells for rapid detection of enteroviruses by shell-vial assay. J Med Microbiol. 2003;52:789&#x2013;791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12909656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pliaka V, Dedepsidis E, Kyriakopoulou Z, Papadi G, Tsakogiannis D, Pratti A, Levidiotou-Stefanou S, Markoulatos P. Growth kinetic analysis of bi-recombinant poliovirus vaccine strains. Virus Genes. 2010;40:200&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20091423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LC, Shyu HW, Chen SH, Lei HY, Yu CK, Yeh TM. Enterovirus 71 infection induces Fas ligand expression and apoptosis of Jurkat cells. J Med Virol. 2006;78:780&#x2013;786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16628611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang CC, Sun MJ, Lei HY, Chen SH, Yu CK, Liu CC, Wang JR, Yeh TM. Human endothelial cell activation and apoptosis induced by enterovirus 71 infection. J Med Virol. 2004;74:597&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15484266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SC, Lin JY, Lo LY, Li ML, Shih SR. Diverse apoptotic pathways in enterovirus 71-infected cells. J Neurovirol. 2004;10:338&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15765805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>