<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36226004</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2229-5178</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Season>May-Jun</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Indian dermatology online journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Indian Dermatol Online J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease: A Single Centre Retrospective Study of 403 New Cases and Brief Review of Relevant Indian Literature to Understand Clinical, Epidemiological, and Virological Attributes of a Long-Lasting Indian Epidemic.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>310</StartPage><EndPage>320</EndPage><MedlinePgn>310-320</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/idoj.idoj_701_21</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There have been sporadic and periodic large-scale epidemics of hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) with cases at risk for significant morbidity and mortality particularly in Southeast Asia since 1997 and in India since early 2003.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We retrospectively studied 403 cases recorded from 2009 to 2019 and reviewed relevant Indian literature published between 2004 and 2019 to understand clinical, epidemiological, and virological attributes of this long-lasting Indian epidemic.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There were 96.8% children and adolescents (M:F 1.6:1) aged 2 months to 18 years and 84% were aged &lt;5 years. Adult family contacts comprised 3.2%. Only 12 sporadic cases occurred during 2009-2011 followed by increased number from 2012 to 2015 peaking with 30.8% cases in 2013 and declining slowly until the year 2019 with small resurge in 2018. The major peaks occurred during summers with small peaks in autumns. Literature review showed 3332 cases presenting between 2004 and 2019 across Indian states with similar epidemiological trends whereas serotyping identified Coxsackievirus A16 (CV A16) in 83%, Coxsackievirus A6 (CV A6) in 17%, Enterovirus 71 in 4.1%, and multiple strains in 11.7% samples, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The overall features of this long-lasting HFMD epidemic; affecting children aged &lt;5 years more often than adults, none or minimum neurological or pulmonary complications in few patients, peaks occurring during summer and autumn months, and identity of the pathogenic virus coincide with global trends. However, the continuous spread of the disease across the country appears in sync with pre-epidemic periods of China and Taiwan. It calls for a continuous surveillance and making HFMD a notifiable disease in India.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2022 Indian Dermatology Online Journal.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Anuj</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Venereology and Leprosy, Dr. Rajendra Prasad Government Medical College, Kangra (Tanda), Himachal Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahajan</LastName><ForeName>Vikram K</ForeName><Initials>VK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Venereology and Leprosy, Dr. Rajendra Prasad Government Medical College, Kangra (Tanda), Himachal Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehta</LastName><ForeName>Karaninder S</ForeName><Initials>KS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Venereology and Leprosy, Dr. Rajendra Prasad Government Medical College, Kangra (Tanda), Himachal Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chauhan</LastName><ForeName>Pushpinder S</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Venereology and Leprosy, Dr. Rajendra Prasad Government Medical College, Kangra (Tanda), Himachal Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manvi</LastName><ForeName>Sujaya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Venereology and Leprosy, Dr. Rajendra Prasad Government Medical College, Kangra (Tanda), Himachal Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chauhan</LastName><ForeName>Amit</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Venereology and Leprosy, Dr. Rajendra Prasad Government Medical College, Kangra (Tanda), Himachal Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Indian Dermatol Online J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101586880</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2229-5178</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coxsackievirus A16</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HFMD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">India</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Southeast Asia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coxsackievirus A6</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">onychomadesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viral infection</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36226004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9549533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/idoj.idoj_701_21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IDOJ-13-310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>He SZ, Chen MY, Xu XR, Yan Q, Niu JJ, Wu WH, et al. Epidemics and aetiology of hand, foot and mouth disease in Xiamen, China, from 2008 to 2015. Epidemiol Infect. 2017;145:1865&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9203317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28367766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogi M, Yano Y, Chikahira M, Takai D, Oshibe T, Arashiro T, et al. Characterization of genome sequences and clinical features of coxsackievirus A6 strains collected in Hyogo, Japan in 1999&#x2013;2013. J Med Virol. 2017;89:1395&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28229467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaminska K, Martinetti G, Lucchini R, Kaya G, Mainetti C. Coxsackievirus A6 and hand, foot and mouth disease:Three case reports of familial child-to-immunocompetent adult transmission and a literature review. Case Rep Dermatol. 2013;5:203&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3764954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24019771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, Zhu S, Guo X, Wang J, Wang D, Yan D, et al. Retrospective seroepidemiology indicated that human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 circulated wildly in central and southern China before large scale outbreaks from 2008. Virol J. 2010;7:300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2989968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21050463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B, Sumi A, Toyoda S, Hu Q, Zhou D, Mise K, et al. Time series analysis of reported cases of hand, foot, and mouth disease from 2010 to 2013 in Wuhan, China. BMC Infect Dis. 2015;15:495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4630926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26530702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO):Western Pacific Region, A guide to clinical management and public health response for hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) 2011.  [Last accessed on 2019 Dec 01].  Available from:http://www.wpro.who.int/publications/docs/GuidancefortheclinicalmanagementofHFMD.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua K, Kasri A. Hand foot and mouth disease due to enterovirus 71 in Malaysia. Virol Sin. 2011;26:221&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8222466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21847753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu K-H, Twu S-J, Chen K-T, Tsai S-F, et al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan enterovirus epidemic working group. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:929&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Yeo A, Phoon MC, Tan EL, Poh CL, Quak SH, et al. The largest outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore in 2008:The role of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A strains. Int J Infect Dis. 2010;14:e1076&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20952237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu WD, Ji H, Shan J, Bao J, Sun Y, Li J, et al. Spatiotemporal dynamics of hand-foot-mouth disease and its relationship with meteorological factors in Jiangsu Province, China. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0131311. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0131311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4488144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26121573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhu Z, Yang W, Ren J, Tan X, Wang Y, et al. An emerging recombinant human enterovirus 71 responsible for the 2008 outbreak of hand foot and mouth disease in Fuyang city of China. Virol J. 2010;7:94. doi:10.1186/1743-422X-7-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20459851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasidhran CK, Sugathan P, Agarwal R, Khare S, Lal S, Jayaram Paniker CK. Hand-foot and mouth disease in Calicot. Indian J Pediatr. 2005;72:17&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15684442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma N, Sarkar A, Mukherjee A, Ghosh A, Dhar S, Malakar R. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease in West Bengal, India in August 2007:A multicentric study. Indian J Dermatol. 2009;54:26&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2800866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20049265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwibedi B, Kar BR, Kar SK. Hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD):A newly emerging infection in Orissa, India. National Med J India. 2010;23:313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21250593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias E, Dias M. Recurring hand foot mouth disease in a child. Ann Trop Med Public Health. 2012;5:40&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas J. Hand foot and mouth disease-an overview. e-J Indian Soc Teledermatol. 2009;3:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta KIS, Mahajan VK. Hand foot and mouth disease. Indian Pediatr. 2010;47:345&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20431163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Media alert from Media &amp;Verification Cell,Hand-foot and mouth disease cases on rise in Baramulla district, Jammu and Kashmir, 300 children affected. Integrated Disease Surveillance Program-National Centre for Disease Control (IDSP-NCD) report (ID JK/KLM/2-16/18/980) dated 07.05.2016 submitted to Ministry of Health &amp;Family Welfare, Government of India.  Available from:https://idsp.nic.in/WriteReadData/Media_Alert_May-2018/4658.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Media alert from Media &amp;Verification Cell, Disease alerts/outbreaks reported and responded to by states/UTs through Integrated Disease Surveillance Programme, Integrated Disease Surveillance Program-National Centre for Disease Control (IDSP-NCD) report (ID JK/LDK/2016/18/981) dated 07.05.2016 submitted to Ministry of Health &amp;Family Welfare, Government of India.  Available from:https://idsp.nic.in/WriteReadData/l892s/72914162941466750136.pdf .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadri SM, Kincaid J, Williams L, Riley C, Rehana K, Hinton T, et al. Epidemic investigation of the largest outbreak of hand foot and mouth disease (HFMD) in Leh, India. J Fam Med Primary Care. 2019;8 only abstract available.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashyap S, Verma GK. Hand-foot-mouth disease:Outbreak in Shimla. Indian Pediatr. 2014;51:155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24632702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma R, Manvi S. Hand, foot and mouth disease-case reports of familial child to immunocompetent adult transmission. J Med Sci Clin Res. 2018;6:32085&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal N, Mittal A, Kayal A, Khare AK, Kuldeep CM, Gupta AK. Outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Udaipur. Indian J Dermatol. 2015;60:108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4318054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25657448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanda C, Singh R, Rana SK. An outbreak of hand&#x2013;foot&#x2013;mouth disease:A report from the hills of northern India. Natl Med J India. 2015;28:126&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26724340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahota R, Kaur N, Singh G, Upadhyay N. Study the current scenario of hand foot mouth disease an Indian prospective. Int J Contemp Pediatr. 2020;7:1558&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh SK, Bandyopadhyay D, Ghosh A, Dutta A, Biswas S, Mandal RK, et al. Mucocutaneous features of hand, foot, and mouth disease:A reappraisal from an outbreak in city of Kolkata. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2010;76:564&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20827002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma N. Relapse in hand, foot and mouth disease:Are we at more risk. Indian J Dermatol. 2013;58:78&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3555383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23372222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nag SS, Dutta A, Mandal RK. Delayed cutaneous findings of hand, foot, and mouth disease. Indian Pediatr. 2016;53:42&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26840671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma N, Chakraborty S, Dutta A, Chandra S. Hand, foot and mouth disease in West Bengl, India:A preliminary report on clinicovirological trend over 3 successive years (2013-2015) Indian J Dermatol. 2017;62:486&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5618835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28979010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora S, Arora G, Tewari V. Hand foot and mouth disease:Emerging epidemics. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2008;74:503&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19052420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borkakoty B, Das M, Jakharia A, Bhattacharya C, Bora C, Baruah PJ, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease caused by Coxsackie viruses A6 and A16 in Assam, Northeast India:A need for surveillance. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2020;86:105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30860171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R, Diwan N, Nair P. Hand, foot, and mouth disease:A case series from rural set up of Gujarat. Indian J Paediatr Dermatol. 2016;17:290&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar BR, Dwibedi B, Kar SK. An outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Bhubaneswar, Odisha. Indian Pediatr. 2013;50:139&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22728634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sane S, Saboo N, Utage V. Observations regarding outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease at Thane, Maharashtra. Pediatr Infect Dis. 2009;1:64&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dharmapalan D, Saxena VK, Pawar SD, Qureshi TH, Surve P. Clinical and molecular investigations of hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in Navi Mumbai, India. Indian Pediatr. 2019;56:1052&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31884439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena VK, Pawar SD, Qureshi THIH, Surve P, Yadav P, Nabi F, et al. Isolation and molecular characterization of coxsackievirus A6 and coxsackievirus A16 from a case of recurrent hand, foot and mouth disease in Mumbai, Maharashtra, India, 2018. Virus Dis. 2020;31:56&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7085487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32206699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganorkar NN, Fulmali PP, Tikute SS, Gopalkrishna V. Genetic characterization of enterovirus strains identified in hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD):Emergence of B1c, A, C1 subgenotypes of CVA16, CVA6, and EV71 strains in India. Infect Genet Evolution. 2017;54:192&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28577914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damle DK. Oral acyclovir for severe hand, foot and mouth disease. Indian J Drugs Dermatol. 2018;4:73&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalkrishna V, Ganorkar NN. Epidemiological and molecular characteristics of circulating Coxsackievirus A16 (CVA16), Coxsackievirus A6 (CVA6) strains and genotype distribution in hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) cases in 2017-18 from Western India. J Med Virol. 2021;93:3572&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32833231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saoji VA. Hand, foot and mouth disease in Nagpur. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2008;74:133&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18388372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar VS, Budur SV, Odappa GH, Bankolli SY, Rao AP. Clinical profile of hand, foot, and mouth disease and its associated complications among children in Shimoga City, southern Karnataka:A hospital based study. Indian J Public Health. 2015;59:141&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26021653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha DP, Raut CG, Jayaprakash H, Hanumaiah H, Shaikh NJ, Manjunatha MJ. Molecular diagnosis of enteroviruses associated with hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) Indian J Pediatr. 2014;81:1242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durga RC, Jagadeesh NR, Padmanabha MP, Ananda Babu M, Jean-Luc B. Large-scale HFMD epidemics caused by coxsackievirus A16 in Bangalore, India during 2013 and 2015. Infect Genet Evolution. 2017;55:228&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28864155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao PK, Veena KM, Jagadishchandra H, Bhat SS, Shetty SR. Hand, foot and mouth disease:Changing Indian scenario. Int J Clin Pediatr Dent. 2012;5:220&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4155884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25206173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao R, Hegde S, Suvarna R, Babu S. Hand foot and mouth disease:A case report from India. J Cranio Max Dis. 2013;2:75&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashyap R-R, Kashyap RS. Hand, foot and mouth disease - a short case report. J Clin Exp Dent. 2015;7:e336&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4483348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26155357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sankar AJS, Samatha Y, Ravi Kiran A, Poornachandra N. Hand foot and mouth disease. J Bioengineer Biomed Sci. 2015;5:137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vani T, Nageswaramma S, Mudavath SR, Ranen DR, Kumar BS, Sagar GP. Clinico-epidemiological study of hand foot &amp;mouth disease. Nat J Res Commun Med. 2019;8:70&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muppa R, Bhupatiraju P, Duddu M, Dandempally A. Hand, foot and mouth disease. J Indian Soc Pedod Prev Dent. 2011;29:165&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21911958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar KB, Kiran AG, Kumar BU. Hand, foot and mouth disease in children:A clinico epidemiological study. Indian J Paediatr Dermatol. 2016;17:7&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagaraju K, Pushkar R, Regalla RR. A Clinico epidemiological study of hand, foot and mouth disease in a tertiary care hospital of tribal area. J Cont Med A Dent. 2019;7:41&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathew B, Thomas S, Velayudhan V, Prasanna R. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in adults:An enigma among diagnosticians - A case series. J Indian Acad Oral Med Radiol. 2015;27:616&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabitha S, Sasidharanpillai S, Sanjay RE, Binitha MP, Riyaz N, Muhammed K, et al. Clinical profile and virology analysis of hand, foot and mouth disease cases from North Kerala, India in 2015&#x2013;2016:A tertiary care hospital-based cross-sectional study. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2018;84:328&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29620046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagarajan M, Chaaithanya IK, Parvez R, Palani S, Maile A, Matta M, et al. Atypical presentation of hand foot mouth disease (HFMD) caused by enterovirus serotype Coxsackievirus A6, in India. J Health Sci. 2019;9:123&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayaraghavan PM, Chandy S, Selvaraj K, Pulimood S, Abraham AM. Virological investigation of hand, foot, and mouth disease in a tertiary care center in South India. J Global Infect Dis. 2012;4:153&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3459432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23055646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thumjaa A. Case series of hand foot mouth disease in children. Int J Contemp Pediatr. 2014;1:14&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivakumar G, Satheesh C, Prasad VS, Ganesh PR. Hand, foot and mouth disease- A case report. J Nepal Dental Assoc. 2014;14:60&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar M, Rigvardhan, Bajpai M. An investigation and management of outbreak of hand foot and mouth disease in southern India. Med Res Chron. 2015;3:115&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganga N. Hand foot and mouth disease like illness in office practice. Indian J Pediatr. 2017;84:216&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27943150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pichaachari S, Subramaniam JN, Sundaram S. Onychomadesis associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease:A prospective observational study from North Chennai. Int J Res Dermatol. 2020;6:367&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haarika V, Soma V, Venkatesh C, Gunasekaran D, Sundararajan P, Srinivasan S. Hand Foot and mouth disease in an infant. Res J Pharm Biol Chem Sci. 2014;5:761&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palani S, Nagarajan M, Biswas AK, Reesu R, Paluru V. Hand, foot and mouth disease in the Andaman Islands, India. Indian Pediatr. 2018;55:408&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29845955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert GL, Dickson KE, Waters MJ, Kennett ML, Land SA, Sneddon M. Outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Victoria, Australia, with a high incidence of neurologic involvement. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1988;7:484&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2841639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg J, Lycke E, Ahlfors K, Johnsson T, Wolontis S, von Zeipel G. New enterovirus type associated with epidemic of aseptic meningitis and-or hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet. 1974;2:112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4136956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishimaru Y, Nakano S, Yamaoka K, Takami S. Outbreaks of hand, foot, and mouth disease by enterovirus 71:High incidence of complication disorders of central nervous system. Arch Dis Child. 1980;55:583&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1627055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6254449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick JL. Enterovirus type 71 infections:A varied clinical pattern sometimes mimicking paralytic poliomyelitis. Rev Infect Dis. 1984;6(Suppl 2):S387&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander JP, Baden L, Pallansch MA, Anderson LJ. Enterovirus 71 infections and neurologic disease:United States, 1977&#x2013;1991. J Infect Dis. 1994;169:905&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8133108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva EE, Winkler MT, Pallansch MA. Role of enterovirus 71 in acute flaccid paralysis after the eradication of poliovirus in Brazil. Emerg Infect Dis. 1996;2:231&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2626804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8903236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J-H, Chan T-C, Shigematsu M, Hwang J-S. Latitude-based approach for detecting aberrations of hand, foot, and mouth disease epidemics. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2015;15:113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4691017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26703896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hii YL, Rocklov J, Ng N. Short term effects of weather on hand, foot and mouth disease. PLoS One. 2011;6:e16796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3037951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21347303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomqvist S, Klemola P, Kaijalainen S, Paananen A, Simonen M-J, Vuorinen T, et al. Co-circulation of coxsackieviruses A6 and A10 in hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in Finland. J Clin Virol. 2010;48:49&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20189452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onozuka D, Hashizume M. The influence of temperature and humidity on the incidence of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan. Sci Total Environ. 2011;410:119&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22014509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvell J, Selig D. Seasonal variations in dermatologic and dermatopathologic diagnoses:A retrospective 15-year analysis of dermatopathologic data. Int J Dermatol. 2016;55:1115&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27061329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim BI, Ki H, Park S, Cho E, Chun BC. Effect of climatic factors on hand, foot, and mouth disease in South Korea, 2010-2013. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0157500. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0157500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4902224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27285850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K-T, Chang H-L, Wang S-T, Cheng Y-T, Yang J-Y. Epidemiologic features of hand-foot-mouth disease and herpangina caused by enterovirus 71 in Taiwan, 1998-2005. Pediatrics. 2007;120:e244&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) Hand, foot and mouth disease. 2012.  [Last accessed on 2019 Dec 01].  Available from:http://www.wpro.who.int/mediacentre/factsheets/fs_10072012_HFMD/en/ </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiff A. Cambodia unravels cause of mystery illness. Lancet. 2012;380:205. doi:10.1016/s0140-6736(12)61200-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22826834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>