<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25964873</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-3249</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Therapeutic and prevention strategies against human enterovirus 71 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>78</StartPage><EndPage>95</EndPage><MedlinePgn>78-95</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5501/wjv.v4.i2.78</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Human enterovirus 71 (HEV71) is the cause of hand, foot and mouth disease and associated neurological complications in children under five years of age. There has been an increase in HEV71 epidemic activity throughout the Asia-Pacific region in the past decade, and it is predicted to replace poliovirus as the extant neurotropic enterovirus of highest global public health significance. To date there is no effective antiviral treatment and no vaccine is available to prevent HEV71 infection. The increase in prevalence, virulence and geographic spread of HEV71 infection over the past decade provides increasing incentive for the development of new therapeutic and prevention strategies against this emerging viral infection. The current review focuses on the potential, advantages and disadvantages of these strategies. Since the explosion of outbreaks leading to large epidemics in China, research in natural therapeutic products has identified several groups of compounds with anti-HEV71 activities. Concurrently, the search for effective synthetic antivirals has produced promising results. Other therapeutic strategies including immunotherapy and the use of oligonucleotides have also been explored. A sound prevention strategy is crucial in order to control the spread of HEV71. To this end the ultimate goal is the rapid development, regulatory approval and widespread implementation of a safe and effective vaccine. The various forms of HEV71 vaccine designs are highlighted in this review. Given the rapid progress of research in this area, eradication of the virus is likely to be achieved.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kok</LastName><ForeName>Chee Choy</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chee Choy Kok, SEALS Microbiology, Level 4, Campus Centre, Prince of Wales Hospital, Randwick 2031 NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101608353</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2220-3249</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drugs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccine</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25964873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4419123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5501/wjv.v4.i2.78</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2002;26:91&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiung GD, Wang JR. Enterovirus infections with special reference to enterovirus 71. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2000;33:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10806956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao HT, Hung KL. Neurologic involvement in an outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection: a hospital-based study. Acta Paediatr Taiwan. 2001;42:27&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11270182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Tseng HW, Wang SM, Wang JR, Su IJ. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998: epidemiologic and clinical manifestations. J Clin Virol. 2000;17:23&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P, Stratov I, Nagarajan L, Davis S. Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin Infect Dis. 2001;32:236&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yip CC, Lau SK, Woo PC, Yuen KY. Human enterovirus 71 epidemics: what&#x2019;s next? Emerg Health Threats J. 2013;6:19780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24119538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng M, El Khatib NF, Tu S, Ren P, Xu S, Zhu Q, Mo X, Pu D, Wang X, Altmeyer R. Seroepidemiology of Enterovirus 71 infection prior to the 2011 season in children in Shanghai. J Clin Virol. 2012;53:285&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22265829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bible JM, Iturriza-Gomara M, Megson B, Brown D, Pantelidis P, Earl P, Bendig J, Tong CY. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 in the United Kingdom from 1998 to 2006. J Clin Microbiol. 2008;46:3192&#x2013;3200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2566106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18650362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowlkes AL, Honarmand S, Glaser C, Yagi S, Schnurr D, Oberste MS, Anderson L, Pallansch MA, Khetsuriani N. Enterovirus-associated encephalitis in the California encephalitis project, 1998-2005. J Infect Dis. 2008;198:1685&#x2013;1691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18959496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapusinszky B, Szomor KN, Farkas A, Tak&#xe1;cs M, Berencsi G. Detection of non-polio enteroviruses in Hungary 2000-2008 and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71, coxsackievirus A16, and echovirus 30. Virus Genes. 2010;40:163&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20044791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirand A, Schuffenecker I, Henquell C, Billaud G, Jugie G, Falcon D, Mahul A, Archimbaud C, Terletskaia-Ladwig E, Diedrich S, et al. Phylogenetic evidence for a recent spread of two populations of human enterovirus 71 in European countries. J Gen Virol. 2010;91:2263&#x2013;2277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20505012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siafakas N, Attilakos A, Vourli S, Stefos E, Meletiadis J, Nikolaidou P, Zerva L. Molecular detection and identification of enteroviruses in children admitted to a university hospital in Greece. Mol Cell Probes. 2011;25:249&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21803150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sanden S, Koopmans M, Uslu G, van der Avoort H. Epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in the Netherlands, 1963 to 2008. J Clin Microbiol. 2009;47:2826&#x2013;2833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2738086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wits&#xf8; E, Palacios G, R&#xf8;nningen KS, Cinek O, Janowitz D, Rewers M, Grinde B, Lipkin WI. Asymptomatic circulation of HEV71 in Norway. Virus Res. 2007;123:19&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16965832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Tao J, Yang X, Yang Z, Zhang L, Liu H, Wu K, Wu J. Antiviral effects of two Ganoderma lucidum triterpenoids against enterovirus 71 infection. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2014;449:307&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24845570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Peng T. Traditional Chinese herbal medicine as a source of molecules with antiviral activity. Antiviral Res. 2013;97:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7114103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23153834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu YP, Woerdenbag HJ. Traditional Chinese herbal medicine. Pharm World Sci. 1995;17:103&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7581215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zhang T, Du J, Cui S, Yang F, Jin Q. Anti-enterovirus 71 effects of chrysin and its phosphate ester. PLoS One. 2014;9:e89668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3943725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24598537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman DJ, Cragg GM. Natural products as sources of new drugs over the 30 years from 1981 to 2010. J Nat Prod. 2012;75:311&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22316239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Chen X, Wang W, Zhang Y, Yang Z, Jin Y, Ge HM, Li E, Yang G. Glycyrrhizic acid as the antiviral component of Glycyrrhiza uralensis Fisch. against coxsackievirus A16 and enterovirus 71 of hand foot and mouth disease. J Ethnopharmacol. 2013;147:114&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7125661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23454684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida T, Amakura Y, Yoshimura M. Structural features and biological properties of ellagitannins in some plant families of the order Myrtales. Int J Mol Sci. 2010;11:79&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2820991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20162003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin LT, Chen TY, Chung CY, Noyce RS, Grindley TB, McCormick C, Lin TC, Wang GH, Lin CC, Richardson CD. Hydrolyzable tannins (chebulagic acid and punicalagin) target viral glycoprotein-glycosaminoglycan interactions to inhibit herpes simplex virus 1 entry and cell-to-cell spread. J Virol. 2011;85:4386&#x2013;4398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3126266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21307190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin LT, Chen TY, Lin SC, Chung CY, Lin TC, Wang GH, Anderson R, Lin CC, Richardson CD. Broad-spectrum antiviral activity of chebulagic acid and punicalagin against viruses that use glycosaminoglycans for entry. BMC Microbiol. 2013;13:187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3750913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23924316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satomi H, Umemura K, Ueno A, Hatano T, Okuda T, Noro T. Carbonic anhydrase inhibitors from the pericarps of Punica granatum L. Biol Pharm Bull. 1993;16:787&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8220326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Xiu J, Zhang L, Qin C, Liu J. Antiviral activity of punicalagin toward human enterovirus 71 in vitro and in vivo. Phytomedicine. 2012;20:67&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23146421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeo SG, Song JH, Hong EH, Lee BR, Kwon YS, Chang SY, Kim SH, Lee SW, Park JH, Ko HJ. Antiviral effects of Phyllanthus urinaria containing corilagin against human enterovirus 71 and Coxsackievirus A16 in vitro. Arch Pharm Res. 2015;38:193&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24752860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Zhang L, Fan X, Qin C, Liu J. Antiviral effect of geraniin on human enterovirus 71 in vitro and in vivo. Bioorg Med Chem Lett. 2012;22:2209&#x2013;2211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22342145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Xiu J, Liu J, Zhang L, Li X, Xu Y, Qin C, Zhang L. Chebulagic Acid, a Hydrolyzable Tannin, Exhibited Antiviral Activity in Vitro and in Vivo against Human Enterovirus 71. Int J Mol Sci. 2013;14:9618&#x2013;9627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3676802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23644889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Joo HS, Yoo KY, Shin BN, Kim IH, Lee CH, Choi JH, Byun K, Lee B, Lim SS, et al. Extract from Terminalia chebula seeds protect against experimental ischemic neuronal damage via maintaining SODs and BDNF levels. Neurochem Res. 2011;36:2043&#x2013;2050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21667226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiota S, Shimizu M, Sugiyama J, Morita Y, Mizushima T, Tsuchiya T. Mechanisms of action of corilagin and tellimagrandin I that remarkably potentiate the activity of beta-lactams against methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus. Microbiol Immunol. 2004;48:67&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14734860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harborne JB, Williams CA. Advances in flavonoid research since 1992. Phytochemistry. 2000;55:481&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11130659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heim KE, Tagliaferro AR, Bobilya DJ. Flavonoid antioxidants: chemistry, metabolism and structure-activity relationships. J Nutr Biochem. 2002;13:572&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12550068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu QC, Wang Y, Liu YP, Zhang RQ, Li X, Su WH, Long F, Luo XD, Peng T. Inhibition of enterovirus 71 replication by chrysosplenetin and penduletin. Eur J Pharm Sci. 2011;44:392&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HQ, Meng S, Li ZR, Peng ZG, Han YX, Guo SS, Cui XL, Li YH, Jiang JD. The antiviral effect of 7-hydroxyisoflavone against Enterovirus 71 in vitro. J Asian Nat Prod Res. 2013;15:382&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23464760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv X, Qiu M, Chen D, Zheng N, Jin Y, Wu Z. Apigenin inhibits enterovirus 71 replication through suppressing viral IRES activity and modulating cellular JNK pathway. Antiviral Res. 2014;109:30&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24971492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Yang Y, Xu Y, Ma C, Qin C, Zhang L. Lycorine reduces mortality of human enterovirus 71-infected mice by inhibiting virus replication. Virol J. 2011;8:483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3212826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22029605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ZF, Mao L, Liu LM, Liu YC, Peng Y, Hong X, Wang HH, Liu HG, Liang H. Potential new inorganic antitumour agents from combining the anticancer traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) matrine with Ga(III), Au(III), Sn(IV) ions, and DNA binding studies. J Inorg Biochem. 2011;105:171&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21194615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Xiu J, Zhang X, Zhang L, Yan K, Qin C, Liu J. Antiviral effect of matrine against human enterovirus 71. Molecules. 2012;17:10370&#x2013;10376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6268984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22932217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong ZQ, Wang JF, Hao YY, Wang Y. Recent advances in the discovery and development of marine microbial natural products. Mar Drugs. 2013;11:700&#x2013;717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3705366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23528949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Ma J, Xiu J, Bai L, Guan F, Zhang L, Liu J, Zhang L. Deferoxamine compensates for decreases in B cell counts and reduces mortality in enterovirus 71-infected mice. Mar Drugs. 2014;12:4086&#x2013;4095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4113816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25003792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo KK, Chang JS, Wang KC, Chiang LC. Water extract of Glycyrrhiza uralensis inhibited enterovirus 71 in a human foreskin fibroblast cell line. Am J Chin Med. 2009;37:383&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19507280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YJ, Lai CC, Lai CH, Sue SC, Lin CW, Hung CH, Lin TH, Hsu WY, Huang SM, Hung YL, et al. Inhibition of enterovirus 71 infections and viral IRES activity by Fructus gardeniae and geniposide. Eur J Med Chem. 2013;62:206&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23353754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Liu Y, Hou X, Peng H, Zhang L, Jiang Q, Shi M, Ji Y, Wang Y, Shi W. Chlorogenic acid inhibits the replication and viability of enterovirus 71 in vitro. PLoS One. 2013;8:e76007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3786884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24098754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song J, Yeo SG, Hong EH, Lee BR, Kim JW, Kim J, Jeong H, Kwon Y, Kim H, Lee S, et al. Antiviral Activity of Hederasaponin B from Hedera helix against Enterovirus 71 Subgenotypes C3 and C4a. Biomol Ther (Seoul) 2014;22:41&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3936428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24596620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li ZH, Li CM, Ling P, Shen FH, Chen SH, Liu CC, Yu CK, Chen SH. Ribavirin reduces mortality in enterovirus 71-infected mice by decreasing viral replication. J Infect Dis. 2008;197:854&#x2013;857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7109938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18279075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang L, Xu M, Yin Z. Antiviral drug discovery for the treatment of enterovirus 71 infections. Antiviral Res. 2013;97:183&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23261847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Palma AM, Vliegen I, De Clercq E, Neyts J. Selective inhibitors of picornavirus replication. Med Res Rev. 2008;28:823&#x2013;884.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18381747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pevear DC, Tull TM, Seipel ME, Groarke JM. Activity of pleconaril against enteroviruses. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 1999;43:2109&#x2013;2115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC89431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10471549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shia KS, Li WT, Chang CM, Hsu MC, Chern JH, Leong MK, Tseng SN, Lee CC, Lee YC, Chen SJ, et al. Design, synthesis, and structure-activity relationship of pyridyl imidazolidinones: a novel class of potent and selective human enterovirus 71 inhibitors. J Med Chem. 2002;45:1644&#x2013;1655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11931618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CS, Lin YT, Shih SR, Lee CC, Lee YC, Tai CL, Tseng SN, Chern JH. Design, synthesis, and antipicornavirus activity of 1-[5-(4-arylphenoxy)alkyl]-3-pyridin-4-ylimidazolidin-2-one derivatives. J Med Chem. 2005;48:3522&#x2013;3535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15887961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Liu SC, Huang PN, Chang HY, Chern JH, Shih SR. Antiviral activity of pyridyl imidazolidinones against enterovirus 71 variants. J Biomed Sci. 2008;15:291&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18196474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chern JH, Shia KS, Hsu TA, Tai CL, Lee CC, Lee YC, Chang CS, Tseng SN, Shih SR. Design, synthesis, and structure-activity relationships of pyrazolo[3,4-d]pyrimidines: a novel class of potent enterovirus inhibitors. Bioorg Med Chem Lett. 2004;14:2519&#x2013;2525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15109643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Chen SJ, Hakimelahi GH, Liu HJ, Tseng CT, Shia KS. Selective human enterovirus and rhinovirus inhibitors: An overview of capsid-binding and protease-inhibiting molecules. Med Res Rev. 2004;24:449&#x2013;474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7168432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15170592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Tsai MC, Tseng SN, Won KF, Shia KS, Li WT, Chern JH, Chen GW, Lee CC, Lee YC, et al. Mutation in enterovirus 71 capsid protein VP1 confers resistance to the inhibitory effects of pyridyl imidazolidinone. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2004;48:3523&#x2013;3529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC514779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15328120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Shimojima M, Tano Y, Miyamura T, Wakita T, Shimizu H. Human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat Med. 2009;15:794&#x2013;797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Yamashita Y, Li J, Hanagata N, Minowa T, Takemura T, Koike S. Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat Med. 2009;15:798&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan CW, Lai JK, Sam IC, Chan YF. Recent developments in antiviral agents against enterovirus 71 infection. J Biomed Sci. 2014;21:14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3924904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24521134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng TY, Chen LC, Shyu HW, Chen SH, Wang JR, Yu CK, Lei HY, Yeh TM. Lactoferrin inhibits enterovirus 71 infection by binding to VP1 protein and host cells. Antiviral Res. 2005;67:31&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15916817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legrand D, Vigi&#xe9; K, Said EA, Elass E, Masson M, Slomianny MC, Carpentier M, Briand JP, Mazurier J, Hovanessian AG. Surface nucleolin participates in both the binding and endocytosis of lactoferrin in target cells. Eur J Biochem. 2004;271:303&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14717698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchetti M, Trybala E, Superti F, Johansson M, Bergstr&#xf6;m T. Inhibition of herpes simplex virus infection by lactoferrin is dependent on interference with the virus binding to glycosaminoglycans. Virology. 2004;318:405&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14972565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Strate BW, Beljaars L, Molema G, Harmsen MC, Meijer DK. Antiviral activities of lactoferrin. Antiviral Res. 2001;52:225&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11675140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenssen H, Andersen JH, Uhlin-Hansen L, Gutteberg TJ, Rekdal &#xd8;. Anti-HSV activity of lactoferricin analogues is only partly related to their affinity for heparan sulfate. Antiviral Res. 2004;61:101&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14670583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Qing J, Sun Y, Rao Z. Suramin inhibits EV71 infection. Antiviral Res. 2014;103:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24374150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huther A, Dietrich U. The emergence of peptides as therapeutic drugs for the inhibition of HIV-1. AIDS Rev. 2007;9:208&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18219364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan CW, Chan YF, Sim KM, Tan EL, Poh CL. Inhibition of enterovirus 71 (EV-71) infections by a novel antiviral peptide derived from EV-71 capsid protein VP1. PLoS One. 2012;7:e34589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3341398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22563456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kajiwara K, Watanabe K, Tokiwa R, Kurose T, Ohno H, Tsutsumi H, Hata Y, Izumi K, Kodama E, Matsuoka M, et al. Bioorganic synthesis of a recombinant HIV-1 fusion inhibitor, SC35EK, with an N-terminal pyroglutamate capping group. Bioorg Med Chem. 2009;17:7964&#x2013;7970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Song Z, Qin B, Zhang X, Chen L, Hu Y, Yuan Z. Rupintrivir is a promising candidate for treating severe cases of enterovirus-71 infection: evaluation of antiviral efficacy in a murine infection model. Antiviral Res. 2013;97:264&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23295352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park KS, Choi YJ, Park JS. Enterovirus infection in Korean children and anti-enteroviral potential candidate agents. Korean J Pediatr. 2012;55:359&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3488610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23133481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Chang HY, Lin PF, Chern JH, Hsu JT, Chang CY, Shih SR. Novel antiviral agent DTriP-22 targets RNA-dependent RNA polymerase of enterovirus 71. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2009;53:2740&#x2013;2747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2704669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19414569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Weng KF, Chang SC, Lin JY, Huang PN, Shih SR. Development of antiviral agents for enteroviruses. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2008;62:1169&#x2013;1173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18931391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Palma AM, P&#xfc;rstinger G, Wimmer E, Patick AK, Andries K, Rombaut B, De Clercq E, Neyts J. Potential use of antiviral agents in polio eradication. Emerg Infect Dis. 2008;14:545&#x2013;551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2570929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18394270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goris N, De Palma A, Toussaint JF, Musch I, Neyts J, De Clercq K. 2&#x2019;-C-methylcytidine as a potent and selective inhibitor of the replication of foot-and-mouth disease virus. Antiviral Res. 2007;73:161&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17055073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graci JD, Too K, Smidansky ED, Edathil JP, Barr EW, Harki DA, Galarraga JE, Bollinger JM, Peterson BR, Loakes D, et al. Lethal mutagenesis of picornaviruses with N-6-modified purine nucleoside analogues. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2008;52:971&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2258490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18180344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harki DA, Graci JD, Galarraga JE, Chain WJ, Cameron CE, Peterson BR. Synthesis and antiviral activity of 5-substituted cytidine analogues: identification of a potent inhibitor of viral RNA-dependent RNA polymerases. J Med Chem. 2006;49:6166&#x2013;6169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2094219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17034123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kishimoto C, Crumpacker CS, Abelmann WH. Ribavirin treatment of murine coxsackievirus B3 myocarditis with analyses of lymphocyte subsets. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1988;12:1334&#x2013;1341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2844874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Bopda-Waffo A, Basu A, Krishnan R, Silberstein E, Taylor DR, Talele TT, Arora P, Kaushik-Basu N. Characterization of aurintricarboxylic acid as a potent hepatitis C virus replicase inhibitor. Antivir Chem Chemother. 2009;20:19&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19794229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Clercq E. Potential antivirals and antiviral strategies against SARS coronavirus infections. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2006;4:291&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7105749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16597209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santhosh KC, Paul GC, De Clercq E, Pannecouque C, Witvrouw M, Loftus TL, Turpin JA, Buckheit RW, Cushman M. Correlation of anti-HIV activity with anion spacing in a series of cosalane analogues with extended polycarboxylate pharmacophores. J Med Chem. 2001;44:703&#x2013;714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11262081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witvrouw M, Fikkert V, Pluymers W, Matthews B, Mardel K, Schols D, Raff J, Debyser Z, De Clercq E, Holan G, et al. Polyanionic (i.e., polysulfonate) dendrimers can inhibit the replication of human immunodeficiency virus by interfering with both virus adsorption and later steps (reverse transcriptase/integrase) in the virus replicative cycle. Mol Pharmacol. 2000;58:1100&#x2013;1108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11040059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yap Y, Zhang X, Andonov A, He R. Structural analysis of inhibition mechanisms of aurintricarboxylic acid on SARS-CoV polymerase and other proteins. Comput Biol Chem. 2005;29:212&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7106521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15979041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung HC, Chen TC, Fang MY, Yen KJ, Shih SR, Hsu JT, Tseng CP. Inhibition of enterovirus 71 replication and the viral 3D polymerase by aurintricarboxylic acid. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2010;65:676&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7110181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20089540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin Z, Chen YL, Schul W, Wang QY, Gu F, Duraiswamy J, Kondreddi RR, Niyomrattanakit P, Lakshminarayana SB, Goh A, et al. An adenosine nucleoside inhibitor of dengue virus. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2009;106:20435&#x2013;20439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2787148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19918064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng CL, Yeo H, Ye HQ, Liu SQ, Shang BD, Gong P, Alonso S, Shi PY, Zhang B. Inhibition of enterovirus 71 by adenosine analog NITD008. J Virol. 2014;88:11915&#x2013;11923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4178731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25100827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao M, Duan H, Liu J, Zhang H, Wang X, Zhu M, Guo J, Zhao Z, Meng L, Peng Y. The multi-targeted kinase inhibitor sorafenib inhibits enterovirus 71 replication by regulating IRES-dependent translation of viral proteins. Antiviral Res. 2014;106:80&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24680956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung WH, Hsieh HL, Yang CM. Enterovirus 71 induces COX-2 expression via MAPKs, NF-kappaB, and AP-1 in SK-N-SH cells: Role of PGE(2) in viral replication. Cell Signal. 2010;22:234&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19800403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YP, Liang ZL, Gao Q, Huang LR, Mao QY, Wen SQ, Liu Y, Yin WD, Li RC, Wang JZ. Safety and immunogenicity of a novel human Enterovirus 71 (EV71) vaccine: a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, Phase I clinical trial. Vaccine. 2012;30:3295&#x2013;3303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22426327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YW, Chang KC, Kao CM, Chang SP, Tung YY, Chen SH. Lymphocyte and antibody responses reduce enterovirus 71 lethality in mice by decreasing tissue viral loads. J Virol. 2009;83:6477&#x2013;6483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng FY, Li JX, Li XL, Chu K, Zhang YT, Ji H, Li L, Liang ZL, Zhu FC. Tolerability and immunogenicity of an inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in Chinese healthy adults and children: an open label, phase 1 clinical trial. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2012;8:668&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22634437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Mao C, Ma S, Wang X, Sun Z, Yi Y, Guo M, Shen X, Sun L, Bi S. Generation of neutralizing monoclonal antibodies against Enterovirus 71 using synthetic peptides. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2009;390:1126&#x2013;1128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19799860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiener TK, Jia Q, Meng T, Chow VT, Kwang J. A novel universal neutralizing monoclonal antibody against enterovirus 71 that targets the highly conserved &#x201c;knob&#x201d; region of VP3 protein. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2014;8:e2895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4038473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24875055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han JF, Cao RY, Deng YQ, Tian X, Jiang T, Qin ED, Qin CF. Antibody dependent enhancement infection of enterovirus 71 in vitro and in vivo. Virol J. 2011;8:106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3060144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21385398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Chen IC, Su LY, Huang KJ, Lei HY, Liu CC. Enterovirus 71 infection of monocytes with antibody-dependent enhancement. Clin Vaccine Immunol. 2010;17:1517&#x2013;1523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20685937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palivizumab , a humanized respiratory syncytial virus monoclonal antibody, reduces hospitalization from respiratory syncytial virus infection in high-risk infants. The IMpact-RSV Study Group. Pediatrics. 1998;102:531&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9738173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo DG, Alonso S, Phoon MC, Ramachandran NP, Chow VT, Poh CL. Identification of neutralizing linear epitopes from the VP1 capsid protein of Enterovirus 71 using synthetic peptides. Virus Res. 2007;125:61&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17222936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lal SK, Kumar P, Yeo WM, Kar-Roy A, Chow VT. The VP1 protein of human enterovirus 71 self-associates via an interaction domain spanning amino acids 66-297. J Med Virol. 2006;78:582&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16555287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang GH, Luo YJ, Wu XY, Si BY, Lin L, Zhu QY. Monoclonal antibody induced with inactived EV71-Hn2 virus protects mice against lethal EV71-Hn2 virus infection. Virol J. 2010;7:106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2887433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20500892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabakaran M, Prabhu N, He F, Hongliang Q, Ho HT, Qiang J, Meng T, Goutama M, Kwang J. Combination therapy using chimeric monoclonal antibodies protects mice from lethal H5N1 infection and prevents formation of escape mutants. PLoS One. 2009;4:e5672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2682562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ter Meulen J, van den Brink EN, Poon LL, Marissen WE, Leung CS, Cox F, Cheung CY, Bakker AQ, Bogaards JA, van Deventer E, et al. Human monoclonal antibody combination against SARS coronavirus: synergy and coverage of escape mutants. PLoS Med. 2006;3:e237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1483912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16796401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leslie GA, Clem LW. Phylogen of immunoglobulin structure and function. 3. Immunoglobulins of the chicken. J Exp Med. 1969;130:1337&#x2013;1352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2138693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5352783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaral JA, Tino De Franco M, Carneiro-Sampaio MM, Carbonare SB. Anti-enteropathogenic Escherichia coli immunoglobulin Y isolated from eggs laid by immunised Leghorn chickens. Res Vet Sci. 2002;72:229&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12076119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kweon CH, Kwon BJ, Woo SR, Kim JM, Woo GH, Son DH, Hur W, Lee YS. Immunoprophylactic effect of chicken egg yolk immunoglobulin (Ig Y) against porcine epidemic diarrhea virus (PEDV) in piglets. J Vet Med Sci. 2000;62:961&#x2013;964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11039591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin JH, Yang M, Nam SW, Kim JT, Myung NH, Bang WG, Roe IH. Use of egg yolk-derived immunoglobulin as an alternative to antibiotic treatment for control of Helicobacter pylori infection. Clin Diagn Lab Immunol. 2002;9:1061&#x2013;1066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12204960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokoyama H, Umeda K, Peralta RC, Hashi T, Icatlo FC, Kuroki M, Ikemori Y, Kodama Y. Oral passive immunization against experimental salmonellosis in mice using chicken egg yolk antibodies specific for Salmonella enteritidis and S. typhimurium. Vaccine. 1998;16:388&#x2013;393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9607060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liou JF, Chang CW, Tailiu JJ, Yu CK, Lei HY, Chen LR, Tai C. Passive protection effect of chicken egg yolk immunoglobulins on enterovirus 71 infected mice. Vaccine. 2010;28:8189&#x2013;8196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7115624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20937321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreesen R, Hennemann B, Krause SW. Adoptive immunotherapy of cancer using monocyte-derived macrophages: rationale, current status, and perspectives. J Leukoc Biol. 1998;64:419&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9766621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart ML, Mosier DA, Chapes SK. Toll-like receptor 4-positive macrophages protect mice from Pasteurella pneumotropica-induced pneumonia. Infect Immun. 2003;71:663&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC145384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12540543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke B, Shen XD, Gao F, Ji H, Qiao B, Zhai Y, Farmer DG, Busuttil RW, Kupiec-Weglinski JW. Adoptive transfer of ex vivo HO-1 modified bone marrow-derived macrophages prevents liver ischemia and reperfusion injury. Mol Ther. 2010;18:1019&#x2013;1025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2890105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20029397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang PA, Recher M, Honke N, Scheu S, Borkens S, Gailus N, Krings C, Meryk A, Kulawik A, Cervantes-Barragan L, et al. Tissue macrophages suppress viral replication and prevent severe immunopathology in an interferon-I-dependent manner in mice. Hepatology. 2010;52:25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20578253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Li X, Fan X, Ma C, Qin C, Zhang L. Adoptive transfer of macrophages from adult mice reduces mortality in mice infected with human enterovirus 71. Arch Virol. 2013;158:387&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23065110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu ML, Lee YP, Wang YF, Lei HY, Liu CC, Wang SM, Su IJ, Wang JR, Yeh TM, Chen SH, et al. Type I interferons protect mice against enterovirus 71 infection. J Gen Virol. 2005;86:3263&#x2013;3269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16298971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J, Yi L, Zhao J, Yu J, Chen Y, Lin MC, Kung HF, He ML. Enterovirus 71 disrupts interferon signaling by reducing the level of interferon receptor 1. J Virol. 2012;86:3767&#x2013;3776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3302529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22258259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaks E, Gavutis M, Uz&#xe9; G, Martal J, Piehler J. Differential receptor subunit affinities of type I interferons govern differential signal activation. J Mol Biol. 2007;366:525&#x2013;539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17174979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi L, Lu J, Kung HF, He ML. The virology and developments toward control of human enterovirus 71. Crit Rev Microbiol. 2011;37:313&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21651436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung HC, Wang HC, Shih SR, Teng IF, Tseng CP, Hsu JT. Synergistic inhibition of enterovirus 71 replication by interferon and rupintrivir. J Infect Dis. 2011;203:1784&#x2013;1790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21536800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Yang Y, Yan X, Chen J, Yu H, Wang W. Influence of vitamin A status on the antiviral immunity of children with hand, foot and mouth disease. Clin Nutr. 2012;31:543&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22197454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimberg A, Nilsson K, Oberg F. Phosphorylation-deficient Stat1 inhibits retinoic acid-induced differentiation and cell cycle arrest in U-937 monoblasts. Blood. 2000;96:2870&#x2013;2878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11023524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo XM, Ross AC. Physiological and receptor-selective retinoids modulate interferon gamma signaling by increasing the expression, nuclear localization, and functional activity of interferon regulatory factor-1. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:36228&#x2013;36236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3846428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16085646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soye KJ, Trottier C, Richardson CD, Ward BJ, Miller WH. RIG-I is required for the inhibition of measles virus by retinoids. PLoS One. 2011;6:e22323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3139622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21811588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X, Liu X, Ma Y, Sun Z, Yang Y, Jin Q, He B, Wang J. The 3C protein of enterovirus 71 inhibits retinoid acid-inducible gene I-mediated interferon regulatory factor 3 activation and type I interferon responses. J Virol. 2010;84:8051&#x2013;8061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2916543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20519382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Yang Y, Xu J, Su L, Wang W. Effect of all-trans-retinoic acid on enterovirus 71 infection in vitro. Br J Nutr. 2014;111:1586&#x2013;1593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24495389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu WW, Hsu YY, Yang JY, Kung SH. Selective inhibition of enterovirus 71 replication by short hairpin RNAs. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2004;325:494&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15530419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim AC, Luhur A, Tan TM, Chow VT, Poh CL. RNA interference against enterovirus 71 infection. Virology. 2005;341:72&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16083932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan EL, Tan TM, Chow VT, Poh CL. Enhanced potency and efficacy of 29-mer shRNAs in inhibition of Enterovirus 71. Antiviral Res. 2007;74:9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17316836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan EL, Tan TM, Tak Kwong Chow V, Poh CL. Inhibition of enterovirus 71 in virus-infected mice by RNA interference. Mol Ther. 2007;15:1931&#x2013;1938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17712333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Xie J, Xu X, Wang J, Ao F, Wan Y, Zhu Y. MicroRNA-548 down-regulates host antiviral response via direct targeting of IFN-&#x3bb;1. Protein Cell. 2013;4:130&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4875363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23150165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen BP, Dai HJ, Yang YH, Zhuang Y, Sheng R. MicroRNA-23b inhibits enterovirus 71 replication through downregulation of EV71 VPl protein. Intervirology. 2013;56:195&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23594713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Z, Ke X, Wang M, He S, Li Q, Zheng C, Zhang Z, Liu Y, Wang H. Human microRNA hsa-miR-296-5p suppresses enterovirus 71 replication by targeting the viral genome. J Virol. 2013;87:5645&#x2013;5656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3648165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23468506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Chen X, Shi Y, Zhou B, Du C, Liu Y, Han S, Yin J, Peng B, He X, et al. miR-27a suppresses EV71 replication by directly targeting EGFR. Virus Genes. 2014;49:373&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25212431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rayburn ER, Zhang R. Antisense, RNAi, and gene silencing strategies for therapy: mission possible or impossible? Drug Discov Today. 2008;13:513&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2497463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18549978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones D. The long march of antisense. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2011;10:401&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21629279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Zhou Z, Li K, Han M, Yang J, Wang S. In vitro and in vivo protection against enterovirus 71 by an antisense phosphorothioate oligonucleotide. Arch Virol. 2014;159:2339&#x2013;2347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24756344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan CW, Chan YF, Quah YW, Poh CL. Inhibition of enterovirus 71 infection by antisense octaguanidinium dendrimer-conjugated morpholino oligomers. Antiviral Res. 2014;107:35&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24769243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung PW, Huang YC, Chang LY, Lin TY, Ning HC. Duration of enterovirus shedding in stool. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2001;34:167&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11605806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J, Ma XJ, Wan JF, Liu YH, Han YL, Chen C, Tian C, Gao C, Wang M, Dong XP. Long persistence of EV71 specific nucleotides in respiratory and feces samples of the patients with Hand-Foot-Mouth Disease after recovery. BMC Infect Dis. 2010;10:178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2895604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20565813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY. Enterovirus 71 in Taiwan. Pediatr Neonatol. 2008;49:103&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19054914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, King CC, Hsu KH, Ning HC, Tsao KC, Li CC, Huang YC, Shih SR, Chiou ST, Chen PY, et al. Risk factors of enterovirus 71 infection and associated hand, foot, and mouth disease/herpangina in children during an epidemic in Taiwan. Pediatrics. 2002;109:e88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bek EJ, McMinn PC. The Pathogenesis and Prevention of Encephalitis due to Human Enterovirus 71. Curr Infect Dis Rep. 2012;14:397&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22639066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang LW, Koh BK, Chan KP, Chua LT, James L, Goh KT. Epidemiology and control of hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore, 2001-2007. Ann Acad Med Singapore. 2009;38:106&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19271036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen KT, Chang HL, Wang ST, Cheng YT, Yang JY. Epidemiologic features of hand-foot-mouth disease and herpangina caused by enterovirus 71 in Taiwan, 1998-2005. Pediatrics. 2007;120:e244&#x2013;e252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta K, Abiko C, Murata T, Matsuzaki Y, Itagaki T, Sanjoh K, Sakamoto M, Hongo S, Murayama S, Hayasaka K. Frequent importation of enterovirus 71 from surrounding countries into the local community of Yamagata, Japan, between 1998 and 2003. J Clin Microbiol. 2005;43:6171&#x2013;6175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16333123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podin Y, Gias EL, Ong F, Leong YW, Yee SF, Yusof MA, Perera D, Teo B, Wee TY, Yao SC, et al. Sentinel surveillance for human enterovirus 71 in Sarawak, Malaysia: lessons from the first 7 years. BMC Public Health. 2006;6:180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1543637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16827926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu SC, Hao YT, Zhang J, Xiao GX, Liu Z, Zhu Q, Ma JQ, Wang Y. Using interrupted time series design to analyze changes in hand, foot, and mouth disease incidence during the declining incidence periods of 2008-2010 in China. Biomed Environ Sci. 2012;25:645&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23228834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, Cardosa MJ, McMinn P, Ooi MH. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect Dis. 2010;10:778&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu TN, Tsai SF, Li SF, Lee TF, Huang TM, Wang ML, Hsu KH, Shen CY. Sentinel surveillance for enterovirus 71, Taiwan, 1998. Emerg Infect Dis. 1999;5:458&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2640775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10341187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KP, Goh KT, Chong CY, Teo ES, Lau G, Ling AE. Epidemic hand, foot and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg Infect Dis. 2003;9:78&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SC, Li WC, Huang KY, Huang YC, Chiu CH, Chen CJ, Hsieh YC, Kuo CY, Shih SR, Lin TY. Efficacy of alcohols and alcohol-based hand disinfectants against human enterovirus 71. J Hosp Infect. 2013;83:288&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23399482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M, Shimizu H, Nagata N, Ami Y, Suzaki Y, Sata T, Iwasaki T, Miyamura T. Temperature-sensitive mutants of enterovirus 71 show attenuation in cynomolgus monkeys. J Gen Virol. 2005;86:1391&#x2013;1401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M, Nagata N, Iwata N, Ami Y, Suzaki Y, Mizuta K, Iwasaki T, Sata T, Wakita T, Shimizu H. An attenuated strain of enterovirus 71 belonging to genotype a showed a broad spectrum of antigenicity with attenuated neurovirulence in cynomolgus monkeys. J Virol. 2007;81:9386&#x2013;9395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17567701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrikova EY, Goetz C, Walters RW, Lawson SK, Peggins JO, Muszynski K, Ruppel S, Poole K, Giardina SL, Vela EM, et al. Attenuation of neurovirulence, biodistribution, and shedding of a poliovirus: rhinovirus chimera after intrathalamic inoculation in Macaca fascicularis. J Virol. 2012;86:2750&#x2013;2759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3302279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22171271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gromeier M, Alexander L, Wimmer E. Internal ribosomal entry site substitution eliminates neurovirulence in intergeneric poliovirus recombinants. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1996;93:2370&#x2013;2375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC39803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8637880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kok CC, Phuektes P, Bek E, McMinn PC. Modification of the untranslated regions of human enterovirus 71 impairs growth in a cell-specific manner. J Virol. 2012;86:542&#x2013;552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3255918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22031931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghipour S, Bek EJ, McMinn PC. Ribavirin-resistant mutants of human enterovirus 71 express a high replication fidelity phenotype during growth in cell culture. J Virol. 2013;87:1759&#x2013;1769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3554166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23175376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghipour S, McMinn PC. A study of the virulence in mice of high copying fidelity variants of human enterovirus 71. Virus Res. 2013;176:265&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7114468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23856384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov M, Voroshilova M, Shindarov L, Lavrova I, Gracheva L, Koroleva G, Vasilenko S, Brodvarova I, Nikolova M, Gyurova S, et al. Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch Virol. 1979;60:329&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong KC, Devi S, Cardosa MJ, Wong KT. Formaldehyde-inactivated whole-virus vaccine protects a murine model of enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis against disease. J Virol. 2010;84:661&#x2013;665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2798416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong C, Wang J, Liu L, Zhao H, Shi H, Zhang Y, Jiang L, Li Q. Optimized development of a candidate strain of inactivated EV71 vaccine and analysis of its immunogenicity in rhesus monkeys. Hum Vaccin. 2010;6:1028&#x2013;1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21150270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CN, Lin YC, Fann C, Liao NS, Shih SR, Ho MS. Protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by passive immunization with subunit VP1 vaccines and inactivated virus. Vaccine. 2001;20:895&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu CK, Chen CC, Chen CL, Wang JR, Liu CC, Yan JJ, Su IJ. Neutralizing antibody provided protection against enterovirus type 71 lethal challenge in neonatal mice. J Biomed Sci. 2000;7:523&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11060501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bek EJ, Hussain KM, Phuektes P, Kok CC, Gao Q, Cai F, Gao Z, McMinn PC. Formalin-inactivated vaccine provokes cross-protective immunity in a mouse model of human enterovirus 71 infection. Vaccine. 2011;29:4829&#x2013;4838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21550375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CS, Yao YC, Lin SC, Lee YP, Wang YF, Wang JR, Liu CC, Lei HY, Yu CK. Retrograde axonal transport: a major transmission route of enterovirus 71 in mice. J Virol. 2007;81:8996&#x2013;9003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17567704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iiai T, Watanabe H, Seki S, Sugiura K, Hirokawa K, Utsuyama M, Takahashi-Iwanaga H, Iwanaga T, Ohteki T, Abo T. Ontogeny and development of extrathymic T cells in mouse liver. Immunology. 1992;77:556&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1421651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1493929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoletti LC, Pinel J, Kennedy RC, Kasper DL. Maternal antibody transfer in baboons and mice vaccinated with a group B streptococcal polysaccharide conjugate. J Infect Dis. 2000;181:653&#x2013;658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10669351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sanden S, van der Avoort H, Lemey P, Uslu G, Koopmans M. Evolutionary trajectory of the VP1 gene of human enterovirus 71 genogroup B and C viruses. J Gen Virol. 2010;91:1949&#x2013;1958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20375223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CW, Lee YP, Wang YF, Yu CK. Formaldehyde-inactivated human enterovirus 71 vaccine is compatible for co-immunization with a commercial pentavalent vaccine. Vaccine. 2011;29:2772&#x2013;2776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21315698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang JY, Chang CP, Tsai HH, Lee CD, Lian WC, Ih-Jen-Su IH, Liu CC, Chou AH, Lu YJ, Chen CY, et al. Selection and characterization of vaccine strain for Enterovirus 71 vaccine development. Vaccine. 2012;30:703&#x2013;711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22142585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kung YA, Hung CT, Liu YC, Shih SR. Update on the development of enterovirus 71 vaccines. Expert Opin Biol Ther. 2014;14:1455&#x2013;1464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24989170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateu MG. Antibody recognition of picornaviruses and escape from neutralization: a structural view. Virus Res. 1995;38:1&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8546007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minor PD. Antigenic structure of picornaviruses. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol. 1990;161:121&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2169382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivasamugham LA, Cardosa MJ, Tan WS, Yusoff K. Recombinant Newcastle Disease virus capsids displaying enterovirus 71 VP1 fragment induce a strong immune response in rabbits. J Med Virol. 2006;78:1096&#x2013;1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16789020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan CS, Cardosa MJ. High-titred neutralizing antibodies to human enterovirus 71 preferentially bind to the N-terminal portion of the capsid protein VP1. Arch Virol. 2007;152:1069&#x2013;1073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17318736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ch&#x2019;ng WC, Stanbridge EJ, Wong KT, Ong KC, Yusoff K, Shafee N. Immunization with recombinant enterovirus 71 viral capsid protein 1 fragment stimulated antibody responses in hamsters. Virol J. 2012;9:155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3462122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22877087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Jiang S, Wang Y. Recombinant VP1 protein expressed in Pichia pastoris induces protective immune responses against EV71 in mice. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2013;430:387&#x2013;393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23159634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F, Zhang ZR, Yuan F, Qin X, Wang M, Huang Y. In vitro and in vivo study of N-trimethyl chitosan nanoparticles for oral protein delivery. Int J Pharm. 2008;349:226&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17825506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Wu W, Xu X. Oral vaccination with liposome-encapsulated recombinant fusion peptide of urease B epitope and cholera toxin B subunit affords prophylactic and therapeutic effects against H. pylori infection in BALB/c mice. Vaccine. 2007;25:7664&#x2013;7673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17913305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu CH, Chu C, He CC, Lin TY. Protection of neonatal mice from lethal enterovirus 71 infection by maternal immunization with attenuated Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium expressing VP1 of enterovirus 71. Microbes Infect. 2006;8:1671&#x2013;1678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16815726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z, Huang Z, Sao C, Huang Y, Zhang F, Ma G, Chen Z, Zeng Z, Qiwen D, Zeng W. Oral immunization of mice using Bifidobacterium longum expressing VP1 protein from enterovirus 71. Arch Virol. 2013;158:1071&#x2013;1077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23275129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xe1;rdenas L, Clements JD. Oral immunization using live attenuated Salmonella spp. as carriers of foreign antigens. Clin Microbiol Rev. 1992;5:328&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC358247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1498769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Coppel RL. Oral vaccine delivery: can it protect against non-mucosal pathogens? Expert Rev Vaccines. 2008;7:729&#x2013;738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18665772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HF, Chang MH, Chiang BL, Jeng ST. Oral immunization of mice using transgenic tomato fruit expressing VP1 protein from enterovirus 71. Vaccine. 2006;24:2944&#x2013;2951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16448730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HL, Huang JY, Chu TW, Tsai TC, Hung CM, Lin CC, Liu FC, Wang LC, Chen YJ, Lin MF, et al. Expression of VP1 protein in the milk of transgenic mice: a potential oral vaccine protects against enterovirus 71 infection. Vaccine. 2008;26:2882&#x2013;2889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18450335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrillo C, Wigdorovitz A, Oliveros JC, Zamorano PI, Sadir AM, G&#xf3;mez N, Salinas J, Escribano JM, Borca MV. Protective immune response to foot-and-mouth disease virus with VP1 expressed in transgenic plants. J Virol. 1998;72:1688&#x2013;1690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC124657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9445079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Li YS, Chiou CC, Suen PC, Lin TY, Chang LY, Huang YC, Tsao KC, Ning HC, Wu TZ, et al. Expression of capsid [correction of caspid] protein VP1 for use as antigen for the diagnosis of enterovirus 71 infection. J Med Virol. 2000;61:228&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10797379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo DG, Alonso S, Chow VT, Poh CL. Passive protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by neutralizing antibodies elicited by a synthetic peptide. Microbes Infect. 2007;9:1299&#x2013;1306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17890123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian X, Su X, Li X, Li H, Li T, Zhou Z, Zhong T, Zhou R. Protection against enterovirus 71 with neutralizing epitope incorporation within adenovirus type 3 hexon. PLoS One. 2012;7:e41381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3407240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22848478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JN, Wang W, Duo JY, Hao Y, Ma CM, Li WB, Lin SZ, Gao XZ, Liu XL, Xu YF, et al. Combined peptides of human enterovirus 71 protect against virus infection in mice. Vaccine. 2010;28:7444&#x2013;7451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20831911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YC, Hsu JT, Huang JH, Ho MS, Ho YC. Formation of enterovirus-like particle aggregates by recombinant baculoviruses co-expressing P1 and 3CD in insect cells. Biotechnol Lett. 2003;25:919&#x2013;925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12889824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YL, Yu CI, Hu YC, Tsai TJ, Kuo YC, Chi WK, Lin AN, Chiang BL. Enterovirus type 71 neutralizing antibodies in the serum of macaque monkeys immunized with EV71 virus-like particles. Vaccine. 2012;30:1305&#x2013;1312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22214888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li HY, Han JF, Qin CF, Chen R. Virus-like particles for enterovirus 71 produced from Saccharomyces cerevisiae potently elicits protective immune responses in mice. Vaccine. 2013;31:3281&#x2013;3287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23726823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Limas WA, Tyo KE, Nielsen J, Ram&#xed;rez OT, Palomares LA. Molecular and process design for rotavirus-like particle production in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. Microb Cell Fact. 2011;10:33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3118324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21569612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung WS, Bakar SA, Sekawi Z, Rosli R. DNA vaccine constructs against enterovirus 71 elicit immune response in mice. Genet Vaccines Ther. 2007;5:6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3225814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17445254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Z, Baizer L, Mumper RJ. Intradermal immunization with novel plasmid DNA-coated nanoparticles via a needle-free injection device. J Biotechnol. 2003;102:105&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12697387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garmory HS, Brown KA, Titball RW. DNA vaccines: improving expression of antigens. Genet Vaccines Ther. 2003;1:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC244903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14606963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenland JR, Letvin NL. Chemical adjuvants for plasmid DNA vaccines. Vaccine. 2007;25:3731&#x2013;3741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17350735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurunathan S, Klinman DM, Seder RA. DNA vaccines: immunology, application, and optimization*. Annu Rev Immunol. 2000;18:927&#x2013;974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10837079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>