<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">22363322</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1664-302X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><PubDate><Year>2012</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Scavenger receptor b2 as a receptor for hand, foot, and mouth disease and severe neurological diseases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>32</StartPage><MedlinePgn>32</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">32</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fmicb.2012.00032</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is one of the major causative agents of hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD). Infection with EV71 is occasionally associated with severe neurological diseases such as acute encephalitis, acute flaccid paralysis, and cardiopulmonary failure. Because cellular receptors for viruses play an important role in cell, tissue, and species tropism, it is important to identify and characterize the receptor molecule. Recently, cellular receptors and host factors that stimulate EV71 infection have been identified. Several lines of evidence suggest that scavenger receptor class B, member 2 (SCARB2) plays critical roles in efficient EV71 infection and the development of disease in humans. In this review, we will summarize the findings of recent studies on EV71 infection and on the roles of SCARB2.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamayoshi</LastName><ForeName>Seiya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurovirology Project, Tokyo Metropolitan Institute of Medical Science Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujii</LastName><ForeName>Ken</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koike</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2012</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101548977</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-302X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EV71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HFMD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SCARB2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurological disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2012</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2012</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22363322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3277273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2012.00032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe S., Ota Y., Koike S., Kurata T., Horie H., Nomura T., Hashizume S., Nomoto A. (1995). Neurovirulence test for oral live polio vaccines using poliovirus-sensitive transgenic mice. Virology 206, 1075&#x2013;108310.1006/viro.1995.1030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/viro.1995.1030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7856082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad K. (2000). Hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak reported in Singapore. Lancet 356, 1338.10.1016/S0140-6736(05)73660-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(05)73660-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11073035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M., Ami Y., Wakita T., Shimizu H. (2008). Cooperative effect of the attenuation determinants derived from poliovirus sabin 1 strain is essential for attenuation of enterovirus 71 in the NOD/SCID mouse infection model. J. Virol. 82, 1787&#x2013;179710.1128/JVI.01798-07</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.01798-07</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2258712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18057246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M., Nagata N., Iwata N., Ami Y., Suzaki Y., Mizuta K., Iwasaki T., Sata T., Wakita T., Shimizu H. (2007). An attenuated strain of enterovirus 71 belonging to genotype a showed a broad spectrum of antigenicity with attenuated neurovirulence in cynomolgus monkeys. J. Virol. 81, 9386&#x2013;939510.1128/JVI.02856-06</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.02856-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17567701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M., Shimizu H., Nagata N., Ami Y., Suzaki Y., Sata T., Iwasaki T., Miyamura T. (2005). Temperature-sensitive mutants of enterovirus 71 show attenuation in cynomolgus monkeys. J. Gen. Virol. 86, 1391&#x2013;140110.1099/vir.0.80784-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/vir.0.80784-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergelson J. M. (2010). &#x201c;Receptors,&#x201d; in The Picornaviruses, eds Ehrenfeld E., Domingo E., Roos R. P. (Washington, DC: ASM Press; ), 73&#x2013;86</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkovic S. F., Dibbens L. M., Oshlack A., Silver J. D., Katerelos M., Vears D. F., Lullmann-Rauch R., Blanz J., Zhang K. W., Stankovich J., Kalnins R. M., Dowling J. P., Andermann E., Andermann F., Faldini E., D&#x2019;Hooge R., Vadlamudi L., Macdonell R. A., Hodgson B. L., Bayly M. A., Savige J., Mulley J. C., Smyth G. K., Power D. A., Saftig P., Bahlo M. (2008). Array-based gene discovery with three unrelated subjects shows SCARB2/LIMP-2 deficiency causes myoclonus epilepsy and glomerulosclerosis. Am. J. Hum. Genet. 82, 673&#x2013;68410.1016/j.ajhg.2007.12.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajhg.2007.12.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2427287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18308289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanz J., Groth J., Zachos C., Wehling C., Saftig P., Schwake M. (2010). Disease-causing mutations within the lysosomal integral membrane protein type 2 (LIMP-2) reveal the nature of binding to its ligand beta-glucocerebrosidase. Hum. Mol. Genet. 19, 563&#x2013;57210.1093/hmg/ddp523</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/ddp523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19933215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo D., Dopazo J., Vega M. A. (1995). The CD36, CLA-1 (CD36L1), and LIMPII (CD36L2) gene family: cellular distribution, chromosomal location, and genetic evolution. Genomics 25, 100&#x2013;10610.1016/0888-7543(95)80114-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0888-7543(95)80114-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7539776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan L. G., Parashar U. D., Lye M. S., Ong F. G., Zaki S. R., Alexander J. P., Ho K. K., Han L. L., Pallansch M. A., Suleiman A. B., Jegathesan M., Anderson L. J. (2000). Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. For the Outbreak Study Group. Clin. Infect. Dis. 31, 678&#x2013;68310.1086/313968</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/313968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P., Song Z., Qi Y., Feng X., Xu N., Sun Y., Wu X., Yao X., Mao Q., Li X., Dong W., Wan X., Huang N., Shen X., Liang Z., Li W. (2012). Molecular determinants of enterovirus 71 viral entry: a cleft around Q172 on VP1 interacts with a variable region on scavenge receptor B 2. J. Biol. Chem. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3307280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22219187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y. C., Yu C. K., Wang Y. F., Liu C. C., Su I. J., Lei H. Y. (2004). A murine oral enterovirus 71 infection model with central nervous system involvement. J. Gen. Virol. 85, 69&#x2013;7710.1099/vir.0.19423-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/vir.0.19423-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14718621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua B. H., Phuektes P., Sanders S. A., Nicholls P. K., McMinn P. C. (2008). The molecular basis of mouse adaptation by human enterovirus 71. J. Gen. Virol. 89, 1622&#x2013;163210.1099/vir.0.83676-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/vir.0.83676-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18559932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov K. M., Lavrova I. K., Martianova L. I., Korolev M. B., Bashkirtsev V. N., Voroshilova M. K. (1979a). Investigation of physicochemical properties of Bulgarian strain 258 of enterovirus type 71. Brief report. Arch. Virol. 60, 359&#x2013;36210.1007/BF01317508</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01317508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov M., Voroshilova M., Shindarov L., Lavrova I., Gracheva L., Koroleva G., Vasilenko S., Brodvarova I., Nikolova M., Gyurova S., Gacheva M., Mitov G., Ninov N., Tsylka E., Robinson I., Frolova M., Bashkirtsev V., Martiyanova L., Rodin V. (1979b). Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch. Virol. 60, 329&#x2013;34010.1007/BF01317508</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01317508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De W., Changwen K., Wei L., Monagin C., Jin Y., Cong M., Hanri Z., Jun S. (2011). A large outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by EV71 and CAV16 in Guangdong, China, 2009. Arch. Virol. 156, 945&#x2013;95310.1007/s00705-011-0929-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00705-011-0929-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21305327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskelinen E. L., Tanaka Y., Saftig P. (2003). At the acidic edge: emerging functions for lysosomal membrane proteins. Trends Cell Biol. 13, 137&#x2013;14510.1016/S0962-8924(03)00005-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0962-8924(03)00005-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12628346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans D. M., Dunn G., Minor P. D., Schild G. C., Cann A. J., Stanway G., Almond J. W., Currey K., Maizel J. V., Jr. (1985). Increased neurovirulence associated with a single nucleotide change in a noncoding region of the Sabin type 3 polio vaccine genome. Nature 314, 548&#x2013;55010.1038/314548a0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/314548a0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2986004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto T., Chikahira M., Yoshida S., Ebira H., Hasegawa A., Totsuka A., Nishio O. (2002). Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol. Immunol. 46, 621&#x2013;627</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamp A. C., Tanaka Y., Lullmann-Rauch R., Wittke D., D&#x2019;hooge R., De Deyn P. P., Moser T., Maier H., Hartmann D., Reiss K., Illert A. L., Von Figura K., Saftig P. (2003). LIMP-2/LGP85 deficiency causes ureteric pelvic junction obstruction, deafness and peripheral neuropathy in mice. Hum. Mol. Genet. 12, 631&#x2013;64610.1093/hmg/12.6.631</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/12.6.631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12620969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara A., Yoneyama T., Hashimoto I. (1983). Isolation of a temperature-sensitive strain of enterovirus 71 with reduced neurovirulence for monkeys. J. Gen. Virol. 64(Pt 2), 499&#x2013;50210.1099/0022-1317-64-2-499</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/0022-1317-64-2-499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6300298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara A., Yoneyama T., Takami S., Hashimoto I. (1984). Genetic and phenotypic characteristics of enterovirus 71 isolates from patients with encephalitis and with hand, foot and mouth disease. Arch. Virol. 79, 273&#x2013;28310.1007/BF01310816</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01310816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6320781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J. F., Cao R. Y., Deng Y. Q., Tian X., Jiang T., Qin E. D., Qin C. F. (2010). Antibody dependent enhancement infection of enterovirus 71 in vitro and in vivo. Virol. J. 8, 106.10.1186/1743-422X-8-106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-422X-8-106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3060144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21385398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto I., Hagiwara A. (1982). Pathogenicity of a poliomyelitis-like disease in monkeys infected orally with enterovirus 71: a model for human infection. Neuropathol. Appl. Neurobiol. 8, 149&#x2013;15610.1111/j.1365-2990.1982.tb00269.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2990.1982.tb00269.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7048123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto I., Hagiwara A., Kodama H. (1978). Neurovirulence in cynomolgus monkeys of enterovirus 71 isolated from a patient with hand, foot and mouth disease. Arch. Virol. 56, 257&#x2013;26110.1007/BF01317855</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01317855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">205198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M., Chen E. R., Hsu K. H., Twu S. J., Chen K. T., Tsai S. F., Wang J. R., Shih S. R. (1999). An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N. Engl. J. Med. 341, 929&#x2013;93510.1056/NEJM199909233411301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199909233411301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horie H., Koike S., Kurata T., Sato-Yoshida Y., Ise I., Ota Y., Abe S., Hioki K., Kato H., Taya C., Nomura T., Hashizume S., Yonekawa H., Nomoto A. (1994). Transgenic mice carrying the human poliovirus receptor: new animal models for study of poliovirus neurovirulence. J. Virol. 68, 681&#x2013;688</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC236503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8289371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S. W., Wang Y. F., Yu C. K., Su I. J., Wang J. R. (2012). Mutations in VP2 and VP1 capsid proteins increase infectivity and mouse lethality of enterovirus 71 by virus binding and RNA accumulation enhancement. Virology 422, 132&#x2013;14310.1016/j.virol.2011.10.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.virol.2011.10.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22078110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain K. M., Leong K. L., Ng M. M., Chu J. J. (2011). The essential role of clathrin-mediated endocytosis in the infectious entry of human enterovirus 71. J. Biol. Chem. 286, 309&#x2013;32110.1074/jbc.M110.168468</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M110.168468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3012988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20956521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamura N., Kohara M., Abe S., Komatsu T., Tago K., Arita M., Nomoto A. (1989). Determinants in the 5&#x2032; noncoding region of poliovirus Sabin 1 RNA that influence the attenuation phenotype. J. Virol. 63, 1302&#x2013;1309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC247827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2536835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khong W. X., Yan B., Yeo H., Tan E. L., Lee J. J., Ng J. K., Chow V. T., Alonso S. (2012). A non mouse-adapted enterovirus 71 (EV71) strain exhibits neurotropism causing neurological manifestations in a novel mouse model of EV71 infection. J. Virol. 86, 2121&#x2013;213110.1128/JVI.06103-11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.06103-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3302383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22130542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koike S., Taya C., Kurata T., Abe S., Ise I., Yonekawa H., Nomoto A. (1991). Transgenic mice susceptible to poliovirus. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 88, 951&#x2013;95510.1073/pnas.88.3.951</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.88.3.951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC50932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1846972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu H., Shimizu Y., Takeuchi Y., Ishiko H., Takada H. (1999). Outbreak of severe neurologic involvement associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr. Neurol. 20, 17&#x2013;2310.1016/S0887-8994(98)00087-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0887-8994(98)00087-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuronita T., Eskelinen E. L., Fujita H., Saftig P., Himeno M., Tanaka Y. (2002). A role for the lysosomal membrane protein LGP85 in the biogenesis and maintenance of endosomal and lysosomal morphology. J. Cell. Sci. 115, 4117&#x2013;413110.1242/jcs.00075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/jcs.00075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12356916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Borgne R., Planque N., Martin P., Dewitte F., Saule S., Hoflack B. (2001). The AP-3-dependent targeting of the melanosomal glycoprotein QNR-71 requires a di-leucine-based sorting signal. J. Cell. Sci. 114, 2831&#x2013;2841</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11683416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R., Zou Q., Chen L., Zhang H., Wang Y. (2011). Molecular analysis of virulent determinants of enterovirus 71. PLoS ONE 6, e26237.10.1371/journal.pone.0026237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0026237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22039449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Dong W., Quan X., Ma C., Qin C., Zhang L. (2011). Transgenic expression of human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is not sufficient for enterovirus 71 infection in mice. Arch. Virol.10.1007/s00705-011-1198-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00705-011-1198-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22187102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum L. C., Wong K. T., Lam S. K., Chua K. B., Goh A. Y., Lim W. L., Ong B. B., Paul G., Abubakar S., Lambert M. (1998). Fatal enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. J. Pediatr. 133, 795&#x2013;79810.1016/S0022-3476(98)70155-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-3476(98)70155-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P., Lindsay K., Perera D., Chan H. M., Chan K. P., Cardosa M. J. (2001a). Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J. Virol. 75, 7732&#x2013;773810.1128/JVI.75.16.7732-7738.2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.75.16.7732-7738.2001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P., Stratov I., Nagarajan L., Davis S. (2001b). Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin. Infect. Dis. 32, 236&#x2013;24210.1086/318454</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/318454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick J. L. (1984). Enterovirus type 71 infections: a varied clinical pattern sometimes mimicking paralytic poliomyelitis. Rev. Infect. Dis. 6(Suppl. 2), S387&#x2013;S39010.1093/clinids/6.Supplement_2.S323</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/clinids/6.Supplement_2.S323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamura K., Nishimura Y., Abo M., Wakita T., Shimizu H. (2011). Adaptive mutations in the genomes of enterovirus 71 strains following infection of mouse cells expressing human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1. J. Gen. Virol. 92, 287&#x2013;29110.1099/vir.0.022418-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/vir.0.022418-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20943886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta K., Abiko C., Murata T., Matsuzaki Y., Itagaki T., Sanjoh K., Sakamoto M., Hongo S., Murayama S., Hayasaka K. (2005). Frequent importation of enterovirus 71 from surrounding countries into the local community of Yamagata, Japan, between 1998 and 2003. J. Clin. Microbiol. 43, 6171&#x2013;617510.1128/JCM.43.12.6171-6175.2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.43.12.6171-6175.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16333123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta K., Aoki Y., Suto A., Ootani K., Katsushima N., Itagaki T., Ohmi A., Okamoto M., Nishimura H., Matsuzaki Y., Hongo S., Sugawara K., Shimizu H., Ahiko T. (2009). Cross-antigenicity among EV71 strains from different genogroups isolated in Yamagata, Japan, between 1990 and 2007. Vaccine 27, 3153&#x2013;315810.1016/j.vaccine.2009.03.060</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2009.03.060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19446185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata N., Iwasaki T., Ami Y., Tano Y., Harashima A., Suzaki Y., Sato Y., Hasegawa H., Sata T., Miyamura T., Shimizu H. (2004). Differential localization of neurons susceptible to enterovirus 71 and poliovirus type 1 in the central nervous system of cynomolgus monkeys after intravenous inoculation. J. Gen. Virol. 85, 2981&#x2013;298910.1099/vir.0.79883-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/vir.0.79883-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15448361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata N., Shimizu H., Ami Y., Tano Y., Harashima A., Suzaki Y., Sato Y., Miyamura T., Sata T., Iwasaki T. (2002). Pyramidal and extrapyramidal involvement in experimental infection of cynomolgus monkeys with enterovirus 71. J. Med. Virol. 67, 207&#x2013;21610.1002/jmv.2209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.2209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11992581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y., Shimojima M., Tano Y., Miyamura T., Wakita T., Shimizu H. (2009). Human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15, 794&#x2013;79710.1038/nm.1964</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.1964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste M. S., Jiang X., Maher K., Nix W. A., Jiang B. (2008). The complete genome sequences for three simian enteroviruses isolated from captive primates. Arch. Virol. 153, 2117&#x2013;212210.1007/s00705-008-0225-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00705-008-0225-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18941864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste M. S., Maher K., Pallansch M. A. (2007). Complete genome sequences for nine simian enteroviruses. J. Gen. Virol. 88, 3360&#x2013;337210.1099/vir.0.83124-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/vir.0.83124-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18024906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omata T., Kohara M., Kuge S., Komatsu T., Abe S., Semler B. L., Kameda A., Itoh H., Arita M., Wimmer E., Nomoto A. (1986). Genetic analysis of the attenuation phenotype of poliovirus type 1. J. Virol. 58, 348&#x2013;358</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC252919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3009852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong K. C., Badmanathan M., Devi S., Leong K. L., Cardosa M. J., Wong K. T. (2008). Pathologic characterization of a murine model of human enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol. 67, 532&#x2013;54210.1097/NEN.0b013e31817713e7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NEN.0b013e31817713e7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18520772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallansch M., Roos R. (2007). &#x201c;Enteroviruses: polioviruses, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses, and newer enteroviruses,&#x201d; in Fields Virology, 5th Edn, eds Knipe D. M., Howley P. M., Griffin D. E., Lamb R. A., Martin M. A., Roizman B., Straus S. E. (Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; ), 839&#x2013;893</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu J. (2008). Enterovirus 71 infection: a new threat to global public health? Lancet Neurol. 7, 868&#x2013;86910.1016/S1474-4422(08)70102-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(08)70102-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18848307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren R. B., Costantini F., Gorgacz E. J., Lee J. J., Racaniello V. R. (1990). Transgenic mice expressing a human poliovirus receptor: a new model for poliomyelitis. Cell 63, 353&#x2013;36210.1016/0092-8674(90)90168-E</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0092-8674(90)90168-E</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2170026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodionov D. G., Honing S., Silye A., Kongsvik T. L., Von Figura K., Bakke O. (2002). Structural requirements for interactions between leucine-sorting signals and clathrin-associated adaptor protein complex AP3. J. Biol. Chem. 277, 47436&#x2013;4744310.1074/jbc.M208965200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M208965200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12370188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt N. J., Lennette E. H., Ho H. H. (1974). An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J. Infect. Dis. 129, 304&#x2013;30910.1093/infdis/129.3.304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/129.3.304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shieh W. J., Jung S. M., Hsueh C., Kuo T. T., Mounts A., Parashar U., Yang C. F., Guarner J., Ksiazek T. G., Dawson J., Goldsmith C., Chang G. J., Oberste S. M., Pallansch M. A., Anderson L. J., Zaki S. R. (2001). Pathologic studies of fatal cases in outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease, Taiwan. Emerging Infect. Dis. 7, 146&#x2013;14810.3201/eid0701.010122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid0701.010122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2631691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11266307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J. R., Tuan Y. C., Tsai H. P., Yan J. J., Liu C. C., Su I. J. (2002). Change of major genotype of enterovirus 71 in outbreaks of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Taiwan between 1998 and 2000. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40, 10&#x2013;1510.1128/JCM.40.7.2584-2590.2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.40.7.2584-2590.2002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S. M., Liu C. C., Tseng H. W., Wang J. R., Huang C. C., Chen Y. J., Yang Y. J., Lin S. J., Yeh T. F. (1999). Clinical spectrum of enterovirus 71 infection in children in southern Taiwan, with an emphasis on neurological complications. Clin. Infect. Dis. 29, 184&#x2013;19010.1086/520149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/520149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10433583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Duo J., Liu J., Ma C., Zhang L., Wei Q., Qin C. (2011). A mouse muscle-adapted enterovirus 71 strain with increased virulence in mice. Microbes Infect. 13, 862&#x2013;87010.1016/j.micinf.2011.04.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.micinf.2011.04.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21612764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y. F., Chou C. T., Lei H. Y., Liu C. C., Wang S. M., Yan J. J., Su I. J., Wang J. R., Yeh T. M., Chen S. H., Yu C. K. (2004). A mouse-adapted enterovirus 71 strain causes neurological disease in mice after oral infection. J. Virol. 78, 7916&#x2013;792410.1128/JVI.78.2.821-833.2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.78.2.821-833.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC446098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westrop G. D., Wareham K. A., Evans D. M., Dunn G., Minor P. D., Magrath D. I., Taffs F., Marsden S., Skinner M. A., Schild G. C., Almond J. W. (1989). Genetic basis of attenuation of the Sabin type 3 oral poliovirus vaccine. J. Virol. 63, 1338&#x2013;1344</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC247831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2536836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S., Koike S. (2011). Identification of a human SCARB2 region that is important for enterovirus 71 binding and infection. J. Virol. 85, 4937&#x2013;494610.1128/JVI.02358-10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.02358-10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3126200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21389126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S., Yamashita Y., Li J., Hanagata N., Minowa T., Takemura T., Koike S. (2009). Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15, 798&#x2013;80110.1038/nm.1992</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.1992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B., Chuang H., Yang K. D. (2009). Sialylated glycans as receptor and inhibitor of enterovirus 71 infection to DLD-1 intestinal cells. Virol. J. 6, 141.10.1186/1743-422X-6-138</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-422X-6-138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2751754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19751532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S. L., Chou Y. T., Wu C. N., Ho M. S. (2011). Annexin II binds to capsid protein VP1 of enterovirus 71 and enhances viral infectivity. J. Virol. 85, 11809&#x2013;1182010.1128/JVI.00301-11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.00301-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3209289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21900167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C. K., Chen C. C., Chen C. L., Wang J. R., Liu C. C., Yan J. J., Su I. J. (2000). Neutralizing antibody provided protection against enterovirus type 71 lethal challenge in neonatal mice. J. Biomed. Sci. 7, 523&#x2013;52810.1007/BF02253368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02253368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11060501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Cui W., Liu L., Wang J., Zhao H., Liao Y., Na R., Dong C., Wang L., Xie Z., Gao J., Cui P., Zhang X., Li Q. (2011). Pathogenesis study of enterovirus 71 infection in rhesus monkeys. Lab. Invest. 91, 1337&#x2013;135010.1038/labinvest.2011.82</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/labinvest.2011.82</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21555996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>