<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34377228</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1943-8141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of translational research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Transl Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Integrative analysis of lncRNA-miRNA-mRNA-associated competing endogenous RNA regulatory network involved in EV71 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7440</StartPage><EndPage>7457</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7440-7457</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The competing endogenous RNA (ceRNA) axis has been shown to play a critical role in the pathogenesis of various viral infections. Generally, the ceRNA network involves long non-coding RNAs (lncRNAs) that act as sponges for miRNA to regulate mRNA expression. However, no information is available regarding the involvement of ceRNA networks in Enterovirus type 71 (EV71) infections. In the present study, data obtained from Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO) database was analyzed using various bioinformatics tools. EV71 infection in rhabdomyosarcoma (RD) cells was associated with differential expression of six lncRNAs, 28 miRNAs, and 349 mRNAs. Gene function enrichment analysis suggested induction of cytoplasmic vesicle process upon EV71 infection. The ceRNA networks were constructed, in which 20 hub genes were predicted by protein-protein interaction. To confirm the MALAT1/miR-194-5p/DUSP1 ceRNA regulatory axis in EV71 infection, real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR) and luciferase reporter assay were performed. The results of the study also revealed the involvement of the MALAT1/miR-194-5p axis in apoptosis induced by EV71 infection, while no association with autophagy was observed. Thus, the present study provided novel insights into the pathogenic mechanism of EV71 infection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJTR Copyright &#xa9; 2021.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Yanzhi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Diagnosis, Tangdu Hospital, Air Force Medical University Xi'an, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Pathogen Biology, Basic Medical School, Air Force Medical University Xi'an, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Zhaowei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Diagnosis, Tangdu Hospital, Air Force Medical University Xi'an, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Diagnosis, Tangdu Hospital, Air Force Medical University Xi'an, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Diagnosis, Tangdu Hospital, Air Force Medical University Xi'an, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Longfei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Diagnosis, Tangdu Hospital, Air Force Medical University Xi'an, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ruicheng</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Diagnosis, Tangdu Hospital, Air Force Medical University Xi'an, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Ke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Diagnosis, Tangdu Hospital, Air Force Medical University Xi'an, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Huizhong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Diagnosis, Tangdu Hospital, Air Force Medical University Xi'an, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Transl Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101493030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1943-8141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus type 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MALAT1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apoptosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bioinformatics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">competing endogenous RNA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">miR-194-5p</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34377228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8340214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Puenpa J, Wanlapakorn N, Vongpunsawad S, Poovorawan Y. The history of enterovirus A71 outbreaks and molecular epidemiology in the asia-pacific region. J Biomed Sci. 2019;26:75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6798416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31627753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Van Tan L, Luo K, Liao Q, Wang L, Qiu Q, Zou G, Liu P, Anh NT, Hong NTT, He M, Wei X, Yu S, Lam TT, Cui J, van Doorn HR, Yu H. Genetic variation of multiple serotypes of enteroviruses associated with hand, foot and mouth disease in Southern China. Virol Sin. 2021;36:61&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu SB, Luo KW, Zhou YH, Dai BB, Liu FF, Yang H, Luo L, Liu J, Wang LL, Li Q, Ren LS, Liao QH, Yu HJ. Hospitalization burden of hand, foot and mouth disease in Anhua county of Hunan province, 2013-2016. Zhonghua Liu Xing Bing Xue Za Zhi. 2019;40:79&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30669736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Principi N. Hand, foot and mouth disease: current knowledge on clinical manifestations, epidemiology, aetiology and prevention. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2018;37:391&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29411190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan YW, Chu JJH. Protecting the most vulnerable from hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancent Infect Dis. 2021;21:308&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Zhou Y, Li H. LncRNA, miRNA and lncRNA-miRNA interaction in viral infection. Virus Res. 2018;257:25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Li X, Hu J, Cao P, Yan Q, Zhang S, Dang W, Lu J. Long noncoding RNAs involvement in epstein-barr virus infection and tumorigenesis. Virol J. 2020;17:51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32272952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng B, Zhou J, Wang H. Host microRNAs and exosomes that modulate influenza virus infection. Virus Res. 2020;279:197885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31981772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao YW, Ho BC, Chen MH, Yu SL. Host relieves lnc-IRAK3-3-sequestered miR-891b to attenuate apoptosis in enterovirus 71 infection. Cell Microbiol. 2019;21:e13043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31099182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Zhang C, Qin L, Li D, Zhou G, Dang D, Chen S, Sun T, Zhang R, Wu W, Xi Y, Jin Y, Duan G. Characterization of critical functions of long non-coding RNAs and mRNAs in rhabdomyosarcoma cells and mouse skeletal muscle infected by enterovirus 71 using RNA-seq. Viruses. 2018;10:556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6213062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30314355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin Z, Guan D, Fan Q, Su J, Zheng W, Ma W, Ke C. LncRNA expression signatures in response to enterovirus 71 infection. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2013;430:629&#x2013;633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23220233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng J, Yao Z, He Y, Zhang R, Yang H, Yao X, Chen L, Zhang H, Cheng J. Long non-coding RNA expression profiles in different severity EV71-infected hand foot and mouth disease patients. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2017;493:1594&#x2013;1600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7092854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28993196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian L, Wang Y, Liu Q, Xia J, Long JE. Prediction of signaling pathways involved in enterovirus 71 infection by algorithm analysis based on miRNA profiles and their target genes. Arch Virol. 2015;160:173&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25287131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Xu L, Lu B, Zhao M, Li L, Sun W, Qiu Z, Zhang B. LncRNA H19/microRNA-675/PPARalpha axis regulates liver cell injury and energy metabolism remodelling induced by hepatitis B X protein via Akt/mTOR signalling. Mol Immunol. 2019;116:18&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31574452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye W, Yao M, Dong Y, Ye C, Wang D, Liu H, Ma H, Zhang H, Qi L, Yang Y, Wang Y, Zhang L, Cheng L, Lv X, Xu Z, Lei Y, Zhang F. Remdesivir (GS-5734) impedes enterovirus replication through viral RNA synthesis inhibition. Front Microbiol. 2020;11:1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7304253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32595613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao M, Dong Y, Wang Y, Liu H, Ma H, Zhang H, Zhang L, Cheng L, Lv X, Xu Z, Zhang F, Lei Y, Ye W. N(6)-methyladenosine modifications enhance enterovirus 71 ORF translation through METTL3 cytoplasmic distribution. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2020;527:297&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32446384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Yuan M, Wang S, Zhang L, Zhang R, Zou X, Wang X, Chen D, Wu Z. STAT3 regulates the type I IFN-mediated antiviral response by interfering with the nuclear entry of STAT1. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20:4870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6801597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31575039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung WH, Lee IT, Hsieh HL, Yang CM. EV71 induces COX-2 expression via c-Src/PDGFR/PI3K/Akt/p42/p44 MAPK/AP-1 and NF-kappaB in rat brain astrocytes. J Cell Physiol. 2010;224:376&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20333648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Cheng X, Yang X, Zhao R, Wang P, Han Y, Luo Z, Cao Y, Zhu C, Xiong Y, Liu Y, Wu K, Wu J. Early growth response-1 facilitates enterovirus 71 replication by direct binding to the viral genome RNA. Int J Biochem Cell Biol. 2015;62:36&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25724735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharyya S, Vrati S. The malat1 long non-coding RNA is upregulated by signalling through the PERK axis of unfolded protein response during flavivirus infection. Sci Rep. 2015;5:17794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4669524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26634309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nan CC, Zhang N, Cheung KCP, Zhang HD, Li W, Hong CY, Chen HS, Liu XY, Li N, Cheng L. Knockdown of lncRNA MALAT1 alleviates LPS-induced acute lung injury via inhibiting apoptosis through the miR-194-5p/FOXP2 axis. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2020;8:586869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33117815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Wang F, Ouyang W, Jiang X, Li W. MALAT1 knockdown inhibits hypopharyngeal squamous cell carcinoma malignancy by targeting microRNA-194. Oncol Lett. 2020;20:173&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7285813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32565945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Y, Zhang F, Chen Q, Huang Z, Li M. LncRNA MALAT1 modified progression of clear cell kidney carcinoma (KIRC) by regulation of miR-194-5p/ACVR2B signaling. Mol Carcinog. 2019;58:279&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30334578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li ML, Lin JY, Chen BS, Weng KF, Shih SR, Calderon JD, Tolbert BS, Brewer G. EV71 3C protease induces apoptosis by cleavage of hnRNP A1 to promote apaf-1 translation. PLoS One. 2019;14:e0221048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6733512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31498791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Hao X, Cao J, Xie X, Wang H. BNIP3 deletion ameliorated enterovirus 71 infection-induced hand, foot and mouth disease via inhibiting apoptosis, autophagy, and inflammation in mice. Int Immunopharmacol. 2020;87:106799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32717566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>You L, Chen J, Liu W, Xiang Q, Luo Z, Wang W, Xu W, Wu K, Zhang Q, Liu Y, Wu J. Enterovirus 71 induces neural cell apoptosis and autophagy through promoting ACOX1 downregulation and ROS generation. Virulence. 2020;11:537&#x2013;553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7250321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32434419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xi X, Zhang X, Wang B, Wang T, Wang J, Huang H, Wang J, Jin Q, Zhao Z. The interplays between autophagy and apoptosis induced by enterovirus 71. PLoS One. 2013;8:e56966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3577684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23437282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu ZW, Zhuang ZC, Chen R, Wang XR, Zhang HL, Li SH, Wang ZY, Wen HL. Enterovirus 71 VP1 protein regulates viral replication in SH-SY5Y cells via the mTOR autophagy signaling pathway. Viruses. 2019;12:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7019657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31861844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SC, Chang CL, Wang PS, Tsai Y, Liu HS. Enterovirus 71-induced autophagy detected in vitro and in vivo promotes viral replication. J Med Virol. 2009;81:1241&#x2013;1252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7166624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19475621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P, Yang S, Hu D, Wei D, Lu J, Zheng H, Nie S, Liu G, Yang H. Enterovirus 71 VP1 promotes mouse Schwann cell autophagy via ER stressmediated PMP22 upregulation. Int J Mol Med. 2019;44:759&#x2013;767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31173167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du N, Li XH, Bao WG, Wang B, Xu G, Wang F. Resveratrolloaded nanoparticles inhibit enterovirus 71 replication through the oxidative stressmediated ERS/autophagy pathway. Int J Mol Med. 2019;44:737&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31173159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barile L, Vassalli G. Exosomes: therapy delivery tools and biomarkers of diseases. Pharmacol Ther. 2017;174:63&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28202367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>