<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16085845</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rapid detection of enteroviruses in small volumes of natural waters by real-time quantitative reverse transcriptase PCR.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4523</StartPage><EndPage>4530</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4523-30</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Despite viral contamination of recreational waters, only bacterial, not viral, indicators are monitored routinely, due to a lack of rapid and cost-effective assays. We used negatively charged filters to capture enteroviruses from seawater and freshwater. Viral RNA was extracted using a commercial kit, and the viruses were quantified by real-time quantitative reverse transcriptase PCR (qRT-PCR). Poliovirus (6.6 to 330,000 virus particles/ml) was added to samples from watersheds in Los Angeles, California, and analysis showed that with 50-ml samples, a cellulose acetate/nitrate (HA) filter yielded final recovery of 51% (r2= 0.99) in fresh water and 23% (r2= 0.90) in seawater. However, for additions of low levels of virus (more likely to represent field samples; &lt;10(4) enterovirus particles/ml), the recovery was lower and more variable, with HA being best in freshwater (17%, r2= 0.97) and the type GF/F glass filter having higher average recovery in seawater (GF/F, 17%; r2= 0.93; HA 12%, r2= 0.87). The optimized method was used with 1-liter field samples from two very different freshwater "creeks" that drain into Santa Monica Bay, California: Topanga Creek (TC), a relatively pristine mountain creek, and Ballona Creek (BC), a concrete-lined urban storm drain. One TC site out of 10 and 2 BC sites out of 7 tested significantly positive for enteroviruses, with higher enterovirus concentrations in BC than in TC (ca. 10 to 25 versus 1 equivalent enterovirus particle/ml). The presented filtration-qRT-PCR approach is fast (&lt;8 h from sampling to results), sensitive, and cost efficient and is promising for monitoring viral contamination in environmental water samples.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fuhrman</LastName><ForeName>Jed A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences and Wrigley Institute for Environmental Studies, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA 90089-0371, USA. fuhrman@usc.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaolin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noble</LastName><ForeName>Rachel T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D023362">Evaluation Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3J2P07GVB6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C005062">acetylcellulose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9004-34-6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002482">Cellulose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9004-70-0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003101">Collodion</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002482" MajorTopicYN="N">Cellulose</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000031" MajorTopicYN="N">analogs &amp; derivatives</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003101" MajorTopicYN="N">Collodion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005374" MajorTopicYN="N">Filtration</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005618" MajorTopicYN="N">Fresh Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005898" MajorTopicYN="N">Glass</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017955" MajorTopicYN="N">Poliovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012623" MajorTopicYN="N">Seawater</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014773" MajorTopicYN="N">Virology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16085845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1183282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.8.4523-4530.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">71/8/4523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Boehm, A. B., J. A. Fuhrman, R. D. Mr&#x161;e, and S. B. Grant. 2003. A tiered approach for identification of a human fecal pollution source at a recreational beach: case study at Avalon Bay, Catalina Island, California, USA. Env. Sci. Technol. 37:673-680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12636264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borrego, J. J., R. Cornax, D. R. Preston, S. R. Farrah, R. McElhaney, and G. Bitton. 1991. Development and application of new positively charged filters for recovery of bacteriophages from water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 57:1218-1222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2059044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, B. D., R. Dulbecco, H. N. Eisen, and H. S. Ginsberg. 1990. Microbiology, 4th ed. J. B. Lippincott, Philadelphia, Pa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson, K. A., D. W. Griffin, and J. H. Paul. 2002. Detection, quantitation and identification of enteroviruses from surface waters and sponge tissue from the Florida Keys using real-time RT-PCR. Water Res. 36:2505-2514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12153016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enriquez, C. E., M. Abbaszadegan, I. L. Pepper, K. J. Richardson, and C. P. Gerba. 1993. Poliovirus detection in water by cell culture and nucleic-acid hybridization. Water Res. 27:1113-1118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba, C. P. 1988. Viral disease transmission by seafoods. Food Technol. 42:99-103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greening, G. E., J. Hewitt, and G. D. Lewis. 2002. Evaluation of integrated cell culture-PCR (C-PCR) for virological analysis of environmental samples. J. Appl. Microbiol. 93:745-750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12392518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin, D. W., K. A. Donaldson, J. H. Paul, and J. B. Rose. 2003. Pathogenic human viruses in coastal waters. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 16:129-143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC145303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12525429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin, D. W., C. J. Gibson, E. K. Lipp, K. Riley, J. H. Paul, and J. B. Rose. 1999. Detection of viral pathogens by reverse transcriptase PCR and of microbial indicators by standard methods in the canals of the Florida Keys. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 65:4118-4125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC99749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10473424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haile, R. W., J. S. Witte, M. Gold, R. Cressey, C. McGee, R. C. Millikan, A. Glasser, N. Harawa, C. Ervin, P. Harmon, J. Harper, J. Dermand, J. Alamillo, K. Barrett, M. Nides, and G. Y. Wang. 1999. The health effects of swimming in ocean water contaminated by storm drain runoff. Epidemiology 10:355-363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10401868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, S., R. Noble, and W. P. Chui. 2001. Human adenoviruses and coliphages in urban runoff-impacted coastal waters of Southern California. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 67:179-184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11133443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, S. C., and W. Chu. 2004. PCR detection of pathogenic viruses in southern California urban rivers. J. Appl. Microbiol. 97:17-28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15186438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katayama, H., A. Shimasaki, and S. Ohgaki. 2002. Development of a virus concentration method and its application to detection of enterovirus and Norwalk virus from coastal seawater. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:1033-1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC123733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11872447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Cann, P., S. Ranarijaona, S. Monpoeho, F. Le Guyader, and V. Ferre. 2004. Quantification of human astroviruses in sewage using real-time RT-PCR. Res. Microbiol. 155:11-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14759703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, H. K., and Y. S. Jeong. 2004. Comparison of total culturable virus assay and multiplex integrated cell culture-PCR for reliability of waterborne virus detection. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 70:3632-3636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC427734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15184167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lennette, E. H., D. A. Lennette, and E. T. Lennette. 1995. Diagnostic procedures for viral, rickettsial, and chlamydial infections, 7th edition. American Public Health Association, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. W., X. W. Wang, C. Q. Yuan, J. L. Zheng, M. Jin, N. Song, X. Q. Shi, and F. H. Chao. 2002. Detection of enteroviruses and hepatitis A virus in water by consensus primer multiplex RT-PCR. World J. Gastroenterol. 8:699-702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4656323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12174381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed, N., A. Elfaitouri, J. Fohlman, G. Friman, and J. Blomberg. 2004. A sensitive and quantitative single-tube real-time reverse transcriptase-PCR for detection of enteroviral RNA. J. Clin. Virol. 30:150-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15125871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monpoeho, S., A. Dehee, B. Mignotte, L. Schwartzbrod, V. Marechal, J. C. Nicolas, S. Billaudel, and V. Ferre. 2000. Quantification of enterovirus RNA in sludge samples using single tube real-time RT-PCR. BioTechniques 29:88-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10907082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monpoeho, S., A. Maul, B. Mignotte-Cadiergues, L. Schwartzbrod, S. Billaudel, and V. Ferre. 2001. Best viral elution method available for quantification of enteroviruses in sludge by both cell culture and reverse transcription-PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 67:2484-2488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11375154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijhuis, M., N. van Maarseveen, R. Schuurman, S. Verkuijlen, M. de Vos, K. Hendriksen, and A. M. van Loon. 2002. Rapid and sensitive routine detection of all members of the genus enterovirus in different clinical specimens by real-time PCR. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:3666-3670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC130891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12354863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble, R. T., and J. A. Fuhrman. 2001. Enteroviruses detected by reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction from the coastal waters of Santa Monica Bay, California: low correlation to bacterial indicator levels. Hydrobiologia 460:175-184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble, R. T., and J. A. Fuhrman. 1998. Use of SYBR Green I for rapid epifluorescence counts of marine viruses and bacteria. Aquat. Microb. Ecol. 14:113-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul, J. H., J. B. Rose, S. C. Jiang, X. T. Zhou, P. Cochran, C. Kellogg, J. B. Kang, D. Griffin, S. Farrah, and J. Lukasik. 1997. Evidence for groundwater and surface marine water contamination by waste disposal wells in the Florida Keys. Water Res. 31:1448-1454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pina, S., M. Puig, F. Lucena, J. Jofre, and R. Girones. 1998. Viral pollution in the environment and in shellfish: human adenovirus detection by PCR as an index of human viruses. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 64:3376-3382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC106735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9726885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds, K. A., C. P. Gerba, M. Abbaszadegan, and I. L. Pepper. 2001. ICC/PCR detection of enteroviruses and hepatitis A virus in environmental samples. Can. J. Microbiol. 47:153-157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11261495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds, K. A., C. P. Gerba, and I. L. Pepper. 1996. Detection of infectious enteroviruses by an integrated cell culture PCR procedure. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 62:1424-1427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8919804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds, K. A., K. Roll, R. S. Fujioka, C. P. Gerba, and I. L. Pepper. 1998. Incidence of enteroviruses in Mamala Bay, Hawaii using cell culture and direct polymerase chain reaction methodologies. Can. J. Microbiol. 44:598-604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9734309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab, K. J., F. H. Neill, M. K. Estes, T. G. Metcalf, and R. L. Atmar. 1998. Distribution of Norwalk virus within shellfish following bioaccumulation and subsequent depuration by detection using RT-PCR. J. Food Prot. 61:1674-1680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9874348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey, M. D., K. J. Schwab, and T. R. Handzel. 1990. A simple membrane-filter method to concentrate and enumerate male-specific RNA coliphages. J. Am. Water Works Assoc. 82:52-59.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>