<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23760234</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>87</Volume><Issue>16</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Caveolar endocytosis is required for human PSGL-1-mediated enterovirus 71 infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9064</StartPage><EndPage>9076</EndPage><MedlinePgn>9064-76</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.00573-13</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) causes hand, foot, and mouth disease and severe neurological disorders in children. Human scavenger receptor class B member 2 (hSCARB2) and P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 (PSGL-1) are identified as receptors for EV71. The underling mechanism of PSGL-1-mediated EV71 entry remains unclear. The endocytosis required for EV71 entry were investigated in Jurkat T and mouse L929 cells constitutively expressing human PSGL-1 (PSGL-1-L929) or human rhabdomyosarcoma (RD) cells displaying high SCARB2 but no PSGL-1 by treatment of specific inhibitors or siRNA. We found that disruption of clathrin-dependent endocytosis prevented EV71 infection in RD cells, while there was no influence in Jurkat T and PSGL-1-L929 cells. Disturbing caveolar endocytosis by specific inhibitor or caveolin-1 siRNA in Jurkat T and PSGL-1-L929 cells significantly blocked EV71 infection, whereas it had no effect on EV71 infection in RD cells. Confocal immunofluorescence demonstrated caveola, and EV71 was directly colocalized. pH-dependent endosomal acidification and intact membrane cholesterol were important for EV71 infection, as judged by the pretreatment of inhibitors that abrogated the infection. A receptor-dominated endocytosis of EV71 infection was observed: PSGL-1 initiates caveola-dependent endocytosis and hSCARB2 activates clathrin-dependent endocytosis.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Hsiang-Yin</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Infectious Disease and Vaccinology, National Health Research Institutes, Zhunan, Miaoli County, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Ya-Ting</ForeName><Initials>YT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Shu-Ling</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsiao</LastName><ForeName>Kuang-Nan</ForeName><Initials>KN</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chia-Chyi</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sia</LastName><ForeName>Charles</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chow</LastName><ForeName>Yen-Hung</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D051242">Caveolin 1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008562">Membrane Glycoproteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C084882">P-selectin ligand protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011991">Receptors, Virus</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051242" MajorTopicYN="N">Caveolin 1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004705" MajorTopicYN="Y">Endocytosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055785" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Knockdown Techniques</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008562" MajorTopicYN="N">Membrane Glycoproteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018613" MajorTopicYN="N">Microscopy, Confocal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011991" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Virus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053586" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Internalization</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23760234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3754029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.00573-13</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.00573-13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Manki A, Oda M, Seino Y. 1997. Neurologic diseases of enterovirus infections: polioviruses, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses, and enteroviruses type 68 to 72. Nihon Rinsho 55:849&#x2013;854 (In Japanese.)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9103882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, Twu SJ, Chen KT, Tsai SF, Wang JR, Shih SR. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929&#x2013;935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Tseng HW, Wang SM, Wang JR, Su IJ. 2000. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998: epidemiologic and clinical manifestations. J. Clin. Virol. 17:23&#x2013;30</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Liu CC, Tseng HW, Wang JR, Huang CC, Chen YJ, Yang YJ, Lin SJ, Yeh TF. 1999. Clinical spectrum of enterovirus 71 infection in children in southern Taiwan, with an emphasis on neurological complications. Clin. Infect. Dis. 29:184&#x2013;190</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10433583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg J, Lycke E, Ahlfors K, Johnsson T, Wolontis S, von Zeipel G. 1974. New enterovirus type associated with epidemic of aseptic meningitis and-or hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet ii:112 (Letter.)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4136956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara A, Tagaya I, Yoneyama T. 1978. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Intervirology 9:60&#x2013;63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">202573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu J. 2008. Enterovirus 71 infection: a new threat to global public health? Lancet Neurol. 7:868&#x2013;869</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18848307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Yamashita Y, Li J, Hanagata N, Minowa T, Takemura T, Koike S. 2009. Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15:798&#x2013;801</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Shimojima M, Tano Y, Miyamura T, Wakita T, Shimizu H. 2009. Human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15:794&#x2013;797</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodeur MR, Brissette L, Falstrault L, Luangrath V, Moreau R. 2008. Scavenger receptor of class B expressed by osteoblastic cells are implicated in the uptake of cholesteryl ester and estradiol from LDL and HDL3. J. Bone Miner Res. 23:326&#x2013;337</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17967141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Villiers WJ, Smart EJ. 1999. Macrophage scavenger receptors and foam cell formation. J. Leukoc. Biol. 66:740&#x2013;746</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10577503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thilakawardhana S, Everett DM, Murdock PR, Dingwall C, Owen JS. 2005. Quantification of apolipoprotein E receptors in human brain-derived cell lines by real-time polymerase chain reaction. Neurobiol. Aging. 26:813&#x2013;823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15718039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Koike S. Identification of a human SCARB2 region that is important for enterovirus 71 binding and infection. J. Virol. 85:4937&#x2013;4946</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3126200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21389126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laszik Z, Jansen PJ, Cummings RD, Tedder TF, McEver RP, Moore KL. 1996. P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is broadly expressed in cells of myeloid, lymphoid, and dendritic lineage and in some nonhematopoietic cells. Blood 88:3010&#x2013;3021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8874199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somers WS, Tang J, Shaw GD, Camphausen RT. 2000. Insights into the molecular basis of leukocyte tethering and rolling revealed by structures of P- and E-selectin bound to SLe(X) and PSGL-1. Cell 103:467&#x2013;479</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11081633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Wakita T, Shimizu H. Tyrosine sulfation of the amino terminus of PSGL-1 is critical for enterovirus 71 infection. PLoS Pathog. 6:e1001174.10.1371/journal.ppat.1001174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1001174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2973824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21079683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cureton DK, Massol RH, Whelan SP, Kirchhausen T. The length of vesicular stomatitis virus particles dictates a need for actin assembly during clathrin-dependent endocytosis. PLoS Pathog. 6:e1001127.10.1371/journal.ppat.1001127</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1001127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2947997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20941355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastaldelli M, Imelli N, Boucke K, Amstutz B, Meier O, Greber UF. 2008. Infectious adenovirus type 2 transport through early but not late endosomes. Traffic 9:2265&#x2013;2278</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18980614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng T, Wang JL, Chen W, Zhang JL, Gao N, Chen ZT, Xu XF, Fan DY, An J. 2009. Entry of dengue virus serotype 2 into ECV304 cells depends on clathrin-dependent endocytosis, but not on caveolae-dependent endocytosis. Can. J. Microbiol. 55:139&#x2013;145</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19295646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le PU, Nabi IR. 2003. Distinct caveolae-mediated endocytic pathways target the Golgi apparatus and the endoplasmic reticulum. J. Cell Sci. 116:1059&#x2013;1071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12584249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macovei A, Radulescu C, Lazar C, Petrescu S, Durantel D, Dwek RA, Zitzmann N, Nichita NB. Hepatitis B virus requires intact caveolin-1 function for productive infection in HepaRG cells. J. Virol. 84:243&#x2013;253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2798426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19846513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelkmans L, Puntener D, Helenius A. 2002. Local actin polymerization and dynamin recruitment in SV40-induced internalization of caveolae. Science 296:535&#x2013;539</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11964480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richterova Z, Liebl D, Horak M, Palkova Z, Stokrova J, Hozak P, Korb J, Forstova J. 2001. Caveolae are involved in the trafficking of mouse polyomavirus virions and artificial VP1 pseudocapsids toward cell nuclei. J. Virol. 75:10880&#x2013;10891</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC114668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11602728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YW, Lin HY, Tsou YL, Chitra E, Hsiao KN, Shao HY, Liu CC, Sia C, Chong P, Chow YH. Human SCARB2-mediated entry and endocytosis of EV71. PLoS One 7:e30507.10.1371/journal.pone.0030507</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0030507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3260287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22272359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain KM, Leong KL, Ng MM, Chu JJ. The essential role of clathrin-mediated endocytosis in the infectious entry of human enterovirus 71. J. Biol. Chem. 286:309&#x2013;321</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3012988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20956521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LH, Rothberg KG, Anderson RG. 1993. Mis-assembly of clathrin lattices on endosomes reveals a regulatory switch for coated pit formation. J. Cell Biol. 123:1107&#x2013;1117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2119875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8245121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothenberger S, Iacopetta BJ, Kuhn LC. 1987. Endocytosis of the transferrin receptor requires the cytoplasmic domain but not its phosphorylation site. Cell 49:423&#x2013;431</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3568132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahn E, Petermann P, Hsu MJ, Rixon FJ, Knebel-Morsdorf D. Entry pathways of herpes simplex virus type 1 into human keratinocytes are dynamin- and cholesterol-dependent. PLoS One 6:e25464.10.1371/journal.pone.0025464</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0025464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3192061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22022400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoki T, Nomura R, Fujimoto T. 1999. Tyrosine phosphorylation of caveolin-1 in the endothelium. Exp. Cell Res. 253:629&#x2013;636</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10585286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parton RG, Joggerst B, Simons K. 1994. Regulated internalization of caveolae. J. Cell Biol. 127:1199&#x2013;1215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2120257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7962085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manders EMM, FJV, Aten JA. 1993. Measurement of colocalization of objects in dual-colour confocal images. J. Microsc. 169:375&#x2013;382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33930978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knipe T, Rieder E, Baxt B, Ward G, Mason PW. 1997. Characterization of synthetic foot-and-mouth disease virus provirions separates acid-mediated disassembly from infectivity. J. Virol. 71:2851&#x2013;2856</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC191410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9060641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li CC, Yang MY, Chen RF, Lin TY, Tsao KC, Ning HC, Liu HC, Lin SF, Yeh WT, Chu YT, Yang KD. 2002. Clinical manifestations and laboratory assessment in an enterovirus 71 outbreak in southern Taiwan. Scand. J. Infect. Dis. 34:104&#x2013;109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11928838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard E, Belouzard S, Goueslain L, Wakita T, Dubuisson J, Wychowski C, Rouille Y. 2006. Hepatitis C virus entry depends on clathrin-mediated endocytosis. J. Virol. 80:6964&#x2013;6972</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1489042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16809302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eash S, Querbes W, Atwood WJ. 2004. Infection of vero cells by BK virus is dependent on caveolae. J. Virol. 78:11583&#x2013;11590</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC523296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15479799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolokoltsov AA, Deniger D, Fleming EH, Roberts NJ, Jr, Karpilow JM, Davey RA. 2007. Small interfering RNA profiling reveals key role of clathrin-mediated endocytosis and early endosome formation for infection by respiratory syncytial virus. J. Virol. 81:7786&#x2013;7800</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1933373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17494077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto A, Tagawa Y, Yoshimori T, Moriyama Y, Masaki R, Tashiro Y. 1998. Bafilomycin A1 prevents maturation of autophagic vacuoles by inhibiting fusion between autophagosomes and lysosomes in rat hepatoma cell line, H-4-II-E cells. Cell Struct. Funct. 23:33&#x2013;42</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9639028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noyce RS, Bondre DG, Ha MN, Lin LT, Sisson G, Tsao MS, Richardson CD. Tumor cell marker PVRL4 (nectin 4) is an epithelial cell receptor for measles virus. PLoS Pathog. 7:e1002240.10.1371/journal.ppat.1002240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1002240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3161989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21901103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatsuo H, Ono N, Tanaka K, Yanagi Y. 2000. SLAM (CDw150) is a cellular receptor for measles virus. Nature 406:893&#x2013;897</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10972291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffers SA, Tusell SM, Gillim-Ross L, Hemmila EM, Achenbach JE, Babcock GJ, Thomas WD, Jr, Thackray LB, Young MD, Mason RJ, Ambrosino DM, Wentworth DE, Demartini JC, Holmes KV. 2004. CD209L (L-SIGN) is a receptor for severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 101:15748&#x2013;15753</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC524836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15496474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Huang KJ, Wu JM, Wang JR, Yu CK, Su IJ, Liu CC. 2003. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J. Infect. Dis. 188:564&#x2013;570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghez D, Lepelletier Y, Lambert S, Fourneau JM, Blot V, Janvier S, Arnulf B, van Endert PM, Heveker N, Pique C, Hermine O. 2006. Neuropilin-1 is involved in human T-cell lymphotropic virus type 1 entry. J. Virol. 80:6844&#x2013;6854</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1489069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16809290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manel N, Kim FJ, Kinet S, Taylor N, Sitbon M, Battini JL. 2003. The ubiquitous glucose transporter GLUT-1 is a receptor for HTLV. Cell 115:449&#x2013;459</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14622599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geraghty RJ, Krummenacher C, Cohen GH, Eisenberg RJ, Spear PG. 1998. Entry of alphaherpesviruses mediated by poliovirus receptor-related protein 1 and poliovirus receptor. Science 280:1618&#x2013;1620</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9616127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery RI, Warner MS, Lum BJ, Spear PG. 1996. Herpes simplex virus-1 entry into cells mediated by a novel member of the TNF/NGF receptor family. Cell 87:427&#x2013;436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8898196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicola AV, McEvoy AM, Straus SE. 2003. Roles for endocytosis and low pH in herpes simplex virus entry into HeLa and Chinese hamster ovary cells. J. Virol. 77:5324&#x2013;5332</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC153978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12692234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YW, Chang KC, Kao CM, Chang SP, Tung YY, Chen SH. 2009. Lymphocyte and antibody responses reduce enterovirus 71 lethality in mice by decreasing tissue viral loads. J. Virol. 83:6477&#x2013;6483</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Wang H, Gong E, Du J, Zhao X, McNutt MA, Wang S, Zhong Y, Gao Z, Zheng J. 2009. Neuropathology in 2 cases of fatal enterovirus type 71 infection from a recent epidemic in the People's Republic of China: a histopathologic, immunohistochemical, and reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction study. Hum. Pathol. 40:1288&#x2013;1295</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidari KI, Weyrich AS, Zimmerman GA, McEver RP. 1997. Engagement of P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 enhances tyrosine phosphorylation and activates mitogen-activated protein kinases in human neutrophils. J. Biol. Chem. 272:28750&#x2013;28756</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9353345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo J, Xu T, Wang X, Ba X, Feng X, Deepak V, Zeng X. PI3K is involved in L-selectin- and PSGL-1-mediated neutrophil rolling on E-selectin via F-actin redistribution and assembly. J. Cell Biochem. 110:910&#x2013;919</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20564190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarbock A, Abram CL, Hundt M, Altman A, Lowell CA, Ley K. 2008. PSGL-1 engagement by E-selectin signals through Src kinase Fgr and ITAM adapters DAP12 and FcR&#x3b3; to induce slow leukocyte rolling. J. Exp. Med. 205:2339&#x2013;2347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2556779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18794338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urzainqui A, Martinez del Hoyo G, Lamana A, de la Fuente H, Barreiro O, Olazabal IM, Martin P, Wild MK, Vestweber D, Gonzalez-Amaro R, Sanchez-Madrid F. 2007. Functional role of P-selectin glycoprotein ligand 1/P-selectin interaction in the generation of tolerogenic dendritic cells. J. Immunol. 179:7457&#x2013;7465</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18025190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarbock A, Muller H, Kuwano Y, Ley K. 2009. PSGL-1-dependent myeloid leukocyte activation. J. Leukoc. Biol. 86:1119&#x2013;1124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19703898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>