<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25505956</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2050-0068</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical &amp; translational immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Transl Immunology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>EV71 vaccine, an invaluable gift for children.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e28</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e28</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/cti.2014.24</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is a major pathogen for severe hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD). Development of vaccines against EV71 would be the most effective approach to prevent the EV71 outbreak. Research and development (R&amp;D) of EV71 vaccine was carried out in several Asian countries. Currently three companies in mainland China have completed Phase III clinical trials of inactivated EV71 whole-virus vaccines, whereas the other two companies have completed Phase I clinical trials separately in Taiwan and in Singapore. Results from those clinical trials have indicated high safety and immunogenicity of EV71 vaccine. Protective efficacies were over 90% on EV71-associated HFMD and over 80% on other EV71-associated diseases. In this paper, we summarize the results from three EV71 vaccine Phase III clinical trials and discuss the challenges of incorporating EV71 vaccine into Expanded Program on Immunization (EPI) in countries with EV71 epidemics.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Zhenglun</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institutes for Food and Drug Control , Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Junzhi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institutes for Food and Drug Control , Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Transl Immunology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101638268</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-0068</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25505956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4237031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/cti.2014.24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">cti201424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>A Guide to clinical management and public health response for hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) 2011. Available from
http://www.wpro.who.int/emerging_diseases/documents/HFMDGuidance/en/
.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing W, Liao Q, Viboud C, Zhang J, Sun J, Wu JT, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease in China, 2008&#x2013;12: an epidemiological study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2014;14:308&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24485991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang ZL, Mao QY, Wang YP, Zhu FC, Li JX, Yao X, et al. Progress on the research and development of inactivated EV71 whole-virus vaccines. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2013;9:1701&#x2013;1705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3906269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23744508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F, Xu W, Xia J, Liang Z, Liu Y, Zhang X, et al. Efficacy, safety and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in China. New Engl J Med. 2014;370:818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Meng FY, Li JX, Li XL, Mao QY, Tao H, et al. Efficacy, safety and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2013;381:2024&#x2013;2032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23726161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Liu L, Mo Z, Wang X, Xia J, Liang Z, et al. An inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. New Engl J Med. 2014;370:829&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Q, Li N, Yu X, Yao X, Li F, Lu F, et al. Antigenicity, animal protective effect and genetic characteristics of candidate vaccine strains of enterovirus 71. Arch Virol. 2012;157:37&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21984267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang ZL, Mao Q, Gao F, Wang J. Progress on the research and development of human enterovirus 71 (EV71) vaccines. Front Med. 2013;7:111&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23247645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang ZL, Mao QY, Gao Q, Li X, Dong C, Yu X, et al. Establishing China's national standards of antigen content and neutralizing antibody responses for evaluation of enterovirus 71 (EV71) vaccines. Vaccine. 2011;29:9668&#x2013;9674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22015395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YP, Liang ZL, Gao Q, Huang LR, Mao QY, Wen SQ, et al. Safety and immunogenicity of a novel human Enterovirus 71 (EV71) vaccine: a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, Phase I clinical trial. Vaccine. 2012;30:3295&#x2013;3303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22426327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YP, Liang ZL, Xia JL, Wu JY, Wang L, Song LF, et al. Immunogenicity, safety and immune persistence of a novel inactivated human enterovirus 71 vaccine: a phase II, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled Trial. J Infect Dis. 2014;209:46&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23922377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng FY, Li JX, Li XL, Chu K, Zhang YT, Ji H, et al. Tolerability and immunogenicity of an inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in Chinese healthy adults and children: an open label, phase 1 clinical trial. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2012;8:668&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22634437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Liang ZL, Li XL, GE HM, Meng FY, Mao QY, et al. Immunogenicity and safety of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy Chinese children and infants: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 2 clinical trial. Lancet. 2013;381:1037&#x2013;1045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23352749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Zhang Y, Wang J, Zhao H, Jiang L, Che Y, et al. Study of the integrated immune response induced by an inactivated EV71 vaccine. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e54451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3553120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23372725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YM, Wang X, Wang JZ, Wang L, Zhang YJ, Chang L, et al. Immunogenicity, safety and lot consistency of a novel inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in Chinese children aged 6 to 59 months. Clin Vaccine Immunol. 2013;20:1805&#x2013;1811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3889509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24108780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Qian Y, Wang S, Serrano JM, Li W, Huang Z, et al. EV71: an emerging infectious disease vaccine target in the Far East. Vaccine. 2010;28:3516&#x2013;3521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20304038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Y, Ku Z, Liu Q, Leng Q, Huang Z. A combination vaccine comprising of inactivated enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 elicits balanced protective immunity against both viruses. Vaccine. 2014;32:2406&#x2013;2412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24657161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Q, Cheng T, Zhu F, Li J, Wang Y, Li Y, et al. The cross-neutralizing activity of enterovirus 71 subgenotype c4 vaccines in healthy Chinese infants and children. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e79599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3834186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24260259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou AH, Liu CC, Chang JY, Jiang R, Hsieh YC, Tsao A, et al. Formalin-inactivated EV71 vaccine candidate induced cross-neutralizing antibody against subgenotypes B1, B4, B5 and C4A in adult volunteers. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e79783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3836818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24278177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee BY, Wateska AR, Bailey RR, Tai JH, Bacon KM, Smith KJ, et al. Forecasting the economic value of an Enterovirus 71 (EV71) vaccine. Vaccine. 2010;28:7731&#x2013;7736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2989421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20923711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CW, Lee YP, Wang YF, Yu CK. Formaldehyde-inactivated human enterovirus 71 vaccine is compatible for co-immunization with a commercial pentavalent vaccine. Vaccine. 2011;29:2772&#x2013;2776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21315698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. Enterovirus vaccines for an emerging cause of brain-stem encephalitis. New Engl J Med. 2014;370:792&#x2013;794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>