<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">26038749</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2222-1751</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Emerging microbes &amp; infections</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Emerg Microbes Infect</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Receptors for enterovirus 71.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e53</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e53</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/emi.2014.49</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is one of the major causative agents of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD). Occasionally, EV71 infection is associated with severe neurological diseases, such as acute encephalitis, acute flaccid paralysis and cardiopulmonary failure. Several molecules act as cell surface receptors that stimulate EV71 infection, including scavenger receptor B2 (SCARB2), P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 (PSGL-1), sialylated glycan, heparan sulfate and annexin II (Anx2). SCARB2 plays critical roles in attachment, viral entry and uncoating, and it can facilitate efficient EV71 infection. The three-dimensional structures of the mature EV71 virion, procapsid and empty capsid, as well as the exofacial domain of SCARB2, have been elucidated. This structural information has greatly increased our understanding of the early steps of EV71 infection. Furthermore, SCARB2 plays essential roles in the development of EV71 neurological disease in vivo. Adult mice are not susceptible to infection by EV71, but transgenic mice that express human SCARB2 become susceptible to EV71 infection and develop similar neurological diseases to those found in humans. This mouse model facilitates the in vivo investigation of many issues related to EV71. PSGL-1, sialylated glycan, heparan sulfate and Anx2 are attachment receptors, which enhance viral infection by retaining the virus on the cell surface. These molecules also contribute to viral infection in vitro either by interacting with SCARB2 or independently of SCARB2. However, the cooperative effects of these receptors, and their contribution to EV71 pathogenicity in vivo, remain to be elucidated.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamayoshi</LastName><ForeName>Seiya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Virology, Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Institute of Medical Science, The University of Tokyo , Tokyo 108-8639, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujii</LastName><ForeName>Ken</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurovirology Project, Tokyo Metropolitan Institute of Medical Science , Tokyo 156-8506, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koike</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurovirology Project, Tokyo Metropolitan Institute of Medical Science , Tokyo 156-8506, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Emerg Microbes Infect</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101594885</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2222-1751</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SCARB2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand, foot and mouth disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurological disease</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26038749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4126179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/emi.2014.49</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">emi201449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Oberste MS, Jiang X, Maher K, Nix WA, Jiang B. The complete genome sequences for three simian enteroviruses isolated from captive primates. Arch Virol. 2008;153:2117&#x2013;2122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18941864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste MS, Maher K, Pallansch MA. Complete genome sequences for nine simian enteroviruses. J Gen Virol. 2007;88:3360&#x2013;3372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18024906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallansch M, Roos R.Enteroviruses. polioviruses, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses, and newer enterovirusesIn: Knipe DM, Howley PM, Griffin DE, Lamb RA, Martin MA, Roizman B, Straus SE (ed.)Fields Virology5th ed. Philadelphia, PA; Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 2007; 839&#x2013;893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, et al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt NJ, Lennette EH, Ho HH. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J Infect Dis. 1974;129:304&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov KM, Lavrova IK, Martianova LI, Korolev MB, Bashkirtsev VN, Voroshilova MK. Investigation of physicochemical properties of Bulgarian strain 258 of enterovirus type 71. Brief report. Arch Virol. 1979;60:359&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov M, Voroshilova M, Shindarov L, et al. Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch Virol. 1979;60:329&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick JL.Enterovirus type 71 infections: a varied clinical pattern sometimes mimicking paralytic poliomyelitis Rev Infect Dis 19846Suppl 2): S387&#x2013;S390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan LG, Parashar UD, Lye MS, et al. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. For the Outbreak Study Group. Clin Infect Dis. 2000;31:678&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P, Lindsay K, Perera D, Chan HM, Chan KP, Cardosa MJ. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J Virol. 2001;75:7732&#x2013;7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P, Stratov I, Nagarajan L, Davis S. Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin Infect Dis. 2001;32:236&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu H, Shimizu Y, Takeuchi Y, Ishiko H, Takada H. Outbreak of severe neurologic involvement associated with Enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr Neurol. 1999;20:17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto T, Chikahira M, Yoshida S, et al. Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol Immunol. 2002;46:621&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JR, Tuan YC, Tsai HP, Yan JJ, Liu CC, Su IJ. Change of major genotype of enterovirus 71 in outbreaks of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Taiwan between 1998 and 2000. J Clin Microbiol. 2002;40:10&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad K. Hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak reported in Singapore. Lancet. 2000;356:1338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11073035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De W, Changwen K, Wei L, et al. A large outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by EV71 and CAV16 in Guangdong, China, 2009. Arch Virol. 2011;156:945&#x2013;953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21305327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yip CC, Lau SK, Woo PC, Yuen KY. Human enterovirus 71 epidemics: what's next. Emerg Health Threats J. 2013;6:19780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24119538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu J. Enterovirus 71 infection: a new threat to global public health. Lancet Neurol. 2008;7:868&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18848307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuthill TJ, Groppelli E, Hogle JM, Rowlands DJ. Picornaviruses. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol. 2010;343:43&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3018333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20397067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergelson JM.ReceptorsIn: Ehrenfeld E, Domingo E, Roos RP (ed.)The Picornaviruses Washington, DC; ASM Press, 2010; 73&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fricks CE, Hogle JM. Cell-induced conformational change in poliovirus: externalization of the amino terminus of VP1 is responsible for liposome binding. J Virol. 1990;64:1934&#x2013;1945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC249347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2157861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuthill TJ, Bubeck D, Rowlands DJ, Hogle JM. Characterization of early steps in the poliovirus infection process: receptor-decorated liposomes induce conversion of the virus to membrane-anchored entry-intermediate particles. J Virol. 2006;80:172&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16352541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danthi P, Tosteson M, Li QH, Chow M. Genome delivery and ion channel properties are altered in VP4 mutants of poliovirus. J Virol. 2003;77:5266&#x2013;5274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC153979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12692228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosteson MT, Wang H, Naumov A, Chow M. Poliovirus binding to its receptor in lipid bilayers results in particle-specific, temperature-sensitive channels. J Gen Virol. 2004;85:1581&#x2013;1589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15166442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy HC, Bostina M, Filman DJ, Hogle JM. Catching a virus in the act of RNA release: a novel poliovirus uncoating intermediate characterized by cryo-electron microscopy. J Virol. 2010;84:4426&#x2013;4441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2863768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20181687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bostina M, Levy H, Filman DJ, Hogle JM. Poliovirus RNA is released from the capsid near a twofold symmetry axis. J Virol. 2011;85:776&#x2013;783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3020038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20980499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumann E, Moser R, Snyers L, Blaas D, Hewat EA. A cellular receptor of human rhinovirus type 2, the very-low-density lipoprotein receptor, binds to two neighboring proteins of the viral capsid. J Virol. 2003;77:8504&#x2013;8511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC165241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12857919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewat EA, Neumann E, Conway JF, et al. The cellular receptor to human rhinovirus 2 binds around the 5-fold axis and not in the canyon: a structural view. EMBO J. 2000;19:6317&#x2013;6325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC305862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11101504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdaguer N, Fita I, Reithmayer M, Moser R, Blaas D. X-ray structure of a minor group human rhinovirus bound to a fragment of its cellular receptor protein. Nat Struct Mol Biol. 2004;11:429&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prchla E, Kuechler E, Blaas D, Fuchs R. Uncoating of human rhinovirus serotype 2 from late endosomes. J Virol. 1994;68:3713&#x2013;3723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC236876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8189509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plevka P, Perera R, Cardosa J, Kuhn RJ, Rossmann MG. Crystal structure of human enterovirus 71. Science. 2012;336:1274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3448362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22383808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Peng W, Ren J, et al. A sensor&#x2013;adaptor mechanism for enterovirus uncoating from structures of EV71. Nat Struct Mol Biol. 2012;19:424&#x2013;429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3378640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22388738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cifuente JO, Lee H, Yoder JD, et al. Structures of the procapsid and mature virion of enterovirus 71 strain 1095. J Virol. 2013;87:7637&#x2013;7645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3700288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23637404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shingler KL, Yoder JL, Carnegie MS, et al. The enterovirus 71 A-particle forms a gateway to allow genome release: a cryoEM study of picornavirus uncoating. PLoS Pathog. 2013;9:e1003240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3605244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23555253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B, Chuang H, Yang KD. Sialylated glycans as receptor and inhibitor of enterovirus 71 infection to DLD-1 intestinal cells. Viral J. 2009;6:141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2751754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19751532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Shimojima M, Tano Y, Miyamura T, Wakita T, Shimizu H. Human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat Med. 2009;15:794&#x2013;797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Yamashita Y, Li J, et al. Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat Med. 2009;15:798&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang SL, Chou YT, Wu CN, Ho MS. Annexin II binds to capsid protein VP1 of enterovirus 71 and enhances viral infectivity. J Virol. 2011;85:11809&#x2013;11820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3209289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21900167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan CW, Poh CL, Sam IC, Chan YF. Enterovirus 71 uses cell surface heparan sulfate glycosaminoglycan as an attachment receptor. J Virol. 2013;87:611&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3536405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23097443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koike S, Taya C, Kurata T, et al. Transgenic mice susceptible to poliovirus. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1991;88:951&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC50932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1846972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren RB, Costantini F, Gorgacz EJ, Lee JJ, Racaniello VR. Transgenic mice expressing a human poliovirus receptor: a new model for poliomyelitis. Cell. 1990;63:353&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2170026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ida-Hosonuma M, Iwasaki T, Yoshikawa T, et al. The alpha/beta interferon response controls tissue tropism and pathogenicity of poliovirus. J Virol. 2005;79:4460&#x2013;4469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1061561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15767446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe Y, Fujii K, Nagata N, et al. The Toll-like receptor 3-mediated antiviral response is important for protection against poliovirus infection in poliovirus receptor transgenic mice. J Virol. 2012;86:185&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3255933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22072781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Guo MS, Lin FH, et al. Purification and characterization of enterovirus 71 viral particles produced from Vero cells grown in a serum-free microcarrier bioreactor system. PloS ONE. 2011;6:e20005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3094384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Song Z, Qi Y, et al. Molecular determinants of enterovirus 71 viral entry: cleft around GLN-172 on VP1 protein interacts with variable region on scavenge receptor B 2. J Biol Chem. 2012;287:6406&#x2013;6420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3307280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22219187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewat EA, Blaas D. Cryoelectron microscopy analysis of the structural changes associated with human rhinovirus type 14 uncoating. J Virol. 2004;78:2935&#x2013;2942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC353739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14990711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewat EA, Neumann E, Blaas D. The concerted conformational changes during human rhinovirus 2 uncoating. Mol Cell. 2002;10:317&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12191477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garriga D, Pickl-Herk A, Luque D, et al. Insights into minor group rhinovirus uncoating: the X-ray structure of the HRV2 empty capsid. PLoS Pathog. 2012;8:e1002473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3252380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22241997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo D, Dopazo J, Vega MA. The CD36, CLA-1 (CD36L1), and LIMPII (CD36L2) gene family: cellular distribution, chromosomal location, and genetic evolution. Genomics. 1995;25:100&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7539776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuronita T, Eskelinen EL, Fujita H, Saftig P, Himeno M, Tanaka Y. A role for the lysosomal membrane protein LGP85 in the biogenesis and maintenance of endosomal and lysosomal morphology. J Cell Sci. 2002;115:4117&#x2013;4131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12356916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanz J, Groth J, Zachos C, Wehling C, Saftig P, Schwake M. Disease-causing mutations within the lysosomal integral membrane protein type 2 (LIMP-2) reveal the nature of binding to its ligand beta-glucocerebrosidase. Hum Mol Genet. 2010;19:563&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19933215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskelinen EL, Tanaka Y, Saftig P. At the acidic edge: emerging functions for lysosomal membrane proteins. Trends Cell Biol. 2003;13:137&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12628346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reczek D, Schwake M, Schroder J, et al. LIMP-2 is a receptor for lysosomal mannose-6-phosphate-independent targeting of beta-glucocerebrosidase. Cell. 2007;131:770&#x2013;783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18022370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Ohka S, Fujii K, Koike S. Functional comparison of SCARB2 and PSGL1 as receptors for enterovirus 71. J Virol. 2013;87:3335&#x2013;3347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3592140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23302872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neculai D, Schwake M, Ravichandran M, et al. Structure of LIMP-2 provides functional insights with implications for SR-BI and CD36. Nature. 2013;504:172&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24162852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Koike S. Identification of a human SCARB2 region that is important for enterovirus 71 binding and infection. J Virol. 2011;85:4937&#x2013;4946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3126200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21389126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain KM, Leong KL, Ng MM, Chu JJ. The essential role of clathrin-mediated endocytosis in the infectious entry of human enterovirus 71. J Biol Chem. 2011;286:309&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3012988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20956521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YW, Lin HY, Tsou YL, et al. Human SCARB2-mediated entry and endocytosis of EV71. PloS ONE. 2012;7:e30507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3260287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22272359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujii K, Nagata N, Sato Y, Ong KC, Wong KT, Yamayoshi S, et al. Transgenic mouse model for the study of entero virus 71 neuropathogenesis. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2013;110:14753&#x2013;14758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3767555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23959904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y, Ong KC, Gao Z, et al. Tonsillar crypt epithelium is an important extra-central nervous system site for viral replication in EV71 encephalomyelitis. Am J Pathol. 2014;184:714&#x2013;720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24378407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YW, Yu SL, Shao HY, et al. Human SCARB2 transgenic mice as an infectious animal model for enterovirus 71. PloS ONE. 2013;8:e57591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3581494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23451246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Iizuka S, Yamashita T, et al. Human SCARB2-dependent infection by coxsackievirus A7, A14, and A16 and enterovirus 71. J Virol. 2012;86:5686&#x2013;5696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3347270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22438546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sako D, Chang XJ, Barone KM, et al. Expression cloning of a functional glycoprotein ligand for P-selectin. Cell. 1993;75:1179&#x2013;1186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7505206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laszik Z, Jansen PJ, Cummings RD, Tedder TF, McEver RP, Moore KL. P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is broadly expressed in cells of myeloid, lymphoid, and dendritic lineage and in some nonhematopoietic cells. Blood. 1996;88:3010&#x2013;3021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8874199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somers WS, Tang J, Shaw GD, Camphausen RT. Insights into the molecular basis of leukocyte tethering and rolling revealed by structures of P- and E-selectin bound to SLe(X) and PSGL-1. Cell. 2000;103:467&#x2013;479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11081633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Wakita T, Shimizu H. Tyrosine sulfation of the amino terminus of PSGL-1 is critical for enterovirus 71 infection. PLoS Pathog. 2010;6:e1001174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2973824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21079683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Lee H, Hafenstein S, et al. Enterovirus 71 binding to PSGL-1 on leukocytes: VP1-145 acts as a molecular switch to control receptor interaction. PLoS Pathog. 2013;9:e1003511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3723564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23935488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamura K, Nishimura Y, Abo M, Wakita T, Shimizu H. Adaptive mutations in the genomes of enterovirus 71 strains following infection of mouse cells expressing human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1. J Gen Virol. 2011;92:287&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20943886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin HY, Yang YT, Yu SL, et al. Caveolar endocytosis is required for human PSGL-1-mediated enterovirus 71 infection. J Virol. 2013;87:9064&#x2013;9076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3754029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23760234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Dong W, Quan X, Ma C, Qin C, Zhang L. Transgenic expression of human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is not sufficient for enterovirus 71 infection in mice. Arch Virol. 2012;157:539&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22187102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajjar KA, Acharya SS. Annexin II and regulation of cell surface fibrinolysis. Ann NY Acad Sci. 2000;902:265&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varki NM, Varki A. Diversity in cell surface sialic acid presentations: implications for biology and disease. Lab Invest. 2007;87:851&#x2013;857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7100186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17632542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>