<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">20685937</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1556-679X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical and vaccine immunology : CVI</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Vaccine Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enterovirus 71 infection of monocytes with antibody-dependent enhancement.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1517</StartPage><EndPage>1523</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1517-23</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/CVI.00108-10</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus (EV) is an RNA virus that has circulated with different serotypes and genotypes worldwide. Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is a major neurotropic virus that causes severe brain stem encephalitis (BE) in infants and young children. The most vulnerable age for fatal infection is 6 to 11 months. This is associated with the coincident decline in maternal antibodies. The current report describes our finding that EV71 can infect human peripheral blood monocytes. We were able to show that EV71 infection is enhanced in the monocytic cell line THP-1 by the presence of subneutralizing concentrations of anti-EV71 antibodies. We also found that antibody-dependent enhancement (ADE) is mediated in part by Fc&#x3b3; receptors. These observations support the concept that ADE augments the infectivity of EV71 for human monocytes and contributes to the age-dependent pathogenesis of EV71-induced disease. The ADE phenomenon must be considered during the development of an EV71 vaccine.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shih-Min</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University and Hospital, 138 Sheng Li Road, Tainan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>I-Chun</ForeName><Initials>IC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Ling-Yao</ForeName><Initials>LY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Kao-Jean</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lei</LastName><ForeName>Huan-Yao</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Ching-Chuan</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Vaccine Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101252125</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1556-679X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D057134">Antibodies, Neutralizing</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000914">Antibodies, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017452">Receptors, IgG</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057134" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Neutralizing</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000914" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019067" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antibody-Dependent Enhancement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009000" MajorTopicYN="N">Monocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017452" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, IgG</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20685937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CVI.00108-10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">CVI.00108-10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 1998. Deaths among children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease-Taiwan, Republic of China, April-July 1998. MMWR Morb. Mortal. Wkly. Rep. 47:629-632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9704628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., C. C. King, K. H. Hsu, et al. 2002. Risk factors of enterovirus 71 infection and associated hand, foot, and mouth disease/herpangina in children during an epidemic in Taiwan. Pediatrics 109:e88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chareonsirisuthigul, T., S. Kalayanarooj, and S. Ubol. 2007. Dengue virus (DENV) antibody-dependent enhancement of infection upregulates the production of anti-inflammatory cytokines, but suppresses anti-DENV free radical and pro-inflammatory cytokine production, in THP-1 cells. J. Gen. Virol. 88:365-375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17251552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chehadeh, W., A. Bouzidi, G. Alm, P. Wattre, and D. Hober. 2001. Human antibodies isolated from plasma by affinity chromatography increase the coxsackievirus B4-induced synthesis of interferon-&#x3b1; by human peripheral blood mononuclear cells in vitro. J. Gen. Virol. 82:1899-1907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11457996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, L. C., H. W. Shyu, S. H. Chen, H. Y. Lei, C. K. Yu, and T. M. Yeh. 2006. Enterovirus 71 infection induces Fas ligand expression and apoptosis of Jurkat cells. J. Med. Virol. 78:780-786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16628611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S. C., H. L. Chang, T. R. Yan, Y. T. Cheng, and K. T. Chen. 2007. An eight-year study of epidemiologic features of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 77:188-191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17620652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherry, J. D. 2004. Enteroviruses and parechoviruses. Textbook of pediatric infectious diseases, p. 1984-2041. In R. D. Feigen and J. D. Cherry (ed.), Textbook of pediatric infectious diseases, 5th ed. Saunders, Philadephia, PA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagan, R., J. A. Jenista, S. L. Prather, K. R. Powell, and M. A. Menegus. 1985. Viremia in hospitalized children with enterovirus infections. J. Pediatr. 106:397-401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2983058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanger, N. A., K. Wardwell, L. Shen, T. F. Tedder, and P. M. Guyre. 1996. Type I (CD64) and type II (CD32) Fc gamma receptor-mediated phagocytosis by human blood dendritic cells. J. Immunol. 157:541-548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8752900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleit, H. B., and C. D. Kobasiuk. 1991. The human monocyte-like cell line THP-1 expresses Fc&#x3b3;RI and Fc&#x3b3;RII. J. Leuk. Biol. 49:556-565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1709200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freistadt, M. S., and K. E. Eberle. 1996. Correlation between poliovirus type 1 mahoney replication in blood cells and neurovirulence. J. Virol. 70:6486-6492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC190685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8709287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber, J. S., and D. M. Mosser. 2001. Reversing lipopolysaccharide toxicity by ligating the macrophage Fcg receptors. J. Immunol. 166:6861-6868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11359846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girn, J., M. Kavoosi, and J. Chantler. 2002. Enhancement of coxsackievirus B3 infection by antibody to a different coxsackievirus strain. J. Gen. Virol. 83:351-358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11807228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halstead, S. B., and E. J. O'Rourke. 1977. Antibody-enhanced dengue virus infection in primate leukocytes. Nature 265:739-741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">404559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkes, R. A. 1964. Enhancement of the infectivity of arboviruses by specific antisera produced in domestic fowls. Aust. J. Exp. Biol. Med. Sci. 42:465-482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14202187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes, P. J., R. Scott, and J. Wheeler. 1994. In vivo production of tumour necrosis factor-a and interleukin-6 in BALB/c mice inoculated intranasally with a high dose of respiratory syncytial virus. J. Med. Virol. 42:323-329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8046422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hober, D., W. Chehadeh, A. Bouzidi, and P. Wattr&#xe9;. 2001. Antibody-dependent enhancement of coxsackievirus B4 infectivity of human peripheral blood mononuclear cells results in increased interferon-&#x3b1; synthesis. J. Infect. Dis. 184:1098-1108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11598831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M., E. R. Chen, K. H. Hsu, et al. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929-935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, S. C., C. L. Chang, P. S. Wang, Y. Tsai, and H. S. Liu. 2009. Enterovirus 71-induced autophagy detected in vitro and in vivo promotes viral replication. J. Med. Virol. 81:1241-1252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7166624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19475621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, S. W., Y. W. Hsu, D. J. Smith, et al. 2009. Reemergence of enterovirus 71 in 2008 in Taiwan: dynamics of genetic and antigenic evolution from 1998 to 2008. J. Clin. Microbiol. 47:3653-3662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19776232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu, B. M., C. H. Chen, and M. T. Wan. 2007. Genetic diversity of epidemic enterovirus 71 strains recovered from clinical and environmental samples in Taiwan. Virus Res. 126:69-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17363101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman, W., B. E. E. Martina, G. F. Rimmelzwaan, R. A. Gruters, and A. D. M. E. Osterhaus. 2009. Vaccine-induced enhancement of viral infections. Vaccine 27:505-512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7131326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19022319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juan, S., Y. Qian, S. Wang, J. M. G. Serrano, W. Li, Z. Huang, and S. Lu. 2010. EV71: an emerging infectious disease vaccine target in the Far East? Vaccine doi:10.1016/j.vaccine.2010.03.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vaccine.2010.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20304038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kliks, S. C., S. Nimmanitya, A. Nisalak, and D. S. Burke. 1988. Evidence that maternal dengue antibodies are important in the development of dengue hemorrhagic fever in infants. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 38:411-419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3354774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kung, C. M., C. C. King, C. N. Lee, L. M. Huang, P. I. Lee, and C. L. Kao. 2007. Differences in replication capacity between enterovirus 71 isolates obtained from patients with encephalitis and those obtained from patients with herpangina in Taiwan. J. Med. Virol. 79:60-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17133556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C. C., H. W. Tseng, S. M. Wang, J. R. Wang, and I. J. Su. 2000. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998: epidemiologic and clinical manifestations. J. Clin. Virol. 17:23-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, S. T., P. S. Chiang, A. S. Chao, et al. 2009. Enterovirus 71 maternal antibodies in infants, Taiwan. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 15:581-584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19331737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahalingam, S., and B. A. Lidbury. 2002. Suppression of lipopolysaccharide-induced antiviral transcription factor (STAT-1 and NF-kB) complexes by antibody-dependent enhancement of macrophage infection by Ross River virus. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 99:13819-13824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC129781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12364588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta, K., Y. Aoki, A. Suto, et al. 2009. Cross-antigenicity among EV71 strains from different genogroups isolated in Yamagata, Japan, between 1990 and 2007. Vaccine 27:3153-3158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19446185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morens, D. M. 1994. Antibody-dependent enhancement of infection and the pathogenesis of viral disease. Clin. Infect. Dis. 19:500-512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7811870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura, Y., M. Shimojima, Y. Tano, T. Miyamura, T. Wakita, and H. Shimizu. 2009. Tatsuo human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15:794-798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochiai, H., M. Kurokawa, K. Hayashi, and S. Niwayama. 1988. Antibody mediated growth of influenza A NWS virus in macrophagelike cell line P388D1. J. Virol. 62:20-26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC250496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3334744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi, M. H., S. C. Wong, Y. Podin, W. Akin, S. Sel, A. Mohan, C. H. Chieng, et al. 2007. Human enterovirus 71 disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: a prospective clinical, virological, and molecular epidemiological study. Clin. Infect. Dis. 44:646-656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17278054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer, P., B. Charley, B. Rombaut, M. Dae&#xc8;ron, and P. Lebon. 2000. Antibody-dependent induction of type I interferons by poliovirus in human mononuclear blood cells requires the type II Fcg receptor (CD32). Virology 278:86-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11112484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-V&#xe9;lez, C. M., M. S. Anderson, C. C. Robinson, et al. 2007. Outbreak of neurologic enterovirus type 71 disease: a diagnostic challenge. Clin. Infect. Dis. 45:950-957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17879907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson, W. E., Jr., D. C. Montefiori, and W. M. Mitchell. 1988. Antibody dependent enhancement of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 infection. Lancet i:790-794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2895317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, N. J., E. H. Lennett, and H. H. Ho. 1974. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of central nervous system. J. Infect. Dis. 129:304-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takada, A., and Y. Kawaoka. 2003. Antibody-dependent enhancement of viral infection: molecular mechanisms and in vivo implications. Rev. Med. Virol. 13:387-398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14625886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tirado, S. M., and K. J. Yoon. 2003. Antibody dependent enhancement of virus infection and disease. Viral Immunol. 16:69-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12725690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuchiya, S., M. Yamabe, Y. Yamaguchi, Y. Kobayashi, T. Konno, and K. Tada. 1980. Establishment and characterization of a human acute monocytic leukemia cell line (THP-1). Int. J. Cancer 26:171-176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6970727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vuorinen, T., R. Vainionpaa, J. Heino, and T. Hyypia. 1999. Enterovirus receptors and virus replication in human leukocytes. J. Gen. Virol. 80:921-927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10211961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., C. C. Liu, H. W. Tseng, et al. 1999. Clinical spectrum of enterovirus 71 infection of children in southern Taiwan, with an emphasis on the neurological complications. Clin. Infect. Dis. 29:184-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10433583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., H. Y. Lei, K. J. Huang, et al. 2003. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: the roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J. Infect. Dis. 188:564-570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S., H. Lei, and C. Liu. 2009. Antibody-dependent enhancement of enterovirus 71 infectivity of mononuclear cells. Abstr. 49th. Intersci. Conf. Antimicrob. Agents. Chemother., abstr. V-1751a, p. 385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, S. S. Y., C. C. Y. Yip, S. K. P. Lau, and K. Y. Yuen. 2010. Human enterovirus 71 and hand, foot and mouth disease. Epidemiol. Infect. doi:10.1017/S0950268809991555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0950268809991555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20056019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi, S., Y. Yamashita, J. Li, N. Hanagata, T. Minowa, T. Takemura, and S. Koike. 2009. Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15:798-801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, F., L. Ren, Z. Xiong, et al. 2009. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in the People's Republic of China in 2008. J. Clin. Microbiol. 47:2351-2352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2708525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>