<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25721492</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-4409</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>143</Volume><Issue>14</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Epidemiology and infection</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Epidemiol Infect</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Case-fatality of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with EV71: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3094</StartPage><EndPage>3102</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3094-102</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1017/S095026881500028X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) associated with enterovirus 71 (EV71) is a growing public health concern. This study aimed to estimate the case-fatality of HFMD associated with EV71 on the basis of a meta-analysis. We searched PubMed, Cochrane, Web of Science, Elsevier, CNKI, Wanfang, and VIP databases. Two authors independently selected relevant studies. The pooled estimate of case-fatality was calculated using a random-effects model. Potential sources of heterogeneity were explored using subgroup analysis, sensitivity analysis and meta-regression. We identified 14 eligible studies with a total population of 112&#xa0;546. The random-effects pooled case-fatality was 1&#xb7;7% (95% confidence interval 1&#xb7;2-2&#xb7;4). The funnel plot was asymmetrical. The estimate of case-fatality was highest in mainland China (1&#xb7;8%). Removal of eight local Chinese studies decreased the original estimate. The pooled case-fatality in the period of 1998-2007 (1&#xb7;5%) was lower than that in the period 2008-2012 (1&#xb7;8%). Control measures for HFMD associated with EV71 are essential because of the increased case-fatality over time, especially in East Asia.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Y Y</ForeName><Initials>YY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics,School of Public Health, Southeast University,Nanjing,China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>H</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics,School of Public Health, Southeast University,Nanjing,China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>X F</ForeName><Initials>XF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Provincial Center for Disease Control and Prevention,China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>B</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics,School of Public Health, Southeast University,Nanjing,China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2015</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Epidemiol Infect</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8703737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0950-2688</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="Y">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009026" MajorTopicYN="N">Mortality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Case-fatality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HFMD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25721492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9151022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S095026881500028X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S095026881500028X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gopalkrishna V, et al. Circulation of multiple enterovirus serotypes causing hand, foot and mouth disease in India. Journal of Clinical Microbiology 2012; 61: 420&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22052995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, et al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan enterovirus epidemic working group. New England Journal of Medicine 1999; 341: 929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YF, et al. Complete genome analysis of coxsackievirus A2, A4, A5, and A10 strains isolated from hand, foot and mouth disease patients in China revealing frequent recombination of human enterovirus A. Journal of Clinical Microbiology 2010; 49: 2426&#x2013;2434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3147834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21543560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puenpa J, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus A6, Thailand, 2012. Emerging Infectious Diseases 2013; 19: 641&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3647428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23631943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M. Enterovirus 71: the virus, its infections and outbreaks. Journal of Microbiology, Immunology, and Infection 2000; 33: 205&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11269363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. A guide to clinical management and public health response for hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD). 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios G, Oberste MS. Enteroviruses as agents of emerging infectious diseases. Journal of Neurovirology 2005; 11: 424&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16287683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt NJ, Lennette EH, Ho HH. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. Journal of Infectious Diseases 1974; 129: 304&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobara F, et al. Properties of virus isolated from an epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease in 1973 in the city of Matsue. Comparison with coxsackievirus group A type 16 prototype. Microbiology and Immunology 1977; 21: 207&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">875762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara A, Tagaya I, Yoneyama T. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Intervirology 1978; 9: 60&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">202573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert GL, et al. Outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Victoria, Australia, with a high incidence of neurologic involvement. Pediatric Infectious Disease Journal 1988; 7: 484&#x2013;488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2841639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar S, et al. Identification of enterovirus 71 isolates from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) with fatal cases of encephalomyelitis in Malaysia. Virus Research 1999; 61: 1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10426204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa MJ, et al. Isolation of subgenus B adenovirus during a fatal outbreak of enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot and mouth disease in Sibu, Sarawak. Lancet 1999; 354: 987&#x2013;991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10501361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, et al. An outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with subgenotype C4 of human enterovirus 71 in Shandong, China. Journal of Clinical Virology 2009; 44: 262&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19269888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, et al. An emerging recombinant human enterovirus 71 responsible for the 2008 outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Fuyang city of China. Virology Journal 2010; 7: 94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20459851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease in China patterns of spread and transmissibility. Epidemiology 2011; 22: 781&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3246273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21968769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian X. Chinese Medical Encyclopedia. Shanghai: Shanghai Science and Technology Press, 1984, pp. 103&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Elm E, et al. The strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Lancet 2007; 370: 1453&#x2013;1457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18064739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciapponi A, et al. Epidemiology of pediatric pneumococcal meningitis and bacteremia in Latin America and the Caribbean: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pediatric Infectious Disease Journal 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24830699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beijer U, Wolf A, Fazel S. Prevalence of tuberculosis, hepatitis C virus, and HIV in homeless people: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Infectious Diseases 2012; 12: 859&#x2013;870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3494003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22914343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo ML, et al. Realizing the meta-analysis of single rate in R software. Journal of Evidence-Based Medicine 2013; 13: 181&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang PX, Li HT, Liu JM. Meta-analysis of non-comparative binary outcomes and its solution by Stata. Journal of Evidence-Based Medicine 2012; 12: 52&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu PV, et al. Epidemiological and virological investigation of hand, foot and mouth disease, southern Vietnam, 2005. Emerging Infectious Diseases 2007; 13: 1733&#x2013;1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang LW, et al. Epidemiology and control of hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore, 2001&#x2013;2007. Annals of the Academy of Medicine, Singapore 2009; 38: 106&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19271036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma E, et al. The enterovirus 71 epidemic in 2008-public health implications for Hong Kong. International Journal of Infectious Diseases 2010; 14: e775&#x2013;e780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20599410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu WS, et al. Enterovirus 71 infection with central nervous system involvement, South Korea. Emerging Infectious Diseases 2010; 16: 1764&#x2013;1766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3294506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21029539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo Y, et al. Epidemiology of hand, foot and mouth disease in Guangxi, China in 2010. Disease Surveillance 2011; 26: 611&#x2013;613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun LM, et al. Epidemiology of hand, foot and mouth disease in Guangdong, China between 2009 and 2010. South China Journal of Preventive Medicine 2011; 37: 9&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji H, et al. Epidemiology and etiology of hand, foot and mouth disease in Jiangsu, China between 2008 and 2010. China Journal of Pediatrics 2012; 4: 261&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22801225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JS, et al. Epidemiology and etiology of hand, foot and mouth disease in Hebei, China between 2009 and 2011. Practical Preventive Medicine 2012; 9: 1284&#x2013;1287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y, et al. Surveillance of hand, foot and mouth disease in China between 2011 and 2012. Disease Surveillance 2013; 12: 975&#x2013;980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li LL, et al. Epidemiology of hand, foot and mouth disease in Guizhou, China between 2008 and 2011. Practical Preventive Medicine 2013; 2: 165&#x2013;167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mou J, et al. Severe hand, foot and mouth disease in Shenzhen, South China: what matters most? Epidemiology and Infection 2014; 142: 776&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9151125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23809877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao GH, et al. Surveillance and pathogens of hand, foot and mouth disease in the first half year of 2013 in Guizhou, China. Chinese Journal of Health Laboratory Technology 2014; 3: 428&#x2013;431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu DS, et al. Epidemiology and pathogens of hand, foot and mouth disease in Gansu, China between 2008 and 2012. Chinese Journal of Virology 2014; 1: 25&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24772894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing WG, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease in China, 2008&#x2013;2012: an epidemiological study. Lancet Infectious Diseases 2014; 14: 308&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24485991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Ministry of People's Republic of China. The hand, foot and mouth disease prevention and control guidelines (2009 version). Clinical Education of General Practice 2010; 8: 125&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G, et al. The risk factors of hand, foot and mouth disease in Chinese mainland people. Indian Journal of Pediatrics 2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24705937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang FJ, Zheng X, Lan QJ. A survey of parents' basic knowledge about hand, foot and mouth disease in community. Chinese Journal of General Practice 2012; 10: 1284&#x2013;1285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin SW, et al. Risk factors of hand, foot and mouth disease in scattered children in Zhejiang, China. Chinese Journal of Preventive Medicine 2010; 11: 871&#x2013;874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai J LH, et al. Risk factors of hand, foot and mouth disease with different clinical features. Disease Surveillance 2011; 26: 202&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An QY, et al. Meta-analysis on risk factors of hand, foot and mouth diseases. Chinese Journal of Health Statistics 2013; 30: 576&#x2013;578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, et al. Risk factors of enterovirus 71 infection and associated hand, foot and mouth disease/herpangina in children during an epidemic in Taiwan. Pediatrics 2002; 109: e88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y, et al. Risk factors of severe hand, foot and mouth disease: a meta-analysis. Scandinavian Journal of Infectious Diseases 2014; 46: 515&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, et al. Study on risk factors for severe hand, foot and mouth disease in China. PLoS ONE 2014; 9: e87603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3906182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24489943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MS, et al. Challenges to licensure of enterovirus 71 vaccines. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases 2012; 6: e1737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3429393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22953003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JX, et al. Development of enterovirus 71 vaccines: from the lab bench to Phase III clinical trials. Expert Review of Vaccines 2014; 13: 609&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24621093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, et al. Efficacy, safety and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet 2013; 381: 2024&#x2013;2032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23726161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in China. New England Journal of Medicine 2014; 370: 818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li RC, et al. An inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. New England Journal of Medicine 2014; 370: 829&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>