<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34412459</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-4351</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>65</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Avian diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Avian Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Establishment of Duplex SYBR Green I-based Real-time PCR Assay for Simultaneous Detection of Duck Hepatitis A Virus-1 and Duck Astrovirus-3.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>281</StartPage><EndPage>286</EndPage><MedlinePgn>281-286</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1637/aviandiseases-D-20-00115</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Duck viral hepatitis (DVH) mainly affects ducklings under 1 month of age, causes liver necrosis, enlargement, and hemorrhage, and is highly lethal, seriously jeopardizing the duck industry. The prevalence of duck hepatitis A virus (DHAV-1) and duck astrovirus type 3 (DAstV-3) is increasing, and coinfection is common. Moreover, the similar clinical characteristics of the DHAV-1 and DAstV-3 infections and the high frequency of coinfection make diagnosis difficult. In this study, to establish a method for the rapid, simultaneous detection of DHAV-1 and DAstV-3, two pairs of specific primers were designed according to their conserved gene regions. An SYBR<sup>&#xae;</sup> Green I-based qPCR assay was successfully established that can quickly and differentially detect the two viruses. Moreover, the assay is highly specific and does not show cross-reaction with other common viruses. The detection limit of the method is 7.34 &#xd7; 10<sup>1</sup> copies/&#xb5;l and 3.78 &#xd7; 10<sup>1</sup> copies/&#xb5;l for DHAV-1 and DAstV-3, respectively, indicating high sensitivity. A total of 34 clinical samples were tested using the established method; the positive rates for DHAV-1 and DAstV-3 were 14.71% and 8.82%, respectively, and that for coinfection was 2.94% (1/34), which was better than that obtained with conventional PCR. In summary, the SYBR Green I-based qPCR assay established in this study has high specificity, good sensitivity and accuracy, high feasibility, and is rapid. Thus, it can be a powerful tool for the coinfection detection of DHAV-1 and DAstV-3 and for future epidemiologic studies.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yeqiu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Province Key Laboratory of Veterinary Pathobiology and Disease Control, College of Animal Science and Technology, Anhui Agricultural University, Hefei 230036, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Yongqiu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Province Key Laboratory of Veterinary Pathobiology and Disease Control, College of Animal Science and Technology, Anhui Agricultural University, Hefei 230036, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hua</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Provincial Center for Animal Disease Control and Prevention, Hefei 230000, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Animal Husbandry Base Teaching and Research Section, College of Animal Science and Technology, Hebei North University, Zhangjiakou 075131, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yongdong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Municipal Key Laboratory of Virology, Ningbo Municipal Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Ningbo 315010, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Province Key Laboratory of Veterinary Pathobiology and Disease Control, College of Animal Science and Technology, Anhui Agricultural University, Hefei 230036, PR China, wangyongcau@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hefei Minghang Breeding Co. Ltd, Hefei 231262, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Avian Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370617</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0005-2086</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D052160">Benzothiazoles</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003959">Diamines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005456">Fluorescent Dyes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011804">Quinolines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>163795-75-3</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C098022">SYBR Green I</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000623845">Avastrovirus 3</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019350" MajorTopicYN="N">Astroviridae Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="Y">veterinary</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052676" MajorTopicYN="N">Avastrovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052160" MajorTopicYN="N">Benzothiazoles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003959" MajorTopicYN="N">Diamines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005240" MajorTopicYN="N">Feasibility Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005456" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluorescent Dyes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004371" MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatitis Virus, Duck</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006524" MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatitis, Viral, Animal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010850" MajorTopicYN="N">Picornaviridae Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="Y">veterinary</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011804" MajorTopicYN="N">Quinolines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060888" MajorTopicYN="N">Real-Time Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012680" MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity and Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa"><AbstractText><i>Art&#xed;culo regular</i>&#x2014;Establecimiento de un ensayo d&#xfa;plex de PCR en tiempo real basado en SYBR Green I para la detecci&#xf3;n simult&#xe1;nea del virus de la hepatitis A del pato-1 y del astrovirus del pato tipo 3. La hepatitis viral del pato (DVH) afecta principalmente a los patitos menores de 1 mes de edad, causa necrosis hep&#xe1;tica, agrandamiento y hemorragia, y es altamente letal, lo que pone en grave peligro la industria del pato. La prevalencia del virus de la hepatitis A del pato (DHAV-1) y del astrovirus del pato tipo 3 (DAstV-3) est&#xe1; aumentando y la coinfecci&#xf3;n es com&#xfa;n. Adem&#xe1;s, las caracter&#xed;sticas cl&#xed;nicas similares de las infecciones por el virus de la hepatitis A del pato y el astrovirus del pato tipo 3 as&#xed; como la alta frecuencia de coinfecci&#xf3;n dificultan el diagn&#xf3;stico. En este estudio, para establecer un m&#xe9;todo para la detecci&#xf3;n r&#xe1;pida y simult&#xe1;nea por el virus de la hepatitis A del pato y el astrovirus del pato tipo 3, se dise&#xf1;aron dos pares de iniciadores espec&#xed;ficos seg&#xfa;n sus regiones g&#xe9;nicas conservadas. Se estableci&#xf3; con &#xe9;xito un ensayo cuantitativo de PCR basado en SYBR<sup>&#xae;</sup> Green I que pudo detectar r&#xe1;pida y diferencialmente los dos virus. Adem&#xe1;s, el ensayo es muy espec&#xed;fico y no muestr&#xf3; reacci&#xf3;n cruzada con otros virus comunes. El l&#xed;mite de detecci&#xf3;n del m&#xe9;todo fue de 7.34 &#xd7; 10<sup>1</sup> copias/&#xb5;l y de 3.78 &#xd7; 10<sup>1</sup> copias/&#xb5;l para el virus de la hepatitis A del pato y para el astrovirus del pato tipo 3, respectivamente, lo que indica una alta sensibilidad. Se analizaron un total de 34 muestras cl&#xed;nicas utilizando el m&#xe9;todo establecido; las tasas positivas para el virus de la hepatitis A del pato y para el astrovirus del pato tipo 3 fueron del 14.71% y 8.82%, respectivamente y la de coinfecci&#xf3;n fue del 2.94% (1/34), que fue mejor que la obtenida con el m&#xe9;todo de PCR convencional. En resumen, el ensayo cuantitativo de PCR basado en SYBR Green I establecido en este estudio tiene alta especificidad, buena sensibilidad y precisi&#xf3;n, alta viabilidad y es r&#xe1;pido. Por lo tanto, puede ser una herramienta poderosa para la detecci&#xf3;n de coinfecciones con el virus de la hepatitis A del pato y astrovirus del pato tipo 3 y para futuros estudios epidemiol&#xf3;gicos.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DAstV-3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DHAV-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SYBR Green I</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">duck viral hepatitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">duplex real-time PCR</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34412459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1637/aviandiseases-D-20-00115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Niu Y, Ma H, Ding Y, Li Z, Sun Y, Li M, Shi Y. The pathogenicity of duck hepatitis A virus types 1 and 3 on ducklings. <i>Poult Sci</i>. 98:6333&#x2013;6339; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng C, Huang Y, Rehman ZU, Hu W, Li C, Liang R, Chen Z, Song K, Wei T, Liu G. Development of an MCA-based real time RT-qPCR assay for the simultaneous detection and differentiation of duck hepatitis a virus types 1 and 3. <i>Virol Sin</i>. 35:666&#x2013;669; 2020.doi:10.1007/s12250-020-00211-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Chen Y, Liu C, Li X, Liu H, Yin X, Bai X, Ge M, Chen H, Liu M, <i>et al</i>. Improved one-tube RT-PCR method for simultaneous detection and genotyping of duck hepatitis A virus subtypes 1 and 3. <i>PLOS ONE</i> 14:e0219750; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Q, Zhu D, Ma G, Cheng A, Wang M, Chen S, Jia R, Liu M, Sun K, Yang Q, <i>et al</i>. A one-step duplex rRT-PCR assay for the simultaneous detection of duck hepatitis A virus genotypes 1 and 3. <i>J Virol Methods</i> 236:207&#x2013;214; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macpherson LW, Avery RJ. Duck virus hepatitis in Canada. <i>Can J Comp Med Vet Sci</i>. 21:26&#x2013;31; 1957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchida T, Suzuki K, Arii M, Shikata T, Fukuda R, Tao YX. Geographical pathology of duck livers infected with duck hepatitis B virus from Chiba and Shimane in Japan and Shanghai in China. <i>Cancer Res</i>. 48:1319&#x2013;25; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen X, Zhu D, Cheng A, Wang M, Chen S, Jia R, Liu M, Sun K, Zhao X, Yang Q, <i>et al</i>. Molecular epidemiology of duck hepatitis a virus types 1 and 3 in China, 2010&#x2013;2015. <i>Transbound Emerg Dis</i>. 65:10&#x2013;15; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi S, Chen H, Chen Z, Fu G, Wan C, Huang Y, Lin S, Cheng L, Fu Q, Lin J, <i>et al</i>. Complete genome sequence of a duck hepatitis a virus 1 isolated from a pigeon in china. <i>Genome Announc</i>. 1: e00451&#x2013;13; 2013. doi:10.1128/genomeA.00451-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farmer H, Chalmers WS, Woolcock PR. The duck fatty kidney syndrome&#x2014;an aspect of duck viral hepatitis. <i>Avian Pathol</i>. 16:227&#x2013;236; 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huy TT, Ushijima H, Win KM, Luengrojanakul P, Shrestha PK, Zhong ZH, Smirnov AV, Taltavull TC, Sata T, Abe K. High prevalence of hepatitis B virus pre-s mutant in countries where it is endemic and its relationship with genotype and chronicity. <i>J Clin Microbiol</i>. 41:5449&#x2013;5455; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattes F, Tong S, Teubner K, Blum HE. Complete nucleotide sequence of a German duck hepatitis B virus. <i>Nucleic Acids Res</i>. 18:6140; 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MC, Kwon YK, Joh SJ, Kim SJ, Tolf C, Kim JH, Sung HW, Lindberg AM, Kwon JH. Recent Korean isolates of duck hepatitis virus reveal the presence of a new geno- and serotype when compared to duck hepatitis virus type 1 type strains. <i>Arch Virol</i>. 152:2059&#x2013;2072; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Ma M, Zhang R, Xu Q, Si X, Wang Y, Xie Z, Jiang S. Simultaneous detection of duck hepatitis A virus types 1 and 3, and of duck astrovirus type 1, by multiplex RT-PCR. <i>Virol Sin</i>. 29:196&#x2013;198; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng CH, Tsai HJ. Molecular characterization of a new serotype of duck hepatitis virus. <i>Virus Res</i>. 126:19&#x2013;31; 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd D, Smyth VJ, Ball NW, Donnelly BM, Wylie M, Knowles NJ, Adair BM. Identification of chicken enterovirus-like viruses, duck hepatitis virus type 2 and duck hepatitis virus type 3 as astroviruses. <i>Avian Pathol</i>. 38:21&#x2013;30; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Q, Liu N, Wang X, Wang F, Zhang D. Genetic characterization of a novel astrovirus in Pekin ducks. <i>Infect Genet Evol</i>. 32:60&#x2013;67; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu N, Wang F, Zhang D. Complete sequence of a novel duck astrovirus. <i>Arch Virol</i>. 159:2823&#x2013;2827; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asplin FD. Duck hepatitis: vaccination against two serological types. <i>Vet Rec</i>. 77:1529&#x2013;1530; 1965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu N, Wang F, Shi J, Zheng L, Wang X, Zhang D. Molecular characterization of a duck hepatitis virus 3-like astrovirus. <i>Vet Microbiol</i>. 170:39&#x2013;47; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Chen Z, Meng C, Liu G. Rapid detection of duck hepatitis A virus genotype C using reverse transcription loop-mediated isothermal amplification. <i>J Virol Methods</i> 196:193&#x2013;198; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Li J, Bi Y, Xu L, Liu W. Development and application of a reverse transcription loop-mediated isothermal amplification method for rapid detection of duck hepatitis A virus type 1. <i>Virus Genes</i> 45:585&#x2013;589; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohll JB, Moon DH, Evans DJ, Almond JW. The 3&#x2032; untranslated region of picornavirus RNA: features required for efficient genome replication. <i>J Virol</i>. 69:7835&#x2013;7844; 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito M, Yamashita T, Tsuzuki H, Takeda N, Sakae K. Isolation and identification of a novel human parechovirus. <i>J Gen Virol</i>. 85:391&#x2013;398; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis TL, Matsui SM. An astrovirus frameshift signal induces ribosomal frameshifting in vitro. <i>Arch Virol</i>. 140:1127&#x2013;1135; 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Cui Y, Li Y, Jiang S, Liu H, Wang J, Li Y. Simultaneous detection of duck circovirus and novel goose parvovirus via SYBR green I-based duplex real-time polymerase chain reaction analysis. <i>Mol Cell Probes</i>. 53:101648; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Li Y, Cui Y, Jiang S, Liu H, Wang J, Li Y. Duplex SYBR Green I-based real-time PCR assay for the rapid detection of canine kobuvirus and canine astrovirus. <i>J Virol Methods</i>. 290:114066; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Q, Yue H, Zhang B, Nie P, Tang C. Development of a real-time quantitative PCR for detecting duck hepatitis a virus genotype C. <i>J Clin Microbiol</i>. 50:3318&#x2013;3323; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao XL, Phillips RM, Li GD, Zhong AQ. Studies on the detection of antibody to duck hepatitis virus by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. <i>Avian Dis</i>. 35:778&#x2013;782; 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haider SA, Calnek BW. In vitro isolation, propagation, and characterization of duck hepatitis virus type III. <i>Avian Dis</i>. 23:715&#x2013;729; 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beuret C. Simultaneous detection of enteric viruses by multiplex real-time RT-PCR. <i>J Virol Methods</i> 115:1&#x2013;8; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Cheng A, Wang M, Xing H. Development and application of a one-step real-time Taqman RT-PCR assay for detection of duck hepatitis virus type1. <i>J Virol Methods</i> 153:55&#x2013;60; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunson RN, Mackie P, Leanord A, Carman WF. First rotavirus, now astrovirus: the evolving benefits of RT-PCR. <i>Commun Dis Public Health</i>. 6:66&#x2013;67; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuda F, Tsugawa H, Fukusaki E. Method for assessing the statistical significance of mass spectral similarities using basic local alignment search tool statistics. <i>Anal Chem</i>. 85:8291&#x2013;8297; 2013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>