<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31966447</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1936-2625</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of clinical and experimental pathology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Clin Exp Pathol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inflammatory cytokine profiles of serum and cerebrospinal fluid in Chinese children with hand, foot and mouth disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>11022</StartPage><EndPage>11029</EndPage><MedlinePgn>11022-11029</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) is mainly caused by enterovirus 71 (EV71) or coxsackie virus A16 infection. Severe HFMD with encephalitis is a life-threatening disease for children. This study aimed to examine the levels of a variety of inflammatory cytokines in HFMD patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Sera of severe or common HFMD patients and cerebrospinal fluids from severe HFMD patients in the acute or recovery phase were collected to analyse 40 cytokines using the Raybiotec Cytokine array. Twenty-six samples of sera or cerebrospinal fluids from HFMD patients were further detected using Milliplex beads.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Numerous inflammatory cytokines, such as IL-8, IP-10, and RAENTES, were enhanced in the sera and cerebrospinal fluids of encephalitis-complicated HFMD patients. Serum IL-12p40 and IL-15 levels were higher in severe HFMD patients compared with common patients. Moreover, IL-8 and IP-10 levels in the cerebrospinal fluid were sharply enhanced by 30-fold on average compared with those in the sera. Cerebrospinal fluid IL-8, IP-10, and RANTES levels were significantly enhanced in the acute phase of severe HFMD patients compared with those in the recovery phase. However, no correlation of serum IL-8 or IP-10 level with its cerebrospinal fluid level was observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">An inflammatory cytokine storm occurs both in sera and cerebrospinal fluids during severe HFMD, which is likely a Th1 cell-associated disease. Cerebrospinal fluid IL-8, IP-10 and RANTES levels could be used as potential biomarkers for diagnosing severe HFMD, whereas the enhanced serum levels of IL-12p40 and IL-15 could be used as candidate predictive factors for severe HFMD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>IJCEP Copyright &#xa9; 2017.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hua</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Wuxi Children's Hospital Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yanping</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Wuxi Children's Hospital Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gong</LastName><ForeName>Weijuan</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Yangzhou University Yangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Integrated Chinese and Western Medicine, School of Medicine, Yangzhou University Yangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, The Affiliated Hospital, Yangzhou University Yangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Co-innovation Center for Prevention and Control of Important Animal Infectious Diseases and Zoonoses Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Key Laboratory of Zoonosis, Yangzhou University Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Clin Exp Pathol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101480565</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1936-2625</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hand</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IL-8</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IP-10</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cerebrospinal fluid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">encephalitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foot and mouth disease (HFMD)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31966447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6965817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nassef C, Ziemer C, Morrell DS. Hand-footand-mouth disease: a new look at a classic viral rash. Curr Opin Pediatr. 2015;27:486&#x2013;491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26087425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lugo D, Krogstad P. Enteroviruses in the early 21st century: new manifestations and challenges. Curr Opin Pediatr. 2016;28:107&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4750492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26709690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muehlenbachs A, Bhatnagar J, Zaki SR. Tissue tropism, pathology and pathogenesis of enterovirus infection. J Pathol. 2015;235:217&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25211036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J, Wang Y, Gan X, Song J, Sun P, Dong XP. Serum cytokine profiles of children with human enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease. J Med Virol. 2014;86:1377&#x2013;1385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24619468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Li R, Xie Z, Huang G, Yuan Q, Zeng J. IL-6, IL-10 and IL-13 are associated with pathogenesis in children with Enterovirus 71 infection. Int J Clin Exp Med. 2014;7:2718&#x2013;2723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4211780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25356130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Li S, Zheng J, Cai C, Ye B, Yang J, Chen Z. Cerebrospinal fluid Th1/Th2 cytokine profiles in children with enterovirus 71-associated meningoencephalitis. Microbiol Immunol. 2015;59:152&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25611005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X, Zhang Y, Liu H, Wang L, Yang F, Hu Y, Ren X, Li G, Yu Y, Sun S, Li Y, Chen X, Li X, Jin Q. Comparative study of the cytokine/chemokine response in children with differing disease severity in enterovirus 71-Induced hand, foot, and mouth disease. PLoS One. 2013;8:e67430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3696071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23840697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Q, Peng W, Chen LI. Coxsackievirus A16 infection stimulates imbalances of T cells in children. Exp Ther Med. 2015;9:2213&#x2013;2218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4473379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26136962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Cai C, Feng J, Li X, Wang Y, Yang J, Chen Z. Peripheral T lymphocyte subset imbalances in children with enterovirus 71-induced hand, foot and mouth disease. Virus Res. 2014;180:84&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24316007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei R, Xu L, Zhang N, Zhu K, Yang J, Yang C, Deng C, Zhu Z, De Groot AS, Altmeyer R, Zeng M, Leng Q. Elevated antigen-specific Th2 type response is associated with the poor prognosis of hand, foot and mouth disease. Virus Res. 2013;177:62&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23886670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolting T, Lindecke A, Koutsilieri E, Maschke M, Husstedt IW, Sopper S, Stuve O, Hartung HP, Arendt G Competence Network HIV/AIDS. Measurement of soluble inflammatory mediators in cerebrospinal fluid of human immunodeficiency virus-positive patients at distinct stages of infection by solid-phase protein array. J Neurovirol. 2009;15:390&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20001608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>den Hertog AL, Montero-Martin M, Saunders RL, Blakiston M, Menting S, Sherchand JB, Lawson L, Oladimeji O, Abdurrahman ST, Cuevas LE, Anthony RM. Cytokine kinetics in the first week of tuberculosis therapy as a tool to confirm a clinical diagnosis and guide therapy. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0129552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4482639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26115421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamik MK, Ghorpade A. CXCL8 as a potential therapeutic target for hiv-associated neurocognitive disorders. Current Drug Targets. 2016;17:111&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu D, Li J, Huang X, Lin A, Gai Z, Chen Z. Impact of IL-8-251A/T gene polymorphism on severity of disease caused by enterovirus 71 infection. Arch Virol. 2016;161:203&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26497182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzi V, Ferrari SM, Giuggioli D, Antonelli A, Ferri C, Fallahi P. Role of CXCL10 in cryoglobulinemia. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2015;33:433&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25571936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira CE, Oda JM, Losi Guembarovski R, de Oliveira KB, Ariza CB, Neto JS, Banin Hirata BK, Watanabe MA. CC chemokine receptor 5: the interface of host immunity and cancer. Dis Markers. 2014;2014:126954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3925608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24591756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holzinger D, Kessel C, Omenetti A, Gattorno M. From bench to bedside and back again: translational research in autoinflammation. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2015;11:573&#x2013;585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26077920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabri B, Abadie V. IL-15 functions as a danger signal to regulate tissue-resident T cells and tissue destruction. Nat Rev Immunol. 2015;15:771&#x2013;783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5079184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26567920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waisman A, Hauptmann J, Regen T. The role of IL-17 in CNS diseases. Acta Neuropathol. 2015;129:625&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25716179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv T, Li J, Han Z, Chen Z. Association of interleukin-17F gene polymorphism with enterovirus 71 encephalitis in patients with hand, foot, and mouth disease. Inflammation. 2013;36:977&#x2013;981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23519962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Liu CC. Cytokine immunopathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brain stem encephalitis. Clin Dev Immunol. 2012;2012:876241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3432373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22956971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elwood E, Lim Z, Naveed H, Galea I. The effect of systemic inflammation on human brain barrier function. Brain Behav Immun. 2017;62:35&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5380128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27810376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>