<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">17954727</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2008</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5522</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>76</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2008</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Infection and immunity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Infect Immun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Highly attenuated Bordetella pertussis strain BPZE1 as a potential live vehicle for delivery of heterologous vaccine candidates.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>111</StartPage><EndPage>119</EndPage><MedlinePgn>111-9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Bordetella pertussis, the causative agent of whooping cough, is a promising and attractive candidate for vaccine delivery via the nasal route, provided that suitable attenuation of this pathogen has been obtained. Recently, the highly attenuated B. pertussis BPZE1 strain has been described as a potential live pertussis vaccine for humans. We investigated here the use of BPZE1 as a live vehicle for heterologous vaccine candidates. Previous studies have reported the filamentous hemagglutinin (FHA), a major B. pertussis adhesin, as a carrier to express foreign antigens in B. pertussis. In this study, we also examined the BrkA autotransporter as a surface display system. Three copies of the neutralizing peptide SP70 from enterovirus 71 (EV71) were fused to FHA or in the passenger domain of BrkA, and each chimera was expressed in BPZE1. The FHA-(SP70)3 and BrkA-(SP70)3 chimeras were successfully secreted and exposed at the bacterial surface, respectively. Nasal administration of the live recombinant strains triggered a strong and sustained systemic anti-SP70 antibody response in mice, although the titers and neutralizing activities against EV71 were significantly higher in the sera of mice immunized with the BrkA-(SP70)3-producing strain. These data indicate that the highly attenuated BPZE1 strain is a potential candidate for vaccine delivery via the nasal route with the BrkA autotransporter as an alternative to FHA for the presentation of the heterologous vaccine antigens.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ho</LastName><ForeName>Si Ying</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Immunology Programme and Department of Microbiology, Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University of Singapore, 28 Medical Drive, CeLS #03-06N, Singapore 117456, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chua</LastName><ForeName>Shi Qian</ForeName><Initials>SQ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Foo</LastName><ForeName>Damian G W</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Locht</LastName><ForeName>Camille</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chow</LastName><ForeName>Vincent T</ForeName><Initials>VT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poh</LastName><ForeName>Chit Laa</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alonso</LastName><ForeName>Sylvie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2007</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Infect Immun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0246127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0019-9567</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001425">Bacterial Outer Membrane Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C090007">BrkA protein, Bordetella pertussis</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D036022">Capsid Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009698">Nucleoproteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014765">Viral Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>122289-52-5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C090319">peptide 31D</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000281" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Intranasal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001402" MajorTopicYN="N">B-Lymphocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001425" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacterial Outer Membrane Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001886" MajorTopicYN="N">Bordetella pertussis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036022" MajorTopicYN="N">Capsid Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017353" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Deletion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009698" MajorTopicYN="N">Nucleoproteins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014765" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Vaccines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2007</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2008</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2007</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2008</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17954727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2223651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.00795-07</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IAI.00795-07</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alonso, S., K. Pethe, N. Mielcarek, D. Raze, and C. Locht. 2001. Role of ADP-ribosyltransferase activity of pertussis toxin in toxin-adhesin redundancy with filamentous hemagglutinin during Bordetella pertussis infection. Infect. Immun. 696038-6043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC98732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11553541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso, S., N. Reveneau, K. Pethe, and C. Locht. 2002. Eighty-kilodalton N-terminal moiety of Bordetella pertussis filamentous hemagglutinin: adherence, immunogenicity, and protective role. Infect. Immun. 704142-4147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC128203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12117922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso, S., E. Willery, G. Renauld-Mongenie, and C. Locht. 2005. Production of nontypeable Haemophilus influenzae HtrA by recombinant Bordetella pertussis with the use of filamentous hemagglutinin as a carrier. Infect. Immun. 734295-4301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1168604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15972522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amsbaugh, D. F., Z. M. Li, and R. D. Shahin. 1993. Long-lived respiratory immune response to filamentous hemagglutinin following Bordetella pertussis infection. Infect. Immun. 611447-1452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC281384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8454349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews, R., A. Herceq, and C. Roberts. 1997. Pertussis notifications in Australia, 1991 to 1997. Commun. Dis. Intell. 21145-148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9188218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes, M. G., and A. A. Weiss. 2001. BrkA protein of Bordetella pertussis inhibits the classical pathway of complement after C1 deposition. Infect. Immun. 693067-3072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC98261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11292725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolivar, F., R. L. Rodriguez, P. J. Greene, M. C. Betlach, H. L. Heynecker, and H. W. Boyer. 1977. Construction and characterization of new cloning vehicles. II. A multipurpose cloning system. Gene 295-113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">344137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cahill, E. S., D. T. O'Hagan, L. Illum, A. Barnard, K. H. G. Mills, and K. Redhead. 1995. Immune responses and protection against Bordetella pertussis infection after intranasal immunization of mice with filamentous hemagglutinin in solution or incorporated in biodegradable microparticles. Vaccine 13455-462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7639014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cainelli Gebara, V., L. Risoleo, A. Lopes, V. Ferreira, W. Quintilio, F. Lepine, W. Silva, and I. Raw. 2007. Adjuvant and immunogenic activities of the 73kDa N-terminal alpha-domain of BrkA autotransporter and Cpn60/60kDa chaperonin of Bordetella pertussis. Vaccine 25621-629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17011680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., D. Perera, B. A. Brown, D. Cheon, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, H. Cho, and P. McMinn. 2003. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 strains and recent outbreaks in the Asia-Pacific region: comparative analysis of the VP1 and VP4 genes. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9461-468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12702227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celentano, L. P., M. Massari, D. Paramatti, S. Salmaso, and A. E. Tozzi. 2005. Resurgence of pertussis in Europe. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 24761-765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16148840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K. P., K. T. Goh, C. Y. Chong, E. S. Teo, G. Lau, and A. E. Ling. 2003. Epidemic hand, foot and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 978-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H. F., M. H. Chang, B. L. Chiang, and S. T. Jeng. 2006. Oral immunization of mice using transgenic tomato fruit expressing VP1 protein from enterovirus 71. Vaccine 242944-2951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16448730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu, C. H., C. Chu, C. C. He, and T. Y. Lin. 2006. Protection of neonatal mice from lethal enterovirus 71 infection by maternal immunization with attenuated Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium expressing VP1 of enterovirus 71. Microbes Infect. 81671-1678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16815726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coppens, I., S. Alonso, R. Antoine, F. Jacob-Dubuisson, G. Renauld-Mongenie, E. Jacobs, and C. Locht. 2001. Production of Neisseria meningitidis transferrin-binding protein B by recombinant Bordetella pertussis. Infect. Immun. 695440-5446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC98655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11500415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutte, L., S. Alonso, N. Reveneau, E. Willery, B. Quatannens, C. Locht, and F. Jacob-Dubuisson. 2003. Role of adhesin release for mucosal colonization by a bacterial pathogen. J. Exp. Med. 197735-742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2193847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12629063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Serres, G., and B. Duval. 2005. Pertussis vaccination beyond childhood. Lancet 3651015-1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15781085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elder, K. D., and E. T. Harvill. 2004. Strain-dependent role of BrkA during Bordetella pertussis infection of the murine respiratory tract. Infect. Immun. 725919-5924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC517575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ewanowich, C. A., A. R. Melton, A. A. Weiss, R. K. Sherburne, and M. S. Peppler. 1989. Invasion of HeLa 229 cells by virulent Bordetella pertussis. Infect. Immun. 572698-2704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC313514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2547718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez, R. C., and A. A. Weiss. 1994. Cloning and sequencing of a Bordetella pertussis serum resistance locus. Infect. Immun. 624727-4738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC303180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7927748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez, R. C., and A. A. Weiss. 1996. Susceptibilities of Bordetella pertussis strains to antimicrobial peptides. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 401041-1043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC163258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8849226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo, G. W. D., S. Alonso, T. K. V. Chow, and C. L. Poh. 2007. Passive protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by neutralizing antibodies elicited by a synthetic peptide. Microbes Infect. 91299-1306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17890123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo, G. W. D., S. Alonso, M. C. Phoon, N. P. Ramachandran, T. K. V. Chow, and C. L. Poh. 2007. Identification of neutralizing linear epitopes from the VP1 capsid protein of enterovirus 71 using synthetic peptides. Virus Res. 12561-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17222936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedin, S., E. Willery, C. Locht, and F. Jacob-Dubuisson. 1998. Evidence that a globular conformation is not compatible with FhaC-mediated secretion of the Bordetella pertussis filamentous haemagglutinin. Mol. Microbiol. 29763-774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9723916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson, I. R., F. Navarro-Garcia, M. Desvaux, R. C. Fernandez, and D. Ala'Aldeen. 2004. Type V protein secretion pathway: the autotransporter story. Microbiol. Mol. Biol. Rev. 68692-744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC539010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15590781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson, I. R., F. Navarro-Garcia, and J. P. Nataro. 1998. The great escape: structure and function of the autotransporter proteins. Trends Microbiol. 6370-378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9778731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M., E. R. Chen, K. H. Hsu, S. J. Twu, K. T. Chen, S. F. Tsai, J. R. Wang, and S. R. Shih. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N. Engl. J. Med. 341929-935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikemura, T. 1985. Codon usage and tRNA content in unicellular and multicellular organisms. Mol. Biol. Evol. 113-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3916708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob-Dubuisson, F., C. Locht, and R. Antoine. 2001. Two-partner secretion in Gram-negative bacteria: a thrifty, specific pathway for large virulence proteins. Mol. Microbiol. 40306-313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11309114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain, S., P. van Ulsen, I. Benz, M. A. Schmidt, R. C. Fernandez, J. Tommassen, and M. B. Goldberg. 2006. Polar localization of the autotransporter family of large bacterial virulence proteins. Infect. Immun. 1884841-4850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1483012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16788193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer, U., K. Rizos, H. Apfel, I. B. Autenrieth, and C. T. Lattermann. 2003. Autodisplay: development of an efficacious system for surface display of antigenic determinants in Salmonella vaccine strains. Infect. Immun. 711944-1952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC152032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12654812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lattemann, C. T., J. Maurer, E. Gerland, and T. F. Meyer. 2000. Autodisplay: functional display of active &#x3b2;-lactamase on the surface of Escherichia coli by the AIDA-I autotransporter. J. Bacteriol. 1823726-3733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC94543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10850987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locht, C. 2000. Live bacterial vectors for intranasal delivery of protective antigens. Pharm. Sci. Technol. Today 3121-128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10754541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locht, C., P. Bertin, F. D. Menozzi, and G. Renauld. 1993. The filamentous hemagglutinin, a multifaceted adhesion produced by Bordetella spp. Mol. Microbiol. 9653-660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8231801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mascart, F., V. Verscheure, A. Malfroot, M. Hainaut, D. Pierard, S. Temerman, A. Peltier, A.-S. Debrie, J. Levy, G. Del Giudice, and C. Locht. 2003. Bordetella pertussis infection in 2-months-old infants promotes type 1 T cell responses. J. Immunol. 1701504-1509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12538714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P. C. 2002. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 2691-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menozzi, F. D., C. Gantiez, and C. Locht. 1991. Identification and purification of transferrin- and lactoferrin-binding proteins of Bordetella pertussis and Bordetella bronchiseptica. Infect. Immun. 593982-3988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC258986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1937757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielcarek, N., S. Alonso, and C. Locht. 2001. Nasal vaccination using live bacterial vectors. Adv. Drug Deliv. Rev. 5155-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11516779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielcarek, N., J. Cornette, A. Schacht, R. Pierce, C. Locht, A. Capron, and G. Riveau. 1997. Intranasal priming with recombinant Bordetella pertussis for the induction of a systemic immune response against a heterologous antigen. Infect. Immun. 65544-550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC176094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9009311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielcarek, N., A-S. Debrie, D. Raze, J. Bertout, C. Rouanet, A. B. Younes, C. Creusy, J. Engle, W. E. Goldman, and C. Locht. 2006. Live attenuated B. pertussis as a single-dose nasal vaccine against whooping cough. PLoS Pathogens 20001-0009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1487175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16839199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielcarek, N., I. Nordstrom, F. Menozzi, C. Locht, and J. Holmgren. 2000. Genital antibody responses in mice after intranasal infection with an attenuated candidate vector strain of Bordetella pertussis. Infect. Immun. 68491-495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10639408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielcarek, N., G. Riveau, F. Remoue, R. Antoine, A. Capron, and C. Locht. 1998. Homologous and heterologous protection after single intranasal administration of live attenuated recombinant Bordetella pertussis. Nat. Biotechnol. 16454-457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9592394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mooi, F. R., I. H. van Loo, and A. J. King. 2001. Adaptation of Bordetella pertussis to vaccination: a cause for its reemergence? Emerg. Infect. Dis. 7526-528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2631860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11485646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver, D. C., G. Huang, and R. C. Fernandez. 2003. Identification of secretion determinants of the Bordetella pertussis BrkA autotransporter. J. Bacteriol. 185489-495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC145336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12511495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver, D. C., G. Huang, E. Nodel, S. Pleasance, and R. C. Fernandez. 2003. A conserved region within the Bordetella pertussis autotransporter BrkA is necessary for folding of its passenger domain. Mol. Microbiol. 471367-1383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12603741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios, G., and M. S. Oberste. 2005. Enterovirus as agent of emerging infectious diseases. J. Neurovirol. 11424-433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16287683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulain-Godefroy, O., F. D. Menozzi, S. Alonso, C., Vendeville, A. Capron, C. Locht, and G. Riveau. 2003. Adjuvant activity of free Bordetella pertussis filamentous hemagglutinin delivered by mucosal routes. Scand. J. Immunol. 58503-510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14629622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quandt, J., and M. F. Hynes. 1993. Versatile suicide vectors which allow direct selection for replacement in Gram-negative bacteria. Gene 12715-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8486283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renauld-Mongenie, G., N. Mielcarek, J. Cornette, A.-M. Schacht, A. Capron, G. Riveau, and C. Locht. 1996. Induction of mucosal immune responses against a heterologous antigen fused to filamentous hemagglutinin after intranasal immunization with recombinant Bordetella pertussis. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 937944-7949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC38854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8755582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reveneau, N., S. Alonso, F. Jacob-Dubuisson, A. Mercenier, and C. Locht. 2001. Tetanus toxin fragment C-specific priming by intranasal infection with recombinant Bordetella pertussis. Vaccine 20926-933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts, G. B. S., and J. F. Boyd. 1987. The histopathology of enterovirus infections in new-born mice. J. Infect. 1545-56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2822811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahin, R., D. F. Amsbaugh, and M. F. Leef. 1992. Mucosal immunization with filamentous hemagglutinin protects against Bordetella pertussis respiratory infection. Infect. Immun. 601482-1488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC257021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1548072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon, J. L., and R. C. Fernandez. 1999. The C-terminal domain of the Bordetella pertussis autotransporter BrkA forms a pore in lipid bilayer membranes. J. Bacteriol. 1815838-5842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC94107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10482528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegrist, C. A. 2001. Neonatal and early life vaccinology. Vaccine 193331-3346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11348697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivasamugham, L. A., M. J. Cardosa, W. S. Tan, and K. Yusoff. 2006. Recombinant Newcastle disease virus capsids displaying enterovirus 71 VP1 fragment induce a strong immune response in rabbits. J. Med. Virol. 781096-1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16789020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stibitz, S. 1994. Use of conditionally counterselectable suicide vectors for allelic exchange. Methods Enzymol. 235458-465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8057916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, C. S., and M. J. Cardosa. 2007. High-titer neutralizing antibodies to human enterovirus 71 preferentially bind to the N-terminal portion of the capsid protein VP1. Arch. Virol. 1571069-1073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17318736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veiga, E., V. De Lorenzo, and L. A. Fernandez. 2004. Structural tolerance of bacterial autotransporters for folded passenger protein domains. Mol. Microbiol. 521069-1080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15130125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, C. N., Y. C. Lin, C. Fann, N. S. Liao, S. R. Shih, and M. S. Ho. 2001. Protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by passive immunization with subunit VP1 vaccines and inactivated virus. Vaccine 20895-904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanisch-Perron, C., J. Vieira, and J. Messing. 1985. Improved M13 phage cloning vectors and host strains: nucleotide sequences of the M13mp18 and pUC19 vectors. Gene 33103-119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2985470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, C. K., C. C. Chen, C. L. Chen, J. R. Wang, C. C. Liu, J. J. Yan, and I. J. Su. 2000. Neutralizing antibody provided protection against enterovirus type 71 lethal challenge in neonatal mice. J. Biomed. Sci. 7523-528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11060501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, C., F. Ruiz-Perez, Z. Yang, Y. Mao, V. L. Hackethal, K. M. Greco, W. Choy, K. Davis, J. R. Butterton, and E. C. Boedeker. 2006. Delivery of heterologous protein antigens via hemolysin or autotransporter systems by an attenuated ler mutant of rabbit enteropathogenic Escherichia coli. Vaccine 243821-3831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16098637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>