<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">30123051</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1449-1907</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of medical sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>T Cell Immunity To Enterovirus 71 Infection In Humans And Implications For Vaccine Development.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1143</StartPage><EndPage>1152</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1143-1152</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7150/ijms.26450</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV-A71) is one of the major pathogens causing hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD). Some strains can lead to neurological disease and fatality in children. Up to date, there is no FDA-approved vaccine to prevent severe HFMD and mortality. Although the inactivated vaccine has advanced to production in China, lack of long-term protection and the requirement of multiple boosters have necessitated the development of other types of vaccines. Recent studies indicate that cellular and not humoral immunity determines the clinical outcome of EV-A71 infections. High levels of cytokines such as IL-1&#x3b2;, IL-6, IL-10 and IFN-&#x3b3; tend to correlate with clinical severity in patients with pulmonary edema and encephalitis. The live attenuated vaccine may serve as the preferred choice as it can induce excellent humoral and cellular immunity as well as live-long immunity. Expression of certain HLA alleles such as TNF-&#x3b1; promoter type II (-308 allele), HLA-A33 and HLA-DR17 responses have been linked to severe HFMD. However, the high variability of MHC genes could restrict T cell recognition and be a major obstacle in the design of peptide vaccines. Hence, the development of a T cell universal vaccine (incorporating both CD4<sup>+</sup> and CD8<sup>+</sup> T cell epitopes) that induces broad, multifunctional and cross-reactive CD8<sup>+</sup> T cell responses maybe desirable.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yee</LastName><ForeName>Pinn Tsin Isabel</ForeName><Initials>PTI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Virus and Vaccine Research, School of Science and Technology, Sunway University, Bandar Sunway, Kuala Lumpur, Selangor 47500, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Poh</LastName><ForeName>Chit Laa</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Virus and Vaccine Research, School of Science and Technology, Sunway University, Bandar Sunway, Kuala Lumpur, Selangor 47500, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Med Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101213954</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1449-1907</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013601" MajorTopicYN="N">T-Lymphocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, foot and mouth disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cellular immunity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunogenicity.</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing Interests: The authors have declared that no competing interest exists.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30123051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6097258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/ijms.26450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijmsv15p1143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO Western Pacific Region. Surveillance summary in the Western Pacific Region. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi EJ, Shin YJ, Kim JH, Kim TG, Chang SY. Enterovirus 71 infection and vaccines. Clin Exp Vaccine Res. 2017;6:4&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5292356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28168168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F, Xu W, Xia J, Liang Z, Liu Y, Zhang X. et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in China. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JX, Song YF, Wang L, Zhang XF, Hu YS, Hu YM. et al. Two-year efficacy and immunogenicity of Sinovac enterovirus 71 vaccine against hand, foot and mouth disease in children. Expert Rev Vaccines. 2016;15:129&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26460695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov K, Ehrenfeld E. New generation of inactivated poliovirus vaccines for universal immunization after eradication of poliomyelitis. Clin Infect Dis. 2008;47:1587&#x2013;1592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2596976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18990066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H, Li HY, Han JF, Deng YQ, Zhu SY, Li XF. et al. Novel recombinant chimeric virus-like particle is immunogenic and protective against both enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 in mice. Sci Rep. 2015;5:7878&#x2013;7895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4297979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25597595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong M, Zhu H, Zhou J, Yang C, Feng J, Huang X. et al. Cryo-electron microscopy study of insect cell-expressed enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 virus-like particles provides a structural basis for vaccine development. J Virol. 2014;88:6444&#x2013;6452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4093858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24672036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Wu S, Xiong Y, Li T, Wen Z, Yan M. et al. Co-circulation and genomic recombination of coxsackievirus A16 and enterovirus 71 during a large outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in central China. PLoS ONE. 2014;9:e96051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4002479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24776922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, An D, Liu W, Mao Q, Jin J, Xu L. et al. Analysis of cross-reactive neutralizing antibodies in human HFMD serum with an EV71 pseudovirus-based assay. PLoS ONE. 2014;9:e100545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4070950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24964084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou AH, Liu CC, Chang JY, Lien SP, Guo MS, Tasi HP. et al. Immunological evaluation and comparison of different EV71 vaccine candidates. Clin Dev Immunol. 2012;2012:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3447357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23008736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Hsiung CA, Lu CY, Lin TY, Huang FY, Lai YH. et al. Status of cellular rather than humoral immunity is correlated with clinical outcome of enterovirus 71. Pediatr Res. 2006;60:466&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7086547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16940249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Meng FY, Li JX, Li XL, Mao QY, Tao H. et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2013;381:2024&#x2013;2032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23726161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber RS, van Beek J, de Jonge J, Luytjes W, van Baarle D. T cell responses to viral infections - opportunities for peptide vaccination. Front Immunol. 2014;5:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3997009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24795718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seder RA, Darrah PA, Roederer M. T-cell quality in memory and protection: implications for vaccine design. Nat Rev Immunol. 2008;8:247&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18323851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demkowicz WE, Littaua RA, Wang J, Ennis FA. Human cytotoxic T-cell memory: long-lived responses to vaccinia virus. J Virol. 1996;70:2627&#x2013;2631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC190113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8642697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swain SL, McKinstry KK, Strutt TM. Expanding roles for CD4+ T cells in immunity to viruses. Nat Rev Immunol. 2012;12:136&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3764486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22266691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Cui D, Yang X, Lou J, Lin J, Ye X. et al. Increased frequency of circulating follicular helper T cells in children with hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by enterovirus 71 infection. J Immunol Res. 2014;2014:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4071862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25013818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang S, Gao N, Li Y, Li M, Wang X, Jia X. et al. Dominant CD4-dependent RNA-dependent RNA polymerase-specific T-cell responses in children acutely infected with human enterovirus 71 and healthy adult controls. Immunology. 2014;142:89&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3992051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24329688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin YW, Chang KC, Kao CM, Chang SP, Tung YY, Chen SH. Lymphocyte and antibody responses reduce enterovirus 71 lethality in mice by decreasing tissue viral loads. J Virol. 2009;83:6477&#x2013;6483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen FH, Tsai CC, Wang LC, Chang KC, Tung YY, Su IJ. et al. Enterovirus 71 infection increases expression of interferon-gamma-inducible protein 10 which protects mice by reducing viral burden in multiple tissues. J Gen Virol. 2013;94:1019&#x2013;1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23288420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khong WX, Foo DGW, Trasti SL, Tan EL, Alonso S. Sustained high levels of interleukin-6 contribute to the pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 in a neonate mouse model. J Virol. 2011;85:3067&#x2013;3076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3067852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21228224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MA, Bevan MJ. Effector and memory CTL differentiation. Annu Rev Immunol. 2007;25:171&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17129182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahid R, Cannon MJ, Chow M. Virus-specific CD4+ and CD8+ cytotoxic T-cell responses and long-term T-cell memory in individuals vaccinated against polio. J Virol. 2005;79:5988&#x2013;5995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1091702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15857985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourgault I, Gomez A, Gomard E, Picard F, Levy JP, Gomrad E. A virus-specific CD4+ cell-mediated cytolytic activity revealed by CD8+ cell elimination regularly develops in uncloned human antiviral cell lines. J Immunol. 1989;142:252&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2535856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai DF, Lin CY, Wu TZ, Chen LK. Recognition of dengue virus protein using epitope-mediated molecularly imprinted film. Anal Chem. 2005;77:5140&#x2013;5143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16097751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martorelli D, Muraro E, Merlo A, Turrini R, Rosato A, Dolcetti R. Role of CD4+ cytotoxic T lymphocytes in the control of viral diseases and dancer. Int Rev Immunol. 2010;29:371&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20635880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachler BC, Humbert M, Palikuqi B, Siddappa NB, Lakhashe SK, Rasmussen RA. et al. Novel biopanning strategy to identify epitopes associated with vaccine protection. J Virol. 2013;87:4403&#x2013;4416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3624354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23388727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thimme R, Wieland S, Steiger C, Ghrayeb J, Reimann KA, Purcell RH. et al. CD8+ T cells mediate viral clearance and disease pathogenesis during acute hepatitis B virus infection. J Virol. 2003;77:68&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC140637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12477811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan ACL, La Gruta NL, Zeng W, Jackson DC. Precursor frequency and competition dictate the HLA-A2-restricted CD8+ T cell responses to influenza A infection and vaccination in HLA-A2.1 transgenic mice. J Immunol. 2011;187:1895&#x2013;1902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21765016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X, Xiao X, Xue Q, Jin Q, He B, Wang J. Cleavage of interferon regulatory factor 7 by enterovirus 71 3C suppresses cellular responses. J Virol. 2013;87:1690&#x2013;1698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3554134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23175366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YP, Wang YF, Wang JR, Huang SW, Yu CK. Enterovirus 71 blocks selectively type I interferon production through the 3C viral protein in mice. J Med Virol. 2012;84:1779&#x2013;1789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22997081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Xi X, Lei X, Zhang X, Cui S, Wang J. et al. Enterovirus 71 protease 2Apro targets MAVS to inhibit anti-viral type I interferon responses. PLoS Path. 2013;9:e1003231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3605153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23555247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J, Yi L, Zhao J, Yu J, Chen Y, Lin MC. et al. Enterovirus 71 disrupts interferon signaling by reducing the interferon receptor 1. J Virol. 2012;86:3767&#x2013;3776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3302529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22258259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Zhang Z, Zhao X, Yu R, Zhang X, Wu S. et al. Enterovirus 71 inhibits cellular type I interferon signaling by downregulating JAK1 protein expression. Viral Immunol. 2014;27:267&#x2013;276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24905060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Pu J, Huang H, Zhang Y, Liu L, Yang E. et al. EV71-infected CD14+ cells modulate the immune activity of T lymphocytes in rhesus monkeys. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2013;2:e44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3820984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26038477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Liu H, Wang L, Yang F, Hu Y, Ren X. et al. Comparative study of the cytokine/chemokine response in children with differing disease severity in enterovirus 71-induced hand, foot, and mouth disease. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e67430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3696071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23840697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haraldsen G, Balogh J, Pollheimer J, Sponheim J, K&#xfc;chler AM. Interleukin-33 - cytokine of dual function or novel alarmin? Trends Immunol. 2009;30:227&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19359217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glabinski AR, Balasingam V, Tani M, Kunkel SL, Strieter RM, Yong VW. et al. Chemokine monocyte chemoattractant protein-1 is expressed by astrocytes after mechanical injury to the brain. J Immunol. 1996;156:4363&#x2013;4368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8666808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng M, Zheng X, Wei R, Zhang N, Zhu K, Xu B. et al. The cytokine and chemokine profiles in patients with hand, foot and mouth disease of different severities in Shanghai, China, 2010. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2013;7:e2599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3868519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24367714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan G, Yang H, Shi L, Sun W, Sui M, Zhang R. et al. Serum inflammatory cytokine levels correlate with hand-foot-mouth disease severity: A nested serial case-control study. PLoS ONE. 2014;9:e112676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4229228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25391156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Huang KJ, Wu JM, Wang JR, Yu CK. et al. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: Roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J Infect Dis. 2003;188:564&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner MA, Ramsay AJ, Buchan GS, Keen DL, Ranasinghe C, Slobbe L. et al. A DNA prime-live vaccine boost strategy in mice can augment IFN-&#x3b3; responses to mycobacterial antigens but does not increase the protective efficacy of two attenuated strains of Mycobacterium bovis against bovine tuberculosis. Immunology. 2003;108:548&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1782916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12667217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloom BR, Flynn J, McDonough K, Kress Y, Chan J. Experimental approaches to mechanisms of protection and pathogenesis in M. tuberculosis infection. Immunobiology. 1994;191:526&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7713567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MA, Tyznik AJ, Bevan MJ. Interleukin-2 signals during priming are required for secondary expansion of CD8+ memory T cells. Nature. 2006;441:890&#x2013;893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2776073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16778891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng KF, Chen LL, Huang PN, Shih SR. Neural pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 infection. Microb Infect. 2010;12:505&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20348010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betts MR, Brenchley JM, Price DA, De Rosa SC, Douek DC, Roederer M. et al. Sensitive and viable identification of antigen-specific CD8+ T cells by a flow cytometric assay for degranulation. J Immunol Methods. 2003;281:65&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14580882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kannanganat S, Ibegbu C, Chennareddi L, Robinson HL, Amara RR. Multiple-cytokine-producing antiviral CD4 T cells are functionally superior to single-cytokine-producing cells. J Virol. 2007;81:8468&#x2013;8476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17553885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan S, Tan X, Sun X, Lu G, Chen CC, Yan J. et al. VP2 dominated CD4+ T cell responses against enterovirus 71 and cross-reactivity against coxsackievirus A16 and polioviruses in a healthy population. J Immunol. 2013;191:1637&#x2013;1647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23863902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo D, Macary P, Alonso S, Poh C. Identification of human CD4 T-cell epitopes on the VP1 capsid protein of enterovirus 71. Viral Immunol. 2008;21:215&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18419256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moutaftsi M, Bui H-H, Peters B, Sidney J, Salek-Ardakani S, Oseroff C. et al. Vaccinia virus-specific CD4+ T cell responses target a set of antigens largely distinct from those targeted by CD8+ T cell responses. J Immunol. 2007;178:6814&#x2013;68120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17513729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivino L, Kumaran EAP, Jovanovic V, Nadua K, Teo EW, Pang SW. et al. Differential targeting of viral components by CD4+ versus CD8+ T lymphocytes in dengue virus infection. J Virol. 2013;87:2693&#x2013;2706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3571409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23255803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, King CC, Hsu KH, Ning HC, Tsao KC, Li CC. et al. Risk factors of enterovirus 71 infection and associated hand, foot, and mouth disease/herpangina in children during an epidemic in Taiwan. Pediatrics. 2002;109:e88&#x2013;e95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang KD, Yang MY, Li CC, Lin SF, Chong MC, Wang CL. et al. Altered cellular but not humoral reactions in children with complicated enterovirus 71 infections in Taiwan. J Infect Dis. 2001;183:850&#x2013;856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11237800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosendahl Huber SK, Luimstra JJ, van Beek J, Hoppes R, Jacobi RHJ, Hendriks M. et al. Chemical modification of influenza CD8+ T-cell epitopes enhances their immunogenicity regardless of immunodominance. PLoS ONE. 2016;11:e0156462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4917206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27333291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinigaglia F, Guttinger M, Kilgus J, Doran DM, Matile H, Etlinger H. et al. A malaria T-cell epitope recognized in association with most mouse and human MHC class II molecules. Nature. 1988;336:778&#x2013;780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2462673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillet JG, Lai MZ, Briner TJ, Smith JA, Gefter ML. Interaction of peptide antigens and class II major histocompatibility complex antigens. Nature. 1986;324:260&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2946957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panina-Bordignon P, Tan A, Termijtelen A, Demotz S, Corradin G, Lanzavecchia A. Universally immunogenic T cell epitopes: promiscuous binding to human MHC class II and promiscuous recognition by T cells. Eur J Immunol. 1989;19:2237&#x2013;2242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2481588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardin EH, Calvo-Calle JM, Oliveira GA, Nussenzweig RS, Schneider M, Tiercy J-M. et al. A totally synthetic polyoxime malaria vaccine containing Plasmodium falciparum B cell and universal T cell epitopes elicits immune responses in volunteers of diverse HLA types. J Immunol. 2001;166:481&#x2013;489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11123327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiskopf D, Angelo MA, de Azeredo EL, Sidney J, Greenbaum JA, Fernando AN. et al. Comprehensive analysis of dengue virus-specific responses supports an HLA-linked protective role for CD8+ T cells. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2013;110:e2046&#x2013;e53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3670335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23580623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loke H, Bethell DB, Phuong CXT, Dung M, Schneider J, White NJ. et al. Strong HLA class I-restricted T cell responses in dengue hemorrhagic fever: A double-edged sword? J Infect Dis. 2001;184:1369&#x2013;1373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11709777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Alwis R, Bangs DJ, Angelo MA, Cerpas C, Fernando A, Sidney J. et al. Immunodominant dengue virus-specific CD8+ T cell responses are associated with a memory PD-1+ phenotype. J Virol. 2016;90:4771&#x2013;4779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4836325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26912627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruger A, Adams P, Hammer J, B&#xf6;cher WO, Schneider PM, Rittner C. et al. Hepatitis B surface antigen presentation and HLA-DRB1* - lessons from twins and peptide binding studies. Clin Exp Immunol. 2005;140:325&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1809359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15807858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devaux P, Cattaneo R. Measles virus phosphoprotein gene products: Conformational flexibility of the P/V protein amino-terminal domain and C protein infectivity factor function. J Virol. 2004;78:11632&#x2013;11640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC523285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15479804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern LJ, Calvo-Calle JM. HLA-DR: Molecular insights and vaccine design. Curr Pharm Des. 2009;15:3249&#x2013;3261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3615543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19860674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goulder P, Price D, Nowak M, Rowland-Jones S, Phillips R, McMichael A. Co-evolution of human immunodeficiency virus and cytotoxic T-lymphocyte responses. Immunol Rev. 1997;159:17&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9416500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz JE, Kuroda MJ, Santra S, Sasseville VG, Simon MA, Lifton MA. et al. Control of viremia in simian immunodeficiency virus infection by CD8+ lymphocytes. Science. 1999;283:857&#x2013;860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9933172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Chang IS, Chen WJ, Huang YC, Chen GW, Shih SR. et al. HLA-A33 is associated with susceptibility to enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatrics. 2008;122:1271&#x2013;1276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19047245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue Y, Li P, Song N, Li B, Li Z, Guo Y. et al. Genomic and immunologic factors associated with viral pathogenesis in a lethal EV71 infected neonatal mouse model. Mol Med Rep. 2016;13:4183&#x2013;4190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4838153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27035332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei R, Yang C, Zeng M, Terry F, Zhu K, Yang C. et al. A dominant EV71-specific CD4+ T cell epitope is highly conserved among human enteroviruses. PLoS ONE. 2012;7:e51957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3522610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23251663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu TC, Wang YF, Lee YP, Wang JR, Liu CC, Wang SM. et al. Immunity to avirulent enterovirus 71 and coxsackie A16 virus protects against enterovirus 71 infection in mice. J Virol. 2007;81:10310&#x2013;10315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2045469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17626076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovsyannikova IG, Jacobson RM, Dhiman N, Vierkant RA, Pankratz VS, Poland GA. Human leukocyte antigen and cytokine receptor gene polymorphisms associated with heterogeneous immune responses to mumps viral vaccine. Pediatrics. 2008;121:e1091&#x2013;e1099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2668976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18450852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>