<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21228224</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>85</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sustained high levels of interleukin-6 contribute to the pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 in a neonate mouse model.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3067</StartPage><EndPage>3076</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3067-76</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.01779-10</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is the major causative agent of hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) in young children and has been consistently associated with the most severe complications of the disease, including central nervous system inflammation and pulmonary edema. Increasing frequency and amplitude of EV71 outbreaks have raised awareness and concerns worldwide. Previous reports proposed that overwhelming virus replication combined with the induction of massive proinflammatory cytokines is responsible for the pathogenicity of EV71. Specifically, elevated interleukin-6 (IL-6) levels were observed consistently in patients and strongly correlated with disease severity. In this study, we show in the neonate mouse model that sustained high levels of IL-6 produced upon EV71 infection lead to severe tissue damage and eventually death of the animals. Administration of anti-IL-6 neutralizing antibodies after the onset of the clinical symptoms successfully improved the survival rates and clinical scores of the infected hosts. Compared to untreated infected controls, anti-IL-6-treated mice displayed reduced tissue damage, absence of splenic atrophy, and increased immune cell activation. In addition, markedly elevated systemic levels of IL-10 were measured in the protected animals. Furthermore, there was no significant difference in virus titers between anti-IL-6-treated mice and untreated mice, indicating that the anti-IL-6 antibody-mediated protection is independent of the virus load. Our findings thus demonstrate that IL-6 plays a major role in EV71-induced immunopathogenesis. As there is still neither vaccine nor treatment available against EV71, anti-IL-6 antibody treatment represents a potential therapeutic approach to providing protection from the most severe complications of the disease.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khong</LastName><ForeName>Wei Xin</ForeName><Initials>WX</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Immunology Programme, Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine, National University of Singapore, CeLS Building 03-05, 28 Medical Drive, Singapore 117597, Republic of Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Foo</LastName><ForeName>Damian G W</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trasti</LastName><ForeName>Scott L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Eng Lee</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alonso</LastName><ForeName>Sylvie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015850">Interleukin-6</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000831" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006651" MajorTopicYN="N">Histocytochemistry</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015850" MajorTopicYN="N">Interleukin-6</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000096" MajorTopicYN="Y">biosynthesis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000633" MajorTopicYN="Y">toxicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007422" MajorTopicYN="N">Intestines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008807" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred BALB C</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009132" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013154" MajorTopicYN="N">Spleen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016019" MajorTopicYN="N">Survival Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019562" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Load</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21228224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3067852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.01779-10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.01779-10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe, Y., A. Horiuchi, M. Miyake, and S. Kimura. 1994. Anti-cytokine nature of natural human immunoglobulin: one possible mechanism of the clinical effect of intravenous immunoglobulin therapy. Immunol. Rev. 139:5-19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7927413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adkins, B., C. Leclerc, and S. Marshall-Clarke. 2004. Neonatal adaptive immunity comes of age. Nat. Rev. 4:553-564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15229474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brockman, M. A., et al. 2009. IL-10 is up-regulated in multiple cell types during viremic HIV infection and reversibly inhibits virus-specific T cells. Blood 114:346-356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2714209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19365081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, L. G., et al. 2000. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia, clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. Clin. Infect. Dis. 31:678-683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., C. Y. Huang, and T. Y. Lin. 1998. Fulminant neurogenic pulmonary oedema with hand, foot and mouth disease. Lancet 352:367-368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9717926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., et al. 1999. Clinical features and risk factors of pulmonary oedema after enterovirus 71-related hand, foot and mouth disease. Lancet 354:1682-1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. C., et al. 2004. A murine oral enterovirus 71 infection model with central nervous system involvement. J. Gen. Virol. 85:69-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14718621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couper, K. N., D. G. Blount, and E. M. Riley. 2008. IL-10: the master regulator of immunity to infection. J. Immunol. 180:5771-5777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18424693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo, D. G. W., et al. 2007. Passive protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by neutralizing antibodies elicited by a synthetic peptide. Microbes Infect. 9:1299-1306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17890123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijbels, K., S. Brocke, J. S. Abrams, and L. Steinman. 1995. Administration of neutralizing antibodies to interleukin-6 (IL-6) reduces experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis and is associated with elevated levels of IL-6 bioactivity in central nervous system and circulation. Mol. Med. 1:795-805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2230023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8612202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert, G. L., et al. 1988. Outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Victoria, Australia, with a high incidence of neurologic involvement. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 7:484-488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2841639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girndt, M., and H. Kohler. 2003. Interleukin-10 (IL-10): an update on its relevance for cardiovascular risk. Nephrol. Dial. Transplant. 18:1976-1979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13679468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto, I., and A. Hagiwara. 1982. Pathogenicity of a poliomyelitis-like disease in monkeys infected orally with enterovirus 71: a model for human infection. Neuropathol. Appl. Neurobiol. 8:149-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7048123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heremans, H., C. Dillen, W. Put, V. J. Damme, and A. Billiau. 1992. Protective effect of anti-interleukin (IL)-6 antibody against endotoxin associated with paradoxically increased IL-6 levels. Eur. J. Immunol. 22:2395-2401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1381315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrero, L. J., et al. 2003. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in peninsular Malaysia, 1997-2000. Arch. Virol. 148:1369-1385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12827466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C. C., et al. 1999. Neurological complications in children with enterovirus 71 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:936-942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishihara, K., and T. Hirano. 2002. IL-6 in autoimmune disease and chronic inflammatory proliferative disease. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 13:357-368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12220549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanda, T., et al. 1996. Modification of viral myocarditis in mice by interleukin-6. Circ. Res. 78:848-856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8620605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kishimoto, T. 2006. Interleukin-6: discovery of a pleiotropic cytokine. Arthritis Res. Ther. 8:2-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3226075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16899106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopf, M., et al. 1994. Impaired immune and acute-phase responses in interleukin-6-deficient mice. Nature 368:339-342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8127368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosai, K., et al. 2008. Gabexate mesilate suppresses influenza pneumonia in mice through inhibition of cytokines. J. Int. Med. Res. 36:322-328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18380943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert, P. H., M. Liu, and C. A. Siegrist. 2005. Can. successful vaccines teach us how to induce efficient protective immune responses? Nat. Med. 211:S54-S62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15812491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy, O. 2007. Innate immunity of the newborn: basic mechanisms and clinical correlates. Nat. Rev. 7:379-390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17457344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., et al. 2002. Different proinflammatory reactions in fatal and non-fatal enterovirus 71 infections: implications for early recognition and therapy. Acta Paediatr. 91:632-635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12162592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., S. H. Hsia, Y. C. Huang, C. T. Wu, and L. Y. Chang. 2003. Proinflammatory cytokine reactions in enterovirus 71 infections of the central nervous system. Clin. Infect. Dis. 36:269-274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12539066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, Y. W., S. W. Wang, Y. Y. Tung, and S. H. Chen. 2009. Enterovirus 71 infection of human dendritic cells. Exp. Biol. Med. (Maywood) 234:1166-1173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19596831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C. C., H. W. Tseng, S. M. Wang, J. R. Wang, and I. J. Su. 2000. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998: epidemiologic and clinical manifestations. J. Clin. Virol. 17:23-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum, L. C., et al. 1998. Fatal enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. J. Pediatr. 133:795-798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangia, A., et al. 2004. IL-10 haplotypes as possible predictors of spontaneous clearance of HCV infection. Cytokine 25:103-109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14698136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marby, D., G. R. Lockhart, R. Raymond, and J. G. Linakis. 2001. Anti-interleukin-6 antibodies attenuate inflammation in a rat meningitis model. Acad. Emerg. Med. 8:946-949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P. C., et al. 2001. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J. Virol. 75:7732-7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore, K. W., D. W. Malefyt, R. R. L. Coffman, and A. O'Garra. 2001. Interleukin-10 and the interleukin-10 receptor. Annu. Rev. Immunol. 19:683-765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11244051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata, N., et al. 2004. Differential localization of neurons susceptible to enterovirus 71 and poliovirus type 1 in the central nervous system of cynomolgus monkeys after intravenous inoculation. J. Gen. Virol. 85:2981-2989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15448361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naicker, D. D., et al. 2009. Interleukin-10 promoter polymorphisms influence HIV-1 susceptibility and primary HIV-1 pathogenesis. J. Infect. Dis. 200:448-452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3137931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19534595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathanson, N. 2008. The pathogenesis of poliomyelitis: what we don't know. Adv. Virus Res. 71:1-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18585526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong, K. C., et al. 2008. Pathologic characterization of a murine model of human enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol. 67:532-542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18520772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poffenberger, M. C., et al. 2009. Lack of IL-6 during Coxsackievirus Infection heightens the early immune response resulting in increased severity of chronic autoimmune myocarditis. PLoS One 4:e6207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2703827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19587788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Program for Monitoring Emerging Diseases. 2001. Enterovirus 71. International Society for Infectious Diseases, Brookline, MA. http://www.promedmail.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed, L. J., and H. Muench. 1938. A simple method of estimating fifty percent endpoints. Am. J. Hyg. 27:4931-4937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki, O., T. Karaki, and J. Imanishi. 1986. Protective effect of interferon on infections with hand, foot, and mouth disease virus in newborn mice. J. Infect. Dis. 153:498-502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3005425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, N. J., E. H. Lennette, and H. H. Ho. 1974. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J. Infect. Dis. 129:304-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegrist, C. A. 2001. Neonatal and early life vaccinology. Vaccine 19:3331-3346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11348697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S., C. L. Poh, and V. T. Chow. 2002. Complete sequence analyses of enterovirus 71 strains from fatal and non-fatal cases of the hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in Singapore (2000). Microbiol. Immunol. 46:801-808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12516778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starnes, H. F. J., et al. 1990. Anti-IL-6 monoclonal antibodies protect against lethal Escherichia coli infection and lethal tumor necrosis factor-challenge in mice. J. Immunol. 145:4185-4191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2124237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, E. L., et al. 2006. Specific detection of enterovirus 71 directly from clinical specimens using real-time RT-PCR hybridization probe assay. Mol. Cell Probes 20:135-140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16460910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, E. L., T. M. C. Tan, V. T. K. Chow, and C. L. Poh. 2007. Inhibition of enterovirus 71 in virus-infected mice by RNA interference. Mol. Ther. 15:1931-1938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17712333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka, T., et al. 2001. Overexpression of interleukin-6 aggravates viral myocarditis: impaired increase in tumor necrosis factor-alpha. J. Mol. Cell Cardiol. 33:1627-1635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11549342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Zaanen, H. C., et al. 1996. Endogenous interleukin 6 production in multiple myeloma patients treated with chimeric monoclonal anti-IL-6 antibodies indicates the existence of a positive feed-back loop. J. Clin. Invest. 98:1441-1448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC507571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8823310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., T. Ho, C. Shen, and C. C. Liu. 2008. Enterovirus 71, one virus and many stories. Pediatr. Neonatol. 49:113-115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19054915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., et al. 2006. Modulation of cytokine production by intravenous immunoglobulin in patients with enterovirus 71-associated brainstem encephalitis. J. Clin. Virol. 37:47-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16861032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., et al. 2003. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J. Infect. Dis. 188:564-570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., et al. 2007. Cerebrospinal fluid and cytokines in enterovirus 71 brain stem encephalitis and echovirus meningitis infections of varying severity. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. 13:677-682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17441979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., et al. 2004. A mouse-adapted enterovirus 71 strain causes neurological disease in mice after oral infection. J. Virol. 78:7916-7924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC446098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng, K. F., L. L. Chen, P. N. Huang, and S. R. Shih. 2010. Neural pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 infection. Microbes Infect. 12:505-510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20348010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 2009. Hand, foot and mouth disease: a rising menace in Asia. World Health Organization for the Western Pacific, Manila, Philippines. http://www.wpro.who.int/media_centre/news/news_20090713.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, J. J., J. R. Wang, C. C. Liu, H. B. Yang, and I. J. Su. 2000. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 in Taiwan 1998&#x2014;a comprehensive pathological, virological and molecular study on a case of fulminant encephalitis. J. Clin. Virol. 17:13-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>