<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23476790</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2090-3138</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2013</Volume><PubDate><Year>2013</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biotechnology research international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biotechnol Res Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Display of the Viral Epitopes on Lactococcus lactis: A Model for Food Grade Vaccine against EV71.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>431315</StartPage><MedlinePgn>431315</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">431315</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2013/431315</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this study, we have developed a system for display of antigens of Enterovirus type 71 (EV71) on the cell surface of L. lactis. The viral capsid protein (VP1) gene from a local viral isolate was utilized as the candidate vaccine for the development of oral live vaccines against EV71 using L. lactis as a carrier. We expressed fusion proteins in E. coli and purified fusion proteins were incubated with L. lactis. We confirmed that mice orally fed with L. lactis displaying these fusion proteins on its surface were able to mount an immune response against the epitopes of EV71. This is the first example of an EV71 antigen displayed on the surface of a food grade organism and opens a new perspective for alternative vaccine strategies against the EV71. We believe that the method of protein docking utilized in this study will allow for more flexible presentations of short peptides and proteins on the surface of L. lactis to be useful as a delivery vehicle.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varma</LastName><ForeName>Nadimpalli Ravi S</ForeName><Initials>NR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cellular and Molecular Imaging Laboratory, Department of Radiology, Henry Ford Hospital, Detroit, MI 48202, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toosa</LastName><ForeName>Haryanti</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Foo</LastName><ForeName>Hooi Ling</ForeName><Initials>HL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alitheen</LastName><ForeName>Noorjahan Banu Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>NB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nor Shamsudin</LastName><ForeName>Mariana</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arbab</LastName><ForeName>Ali S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yusoff</LastName><ForeName>Khatijah</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdul Rahim</LastName><ForeName>Raha</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 CA160216</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Biotechnol Res Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101552363</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2090-3146</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2012</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23476790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3586462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/431315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>King AMQ, Brown F, Christian P, Hovi T, Hyypia T. Picornaviridae. In: Van Regenmortel MHV, Fauquet CM, Bishop DHL, Calisher CH, editors. Virus Taxonomy. Seventh Report of the International Committee For the Taxonomy of Viruses. New York, NY, USA: Academic Press; 2000. pp. 657&#x2013;673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa MJ, Krishnan S, Tio PH, Perera D, Wong SC. Isolation of subgenus B adenovirus during a fatal outbreak of enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sibu, Sarawak. The Lancet. 1999;354(9183):987&#x2013;991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10501361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Huang YC, Lin TY. Fulminant neurogenic pulmonary oedema with hand, foot, and mouth disease. The Lancet. 1998;352(9125):367&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9717926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu K, Shimizu Y, Takeuchi Y, Ishiko H, Takada H. Outbreak of severe neurologic involvement associated with Enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatric Neurology. 1999;20:17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum LCS, Wong KT, Lam SK, et al. Fatal enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. Journal of Pediatrics. 1998;133(6):795&#x2013;798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P, Lindsay K, Perera D, Hung Ming Chan, Kwai Peng Chan, Cardosa MJ. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. Journal of Virology. 2001;75(16):7732&#x2013;7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liau MY, Chiang RJ, Li SY, et al. Development of vaccines against enterovirus 71. APEC Enteroviral Watch Program for Children, International Scientific Symposium Proceedings; 2000; pp. 81&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu CK, Chen CC, Chen CL, et al. Neutralizing antibody provided protection against enterovirus type 71 lethal challenge in neonatal mice. Journal of Biomedical Science. 2000;7(6):523&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11060501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamberlain L, Wells JM, Robinson K, Schofield K, Le Page RWF. Mucosal immunization with recombinant Lactococcus lactis . In: Pozzi G, Wells JM, editors. Gram-Positive Bacteria as Vaccine Vehicles For Mucosal Immunization. Austin, Tex, USA: Landes Bioscience; 1997. pp. 83&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin KQ, Hoshino Y, Toda Y, et al. Immunogenicity and protective efficacy of orally administered recombinant Lactococcus lactis expressing surface-bound HIV Env. Blood. 2003;102(1):223&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12649143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells JM, Wilson PW, Norton PM, Gasson MJ, Le Page RWF. Lactococcus lactis: high-level expression of tetanus toxin fragment C and protection against lethal challenge. Molecular Microbiology. 1993;8(6):1155&#x2013;1162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8361360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasson MJ. Plasmid complements of Streptococcus lactis NCDO 712 and other lactic streptococci after protoplast-induced curing. Journal of Bacteriology. 1983;154(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC217423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6403500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raha AR, Varma NRS, Yusoff K, Ross E, Foo HL. Cell surface display system for Lactococcus lactis: a novel development for oral vaccine. Applied Microbiology and Biotechnology. 2005;68(1):75&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15635459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laemmli UK. Cleavage of structural proteins during the assembly of the head of bacteriophage T4. Nature. 1970;227(5259):680&#x2013;685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5432063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosma T, Kanninga R, Neef J, et al. Novel surface display system for proteins on non-genetically modified gram-positive bacteria. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2006;72(1):880&#x2013;889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1352190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16391130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roosmalen ML, Kanninga R, Khattabi ME, et al. Mucosal vaccine delivery of antigens tightly bound to an adjuvant particle made from food-grade bacteria. Methods. 2006;38:144&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16414272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steidler L, Hans W, Schotte L, et al. Treatment of murine colitis by Lactococcus lactis secreting interleukin-10. Science. 2000;289(5483):1352&#x2013;1355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10958782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dieye Y, Hoekman AJW, Clier F, Juillard V, Boot HJ, Piard JC. Ability of Lactococcus lactis to export viral capsid antigens: a crucial step for development of live vaccines. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2003;69(12):7281&#x2013;7288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC309906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14660377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramasamy R, Yasawardena S, Zomer A, Venema G, Kok J, Leenhouts K. Immunogenicity of a malaria parasite antigen displayed by Lactococcus lactis in oral immunisations. Vaccine. 2006;24(18):3900&#x2013;3908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7115539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16545511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng NW, Ya CL, Cathy F, Nan SL, Shih RS, Mei SH. Protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by passive immunization with subunit VP1 vaccines and inactivated virus. Vaccine. 2001;20(5-6):895&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page GS, Mosser AG, Hogle JM, Filman DJ, Rueckert RR, Chow M. Three-dimensional structure of poliovirus serotype 1 neutralizing determinants. Journal of Virology. 1988;62(5):1781&#x2013;1794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC253228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2451757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith TJ, Chase ES, Schmidt TJ, Olson NH, Baker TS. Neutralizing antibody to human rhinovirus 14 penetrates the receptor- binding canyon. Nature. 1996;383(6598):350&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4167671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8848050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hovi T, Roivainen M. Peptide antisera targeted to a conserved sequence in poliovirus capsid protein VP1 cross-react widely with members of the genus Enterovirus . Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 1993;31(5):1083&#x2013;1087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC262883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8388885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roivainen M, Piirainen L, Rysa T, Narvanen A, Hovi T. An immunodominant N-terminal region of VP1 protein of poliovirion that is buried in crystal structure can be exposed in solution. Virology. 1993;195(2):762&#x2013;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8393243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buist G. AcmA of Lactococcus lactis, a cell-binding major autolysin [Ph.D. thesis] Groninge, The Netherlands: University of Groningen; 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leenhouts KJ, Buist G, Kok J. Anchoring of proteins to lactic acid bacteria. Antonie van Leeuwenhoek. 1999;76(1&#x2013;4):367&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10532392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steen A, Buist G, Leenhouts KJ, et al. Cell wall attachment of a widely distributed peptidoglycan binding domain is hindered by cell wall constituents. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 2003;278(26):23874&#x2013;23881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12684515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baneyx F. Recombinant protein expression in Escherichia coli . Current Opinion in Biotechnology. 1999;10(5):411&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10508629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab H. Principles of genetic engineering for Escherichia coli . In: Rehm HJ, Reed G, Puhler A, Stadler P, editors. Biotechnology: Genetic Fundamentals and Genetic Engineering. 2nd edition. Weinheim, Germany: VCH Verlagsgesellschaft MbH; 1993. pp. 375&#x2013;419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker RI. New strategies for using mucosal vaccination to achieve more effective immunization. Vaccine. 1994;12(5):387&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8023545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora AL, Tam JP. Controlled lipidation and encapsulation of peptides as a useful approach to mucosal immunizations. Journal of Immunology. 1998;161(7):3616&#x2013;3623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9759884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>