<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31785100</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1348-0421</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Microbiology and immunology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Microbiol Immunol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Virucidal activity and the antiviral mechanism of acidic polysaccharides against Enterovirus 71 infection in vitro.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>189</StartPage><EndPage>201</EndPage><MedlinePgn>189-201</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1348-0421.12763</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is the predominant pathogen for severe hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) in children younger than 5 years, and currently no effective drugs are available for EV71. Thus, there is an urgent need to develop new drugs for the control of EV71 infection. In this study, LJ04 was extracted from Laminaria japonica using diethylaminoethyl cellulose-52 with 0.4&#x2009;mol/l NaCl as the eluent, and its virucidal activity was evaluated based on its cytopathic effects on a microplate. LJ04 is composed of fucose, galactose, and mannose and mainly showed good virucidal activity against EV71. The antiviral mechanisms of LJ04 were the direct inactivation of the virus, the blockage of virus binding, disruptions to viral entry, and weak inhibitory activity against the nonstructural protein 3C. The two most important findings from this study were that LJ04 inhibited EV71 proliferation in HM1900 cells, which are a human microglia cell line, and that LJ04 can directly inactivate EV71 within 2&#x2009;hr at 37&#xb0;C. This study demonstrates for the first time the ability of a polysaccharide from L. japonica to inhibit viral and 3C activity; importantly, the inhibition of 3C might have a minor effect on the antiviral effect of LJ04. Consequently, our results identify LJ04 as a potential drug candidate for the control of severe EV71 infection in clinical settings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 The Societies and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhihui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8412-5235</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Central Lab, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Laboratory, Liaocheng People's Hospital of Taishan Medical University, Liaocheng, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Central Lab, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaowen</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Central Lab, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Laicheng</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Central Lab, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xian</LastName><ForeName>Qingjie</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Laboratory, Liaocheng People's Hospital of Taishan Medical University, Liaocheng, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Zhaoxi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Laboratory, Liaocheng People's Hospital of Taishan Medical University, Liaocheng, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Shuntao</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Laboratory, Liaocheng People's Hospital of Taishan Medical University, Liaocheng, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Yinguang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Laboratory, Liaocheng People's Hospital of Taishan Medical University, Liaocheng, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yueran</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Central Lab, Shandong Provincial Hospital Affiliated to Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ZR201702160291</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Shandong Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>81000720</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Microbiol Immunol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7703966</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0385-5600</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000998">Antiviral Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010936">Plant Extracts</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011134">Polysaccharides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017361">Viral Nonstructural Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014764">Viral Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000998" MajorTopicYN="N">Antiviral Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007795" MajorTopicYN="Y">Laminaria</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010936" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Extracts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011134" MajorTopicYN="N">Polysaccharides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017361" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Nonstructural Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014764" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053585" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Attachment</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053586" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Internalization</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014779" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Replication</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">3C protease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acidic polysaccharides</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foot and mouth disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">virucidal activity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31785100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1348-0421.12763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ng Q, He F, Kwang J. Recent progress towards novel EV71 anti-therapeutics and vaccines. Viruses. 2015;7:6441-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P, Stratov I, Nagarajan L, Davis S. Neurological manifestations of Enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin Infect Dis. 2001;32:236-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta K, Aoki Y, Suto A, et al. Cross-antigenicity among EV71 strains from different genogroups isolated in Yamagata, Japan, between 1990 and 2007. Vaccine. 2009;27:3153-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DS, Lee YI, Ahn JB, et al. Massive pulmonary hemorrhage in Enterovirus 71-infected hand, foot, and mouth disease. Korean J Pediatr. 2015;58:112-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan LG, Parashar UD, Lye MS, et al. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. For the Outbreak Study Group. Clin Infect Dis. 2000;31:678-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah VA, Chong CY, Chan KP, Ng W, Ling AE. Clinical characteristics of an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore. Ann Acad Med Singapore. 2003;32:381-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van TuP, Thao NTT, Perera D, et al. Epidemiologic and virologic investigation of hand, foot, and mouth disease, southern Vietnam, 2005. Emerg Infect Dis. 2007;13:1733-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo ST, Chiang PS, Chung WY, et al. Reemergence of Enterovirus 71 epidemic in northern Taiwan, 2012. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0116322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan ZK, Jin H, Li JX, et al. Disease burden of Enterovirus 71 in rural central China: a community-based survey. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2015;11:2400-2405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, Cardosa MJ, McMinn P, Ooi MH. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of Enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect Dis. 2010;10:778-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum LC, Wong KT, Lam SK, Chua KB, Goh AY. Neurogenic pulmonary oedema and Enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. Lancet. 1998;352:1391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Huang LM, Gau SS, et al. Neurodevelopment and cognition in children after Enterovirus 71 infection. N Engl J Med. 2007;356:1226-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao C, Hu K, Xi C, Li N, Wei Y. Transcriptomic analysis of cells in response to EV71 infection and 2Apro as a trigger for apoptosis via TXNIP gene. Genes Genomics. 2019;41:343-357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Qiao Q, Hao SB, et al. Nonstructural protein 2A modulates replication and virulence of Enterovirus 71. Virus Res. 2018;244:262-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang L, Xu M, Yin Z. Antiviral drug discovery for the treatment of Enterovirus 71 infections. Antiviral Res. 2013;97:183-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios G, Oberste MS. Enteroviruses as agents of emerging infectious diseases. J Neurovirol. 2005;11:424-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Liu L, Mo Z, et al. An inactivated Enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:829-37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Meng FY, Li JX, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant Enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2013;381:2024-32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Z, Wang J. EV71 vaccine, an invaluable gift for children. Clin Transl Immunology. 2014;3:e28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harden EA, Falshaw R, Carnachan SM, Kern ER, Prichard MN. Virucidal activity of polysaccharide extracts from four algal species against herpes simplex virus. Antiviral Res. 2009;83:282-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph MM, Aravind SR, George SK, Raveendran Pillai K, Mini S, Sreelekha TT. Anticancer activity of galactoxyloglucan polysaccharide-conjugated doxorubicin nanoparticles: mechanistic insights and interactome analysis. Eur J Pharm Biopharm. 2015;93:183-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Q, Li J, Yan J, et al. Lycium barbarum polysaccharides ameliorates renal injury and inflammatory reaction in alloxan-induced diabetic nephropathy rabbits. Life Sci. 2016;157:82-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schepetkin IA, Quinn MT. Botanical polysaccharides: macrophage immunomodulation and therapeutic potential. Int Immunopharmacol. 2006;6:317-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue Y, Li Z, Li P, et al. Antiviral activity of a polysaccharide from Laminaria japonica against Enterovirus 71. Biomed Pharmacother. 2017;96:256-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao C, Xi C, Hu K, et al. Inhibition of Enterovirus 71 replication and viral 3C protease by quercetin. Virol J. 201815:116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Z, Yang L, Ding G, et al. Sophocarpine against Enterovirus 71 in vitro. Exp Ther Med. 2017;14:3792-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li ZH, Yue YY, Li P, et al. MA104 Cell line presents characteristics suitable for Enterovirus A71 isolation and proliferation. Microbiol Immunol. 2015;59:477-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Lu F, Wei X, Zhao R. Fucoidan: structure and bioactivity. Molecules. 2008;13:1671-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin JO, Zhang W, Du JY, Wong KW, Oda T, Yu Q. Fucoidan can function as an adjuvant in vivo to enhance dendritic cell maturation and function and promote antigen-specific T cell immune responses. PLoS One. 2014;9:e99396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu F, Zhao X, Hu S, et al. Amphotericin B inhibits Enterovirus 71 replication by impeding viral entry. Sci Rep. 2016;6:33150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z, Ding Y, Cao L, Ding G, Wang Z, Xiao W. Isochlorogenic acid C prevents Enterovirus 71 infection via modulating redox homeostasis of glutathione. Sci Rep. 2017;7:16278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakata K, Takeda S, Tanaka A, Kwang J, Komano J. Antiviral activity of acid beta-glucosidase 1 on Enterovirus 71, a causative agent of hand, foot and mouth disease. J Gen Virol. 2017;98:643-51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Wang W, Hao C, et al. Antiviral activity against Enterovirus 71 of sulfated rhamnan isolated from the green alga Monostroma latissimum. Carbohydr Polym. 2018;200:43-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren P, Zou G, Bailly B, et al. The approved pediatric drug suramin identified as a clinical candidate for the treatment of EV71 infection-suramin inhibits EV71 infection in vitro and in vivo. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2014;3:e62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang JS, Wang KC, Chiang LC. Sheng-Ma-Ge-Gen-Tang inhibited Enterovirus 71 infection in human foreskin fibroblast cell line. J Ethnopharmacol. 2008;119:104-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zengjun Jin, Lixin Yang, Guotao Ding, et al. Sophocarpine against Enterovirus 71 in vitro. Exp Ther Med. 2017;14:3792-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceole LF, Companhoni MVP, Sanches Lopes SM, et al. Anti-herpes activity of polysaccharide fractions from Stevia rebaudiana leaves. Nat Prod Res. 2018;22:1-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z, Yu C, Wang W, et al. Aloe polysaccharides inhibit influenza A virus infection-A promising natural anti-flu drug. Front Microbiol. 2018;9:2338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao YG, Hao Y, Li ZH, Liu ST, Wang, LX. Antiviral activity of polysaccharide extract from Laminaria japonica against respiratory syncytial virus. Biomed Pharmacother. 2016;84:1705-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourianfar HR, Poh CL, Fecondo J, Grollo L. In vitro evaluation of the antiviral activity of heparan sulfate mimetic compounds against Enterovirus 71. Virus Res. 2012;169:22-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C, Wei K, Liu L, et al. Taishan Pinus massoniana pollen polysaccharide inhibits subgroup J avian leucosis virus infection by directly blocking virus infection and improving immunity. Sci Rep. 2017;7:44353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Tao J, Yang X, et al. Antiviral effects of two Ganoderma lucidum triterpenoids against Enterovirus 71 infection. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2014;449:307-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Liu X, Liu H, et al. Astragalus polysaccharides inhibit avian infectious bronchitis virus infection by regulating viral replication. Microb Pathog. 2018;114:124-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen D, Tian X, Zou X, et al. Harmine, a small molecule derived from natural sources, inhibits Enterovirus 71 replication by targeting NF-&#x3ba;B pathway. Int Immunopharmacol. 2018;60:111-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HQ, Hu J, Yan HY, Wu S, Li YH. Corydaline inhibits Enterovirus 71 replication by regulating COX-2 expression. J Asian Nat Prod Res. 2017;19:1124-33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J, Niu Y, Wang C, et al. Discovery of 3-benzyl-1,3-benzoxazine-2,4-dione analogues as allosteric mitogen-activated kinase kinase (MEK) inhibitors and anti-Enterovirus 71 (EV71) agents. Bioorg Med Chem. 2016;24:3472-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Cao L, Zhai Y, et al. Inhibition of Enterovirus 71 replication by an &#x3b1;-hydroxy-nitrile derivative NK-1.9k. Antiviral Res. 2017;141:91-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai Y, Ma Y, Ma F, et al. Structure-activity relationship study of peptidomimetic aldehydes as Enterovirus 71 3C protease inhibitors. Eur J Med Chem. 2016;124:559-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao M, Duan H, Liu J, et al. The multi-targeted kinase inhibitor sorafenib inhibits Enterovirus 71 replication by regulating IRES-dependent translation of viral proteins. Antiviral Res. 2014;106:80-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian GY, Li ST, Song ML, Zheng MS, Li W. Synthesis of Achyranthes bidentata polysaccharide sulfate and its antivirus activity. Yao Xue Xue Bao. 1995;30:107-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muschin T, Budragchaa D, Kanamoto T, et al. Chemically sulfated natural galactomannans with specific antiviral and anticoagulant activities. Int J Biol Macromol. 2016;89:415-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma HY, Lu CY, Tsao KC, et al. Association of EV71 3C polymorphisms with clinical severity. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2018;51:608-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B, Yue Y, Zhang Y, et al. A novel Enterovirus 71 (EV71) virulence determinant: the 69th residue of 3C protease modulates pathogenicity. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2017;7:26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ventoso I, Carrasco L. A poliovirus 2A(pro) mutant unable to cleave 3CD shows inefficient viral protein synthesis and transactivation defects. J Virol. 1995;69:6280-88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z, Ding Y, Ke Z, et al. Luteoloside acts as 3C protease inhibitor of Enterovirus 71 in vitro. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0148693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Cao L, Zhai Y, Yin Z, Sun Y, Shang L. Structure of the Enterovirus 71 3C protease in complex with NK-1.8k and indications for the development of antienterovirus protease inhibitor. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2017;61(7):e00298-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su YS, Tsai AH, Ho YF, Huang SY, Liu YC, Hwang LH. Stimulation of the Internal Ribosome Entry Site (IRES)-dependent translation of Enterovirus 71 by DDX3X RNA helicase and viral 2A and 3C proteases. Front Microbiol. 2018;9:1324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belsham GJ, McInerney GM, Ross-Smith N. Foot-and-mouth disease virus 3C protease induces cleavage of translation initiation factors eIF4A and eIF4G within infected cells. J Virol. 2000;74:272-80.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>