<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31898369</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4644</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>121</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cellular biochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cell Biochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>EV71 infection induces cell apoptosis through ROS generation and SIRT1 activation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4321</StartPage><EndPage>4331</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4321-4331</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcb.29628</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Several studies have substantiated the correlation between reactive oxygen species (ROS) and Sirtuin 1 (SIRT1). Normally, enterovirus 71 (EV71) is associated with severe clinical manifestations and death. However, the effect of EV71 on the induction of cellular death and the interplay between ROS/SIRT1 in cell death has not been confirmed yet. In the current study, an increase in the number of apoptotic cells was observed as soon as the EV71 infection was initiated in cells and mice. Furthermore, EV71 infection also promoted a rise in the levels of three commonly known proinflammatory cytokines, interleukin 1&#x3b2; (IL-1&#x3b2;), IL-6, and tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1;. During EV71-induced apoptosis in the different cell lines, ROS generation and SIRT1 downregulation were observed. Further investigations showed that the administration of ROS inhibitor, N-acetyl- l-cysteine (NAC), reduced the level of apoptosis and inflammation, reduced EV71 propagation, and increased SIRT1 expression in EV71-infected cells. In addition, combined administration of NAC and EX527 (SIRT1 inhibitor) restored apoptosis in the EV71-infected cells, which was reduced due to NAC. This data demonstrated that ROS generation is positively associated with EV71-induced apoptosis and inflammation, while this effect could be reversed by SIRT1 inhibition. Collectively, we have shown that EV71 induces apoptosis and inflammation by promoting ROS generation and reducing SIRT1 expression.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Hongyan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0158-3979</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Department, China-Japan Union Hospital, Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bai</LastName><ForeName>Zhenzi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3173-0463</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Department, China-Japan Union Hospital, Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Chenghua</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Department, China-Japan Union Hospital, Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheng</LastName><ForeName>Chuanlun</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Department, China-Japan Union Hospital, Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Xiaonan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1722-357X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Department, China-Japan Union Hospital, Jilin University, Changchun, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cell Biochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8205768</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0730-2312</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D036022">Capsid Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016207">Cytokines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012333">RNA, Messenger</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017382">Reactive Oxygen Species</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.5.1.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C447939">SIRT1 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.5.1.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C470545">Sirt1 protein, mouse</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.5.1.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D056564">Sirtuin 1</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017209" MajorTopicYN="Y">Apoptosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036022" MajorTopicYN="N">Capsid Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002522" MajorTopicYN="N">Chlorocebus aethiops</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016207" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019073" MajorTopicYN="N">HT29 Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006367" MajorTopicYN="N">HeLa Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008813" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred ICR</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012333" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Messenger</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017382" MajorTopicYN="N">Reactive Oxygen Species</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="Y">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056564" MajorTopicYN="N">Sirtuin 1</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000074084" MajorTopicYN="N">THP-1 Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014709" MajorTopicYN="N">Vero Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EV71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ROS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SIRT1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apoptosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31898369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.29628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Lui YLE, Lin Z, Lee JJ, Chow VTK, Poh CL, Tan EL. Beta-actin variant is necessary for Enterovirus 71 replication. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2013;433:607-610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. Recent advances in the molecular epidemiology and control of human enterovirus 71 infection. Curr Opin Virol. 2012;2:199-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel KP, Bergelson JM. Receptors identified for hand, foot and mouth virus. Nat Med. 2009;15:728-729.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho BC, Yu SL, Chen JJW, et al. Enterovirus-induced miR-141 contributes to shutoff of host protein translation by targeting the translation initiation factor eIF4E. Cell Host Microbe. 2011;9:58-69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang HI, Weng KF, Shih SR. Viral and host factors that contribute to pathogenicity of enterovirus 71. Future Microbiol. 2012;7:467-479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong SSY, Yip CCY, Lau SKP, Yuen KY. Human enterovirus 71 and hand, foot and mouth disease. Epidemiol Infect. 2010;138:1071-1089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatproedprai S, Tempark T, Wanlapakorn N, Puenpa J, Wananukul S, Poovorawan Y. Unusual skin manifestation of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with coxsackievirus A6: cases report. SpringerPlus. 2015;4:362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Zhang W, Zhang Y, et al. Clinical features of severe cases of hand, foot and mouth disease with EV71 virus infection in China. Arch Med Sci. 2014;10:510-516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Ho MS, Lin KH, et al. Genetic analysis of enterovirus 71 isolated from fatal and non-fatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease during an epidemic in Taiwan, 1998. Virus Res. 2000;68:127-136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Hsia SH, Huang YC, Wu CT, Chang LY. Proinflammatory cytokine reactions in enterovirus 71 infections of the central nervous system. Clin Infect Dis. 2003;36:269-274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebasti&#xe1;n C, Satterstrom FK, Haigis MC, Mostoslavsky R. From sirtuin biology to human diseases: an update. J Biol Chem. 2012;287:42444-42452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon H-S, Brent MM, Getachew R, et al. Human immunodeficiency virus type 1 Tat protein inhibits the SIRT1 deacetylase and induces T cell hyperactivation. Cell Host Microbe. 2008;3:158-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srisuttee R, Koh SS, Kim SJ, et al. Hepatitis B virus X (HBX) protein upregulates &#x3b2;-catenin in a human hepatic cell line by sequestering SIRT1 deacetylase. Oncol Rep. 2012;28:276-282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu JW, Sun LJ, Liu W, Zhao YH, Kang P, Yan BZ. Hepatitis C virus core protein induces hepatic metabolism disorders through down-regulation of the SIRT1-AMPK signaling pathway. Int J Infect Dis. 2013;17:e539-e545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng ML, Weng SF, Kuo CH, Ho HY. Enterovirus 71 induces mitochondrial reactive oxygen species generation that is required for efficient replication. PLoS One. 2014;9:e113234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Lin Z, Xu T, et al. Delivery of VP1 siRNA to inhibit the EV71 virus using functionalized silver nanoparticles through ROS-mediated signaling pathways. RSC Adv. 2017;7:1453-1463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chae HD, Broxmeyer HE. SIRT1 deficiency downregulates PTEN/JNK/FOXO1 pathway to block reactive oxygen species-induced apoptosis in mouse embryonic stem cells. Stem Cells Dev. 2010;20:1277-1285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng R, Chen Y, Zhao S, Cui G. Autophagy counteracts apoptosis in human multiple myeloma cells exposed to oridonin in vitro via regulating intracellular ROS and SIRT1. Acta Pharmacol Sin. 2012;33:91-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa K, Wakino S, Yoshioka K, et al. Sirt1 protects against oxidative stress-induced renal tubular cell apoptosis by the bidirectional regulation of catalase expression. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2008;372:51-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torchinsky MB, Garaude J, Blander JM. Infection and apoptosis as a combined inflammatory trigger. Curr Opin Immunol. 2010;22:55-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lal SK, Kumar P, Yeo WM, Kar-Roy A, Chow VTK. The VP1 protein of human enterovirus 71 self-associates via an interaction domain spanning amino acids 66-297. J Med Virol. 2006;78:582-590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho HY, Cheng ML, Weng SF, et al. Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency enhances enterovirus 71 infection. J Gen Virol. 2008;89:2080-2089.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand SK, Tikoo SK. Viruses as modulators of mitochondrial functions. Adv Virol. 2013;2013:738794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahmani Z, Huh KW, Lasher R, Siddiqui A. Hepatitis B virus X protein colocalizes to mitochondria with a human voltage-dependent anion channel, HVDAC3, and alters its transmembrane potential. J Virol. 2000;74:2840-2846.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang SM, Sun DC, Lou S, et al. HBx protein of hepatitis B virus (HBV) can form complex with mitochondrial HSP60 and HSP70. Arch Virol. 2005;150:1579-1590.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koike K. Hepatitis C virus contributes to hepatocarcinogenesis by modulating metabolic and intracellular signaling pathways. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2007;22:S108-S111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriya K, Nakagawa K, Santa T, et al. Oxidative stress in the absence of inflammation in a mouse model for hepatitis C virus-associated hepatocarcinogenesis. Cancer Res. 2001;61:4365-4370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwer B, Ren S, Pietschmann T, et al. Targeting of hepatitis C virus core protein to mitochondria through a novel C-terminal localization motif. J Virol. 2004;78:7958-7968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs JS, Malide D, Hornung F, Bennink JR, Yewdell JW. The influenza A virus PB1-F2 protein targets the inner mitochondrial membrane via a predicted basic amphipathic helix that disrupts mitochondrial function. J Virol. 2003;77:7214-7224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada H, Chounan R, Higashi Y, Kurihara N, Kido H. Mitochondrial targeting sequence of the influenza A virus PB1-F2 protein and its function in mitochondria. FEBS Lett. 2004;578:331-336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caito S, Hwang J, Chung S, Yao H, Sundar IK, Rahman I. PARP-1 inhibition does not restore oxidant-mediated reduction in SIRT1 activity. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2010;392:264-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajendrasozhan S, Yang SR, Kinnula VL, Rahman I. SIRT1, an antiinflammatory and antiaging protein, is decreased in lungs of patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2008;177:861-870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang SR, Wright J, Bauter M, Seweryniak K, Kode A, Rahman I. Sirtuin regulates cigarette smoke-induced proinflammatory mediator release via RelA/p65 NF-&#x3ba;B in macrophages in vitro and in rat lungs in vivo: implications for chronic inflammation and aging. Am J Physiol. 2007;292:L567-L576.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>