<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">26368058</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Seroprevalence of Enterovirus 71 Antibody Among Children in China: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1399</StartPage><EndPage>1406</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1399-406</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000000900</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Hand, foot and mouth disease mostly affects children and carries a substantial disease burden in the Western Pacific region. Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is the most virulent causative agent, and a monovalent vaccine against EV71 will soon become commercially available in China. An improved understanding of EV71 epidemiology would aid policy decisions regarding childhood immunization in China. We aimed to assess and summarize information to date from individual seroepidemiologic studies of EV71 in mainland China to determine patterns of the age-specific risk of infection.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies of children aged 0-15 years, published in English or Chinese, was conducted. Estimates of seroprevalence were summarized by age group. A mixed-effects regression model was used to explore factors covarying with EV71 seroprevalence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We identified 42 published studies, 15 in English. We found that an average of 78% of neonates was seropositive to EV71 infection, but such maternally conferred immunity almost completely waned by 5 months. The seroprevalence of EV71 antibody increased directly with age among preschool children, from 26% (95% confidence interval: 18%-33%) at 1 year to 70% (95% confidence interval: 62%-78%) at 5 years. Age of subjects, sample size, sampling year, sampling method, geographic latitude and publication language were associated with variations of individual seroprevalence estimates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Seroprevalence of EV71 antibody gradually declined during the first 5 months in infants. Infection of EV71 was most likely to occur between 2 and 4 years. Our findings may be useful in informing population-based EV71 vaccination strategies.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Bingyi</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the *School of Public Health, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, China; and &#x2020;Division of Infectious Disease, Key Laboratory of Surveillance and Early-Warning on Infectious Disease, Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Joseph T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lau</LastName><ForeName>Eric H Y</ForeName><Initials>EH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leung</LastName><ForeName>Gabriel M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Hongjie</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cowling</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>U54 GM088558</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N">China</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016036" MajorTopicYN="N">Seroepidemiologic Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>CONFLICTS OF INTEREST</b>. The authors report no other potential conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26368058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS722009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4718881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000000900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lee MS, Lin TY, Chiang PS, et al. An investigation of epidemic enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 2008: clinical, virologic, and serologic features. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2010;29:1030&#x2013;1034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20543760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan LG, Parashar UD, Lye MS, et al. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in sarawak, malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. For the Outbreak Study Group. Clin Infect Dis. 2000;31:678&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu H, Utama A, Yoshii K, et al. Enterovirus 71 from fatal and nonfatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease epidemics in Malaysia, Japan and Taiwan in 1997&#x2013;1998. Jpn J Infect Dis. 1999;52:12&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10808253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Yeo A, Phoon MC, et al. The largest outbreak of hand; foot and mouth disease in Singapore in 2008: the role of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A strains. Int J Infect Dis. 2010;14:e1076&#x2013;e1081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20952237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishimaru Y, Nakano S, Yamaoka K, Takami S. Outbreaks of hand, foot, and mouth disease by enterovirus 71. High incidence of complication disorders of central nervous system. Arch Dis Child. 1980;55:583&#x2013;588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1627055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6254449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, Cardosa MJ, McMinn P, Ooi MH. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect Dis. 2010;10:778&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing W, Liao Q, Viboud C, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China, 2008&#x2013;12: an epidemiological study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2014;14:308&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24485991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa MJ, Krishnan S, Tio PH, Perera D, Wong SC. Isolation of subgenus B adenovirus during a fatal outbreak of enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sibu, Sarawak. Lancet. 1999;354:987&#x2013;991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10501361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsueh C, Jung SM, Shih SR, et al. Acute encephalomyelitis during an outbreak of enterovirus type 71 infection in Taiwan: report of an autopsy case with pathologic, immunofluorescence, and molecular studies. Mod Pathol. 2000;13:1200&#x2013;1205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11106077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Health and Family Planning Commission of the PRC. National notifiable disease situation in 2014.  [Accessed May 9 2015]; Available at:  http://www.nhfpc.gov.cn.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Yin H, An Z, Feng Z. Considerations for developing an immunization strategy with enterovirus 71 vaccine. Vaccine. 2015;33:1107&#x2013;1112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25444807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong P, Liu CC, Chow YH, Chou AH, Klein M. Review of enterovirus 71 vaccines. Clin Infect Dis. 2015;60:797&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25352588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Meng FY, Li JX, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2013;381:2024&#x2013;2032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23726161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Liu L, Mo Z, et al. An inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:829&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F, Xu W, Xia J, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in China. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang XY, Liu GH, Chen HM, et al. Seroepidemiological study of enterovirus 71 in Henan province. Zhongguo Bing Yuan Sheng Wu Xue Za Zhi. 2010;5:617&#x2013;639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu MH. Fudan University. Shanghai: Fudan University; 2012. Pathogen composition causing hand foot and mouth disease (HFMD) and seroepidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection in Shanghai, China. Vol. Master.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson EB. Probable inference, the law of succession, and statistical inference. Journal of the American Statistical Association. 1927;22:209&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newcombe RG. Two-sided confidence intervals for the single proportion: comparison of seven methods. Stat Med. 1998;17:857&#x2013;872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9595616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamseer L, Moher D, Clarke M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015: elaboration and explanation. BMJ. 2015;349:g7647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25555855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egger M, Smith GD. Bias in location and selection of studies. BMJ. 1998;316:61&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2665334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9451274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV, Vevea JL. Fixed-and random-effects models in meta-analysis. Psychological methods. 1998;3:486&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cochran WG. The combination of estimates from different experiments. Biometrics. 1954;10:101&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327:557&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer W. Conducting meta-analyses in R with the metafor package. Journal of Statistical Software. 2010;36:1&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Liang ZL, Meng FY, et al. Retrospective study of the incidence of HFMD and seroepidemiology of antibodies against EV71 and CoxA16 in prenatal women and their infants. PLoS One. 2012;7:e37206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3360679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22662137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo XB, Zhu SL, Wang DY. Seroepidemiology investigation of HEV71 in healthy children of 1&#x2013;6 years old in three counties of China in 2005. Zhongguo Yi Miao He Mian Yi. 2009;15:141&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20077660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu WG, Wang YL. Seroepidemiological study of Enterovirus 71 infection in children aged 1 through 6 years in Changzhou in 2006. Shi Yong Yu Fang Yi Xue. 2013;20:179&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao QY, Yang ZW, Yu X, et al. Epidemic tendency of neutralizing antibody against Enterovirus 71 and Coxsackievirus A 16 in infants in rural area of Kaifeng City, Henan Province, China. Zhongguo Sheng Wu Zhi Pin Xue Za Zhi. 2009;22:911&#x2013;922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou SL, Li LL, He YQ. Serological epidemiology investigation of Enterovirus type 71 infection in Shenzhen. Re Dai Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2007;7:66&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng HL, Ma SW, Mi B, et al. Survey on Enterovirus subclinical infection of healthy children in Xi'an. Yi Xue Lin Chuang Yan Jiu. 2012;29:204&#x2013;208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao QY, Liao XY, Yu X, et al. Dynamic change of mother-source neutralizing antibodies against enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 in infants. Chin Med J (Engl) 2010;123:1679&#x2013;1684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20819628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni H, Yi B, Yin J, et al. Epidemiological and etiological characteristics of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Ningbo, China, 2008&#x2013;2011. J Clin Virol. 2012;54:342&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22652041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Liang ZL, Li XL, et al. Immunogenicity and safety of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy Chinese children and infants: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 2 clinical trial. Lancet. 2013;381:1037&#x2013;1045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23352749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Wang M, Chang H, et al. Prevalence of antibodies against enterovirus 71 in children from Lu'an City in Central China. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2011;64:528&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22116336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Wang JZ, Li XL, et al. Reactogenicity and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in Chinese healthy children and infants. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2012;31:1158&#x2013;1165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22926209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, Zhu S, Guo X, et al. Retrospective seroepidemiology indicated that human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 circulated wildly in central and southern China before large-scale outbreaks from 2008. Virol J. 2010;7:300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2989968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21050463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YP, Liang ZL, Gao Q, et al. Safety and immunogenicity of a novel human Enterovirus 71 (EV71) vaccine: a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, Phase I clinical trial. Vaccine. 2012;30:3295&#x2013;3303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22426327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng M, El Khatib NF, Tu S, et al. Seroepidemiology of Enterovirus 71 infection prior to the 2011 season in children in Shanghai. J Clin Virol. 2012;53:285&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22265829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Yi L, Su J, et al. Seroepidemiology of human enterovirus71 and coxsackievirusA16 among children in Guangdong province, China. BMC Infect Dis. 2013;13:322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3717138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23855481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji H, Li L, Liu Y, et al. Seroepidemiology of human enterovirus71 and coxsackievirusA16 in Jiangsu province, China. Virol J. 2012;9:248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3545860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23102275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Yi L, Su J, et al. Seroprevalence of human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 in Guangdong, China, in pre- and post-2010 HFMD epidemic period. PLoS One. 2013;8:e80515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3850913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24324604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai YS, Yang AN, Zhang J, Sun WW, Wang J, Guo AL. Survey on prevalence of EV71 and ECHO infection among population received physical examination in Yinchuan City. Ningxia Yi Ke Da Xue Xue Bao. 2012;34:453&#x2013;455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Q, Zhu FC, Li L, Li DH, Liu YM. Serum epidemiology survey of HEV 71 among children in Ganyu County. Jiangsu Yu Fang Yi Xue. 2011;22:4&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou HB, Zhou HT, Zeng HS, Chen RL. IgG antibody levels in healthy people of Futian District of Shenzhen City. Zhi Ye Yu Jian Kang. 2012;28:3107&#x2013;3108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu FR, Liu Q, Li G, Li JM, Ye WX, Ye BL. Seroepidemiology study on EV71 infection among healthy children in Longgang District, Shenzhen City. Hua Nan Yu Fang Yi Xue. 2013;39:40&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao YH, Chen QJ, Liao LH, Cao CY, Yang XH, Luo ZF. Seroepidemiology study on Enterovirus 71 in Longyan City. Hai Xia Yu Fang Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2012;18:28&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang DX, Yang F, Wang B, et al. Subclinical infection of hand-foot-mouth disease in Shenzhen City. Zhongguo Re Dai Yi Xue. 2011;11:1332&#x2013;1333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W, Ju LW, Jiang LF, Shen HG, Wang QL, Jiang QW. Serum levels of antibody against enterovirus 71 in healthy children at Shanghai in 2011. Zhonghua Chuan Ran Bing Za Zhi. 2013;31:650&#x2013;653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JM, Xu YJ, Wang QY. Investigation of enterovirus 71 antibody levels among children in the Longgang District, City of Shenzhen. Zhongguo Bing Yuan Sheng Wu Xue Za Zhi. 2012;7:924&#x2013;926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JM, Zhang Y, Gao L, et al. Seroepidemiology investigation of neutralizing antibody against enterovirus 71 among healthy people in Tianjin. Zhonghua Liu Xing Bing Xue Za Zhi. 2011;32:568&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21781473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang XH, Yan YS. Cause of HFMD epidemic caused by HEV71 in Fujian Province: seroepidemiology and molecular epidemiology of HEV71. 10th Conference on Epidemiology in Eastern China; Hefei, China.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y, Gong T, Shi Y, et al. Seroepidemiology investigation on HEV71 in the population in Nanchang in early 2010. Xian Dai Yu Fang Yi Xue. 2013;40:7&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai MS, Ren Y. Investigation on HFMD recessive infection in healthy population in some community of Shenzhen in 2012. Zhongguo Wei Sheng Jian Yan. 2013;23:2355&#x2013;2357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao SC, Zhang SJ, Yue JN, Ma YC, Jiang SY. Seroepidemiologic investigation of HEV71 among children in Xining city. Zhongguo Gong Gong Wei Sheng. 2011;27:361&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuang L, Wang CB, Liang ZF, zhong JY, Xiao MS, Zhu B. Investigation on enterovirus 71 antibody levels among children in Guangzhou area. Zhongguo Xun Zheng Er Ke Za Zhi. 2011;6:211&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo RL, Deng J, Li Yx, Ma Yx. Serum epidemiological study of HFMD in Handan, 2009. Zhongguo Bing Yuan Sheng Wu Xue Za Zhi. 2011;6:848&#x2013;850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen XL, Wen SQ, Wei D. Survey on level of antibody against EV71 and Cox A 16 among children aged 0 to 15 in Mengshan County. Yi Yao Qian Yan. 2012;2:115&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen XQ, Zhang ZY, Pang HY. Monitoring and analysis of the levels of neutralizing antibody against enterovirus 71 in individuals under the age of 15 in Donghai County. Xian Dai Yu Fang Yi Xue. 2013;40:3875&#x2013;3877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin XW, Xie RN, Zeng C, Zheng YY. Investigation of Human Enterovirus 71 infection among clinical cases and healthy people in Chaoshan District. Yi Xue Jian Yan Yu Lin Chuang. 2007;18:66&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen RL, Pan RY, Lai ZF, Mo HL, Xhang Y, Zhou HT. The microneutralization assay for the detection of neutralizing antibodies against EV71 and CV A 16 among healthy population. Zhongguo Yu Fang Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2013;14:362&#x2013;365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li ZF, Liu TX, Yang GP, Xia xT. Seroepidemiological investigation on enterovirus 71 among children in Lipu County, Guangxi in 2010. Ying Yong Yu Fang Yi Xue. 2013;19:281&#x2013;283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YM, Wang X, Wang JZ, et al. Immunogenicity, safety, and lot consistency of a novel inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in Chinese children aged 6 to 59 months. Clin Vaccine Immunol. 2013;20:1805&#x2013;1811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3889509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24108780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi EE, Phoon MC, Ishak B, Chan SH. Seroepidemiology of human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg Infect Dis. 2002;8:995&#x2013;997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2732542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12194783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran CB, Nguyen HT, Phan HT, et al. The seroprevalence and seroincidence of enterovirus71 infection in infants and children in Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam. PLoS One. 2011;6:e21116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3134465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21765891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linsuwanon P, Puenpa J, Huang SW, et al. Epidemiology and seroepidemiology of human enterovirus 71 among Thai populations. J Biomed Sci. 2014;21:16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3937078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24548776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo ST, Chiang PS, Chao AS, et al. Enterovirus 71 maternal antibodies in infants, Taiwan. Emerg Infect Dis. 2009;15:581&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19331737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang LW, Phoon MC, Wu Y, Cutter J, James L, Chow VT. The changing seroepidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection among children and adolescents in Singapore. BMC Infect Dis. 2011;11:270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21988931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diedrich S, Weinbrecht A, Schreier E. Seroprevalence and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in Germany. Arch Virol. 2009;154:1139&#x2013;1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19506798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabenau HF, Richter M, Doerr HW. Hand, foot and mouth disease: seroprevalence of Coxsackie A16 and Enterovirus 71 in Germany. Med Microbiol Immunol. 2010;199:45&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19941005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, King CC, Hsu KH, et al. Risk factors of enterovirus 71 infection and associated hand, foot, and mouth disease/herpangina in children during an epidemic in Taiwan. Pediatrics. 2002;109:e88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu CY, Lee CY, Kao CL, et al. Incidence and case-fatality rates resulting from the 1998 enterovirus 71 outbreak in Taiwan. J Med Virol. 2002;67:217&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11992582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhmadishina LV, Eremeeva TP, Trotsenko OE, Ivanova OE, Mikhailov MI, Lukashev AN. Seroepidemiology and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in Russia. PLoS One. 2014;9:e97404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4018281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24819617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Tan XJ, Wang HY, et al. An outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with subgenotype C4 of human enterovirus 71 in Shandong, China. J Clin Virol. 2009;44:262&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19269888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhu Z, Yang W, et al. An emerging recombinant human enterovirus 71 responsible for the 2008 outbreak of hand foot and mouth disease in Fuyang city of China. Virol J. 2010;7:94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20459851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu M, Li Z, Wang J, et al. Determinants of the incidence of hand, foot and mouth disease in China using geographically weighted regression models. PLoS One. 2012;7:e38978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3377651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22723913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng H, Duan G, Zhang R, Zhang W. Time series analysis of hand-foot-mouth disease hospitalization in Zhengzhou: establishment of forecasting models using climate variables as predictors. PLoS One. 2014;9:e87916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3909295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24498221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng T, Huang Y, Yu S, et al. Spatial-temporal clusters and risk factors of hand, foot, and mouth disease at the district level in Guangdong Province, China. PLoS One. 2013;8:e56943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3578924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23437278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao LX, Wu B, Bao WX, et al. Epidemiology of hand, foot, and mouth disease and genotype characterization of Enterovirus 71 in Jiangsu, China. J Clin Virol. 2010;49:100&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20719557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Z, Trikalinos TA, Kavvoura FK, Lau J, Ioannidis JP. Local literature bias in genetic epidemiology: an empirical evaluation of the Chinese literature. PLoS Med. 2005;2:e334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1285066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16285839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu F, Yan Q, Wang H, et al. Performance of detecting IgM antibodies against enterovirus 71 for early diagnosis. PLoS One. 2010;5:e11388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2894942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20613983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Z, Mao Q, Gao Q, et al. Establishing China's national standards of antigen content and neutralizing antibody responses for evaluation of enterovirus 71 (EV71) vaccines. Vaccine. 2011;29:9668&#x2013;9674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22015395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wendelboe AM, Van Rie A, Salmaso S, Englund JA. Duration of immunity against pertussis after natural infection or vaccination. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2005;24:S58&#x2013;S61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15876927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waaijenborg S, Hahne SJ, Mollema L, et al. Waning of maternal antibodies against measles, mumps, rubella, and varicella in communities with contrasting vaccination coverage. J Infect Dis. 2013;208:10&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4043230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23661802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leuridan E, Hens N, Hutse V, Ieven M, Aerts M, Van Damme P. Early waning of maternal measles antibodies in era of measles elimination: longitudinal study. BMJ. 2010;340:c1626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20483946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>