<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27273688</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2017</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Epidemiology of Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease in Asia: A Systematic Review and Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e285</StartPage><EndPage>e300</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e285-300</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000001242</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CONTEXT">Hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) is a widespread pediatric disease caused primarily by human enterovirus 71 (EV-A71) and Coxsackievirus A16 (CV-A16).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This study reports a systematic review of the epidemiology of HFMD in Asia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES">PubMed, Web of Science and Google Scholar were searched up to December 2014.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY SELECTION">Two reviewers independently assessed studies for epidemiologic and serologic information about prevalence and incidence of HFMD against predetermined inclusion/exclusion criteria.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA EXTRACTION">Two reviewers extracted answers for 8 specific research questions on HFMD epidemiology. The results are checked by 3 others.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">HFMD is found to be seasonal in temperate Asia with a summer peak and in subtropical Asia with spring and fall peaks, but not in tropical Asia; evidence of a climatic role was identified for temperate Japan. Risk factors for HFMD include hygiene, age, gender and social contacts, but most studies were underpowered to adjust rigorously for confounding variables. Both community-level and school-level transmission have been implicated, but their relative importance for HFMD is inconclusive. Epidemiologic indices are poorly understood: No supporting quantitative evidence was found for the incubation period of EV-A71; the symptomatic rate of EV-A71/Coxsackievirus A16 infection was from 10% to 71% in 4 studies; while the basic reproduction number was between 1.1 and 5.5 in 3 studies. The uncertainty in these estimates inhibits their use for further analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LIMITATIONS">Diversity of study designs complicates attempts to identify features of HFMD epidemiology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Knowledge on HFMD remains insufficient to guide interventions such as the incorporation of an EV-A71 vaccine in pediatric vaccination schedules. Research is urgently needed to fill these gaps.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koh</LastName><ForeName>Wee Ming</ForeName><Initials>WM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the *Saw Swee Hock School of Public Health, National University of Singapore and National University Health System, Singapore; &#x2020;Standard Analytics, New York, New York; &#x2021;Rollins School of Public Health, Emory University, Atlanta, Georgia; &#xa7;Duke-NUS Graduate Medical School, Singapore; &#xb6;Communicable Disease Centre, Tan Tock Seng Hospital, Singapore; &#x2016;Nuffield Department of Medicine, University of Oxford, United Kingdom; and **Yale-NUS College, National University of Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bogich</LastName><ForeName>Tiffany</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siegel</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chong</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth Y</ForeName><Initials>EY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Chong Yew</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Mark Ic</ForeName><Initials>MI</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horby</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cook</LastName><ForeName>Alex R</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001208" MajorTopicYN="N">Asia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004196" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Outbreaks</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012424" MajorTopicYN="N">Rural Population</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014505" MajorTopicYN="N">Urban Population</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Supported by Singapore&#x2019;s Ministry of Health Services Research (HSRG12MAY023), Communicable Disease Public Health Research (CDPHRG12NOV021), the Centre for Infectious Disease Epidemiology and Research, the Ministry of Education Tier 1 grant and the President&#x2019;s Graduate Fellowship to W.M.K. The funders had no role in the decision to publish. T.B. is employed by commercial company, Standard Analytics. The remaining authors have no financial relationships relevant to this article to disclose. The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27273688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5130063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000001242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huang MC, Wang SM, Hsu YW, et al. Long-term cognitive and motor deficits after enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in children. Pediatrics. 2006;118:e1785&#x2013;e1788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17116698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Huang LM, Gau SS, et al. Neurodevelopment and cognition in children after enterovirus 71 infection. N Engl J Med. 2007;356:1226&#x2013;1234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17377160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization Western Pacific Region. Hand, foot, and mouth disease situation update. 2014. Dec 29,  Available at:  http://www.wpro.who.int/emerging_diseases/hfmd_biweekly_29dec2014.pdf?ua=1. Accessed March 11, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang LW, Koh BK, Chan KP, et al. Epidemiology and control of hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore, 2001&#x2013;2007. Ann Acad Med Singapore. 2009;38:106&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19271036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SP, Huang YC, Li WC, et al. Comparison of clinical features between coxsackievirus A2 and enterovirus 71 during the enterovirus outbreak in Taiwan, 2008: a children&#x2019;s hospital experience. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2010;43:99&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20457425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo S-H, Huang Y-C, Huang C-G, et al. Clinical and epidemiologic features of coxsackievirus A6 infection in children in northern Taiwan between 2004 and 2009. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2011;44:252&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21524960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Infectious Diseases, Japan. Infectious disease weekly report, (IDWR), IDWR Surveillance Data Table, Sentinel-reporting Diseases.  Available at:  http://www.nih.go.jp/niid/en/survaillance-data-table-english.html. Accessed October 30, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centre for Health Protection, Department of Health, Hong Kong. Updated situation of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) and enterovirus infection 2010. 2010. Aug,  Available at:  http://www.chp.gov.hk/files/pdf/updated_situation_of_hand_foot_and_mouth_disease_hfmd_r.pdf. Accessed November 5, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taiwan Centers for Disease Control, Taipei (Taiwan) Taiwan national infectious disease statistics system. 2014. Apr 15,  Available at:  http://nidss.cdc.gov.tw/en/. Accessed October 30, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huwaldt J.  Plot digitizer (version 2.6.3) 2013. Jul 05,  Available at:  http://sourceforge.net/projects/plotdigitizer/. Accessed October 29, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. Vienna, Austria: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Wang X, Liu Y, et al. Detecting spatial-temporal clusters of HFMD from 2007 to 2011 in Shandong Province, China. PLoS One. 2013;8:e63447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3660332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23704909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Jiang L, Thammawijaya P, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease in Yunnan Province, China, 2008&#x2013;2010. Asia Pac J Public Health. 2015;27:769&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22199158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng T, Huang Y, Yu S, et al. Spatial-temporal clusters and risk factors of hand, foot, and mouth disease at the district level in Guangdong Province, China. PLoS One. 2013;8:e56943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3578924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23437278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di B, Zhang Y, Xie H, et al. Circulation of coxsackievirus A6 in hand-foot-mouth disease in Guangzhou, 2010-2012. Virol J. 2014;11:157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4169826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25178398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YR, Sun LL, Xiao WL, et al. Epidemiology and clinical characteristics of hand foot, and mouth disease in a Shenzhen sentinel hospital from 2009 to 2011. BMC Infect Dis. 2013;13:539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3829808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24225231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma E, Chan KC, Cheng P, et al. The enterovirus 71 epidemic in 2008&#x2014;public health implications for Hong Kong. Int J Infect Dis. 2010;14:e775&#x2013;e780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20599410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma E, Lam T, Chan KC, et al. Changing epidemiology of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Hong Kong, 2001-2009. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2010;63:422&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21099093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee T-C, Guo H-R, Su H-JJ, et al. Diseases caused by enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2009;28:904&#x2013;910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20118685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang TT, Huang LM, Lu CY, et al. Clinical features and factors of unfavorable outcomes for non-polio enterovirus infection of the central nervous system in northern Taiwan, 1994-2003. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2005;38:417&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16341342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatproedprai S, Theanboonlers A, Korkong S, et al. Clinical and molecular characterization of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Thailand, 2008-2009. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2010;63:229&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20657060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linsuwanon P, Puenpa J, Huang SW, et al. Epidemiology and seroepidemiology of human enterovirus 71 among Thai populations. J Biomed Sci. 2014;21:16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3937078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24548776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samphutthanon R, Tripathi NK, Ninsawat S, et al. Spatio-temporal distribution and hotspots of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) in northern Thailand. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2014;11:312&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3924446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24366049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu PV, Thao NTT, Perera D, et al. Epidemiologic and virologic investigation of hand, foot, and mouth disease, southern Vietnam, 2005. Emerg Infect Dis. 2007;13:1733&#x2013;1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen NT, Pham HV, Hoang CQ, et al. Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of children who died from hand, foot and mouth disease in Vietnam, 2011. BMC Infect Dis. 2014;14:341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4068316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24942066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podin Y, Gias EL, Ong F, et al. Sentinel surveillance for human enterovirus 71 in Sarawak, Malaysia: lessons from the first 7 years. BMC Public Health. 2006;6:180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1543637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16827926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KP, Goh KT, Chong CY, et al. Epidemic hand, foot and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg Infect Dis. 2003;9:78&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hii YL, Rockl&#xf6;v J, Ng N. Short term effects of weather on hand, foot and mouth disease. PLoS One. 2011;6:e16796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3037951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21347303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Yeo A, Phoon MC, et al. The largest outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore in 2008: the role of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A strains. Int J Infect Dis. 2010;14:e1076&#x2013;e1081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20952237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawada K, Nakamura Y, Ito S. On the hand, foot and mouth disease prevailed in Ohmiya city in summer, 1967. Nihon Shonika Gakkai Zasshi. 1968;74:1594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan MCK, Wong HB. Hand-foot and mouth disease. J Singapore Paediatr Soc. 1973;15:31&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY. Enterovirus 71 in Taiwan. Pediatr Neonatol. 2008;49:103&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19054914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C. The prevalence of hand, foot and mouth disease. J Pediatr Pharm. 2008;14:64&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun LM, Zheng HY, Zheng HZ, et al. An enterovirus 71 epidemic in Guangdong Province of China, 2008: epidemiological, clinical, and virogenic manifestations. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2011;64:13&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Tan XJ, Wang HY, et al. An outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with subgenotype C4 of human enterovirus 71 in Shandong, China. J Clin Virol. 2009;44:262&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19269888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding N-Z, Wang X-M, Sun S-W, et al. Appearance of mosaic enterovirus 71 in the 2008 outbreak of China. Virus Res. 2009;145:157&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19540282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Cao Z, Zeng DD, et al. Epidemiological analysis, detection, and comparison of space-time patterns of Beijing hand-foot-mouth disease (2008&#x2013;2012). PLoS One. 2014;9:e92745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3963949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24663329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Wu X, Jia L, et al. Estimating the number of hand, foot and mouth disease amongst children aged under-five in Beijing during 2012, based on a telephone survey of healthcare seeking behavior. BMC Infect Dis. 2014;14:437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4149051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25117760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian H, Zhang Y, Sun Q, et al. Prevalence of multiple enteroviruses associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Shijiazhuang city, Hebei Province, China: outbreaks of coxsackieviruses A10 and B3. PLoS One. 2014;9:e84233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3879295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24392117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z, Zeng D, Wang Q, et al. An epidemiological analysis of the Beijing 2008 hand-foot-mouth epidemic. Chin Sci Bull. 2010;55:1142&#x2013;1149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Sun Y, Lin C, et al. A case-control study to identify environmental risk factors for hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreaks in Beijing. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2014;67:95&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24647250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De W, Changwen K, Wei L, et al. A large outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by EV71 and CAV16 in Guangdong, China, 2009. Arch Virol. 2011;156:945&#x2013;953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21305327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Yi L, Su J, et al. Seroprevalence of human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 in Guangdong, China, in pre- and post-2010 HFMD epidemic period. PLoS One. 2013;8:e80515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3850913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24324604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu W, Liu CF, Yan L, et al. Distribution of enteroviruses in hospitalized children with hand, foot and mouth disease and relationship between pathogens and nervous system complications. Virol J. 2012;9:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3268717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22230340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhu Z, Yang W, et al. An emerging recombinant human enterovirus 71 responsible for the 2008 outbreak of hand foot and mouth disease in Fuyang city of China. Virol J. 2010;7:94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20459851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingjun T, Yoshida H, Yan W, et al. Molecular typing and epidemiology of non-polio enteroviruses isolated from Yunnan Province, the People&#x2019;s Republic of China. J Med Virol. 2008;80:670&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18297723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Wang M, Chang H, et al. Prevalence of antibodies against enterovirus 71 in children from Lu&#x2019;an city in Central China. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2011;64:528&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22116336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa MJ, Perera D, Brown BA, et al. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 strains and recent outbreaks in the Asia-Pacific region: comparative analysis of the VP1 and VP4 genes. Emerg Infect Dis. 2003;9:461&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12702227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu MY, Liu W, Luo J, et al. Characterization of an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Nanchang, China in 2010. PLoS One. 2011;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21980416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Q, Hao Y, Ma J, et al. Surveillance of hand, foot, and mouth disease in mainland China (2008&#x2013;2009). Biomed Env Sci. 2011;24:349&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22108323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao LX, Wu B, Bao WX, et al. Epidemiology of hand, foot, and mouth disease and genotype characterization of enterovirus 71 in Jiangsu, China. J Clin Virol. 2010;49:100&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20719557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He S-J, Han J-F, Ding X-X, et al. Characterization of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 isolated in hand, foot, and mouth disease patients in Guangdong, 2010. Int J Infect Dis. 2013;17:e1025&#x2013;e1030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23791223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jee YM, Cheon D-S, Kim K, et al. Genetic analysis of the VP1 region of human enterovirus 71 strains isolated in Korea during 2000. Arch Virol. 2003;148:1735&#x2013;1746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14505086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baek K, Yeo S, Lee B, et al. Epidemics of enterovirus infection in Chungnam Korea, 2008 and 2009. Virol J. 2011;8:297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3130694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21668960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SJ, Kim J-H, Kang J-H, et al. Risk factors for neurologic complications of hand, foot and mouth disease in the Republic of Korea, 2009. J Korean Med Sci. 2013;28:120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3546090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23341722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miwa C, Ohtani M, Watanabe H, et al. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease in Gifu Prefecture in 1978. Jpn J Med Sci Biol. 1980;33:167&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6259389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobara F, Itagaki A, Ito Y, et al. Properties of virus isolated from an epidemic of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in 1973 in the city of Matsue. Comparison with coxsackievirus group A type 16 prototype. Microbiol Immunol. 1977;21:207&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">875762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara A, Tagaya I, Yoneyama T. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Intervirology. 1978;9:60&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">202573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tagaya I, Moritsugu Y. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease in Japan. Jpn J Med Sci Biol. 1973;26:143&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4543070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimiya Y, Oyama S, Numazaki Y, et al. Serologic relationship of coxsackie A-16 viruses from the epidemic of hand-foot-and mouth disease in Japan, 1970, to the prototype strain. Jpn J Microbiol. 1974;18:379&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4216656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itagaki A, Gobara F, Ito Y, et al. A survey on enterovirus infections in Matsue city, Shimane Prefecture in the period from May, 1969 to March, 1971. J Jpn Assoc Infect Dis. 1972;46:280&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4346608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tagaya I, Tachibana K. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease in Japan, 1972&#x2013;1973: difference in epidemiologic and virologic features from the previous one. Jpn J Med Sci Biol. 1975;28:231&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">175202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobara F, Itagaki A, Ito Y, et al. A survey on enterovirus infection in Matsue city, Shimane Prefecture in the period from April to October, 1973. J Jpn Assoc Infect Dis. 1975;49:282&#x2013;287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">171325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishimaru Y, Nakano S, Yamaoka K, et al. Outbreaks of hand, foot, and mouth disease by enterovirus 71. High incidence of complication disorders of central nervous system. Arch Dis Child. 1980;55:583&#x2013;588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1627055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6254449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tagaya I, Takayama R, Hagiwara A. A large-scale epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with enterovirus 71 infection in Japan in 1978. Jpn J Med Sci Biol. 1981;34:191&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6273621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosoya M, Kawasaki Y, Sato M, et al. Genetic diversity of coxsackievirus A16 associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease epidemics in Japan from 1983 to 2003. J Clin Microbiol. 2007;45:112&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1828949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17093028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta K, Abiko C, Murata T, et al. Frequent importation of enterovirus 71 from surrounding countries into the local community of Yamagata, Japan, between 1998 and 2003. J Clin Microbiol. 2005;43:6171&#x2013;6175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16333123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu H, Shimizu Y, Takeuchi Y, et al. Outbreak of severe neurologic involvement associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr Neurol. 1999;20:17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bible JM, Pantelidis P, Chan PK, et al. Genetic evolution of enterovirus 71: epidemiological and pathological implications. Rev Med Virol. 2007;17:371&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17487831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto T, Chikahira M, Yoshida S, et al. Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol Immunol. 2002;46:621&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, et al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J-R, Tuan Y-C, Tsai H-P, et al. Change of major genotype of enterovirus 71 in outbreaks of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Taiwan between 1998 and 2000. J Clin Microbiol. 2002;40:10&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CC, Tseng HW, Wang SM, et al. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998: epidemiologic and clinical manifestations. J Clin Virol. 2000;17:23&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JR, Tsai HP, Chen PF, et al. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998. II. Laboratory diagnosis and genetic analysis. J Clin Virol. 2000;17:91&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10942089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuda GM, Chang WK, Yeung CY, et al. Monoplegia caused by enterovirus 71: an outbreak in Hong Kong. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1987;6:206&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3562141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasidharan CK, Sugathan P, Agarwal R, et al. Hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Calicut. Indian J Pediatr. 2005;72:17&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15684442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beig FK, Malik A, Rizvi M, et al. Etiology and clinico-epidemiological profile of acute viral encephalitis in children of western Uttar Pradesh, India. Int J Infect Dis. 2010;14:e141&#x2013;e146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20106698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saoji VA. Hand, foot and mouth disease in Nagpur. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2008;74:133&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18388372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma N, Sarkar A, Mukherjee A, et al. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease in West Bengal, India in August, 2007: a multicentric study. Indian J Dermatol. 2009;54:26&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2800866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20049265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar BR, Dwibedi B, Kar SK. An outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Bhubaneswar, Odisha. Indian Pediatr. 2013;50:139&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22728634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashyap S, Verma GK. Hand-foot-mouth disease: outbreak in Shimla. Indian Pediatr. 2014;51:155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24632702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puenpa J, Mauleekoonphairoj J, Linsuwanon P, et al. Prevalence and characterization of enterovirus infections among pediatric patients with hand foot mouth disease, herpangina and influenza like illness in Thailand, 2012. PLoS One. 2014;9:e98888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4041783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24887237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa MJ, Krishnan S, Tio PH, et al. Isolation of subgenus B adenovirus during a fatal outbreak of enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sibu, Sarawak. Lancet. 1999;354:987&#x2013;991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10501361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooi PS, Chua BH, Lee CS, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease: university Malaya Medical Centre experience. Med J Malaysia. 2002;57:88&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14569723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum LC, Wong KT, Lam SK, et al. Fatal enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. J Pediatr. 1998;133:795&#x2013;798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shekhar K, Lye MS, Norlijah O, et al. Deaths in children during an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Peninsular Malaysia&#x2013;clinical and pathological characteristics. Med J Malaysia. 2005;60:297&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16379183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Mohan A, et al. Identification and validation of clinical predictors for the risk of neurological involvement in children with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak. BMC Infect Dis. 2009;9:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2637878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19152683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh KT, Doraisingham S, Tan JL, et al. An outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Singapore. Bull World Health Organ. 1982;60:965&#x2013;969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2535982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6297819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar S, Sam IC, Yusof J, et al. Enterovirus 71 outbreak, Brunei. Emerg Infect Dis. 2009;15:79&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19116058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudo T, Morita M. [Hand, foot and mouth disease]. Nihon Rinsho. 1971;29:1137&#x2013;1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4931315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi EE, Phoon MC, Ishak B, et al. Seroepidemiology of human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg Infect Dis. 2002;8:995&#x2013;997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2732542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12194783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C-Y, Lee C-Y, Kao C-L, et al. Incidence and case-fatality rates resulting from the 1998 enterovirus 71 outbreak in Taiwan. J Med Virol. 2002;67:217&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11992582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, Zhu S, Guo X, et al. Retrospective seroepidemiology indicated that human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 circulated wildly in central and southern China before large-scale outbreaks from 2008. Virol J. 2010;7:300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2989968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21050463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan F, Yang T, Ma H, et al. Risk factors for hand, foot, and mouth disease and herpangina and the preventive effect of hand-washing. Pediatrics. 2011;127:e898&#x2013;e904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21422083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SK, Park B, Ki M, et al. Transmission of seasonal outbreak of childhood enteroviral aseptic meningitis and hand-foot-mouth disease. J Korean Med Sci. 2010;25:677&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2858824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20436701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, King CC, Hsu KH, et al. Risk factors of enterovirus 71 infection and associated hand, foot, and mouth disease/herpangina in children during an epidemic in Taiwan. Pediatrics. 2002;109:e88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Dang S, Deng H, et al. Breastfeeding, previous Epstein-Barr virus infection, enterovirus 71 infection, and rural residence are associated with the severity of hand, foot, and mouth disease. Eur J Pediatr. 2013;172:661&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23344210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiaoyun F, Xiongfei J, Lihuan L, et al. Epidemiology and etiological characteristics of hand, foot and mouth disease in Huizhou city between 2008 and 2011. Arch Virol. 2013;158:895&#x2013;899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23229012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan L, Li X, Yu Y, et al. Distribution and risk factors of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Changchun, northeastern China. Chin Sci Bull. 2014;59:533&#x2013;538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Fu Y, Xu A, et al. A spatial-temporal ARMA model of the incidence of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Wenzhou, China. Abstr Appl Anal. 2014;2014:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Feng Z, Yang Y, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China: patterns of spread and transmissibility. Epidemiology. 2011;22:781&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3246273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21968769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu D, Zhao XY, Yao Y, et al. A new factor influencing pathogen detection by molecular assay in children with both mild and severe hand, foot, and mouth disease. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2013;76:162&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7126308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23535205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng M, Li Y-F, Wang X-H, et al. Epidemiology of hand, foot, and mouth disease in children in Shanghai 2007&#x2013;2010. Epidemiol Infect. 2012;140:1122&#x2013;1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21878145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang LW, Phoon MC, Wu Y, et al. The changing seroepidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection among children and adolescents in Singapore. BMC Infect Dis. 2011;11:270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21988931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X-F, Gao S, Xia J-F, et al. Epidemic characteristics of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Shanghai from 2009 to 2010: enterovirus 71 subgenotype C4 as the primary causative agent and a high incidence of mixed infections with coxsackievirus A16. Scand J Infect Dis. 2012;44:297&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22176514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng M, El Khatib NF, Tu S, et al. Seroepidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection prior to the 2011 season in children in Shanghai. J Clin Virol. 2012;53:285&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22265829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Sun J, Chang Z, et al. Characterization of hand, foot, and mouth disease in China between 2008 and 2009. Biomed Env Sci. 2011;24:214&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21784305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Tsao KC, Hsia SH, et al. Transmission and clinical features of enterovirus 71 infections in household contacts in Taiwan. JAMA. 2004;291:222&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14722149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K-T, Chang H-L, Wang S-T, et al. Epidemiologic features of hand-foot-mouth disease and herpangina caused by enterovirus 71 in Taiwan, 1998 2005. Pediatrics. 2007;120:e244&#x2013;e252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SC, Chang HL, Yan TR, et al. An eight-year study of epidemiologic features of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2007;77:188&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17620652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yen FB, Chang LY, Kao CL, et al. Coxsackieviruses infection in northern Taiwan&#x2013;epidemiology and clinical characteristics. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2009;42:38&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19424557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momoki ST. Surveillance of enterovirus infections in Yokohama city from 2004 to 2008. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2009;62:471&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19934543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan Y-F, Sam I-C, Wee K-L, et al. Enterovirus 71 in Malaysia: a decade later. Neurol Asia. 2011;16:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki Y, Taya K, Nakashima K, et al. Risk factors for severe hand foot and mouth disease. Pediatr Int. 2010;52:203&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19663940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frydenberg A, Starr M. Hand, foot and mouth disease. Aust Fam Physician. 2003;32:594&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12973865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong SSY, Yip CCY, Lau SKP, et al. Human enterovirus 71 and hand, foot and mouth disease. Epidemiol Infect. 2010;138:1071&#x2013;1089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20056019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma E, Fung C, Yip SH, et al. Estimation of the basic reproduction number of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 in hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreaks. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2011;30:675&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21326133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onozuka D, Hashizume M. The influence of temperature and humidity on the incidence of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan. Sci Total Environ. 2011;410&#x2013;411:119&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22014509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale MH. Hand, foot and mouth disease&#x2013;1973. J R Coll Gen Pract. 1975;25:35&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2157646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1177202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Lin TY, Hsu KH, et al. Clinical features and risk factors of pulmonary oedema after enterovirus-71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet. 1999;354:1682&#x2013;1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee M-S, Chiang P-S, Luo S-T, et al. Incidence rates of enterovirus 71 infections in young children during a nationwide epidemic in Taiwan, 2008&#x2013;09. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2012;6:e1476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3279337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22348156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallinga J, Teunis P. Different epidemic curves for severe acute respiratory syndrome reveal similar impacts of control measures. Am J Epidemiol. 2004;160:509&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7110200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15353409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi BC, Pak AW. A simple approximate mathematical model to predict the number of severe acute respiratory syndrome cases and deaths. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2003;57:831&#x2013;835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1732283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14573591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Zhang J, Zhang X. Modeling and preventive measures of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) in China. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2014;11:3108&#x2013;3117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3987023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24633146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urashima M, Shindo N, Okabe N. Seasonal models of herpangina and hand-foot-mouth disease to simulate annual fluctuations in urban warming in Tokyo. Jpn J Infect Dis. 2003;56:48&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12824684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang HL, Chio CP, Su HJ, et al. The association between enterovirus 71 infections and meteorological parameters in Taiwan. PLoS One. 2012;7:e46845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3465260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23071650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma E, Lam T, Wong C, et al. Is hand, foot and mouth disease associated with meteorological parameters? Epidemiol Infect. 2010;138:1779&#x2013;1788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20875200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Deng T, Yu S, et al. Effect of meteorological variables on the incidence of hand, foot, and mouth disease in children: a time-series analysis in Guangzhou, China. BMC Infect Dis. 2013;13:134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3626782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23497074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abad FX, Pint&#xf3; RM, Bosch A. Survival of enteric viruses on environmental fomites. Appl Environ Microbiol. 1994;60:3704&#x2013;3710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7986043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JF, Guo YS, Christakos G, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease: spatiotemporal transmission and climate. Int J Health Geogr. 2011;10:25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3079592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21466689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe9;langer M, Gray-Donald K, O&#x2019;Loughlin J, et al. Influence of weather conditions and season on physical activity in adolescents. Ann Epidemiol. 2009;19:180&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19217000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lofgren E, Fefferman NH, Naumov YN, et al. Influenza seasonality: underlying causes and modeling theories. J Virol. 2007;81:5429&#x2013;5436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1900246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17182688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singapore Ministry of Health. Hand, foot &amp; mouth disease: updates.   https://www.moh.gov.sg/content/moh_web/home/diseases_and_conditions/h/hand_foot_mouth_disease.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Lin C, Qu M, et al. Excretion of enterovirus 71 in persons infected with hand, foot and mouth disease. Virol J. 2013;10:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3560202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23343115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Meng FY, Li JX, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2013;381:2024&#x2013;2032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23726161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Liu L, Mo Z, et al. An inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:829&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F, Xu W, Xia J, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in China. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, et al. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect Dis. 2010;10:778&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong CW, Bible JM. Global epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Future Virol. 2009;4:501&#x2013;510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yip CCY, Lau SKP, Woo PCY, et al. Human enterovirus 71 epidemics: what&#x2019;s next? Emerg Health Threats J. 2013;6:19780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24119538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Lewthwaite P, et al. Clinical features, diagnosis, and management of enterovirus 71. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9:1097&#x2013;1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y, Wang S, Zhang L, et al. Risk factors of severe hand, foot and mouth disease: a meta-analysis. Scand J Infect Dis. 2014;46:515&#x2013;522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao YY, Jin H, Zhang XF, et al. Case-fatality of hand, foot and mouth disease associated with EV71: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Epidemiol Infect. 2015;143:3094&#x2013;3102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9151022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25721492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia MY, Chiang PS, Chung WY, et al. Epidemiology of enterovirus 71 infections in Taiwan. Pediatr Neonatol. 2014;55:243&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24120535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>