<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24078828</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1741-427X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2013</Volume><PubDate><Year>2013</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Evidence-based complementary and alternative medicine : eCAM</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Eupafolin and Ethyl Acetate Fraction of Kalanchoe gracilis Stem Extract Show Potent Antiviral Activities against Enterovirus 71 and Coxsackievirus A16.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>591354</StartPage><MedlinePgn>591354</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">591354</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2013/591354</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) and coxsackievirus A16 (CoxA16) are main pathogens of hand-foot-and-mouth disease, occasionally causing aseptic meningitis and encephalitis in tropical and subtropical regions. Kalanchoe gracilis, Da-Huan-Hun, is a Chinese folk medicine for treating pain and inflammation, exhibiting antioxidant and anti-inflammatory activities. Our prior report (2012) cited K. gracilis leaf extract as moderately active against EV71 and CoxA16. This study further rates antienteroviral potential of K. gracilis stem (KGS) extract to identify potent antiviral fractions and components. The extract moderately inhibits viral cytopathicity and virus yield, as well as in vitro replication of EV71 (IC50 = 75.18&#x2009; &#x3bc; g/mL) and CoxA16 (IC50 = 81.41&#x2009; &#x3bc; g/mL). Ethyl acetate (EA) fraction of KGS extract showed greater antiviral activity than that of n-butanol or aqueous fraction: IC50 values of 4.21&#x2009; &#x3bc; g/mL against EV71 and 9.08&#x2009; &#x3bc; g/mL against CoxA16. HPLC analysis, UV-Vis absorption spectroscopy, and plaque reduction assay indicate that eupafolin is a vital component of EA fraction showing potent activity against EV71 (IC50 = 1.39&#x2009; &#x3bc; M) and CoxA16 (IC50 = 5.24&#x2009; &#x3bc; M). Eupafolin specifically lessened virus-induced upregulation of IL-6 and RANTES by inhibiting virus-induced ERK1/2, AP-1, and STAT3 signals. Anti-enteroviral potency of KGS EA fraction and eupafolin shows the clinical potential against EV71 and CoxA16 infection.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ching-Ying</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chinese Pharmaceutical Sciences and Chinese Medicine Resources, China Medical University, Taichung 404, Taiwan ; Department of Medical Laboratory Science and Biotechnology, China Medical University, Taichung 404, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Shun-Chueh</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Zhen-Rung</ForeName><Initials>ZR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ho</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Ling</ForeName><Initials>YL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jou</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Jen</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kung</LastName><ForeName>Szu-Hao</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yongjun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Yuan-Shiun</ForeName><Initials>YS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Cheng-Wen</ForeName><Initials>CW</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Evid Based Complement Alternat Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101215021</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1741-427X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2013</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24078828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3775429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/591354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sanders SA, Herrero LJ, McPhie K, et al. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 over two decades in an Australian urban community. Archives of Virology. 2006;151(5):1003&#x2013;1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16369861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Chow VTK, Phoon MC, Chan KP, Poh CL. Direct detection of enterovirus 71 (EV71) in clinical specimens from a hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak in Singapore by reverse transcription-PCR with universal enterovirus and EV71-specific primers. Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 2002;40(8):2823&#x2013;2827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12149336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishimaru Y, Nakano S, Yamaoka K, Takami S. Outbreaks of hand, foot, and mouth disease by enterovirus 71. High incidence of complication disorders of central nervous system. Archives of Disease in Childhood. 1980;55(8):583&#x2013;588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1627055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6254449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallansch MA, Roos RP. Enteroviruses: polioviruses, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses, and newer enteroviruses. In: Knipe DN, Howley PM, Griffin DE, et al., editors. Fields Virology. 5th edition. 2007. pp. 839&#x2013;894.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Z, Yalcin AO, Tichelaar FD, et al. From sphere to multipod: thermally induced transitions of cdse nanocrystals studied by molecular dynamics simulations. Journal of the American Chemical Society. 2013;135:8 pages.ja401406q</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23528240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan X-F, Gao S, Xia J-F, Ye R, Yu H, Long J-E. Epidemic characteristics of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Shanghai from 2009 to 2010: enterovirus 71 subgenotype C4 as the primary causative agent and a high incidence of mixed infections with coxsackievirus A16. Scandinavian Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2012;44(4):297&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22176514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalkrishna V, Patil PR, Patil GP, Chitambar SD. Circulation of multiple enterovirus serotypes causing hand, foot and mouth disease in India. Journal of Medical Microbiology. 2012;61(3):420&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22052995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao MC. Handbook of Taiwan Medicinal Plants. Taiwan: Southern Materials Center; 1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai Z-R, Peng W-H, Ho Y-L, et al. Analgesic and anti-inflammatory activities of the methanol extract of kalanchoe gracilis (L.) DC stem in mice. American Journal of Chinese Medicine. 2010;38(3):529&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20503470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai Z-R, Ho Y-L, Huang S-C, et al. Antioxidant, anti-inflammatory and antiproliferative activities of kalanchoe gracilis (L.) DC stem. American Journal of Chinese Medicine. 2011;39(6):1275&#x2013;1290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22083996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas M, Deters AM, Hensel A. Anti-inflammatory activity of Eupatorium perfoliatum L. extracts, eupafolin, and dimeric guaianolide via iNOS inhibitory activity and modulation of inflammation-related cytokines and chemokines. Journal of Ethnopharmacology. 2011;137(1):371&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21669270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hensel A, Maas M, Sendker J, et al. Eupatorium perfoliatum L.: phytochemistry, traditional use and current applications. Journal of Ethnopharmacology. 2011;138(3):641&#x2013;651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22004891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung K-S, Choi J-H, Back N-I, et al. Eupafolin, a flavonoid isolated from Artemisia princeps, induced apoptosis in human cervical adenocarcinoma HeLa cells. Molecular Nutrition and Food Research. 2010;54(9):1318&#x2013;1328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20397191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CY, Huang SC, Zhang Y, et al. Antiviral ability of Kalanchoe gracilis leaf extract against enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16. Evidence-Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine. 2012;2012:13 pages.503165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3361180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22666293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salama MM, Kandil ZA, Islam WT. Cytotoxic compounds from the leaves of Gaillardia aristata pursh. growing in Egypt. Natural Product Research. 2012;26(22):2057&#x2013;2062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21846263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai M-T, Cheng Y-H, Liu Y-N, Liao N-C, Lu W-W, Kung S-H. Real-time monitoring of human enterovirus (HEV)-infected cells and anti-HEV 3C protease potency by fluorescence resonance energy transfer. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy. 2009;53(2):748&#x2013;755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2630644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19015331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin C-W, Wu C-F, Hsiao N-W, et al. Aloe-emodin is an interferon-inducing agent with antiviral activity against Japanese encephalitis virus and enterovirus 71. International Journal of Antimicrobial Agents. 2008;32(4):355&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7126984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18701259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih S-R, Tsai K-N, Li Y-S, Chueh C-C, Chan E-C. Inhibition of enterovirus 71-induced apoptosis by allophycocyanin isolated from a blue-green alga Spirulina platensis . Journal of Medical Virology. 2003;70(1):119&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12629652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi HJ, Song JH, Park KS, Baek SH. In vitro anti-enterovirus 71 activity of gallic acid from Woodfordia fruticosa flowers. Letters in Applied Microbiology. 2010;50(4):438&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20149083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Q-C, Wang Y, Liu Y-P, et al. Inhibition of enterovirus 71 replication by chrysosplenetin and penduletin. European Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences. 2011;44(3):392&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong X, Zhou J, Zhu W, et al. Excessive proinflammatory cytokine and chemokine responses of human monocyte- derived macrophages to enterovirus 71 infection. BMC Infectious Diseases. 2012;12(article 224):9 pages.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3519709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22994237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lien CC, Trai YM. Enterovirus 71 infection of human immune cells induces the production of proinflammatory cytokines. Journal of Biomedical Sciencr. 2009;12(3):82&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung W-H, Lee I-T, Hsieh H-L, Yang C-M. EV71 induces COX-2 expression via c-Src/PDGFR/PI3K/Akt/p42/p44 MAPK/AP-1 and NF-&#x3ba;B in rat brain astrocytes. Journal of Cellular Physiology. 2010;224(2):376&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20333648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>