<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16000783</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Isolation and detection of enterovirus RNA from large-volume water samples by using the NucliSens miniMAG system and real-time nucleic acid sequence-based amplification.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3734</StartPage><EndPage>3740</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3734-40</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Concentration of water samples is a prerequisite for the detection of the low virus levels that are present in water and may present a public health hazard. The aim of this study was to develop a rapid, standardized molecular method for the detection of enteroviruses in large-volume surface water samples, using a concentration method suitable for the detection of infectious viruses as well as virus RNA. Concentration of water was achieved by a conventional filter adsorption-elution method and ultrafiltration, resulting in a 10,000-fold concentration of the sample. Isolation of virus RNA by a silica-based RNA extraction method was compared with the nonmagnetic and magnetic NucliSens RNA isolation methods. By using the silica-based RNA extraction method in two out of five samples, enterovirus RNA was detected, whereas four out of five samples were positive following RNA isolation with magnetic silica beads. Moreover, estimated RNA levels increased at least 100 to 500 times. Furthermore, we compared enterovirus detection by an in-house reverse transcription (RT)-PCR with a novel commercially available real-time nucleic acid sequence-based amplification (NASBA) assay. We found that the rapid real-time NASBA assay was slightly less sensitive than our in-house RT-PCR. The advantages, however, of a commercial real-time NASBA assay, like the presence of an internal control RNA, standardization, and enormous decrease in turnaround time, makes it an attractive alternative to RT-PCR.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rutjes</LastName><ForeName>Saskia A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Public Health and the Environment (RIVM), Microbiological Laboratory for Health Protection (MGB), Health-Related Water Microbiology, P.O. Box 1/Antonie van Leeuwenhoeklaan 9, 3720 BA Bilthoven, The Netherlands. saskia.rutjes@rivm.nl</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Italiaander</LastName><ForeName>Ronald</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van den Berg</LastName><ForeName>Harold H J L</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lodder</LastName><ForeName>Willemijn J</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Roda Husman</LastName><ForeName>Ana Maria</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D023362">Evaluation Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011933">Reagent Kits, Diagnostic</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7631-86-9</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012822">Silicon Dioxide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005374" MajorTopicYN="N">Filtration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008280" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="Y">analysis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011933" MajorTopicYN="Y">Reagent Kits, Diagnostic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045483" MajorTopicYN="N">Rivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D021161" MajorTopicYN="N">Self-Sustained Sequence Replication</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012822" MajorTopicYN="N">Silicon Dioxide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014776" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Cultivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16000783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1169005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.7.3734-3740.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">71/7/3734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amvrosieva, T. V., L. P. Titov, M. Mulders, T. Hovi, O. V. Dyakonova, V. I. Votyakov, Z. B. Kvacheva, V. F. Eremin, R. M. Sharko, S. V. Orlova, O. N. Kazinets, and Z. F. Bogush. 2001. Viral water contamination as the cause of aseptic meningitis outbreak in Belarus. Centr. Eur. J. Public Health 9:154-157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11505740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beller, M., A. Ellis, S. H. Lee, M. A. Drebot, S. A. Jenkerson, E. Funk, M. D. Sobsey, O. D. Simmons III, S. S. Monroe, T. Ando, J. Noel, M. Petric, J. P. Middaugh, and J. S. Spika. 1997. Outbreak of viral gastroenteritis due to a contaminated well. JAMA 278:563-568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9268277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomqvist, S., C. Savolainen, P. Laine, P. Hirtti&#xf6;, E. Lamminsalo, E. Penttil&#xe4;, S. J&#xf6;ks, M. Roivainen, and T. Hovi. 2004. Characterization of a highly evolved vaccine-derived poliovirus type 3 isolate from sewage in Estonia. J. Virol. 78:4876-4883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC387693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15078968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boom, R., C. J. Sol, M. M. Salimans, C. L. Jansen, P. M. Wertheim van Dillen, and J. S. O. van der Noordaa. 1990. Rapid and simple method for purification of nucleic acids. J. Clin. Microbiol. 28:495-503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC269651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1691208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgener, M., U. Candrian, and M. Gilgen. 2003. Comparative evaluation of four large-volume RNA extraction kits in the isolation of viral RNA from water samples. J. Virol. Methods 108:165-170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12609683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compton, J. 1991. Nucleic acid sequence-based amplification. Nature 350:91-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1706072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook, N. 2003. The use of NASBA for the detection of microbial pathogens in food and environmental samples. J. Microbiol. Methods 53:165-174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12654488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahling, D. R., and B. A. Wright. 1986. Optimization of the BGM cell line culture and viral assay procedures for monitoring viruses in the environment. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 51:790-812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC238965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3010860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson, K. A., D. W. Griffin, and J. H. Paul. 2002. Detection, quantitation and identification of enteroviruses from surface waters and sponge tissue from the Florida Keys using real-time RT-PCR. Water Res. 36:2505-2514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12153016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox, J. D., S. Han, A. Samuelson, Y. Zhang, M. L. Neale, and D. Westemoreland. 2002. Development and evaluation of nucleic acid sequence based amplification (NASBA) for diagnosis of enterovirus infections using the NucliSens Basic Kit. J. Clin. Virol. 24:117-130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11744436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilgen, M., D. Germann, J. Luthy, and P. Hubner. 1997. Three-step isolation method for sensitive detection of enterovirus, rotavirus, hepatitis A virus, and small round structured viruses in water samples. Int. J. Food Microbiol. 37:189-199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafliger, D., P. Hubner, and J. Luthy. 2000. Outbreak of viral gastroenteritis due to sewage-contaminated drinking water. Int. J. Food Microbiol. 54:123-126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10746582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heim, A., and J. Schumann. 2002. Development and evaluation of a nucleic acid sequence based amplification (NASBA) protocol for the detection of enterovirus RNA in cerebrospinal fluid samples. J. Virol. Methods 103:101-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11906737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hibbitts, S., A. Rahman, R. John, D. Westmoreland, and J. D. Fox. 2003. Development and evaluation of NucliSens basic kit NASBA for diagnosis of parainfluenza virus infection with &#x2018;end-point&#x2019; and &#x2018;real-time&#x2019; detection. J. Virol. Methods 108:145-155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12609681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hot, D., O. Legeay, J. Jacques, C. Gantzer, Y. Caudrelier, K. Guyard, M. Lange, and L. Andreoletti. 2003. Detection of somatic phages, infectious enteroviruses and enterovirus genomes as indicators of human enteric viral pollution in surface water. Water Res. 37:4703-4710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14568057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hovi, T., M. Stenvik, H. Partanen, and A. Kangas. 2001. Poliovirus surveillance by examining sewage specimens. Quantitative recovery of virus after introduction into sewerage at remote upstream location. Epidemiol. Infect. 127:101-106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2869716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11561962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda, R. M., S. F. Kondracki, P. D. Drabkin, G. S. Birkhead, and D. L. Morse. 1993. Pleurodynia among football players at a high school. An outbreak associated with coxsackievirus B1. JAMA 270:2205-2206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8411604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jean, J., B. Blais, A. Darveau, and I. Fliss. 2001. Detection of hepatitis A virus by the nucleic acid sequence-based amplification technique and comparison with reverse transcription-PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 67:5593-5600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC93348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11722911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kares, S., M. Lonnrot, P. Vuorinen, S. Oikarinen, S. Taurianen, and H. Hyoty. 2004. Real-time PCR for rapid diagnosis of entero- and rhinovirus infections using LightCycler. J. Clin. Virol. 29:99-104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kee, F., G. McElroy, D. Stewart, P. Coyle, and J. Watson. 1994. A community outbreak of echovirus infection associated with an outdoor swimming pool. J. Public Health Med. 16:145-148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7946487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landry, M. L., R. Garner, and D. Ferfuson. 2003. Rapid enterovirus RNA detection in clinical specimens by using nucleic acid sequence-based amplification. J. Clin. Microbiol. 41:346-350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC149595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12517871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodder, W. J., and A. M. de Roda Husman. 2005. Presence of noroviruses and other enteric viruses in sewage surface waters in The Netherlands. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 71:1453-1461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1065170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15746348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodder, W. J., J. Vinje, R. van de Heide, A. M. de Roda Husman, E. J. T. M. Leenen, and M. P. G. Koopmans. 1999. Molecular detection of Norwalk-like caliciviruses in sewage. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 65:5624-5627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC91771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10584031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mood, A. M., F. A. Graybill, and D. C. Boes. 1974. Introduction to the theory of statistics, 3rd ed. McGraw-Hill Book Company, New York, N.Y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijhuis, M., N. van Maarseveen, R. Schuurman, S. Verkuijlen, M. de Vos, K. Kendriksen, and A. M. van Loon. 2002. Rapid and sensitive routine detection of all members of the genus Enterovirus in different clinical specimens by real-time PCR. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:3666-3670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC130891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12354863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallansch, M. A., and R. P. Roos. 2001. Enteroviruses: Polioviruses, Coxsackieviruses, Echoviruses and newer enteroviruses. In D. M. Knipe, P. M. Howley, D. E. Griffin, R. A. Lamb, M. A. Martin, B. Roizman, and S. E. Straus (ed.), Fields virology, 4th ed. [Online.] Lippincott Willliams &amp; Wilkins, Philadelphia, Pa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xf6;yry, T., M. Stenvik, and T. Hovi. 1988. Viruses in sewage waters during and after a poliomyelitis outbreak and subsequent nationwide oral poliovirus vaccination campaign in Finland. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 54:371-374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC202459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2833160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabenau, H. F., A. M. K. Clarici, G. Muhlbauer, A. Berger, A. Vince, S. Muller, E. Daghofer, B. I. Danther, E. Marth, and H. H. Kessler. 2002. Rapid detection of enterovirus infection by automated RNA extraction and real-time fluorescence PCR. J. Clin. Virol. 25:155-164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12367649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab, K. J., R. De Leon, and M. D. Sobsey. 1995. Concentration and purification of beef extract mock eluated from water samples for the detection of enteroviruses, hepatitis A virus, and Norwalk virus by reverse trancription-PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 61:531-537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7574592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Olphen, M., J. G. Kapsenberg, E. van de Baan, and W. A. Kroon. 1984. Removal of enteric viruses from surface water at eight waterworks in The Netherlands. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 47:927-932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC240016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6331309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weusten, J. J., P. A. Wouters, M. C. van Zuijlen, and P. A. van de Wiel. 2002. Stochastic processes defining sensitivity and variability of internally calibrated quantitative NASBA-based viral load assays. Nucleic Acids Res. 30:e137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC140086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12490728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyn-Jones, A. P., and J. Sellwood. 2001. Enteric viruses in the aquatic environment. J. Appl. Microbiol. 91:945-962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11851802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>