<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32433221</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epidemiology of Hand, Foot, and Mouth Disease Before and After the Introduction of Enterovirus 71 Vaccines in Chengdu, China, 2009-2018.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>969</StartPage><EndPage>978</EndPage><MedlinePgn>969-978</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000002745</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) has posed a serious threat to children's health. Three inactivated monovalent enterovirus 71 (EV71) vaccines are proved to be highly efficacious in phase III clinical trials and are now available in China.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We analyzed the citywide surveillance data on HFMD cases in Chengdu during 2009-2018, and estimated cumulative first-dose EV71 vaccination coverage among children eligible to EV71 vaccination after August 2016 in Chengdu. Time series susceptible-infected-recovered model was developed to analyze basic reproduction number and herd immunity threshold of HFMD. Overall and serotype-specific HFMD incidences and severity risks were compared before and after the EV71 vaccination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Among 3 laboratory-identified serotype categories, i.e. EV71, coxsackievirus A16 (CV-A16), and other enteroviruses, the major serotype attributed to HFMD has been changing across years. The cumulative first-dose EV71 vaccination coverage rate was estimated as 60.8% during the study period in Chengdu. By contrast, herd immunity threshold for EV71-related HFMD was 94.0%. After introduction of EV71 vaccines, the overall incidence of HFMD increased 60.8%, mainly driven by 173.7% and 11.8% increased in HFMD caused by other enteroviruses and CV-A16, respectively, which offset a significant reduction in the incidence of HFMD caused by EV71. The overall case-severity risk decreased from 1.4% to 0.3%, with significantly declined presented in all serotype categories.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The incidence and severity of EV71-related HFMD decreased following implementation of EV71 vaccination. Developing multivalent vaccines and strengthening laboratory-based surveillance could further decline burden of HFMD.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Yutong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatitics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zhenhua</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatitics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Ke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunization Planning, Chengdu Municipal Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xianzhi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatitics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kong</LastName><ForeName>Jinwang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatitics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoxia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatitics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Xiong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatitics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Bing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatitics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luan</LastName><ForeName>Rongsheng</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatitics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatitics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015164">Vaccines, Inactivated</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014765">Viral Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014611" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccination</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073887" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccination Coverage</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015164" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccines, Inactivated</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014765" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Vaccines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32433221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000002745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-202010000-00021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xing W, Liao Q, Viboud C, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China, 2008&#x2013;12: an epidemiological study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2014;14:308&#x2013;318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh WM, Bogich T, Siegel K, et al. The epidemiology of hand, foot and mouth disease in Asia: a systematic review and analysis. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2016;35:e285&#x2013;e300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang ZC, Kou ZQ, Bai YJ, et al. Epidemiological research on hand, foot, and mouth disease in mainland China. Viruses. 2015;7:6400&#x2013;6411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Lewthwaite P, et al. Clinical features, diagnosis, and management of enterovirus 71. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9:1097&#x2013;1105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B, Liu F, Liao Q, et al. Epidemiology of hand, foot and mouth disease in China, 2008 to 2015 prior to the introduction of EV-A71 vaccine. Euro Surveill. 2017;22:16&#x2013;00824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuguto F, Setsuko I, Miki E, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus A6, Japan, 2011. Emerg Infect Dis J. 2012;18:337&#x2013;339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng H, Lu J, Yang F, et al.; Guangdong Provincial HFMD Surveillance Group. The increasing epidemic of hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus-A6, Guangdong, China, 2017. J Infect. 2018;76:220&#x2013;223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SH, Wang A, Liu PP, et al. Divergent pathogenic properties of circulating coxsackievirus A6 associated with emerging hand, foot, and mouth disease. J Virol. 2018;92:e00303-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y, Zhang Y, Ji T, et al. Persistent circulation of coxsackievirus A6 of genotype D3 in mainland of China between 2008 and 2015. Sci Rep. 2017;7:5491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimmis BD, Downing C, Tyring S. Hand-foot-and-mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus A6 on the rise. Cutis. 2018;102:353&#x2013;356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han JF, Xu S, Zhang Y, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak caused by coxsackievirus A6, China, 2013. J Infect. 2014;69:303&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zha J, Ma Z. Epidemiological and genetic analysis concerning the coxsackievirus A6 related endemic outbreak of hand-foot-mouth disease in Taizhou, China, during 2013. J Med Virol. 2015;87:2000&#x2013;2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian L, Wang Y, Yao X, et al. Coxsackievirus A6: a new emerging pathogen causing hand, foot and mouth disease outbreaks worldwide. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2015;13:1061&#x2013;1071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>China Food and Drug Administration. Announcement on licensed drugs approved by China Food and Drug Administration (No. 4 in 2016). 2016Available from: http://www.nmpa.gov.cn/WS04/CL2168/329339.html. Accessed March 20, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei M, Meng F, Wang S, et al. 2-year efficacy, immunogenicity, and safety of vigoo enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy Chinese children: a randomized open-label study. J Infect Dis. 2017;215:56&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F, Xu W, Xia J, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in China. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:818&#x2013;828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Liu L, Mo Z, et al. An inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:829&#x2013;837.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Meng FY, Li JX, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2013;381:2024&#x2013;2032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Song J, Wang J, et al. Cost-effectiveness of a national enterovirus 71 vaccination program in China. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2017;11:e0005899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JT, Jit M, Zheng Y, et al. Routine pediatric enterovirus 71 vaccination in China: a cost-effectiveness analysis. PLoS Med. 2016;13:e1001975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chengdu Bureau of Statistics (Internet). Statistical yearbook of Chengdu; 2009-2018. 2019Available from: http://cdstats.chengdu.gov.cn/tjgzxxw/xhtml/tjxx_content.html?id=123764&amp;channel=. Accessed March 20, 2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi S, Liao Q, Van Boeckel TP, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in china: modeling epidemic dynamics of enterovirus serotypes and implications for vaccination. PLoS Med. 2016;13:e1001958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reich NG, Shrestha S, King AA, et al. Interactions between serotypes of dengue highlight epidemiological impact of cross-immunity. J R Soc Interface. 2013;10:20130414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi S, Metcalf CJE, Arima Y, et al. Epidemic dynamics, interactions and predictability of enteroviruses associated with hand, foot and mouth disease in Japan. J R Soc Interface. 2018;15:20180507.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Feng Z, Yang Y, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China: patterns of spread and transmissibility. Epidemiology. 2011;22:781&#x2013;792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerra FM, Bolotin S, Lim G, et al. The basic reproduction number (R0) of measles: a systematic review. Lancet Infect Dis. 2017;17:e420&#x2013;e428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine P, Eames K, Heymann DL. &#x201c;Herd immunity&#x201d;: a rough guide. Clin Infect Dis. 2011;52:911&#x2013;916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeling MJ, Rohani P. Modeling Infectious Diseases in Humans and Animals. 2008.Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delamater PL, Street EJ, Leslie TF, et al. Complexity of the basic reproduction number (R0). Emerg Infect Dis. 2019;25:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Z, Zhang W, Zhang D, et al. Estimating the basic reproduction rate of HFMD using the time series SIR model in Guangdong, China. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0179623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gargano LM, Underwood NL, Sales JM, et al. Influence of sources of information about influenza vaccine on parental attitudes and adolescent vaccine receipt. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2015;11:1641&#x2013;1647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calo WA, Gilkey MB, Shah P, et al. Parents&#x2019; willingness to get human papillomavirus vaccination for their adolescent children at a pharmacy. Prev Med. 2017;99:251&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Wang H, Lu Y, et al. Willingness and influential factors of parents to vaccinate their children with novel inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccines in Guangzhou, China. Vaccine. 2018;36:3772&#x2013;3778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Zhou Y, Cheng Y, et al. Effectiveness of EV-A71 vaccination in prevention of paediatric hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with EV-A71 virus infection requiring hospitalisation in Henan, China, 2017-18: a test-negative case-control study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2019;3:697&#x2013;704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Chang Z, Wu P, et al. Emerging enteroviruses causing hand, foot and mouth disease, China, 2010-2016. Emerg Infect Dis. 2018;24:1902&#x2013;1906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirand A, le Sage FV, Pereira B, et al. Ambulatory pediatric surveillance of hand, foot and mouth disease as signal of an outbreak of coxsackievirus A6 infections, France, 2014-2015. Emerg Infect Dis. 2016;22:1884&#x2013;1893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YQ, Xie GC, Li DD, et al. Prevalence of coxsackievirus A6 and enterovirus 71 in hand, foot and mouth disease in Nanjing, China in 2013. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2015;34:951&#x2013;957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singleton RJ, Hennessy TW, Bulkow LR, et al. Invasive pneumococcal disease caused by nonvaccine serotypes among alaska native children with high levels of 7-valent pneumococcal conjugate vaccine coverage. JAMA. 2007;297:1784&#x2013;1792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salleras L, Dom&#xed;nguez A, Ciruela P, et al. Changes in serotypes causing invasive pneumococcal disease (2005-2007 vs. 1997-1999) in children under 2 years of age in a population with intermediate coverage of the 7-valent pneumococcal conjugated vaccine. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2009;15:997&#x2013;1001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinberger DM, Malley R, Lipsitch M. Serotype replacement in disease after pneumococcal vaccination. Lancet. 2011;378:1962&#x2013;1973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian L, Gao F, Mao Q, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease associated with coxsackievirus A10: more serious than it seems. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2019;17:233&#x2013;242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broccolo F, Drago F, Ciccarese G, et al. Severe atypical hand-foot-and-mouth disease in adults due to coxsackievirus A6: clinical presentation and phylogenesis of CV-A6 strains. J Clin Virol. 2019;110:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Z, Zhao Y, Luo Y, et al. Ongoing change of severe hand, foot, and mouth disease pathogens in Yunnan, China, 2012 to 2016. J Med Virol. 2019;95:881&#x2013;885.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esposito S, Principi N. Hand, foot and mouth disease: current knowledge on clinical manifestations, epidemiology, aetiology and prevention. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2018;37:391&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YP, Liang ZL, Xia JL, et al. Immunogenicity, safety, and immune persistence of a novel inactivated human enterovirus 71 vaccine: a phase II, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Infect Dis. 2014;209:46&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, An Z, Huo D, et al. Enterovirus A71 vaccine effectiveness in preventing enterovirus A71 infection among medically-attended hand, foot, and mouth disease cases, Beijing, China. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2019;15:1183&#x2013;1190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Yang Z, DI B, et al. Hand-foot-and-mouth disease and weather factors in Guangzhou, southern China. Epidemiol Infect. 2014;142:1741&#x2013;1750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long L, Gao LD, Hu SX, et al. Risk factors for death in children with severe hand, foot, and mouth disease in Hunan, China. Infect Dis (Lond). 2016;48:744&#x2013;748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Guerche-S&#xe9;blain C, Caini S, Paget J, et al. Epidemiology and timing of seasonal influenza epidemics in the Asia-Pacific region, 2010-2017: implications for influenza vaccination programs. BMC Public Health. 2019;19:331.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>