<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27826325</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1738-1061</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>59</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Korean journal of pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Korean J Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enterovirus 71 infection and neurological complications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>395</StartPage><EndPage>401</EndPage><MedlinePgn>395-401</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Since the outbreak of the enterovirus 71 (EV71) infection in Malaysia in 1997, large epidemics of EV71 have occurred in the Asia-Pacific region. Many children and infants have died from serious neurological complications during these epidemics, and EV71 infection has become a serious public health problem in these areas. EV71 infection causes hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) in children, and usually resolves spontaneously. However, EV71 occasionally involves the central nervous system (CNS), and induces diverse neurological complications such as brainstem encephalitis, aseptic meningitis, and acute flaccid paralysis. Among those complications, brainstem encephalitis is the most critical neurological manifestation because it can cause neurogenic pulmonary hemorrhage/edema leading to death. The characteristic clinical symptoms such as myoclonus and ataxia, cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) pleocytosis, and brainstem lesions on magnetic resonance imaging, in conjunction with the skin rash of HFMD and the isolation of EV71 from a stool, throat-swab, or CSF sample are typical findings indicating CNS involvement of EV71 infection. Treatment with intravenous immunoglobulin and milrinone are recommended in cases with severe neurological complications from EV71 infection, such as brainstem encephalitis. Despite the recent discovery of receptors for EV71 in human cells, such as the scavenger receptor B2 and P-selection glycoprotein ligand 1, it is not known why EV71 infection predominantly involves the brainstem. Recently, 3 companies in China have completed phase III clinical trials of EV71 vaccines. However, the promotion and approval of these vaccines in various countries are problems yet to be resolved.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Kyung Yeon</ForeName><Initials>KY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Ulsan University Hospital, University of Ulsan College of Medicine, Ulsan, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Korean J Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101215374</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1738-1061</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain stem</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurological manifestations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary edema</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccines</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2015</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2015</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27826325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5099286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3345/kjp.2016.59.10.395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. The emergence of enterovirus 71 as a major cause of acute neurological disease in young children of the Asia-Pacific region. J Pediatr Infect Dis. 2006:17&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Lewthwaite P, Cardosa MJ, Solomon T. Clinical features, diagnosis, and management of enterovirus 71. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9:1097&#x2013;1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt NJ, Lennette EH, Ho HH. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J Infect Dis. 1974;129:304&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov M, Voroshilova M, Shindarov L, Lavrova I, Gracheva L, Koroleva G, et al. Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch Virol. 1979;60:329&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy G, Takatsy S, Kukan E, Mihaly I, Domok I. Virological diagnosis of enterovirus type 71 infections: experiences gained during an epidemic of acute CNS diseases in Hungary in 1978. Arch Virol. 1982;71:217&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6285858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan LG, Parashar UD, Lye MS, Ong FG, Zaki SR, Alexander JP, et al. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in sarawak, malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. For the Outbreak Study Group. Clin Infect Dis. 2000;31:678&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Ho MS, Lin KH, Wu SL, Chen YT, Wu CN, et al. Genetic analysis of enterovirus 71 isolated from fatal and non-fatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease during an epidemic in Taiwan, 1998. Virus Res. 2000;68:127&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10958984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, Twu SJ, Chen KT, Tsai SF, et al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P, Stratov I, Nagarajan L, Davis S. Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin Infect Dis. 2001;32:236&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng M, El Khatib NF, Tu S, Ren P, Xu S, Zhu Q, et al. Seroepidemiology of Enterovirus 71 infection prior to the 2011 season in children in Shanghai. J Clin Virol. 2012;53:285&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22265829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yip CC, Lau SK, Woo PC, Yuen KY. Human enterovirus 71 epidemics: what's next? Emerg Health Threats J. 2013;6:19780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24119538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Yeo A, Phoon MC, Tan EL, Poh CL, Quak SH, et al. The largest outbreak of hand; foot and mouth disease in Singapore in 2008: the role of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A strains. Int J Infect Dis. 2010;14:e1076&#x2013;e1081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20952237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thoa le PK, Chiang PS, Khanh TH, Luo ST, Dan TN, Wang YF, et al. Genetic and antigenic characterization of enterovirus 71 in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, 2011. PLoS One. 2013;8:e69895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3726754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23922846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiff A. Cambodia unravels cause of mystery illness. Lancet. 2012;380:206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22826834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowlkes AL, Honarmand S, Glaser C, Yagi S, Schnurr D, Oberste MS, et al. Enterovirus-associated encephalitis in the California encephalitis project, 1998-2005. J Infect Dis. 2008;198:1685&#x2013;1691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18959496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sanden S, Koopmans M, Uslu G, van der Avoort H. Epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in the Netherlands, 1963 to 2008. J Clin Microbiol. 2009;47:2826&#x2013;2833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2738086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirand A, Schuffenecker I, Henquell C, Billaud G, Jugie G, Falcon D, et al. Phylogenetic evidence for a recent spread of two populations of human enterovirus 71 in European countries. J Gen Virol. 2010;91(Pt 9):2263&#x2013;2277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20505012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witso E, Palacios G, Ronningen KS, Cinek O, Janowitz D, Rewers M, et al. Asymptomatic circulation of HEV71 in Norway. Virus Res. 2007;123:19&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16965832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bible JM, Iturriza-Gomara M, Megson B, Brown D, Pantelidis P, Earl P, et al. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 in the United Kingdom from 1998 to 2006. J Clin Microbiol. 2008;46:3192&#x2013;3200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2566106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18650362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapusinszky B, Szomor KN, Farkas A, Tak&#xe1;cs M, Berencsi G. Detection of non-polio enteroviruses in Hungary 2000-2008 and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71, coxsackievirus A16, and echovirus 30. Virus Genes. 2010;40:163&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20044791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siafakas N, Attilakos A, Vourli S, Stefos E, Meletiadis J, Nikolaidou P, et al. Molecular detection and identification of enteroviruses in children admitted to a university hospital in Greece. Mol Cell Probes. 2011;25:249&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21803150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu WS, Kang B, Hong J, Hwang S, Kim J, Cheon DS. Clinical and etiological characteristics of enterovirus 71-related diseases during a recent 2-year period in Korea. J Clin Microbiol. 2010;48:2490&#x2013;2494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2897491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20463159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi CS, Choi YJ, Choi UY, Han JW, Jeong DC, Kim HH, et al. Clinical manifestations of CNS infections caused by enterovirus type 71. Korean J Pediatr. 2011;54:11&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3040360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21359055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Liu CC. Enterovirus 71: epidemiology, pathogenesis and management. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2009;7:735&#x2013;742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19681701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Lin TY, Hsu KH, Huang YC, Lin KL, Hsueh C, et al. Clinical features and risk factors of pulmonary oedema after enterovirus-71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet. 1999;354:1682&#x2013;1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Hsia SH, Wu CT, Huang YC, Lin KL, Fang TY, et al. Outcome of enterovirus 71 infections with or without stage-based management: 1998 to 2002. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2004;23:327&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15071287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong P, Liu CC, Chow YH, Chou AH, Klein M. Review of enterovirus 71 vaccines. Clin Infect Dis. 2015;60:797&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25352588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen KT, Chang HL, Wang ST, Cheng YT, Yang JY. Epidemiologic features of hand-foot-mouth disease and herpangina caused by enterovirus 71 in Taiwan, 1998-2005. Pediatrics. 2007;120:e244&#x2013;e252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Liu CC, Tseng HW, Wang JR, Huang CC, Chen YJ, et al. Clinical spectrum of enterovirus 71 infection in children in southern Taiwan, with an emphasis on neurological complications. Clin Infect Dis. 1999;29:184&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10433583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Jiang L, Peng HL. Clinical analysis of 134 children with nervous system damage caused by enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2015;34:718&#x2013;723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25860536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KY, Lee YJ, Kim TH, Cheon DS, Nam SO. Clinico-radiological spectrum in enterovirus 71 infection involving the central nervous system in children. J Clin Neurosci. 2014;21:416&#x2013;420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24169271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Liu CC. Update of enterovirus 71 infection: epidemiology, pathogenesis and vaccine. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2014;12:447&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24579906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Tsao KC, Hsia SH, Shih SR, Huang CG, Chan WK, et al. Transmission and clinical features of enterovirus 71 infections in household contacts in Taiwan. JAMA. 2004;291:222&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14722149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MS, Chang LY. Development of enterovirus 71 vaccines. Expert Rev Vaccines. 2010;9:149&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20109026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Yamashita Y, Li J, Hanagata N, Minowa T, Takemura T, et al. Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat Med. 2009;15:798&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Shimojima M, Tano Y, Miyamura T, Wakita T, Shimizu H. Human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat Med. 2009;15:794&#x2013;797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Chang LY, Hsia SH, Huang YC, Chiu CH, Hsueh C, et al. The 1998 enterovirus 71 outbreak in Taiwan: pathogenesis and management. Clin Infect Dis. 2002;34(Suppl 2):S52&#x2013;S57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11938497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang MC, Wang SM, Hsu YW, Lin HC, Chi CY, Liu CC. Long-term cognitive and motor deficits after enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in children. Pediatrics. 2006;118:e1785&#x2013;e1788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17116698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KY, Yeh HR. Continuous myocloni and tonic spasms in a 2-month-old infant with enterovirus 71 brain stem encephalitis. Neuropediatrics. 2015;46:52&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25290724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho HK, Lee NY, Lee H, Kim HS, Seo JW, Hong YM, et al. Enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot and mouth diseases with neurologic symptoms, a university hospital experience in Korea, 2009. Korean J Pediatr. 2010;53:639&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2994124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21189930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen WC, Chiu HH, Chow KC, Tsai CH. MR imaging findings of enteroviral encephaloymelitis: an outbreak in Taiwan. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 1999;20:1889&#x2013;1895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7657785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10588115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang S, Suh SI, Ha SM, Byeon JH, Eun BL, Lee YH, et al. Enterovirus 71-related encephalomyelitis: usual and unusual magnetic resonance imaging findings. Neuroradiology. 2012;54:239&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21861081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Chen F, Liu T, Wang L. MRI findings of neurological complications in hand-foot-mouth disease by enterovirus 71 infection. Int J Neurosci. 2012;122:338&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22248036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng H, Wen F, Gan Y, Huang W. MRI and associated clinical characteristics of EV71-induced brainstem encephalitis in children with hand-foot-mouth disease. Neuroradiology. 2012;54:623&#x2013;630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22200974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian ZY, Huang B, He SR, Liang CH, Guo YX. Diffusion-weighted imaging in the diagnosis of enterovirus 71 encephalitis. Acta Radiol. 2012;53:208&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22184685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Chang LY, Huang YC, Hsu KH, Chiu CH, Yang KD. Different proinflammatory reactions in fatal and non-fatal enterovirus 71 infections: implications for early recognition and therapy. Acta Paediatr. 2002;91:632&#x2013;635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12162592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Hsia SH, Huang YC, Wu CT, Chang LY. Proinflammatory cytokine reactions in enterovirus 71 infections of the central nervous system. Clin Infect Dis. 2003;36:269&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12539066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Su LY, Wu JM, Yu CK, Wang JR, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid cytokines in enterovirus 71 brain stem encephalitis and echovirus meningitis infections of varying severity. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2007;13:677&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17441979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S, Fujii K, Koike S. Receptors for enterovirus 71. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2014;3:e53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4126179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26038749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YC, Yu CK, Wang YF, Liu CC, Su IJ, Lei HY. A murine oral enterovirus 71 infection model with central nervous system involvement. J Gen Virol. 2004;85(Pt 1):69&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14718621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung PW, Huang YC, Chang LY, Lin TY, Ning HC. Duration of enterovirus shedding in stool. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2001;34:167&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11605806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kung YA, Hung CT, Liu YC, Shih SR. Update on the development of enterovirus 71 vaccines. Expert Opin Biol Ther. 2014;14:1455&#x2013;1464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24989170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shipley JB, Tolman D, Hastillo A, Hess ML. Milrinone: basic and clinical pharmacology and acute and chronic management. Am J Med Sci. 1996;311:286&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8659556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong M, Lin XZ, Lu GT, Zheng LJ. Preoperative inhalation of milrinone attenuates inflammation in patients undergoing cardiac surgery with cardiopulmonary bypass. Med Princ Pract. 2012;21:30&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22024477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chi CY, Khanh TH, Thoa le PK, Tseng FC, Wang SM, Thinh le Q, et al. Milrinone therapy for enterovirus 71-induced pulmonary edema and/or neurogenic shock in children: a randomized controlled trial. Crit Care Med. 2013;41:1754&#x2013;1760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23685637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Huang MC, Wu JM, Chen CT, Wang JN, et al. Therapeutic efficacy of milrinone in the management of enterovirus 71-induced pulmonary edema. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2005;39:219&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15635619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Huang LM, Gau SS, Wu YY, Hsia SH, Fan TY, et al. Neurodevelopment and cognition in children after enterovirus 71 infection. N Engl J Med. 2007;356:1226&#x2013;1234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17377160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Meng FY, Li JX, Li XL, Mao QY, Tao H, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2013;381:2024&#x2013;2032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23726161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Liu L, Mo Z, Wang X, Xia J, Liang Z, et al. An inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:829&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F, Xu W, Xia J, Liang Z, Liu Y, Zhang X, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in China. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>