<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27087810</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1687-8639</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2016</Volume><PubDate><Year>2016</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advances in virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Direct Detection and Identification of Enteroviruses from Faeces of Healthy Nigerian Children Using a Cell-Culture Independent RT-Seminested PCR Assay.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1412838</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1412838</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1412838</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2016/1412838</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recently, a cell-culture independent protocol for detection of enteroviruses from clinical specimen was recommended by the WHO for surveillance alongside the previously established protocols. Here, we investigated whether this new protocol will show the same enterovirus diversity landscape as the established cell-culture dependent protocols. Faecal samples were collected from sixty apparently healthy children in Ibadan, Nigeria. Samples were resuspended in phosphate buffered saline, RNA was extracted, and the VP1 gene was amplified using WHO recommended RT-snPCR protocol. Amplicons were sequenced and sequences subjected to phylogenetic analysis. Fifteen (25%) of the 60 samples yielded the expected band size. Of the 15 amplicons sequenced, 12 were exploitable. The remaining 3 had electropherograms with multiple peaks and were unexploitable. Eleven of the 12 exploitable sequences were identified as Coxsackievirus A1 (CVA1), CVA3, CVA4, CVA8, CVA20, echovirus 32 (E32), enterovirus 71 (EV71), EVB80, and EVC99. Subsequently, the last exploitable sequence was identified as enterobacteriophage baseplate gene by nucleotide BLAST. The results of this study document the first description of molecular sequence data on CVA1, CVA8, and E32 strains present in Nigeria. The result further showed that species A enteroviruses were more commonly detected in the region when cell-culture bias is bypassed.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Faleye</LastName><ForeName>Temitope Oluwasegun Cephas</ForeName><Initials>TO</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7706-9493</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, College of Medicine, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria; Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Science, Ekiti State University, Ado Ekiti, Ekiti, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adewumi</LastName><ForeName>Moses Olubusuyi</ForeName><Initials>MO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, College of Medicine, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coker</LastName><ForeName>Bamidele Atinuke</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Science, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nudamajo</LastName><ForeName>Felix Yasha</ForeName><Initials>FY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Science, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adeniji</LastName><ForeName>Johnson Adekunle</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Virology, College of Medicine, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria; WHO National Polio Laboratory, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101508613</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1687-8639</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27087810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4818813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/1412838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tapparel C., Siegrist F., Petty T. J., Kaiser L. Picornavirus and enterovirus diversity with associated human diseases. Infection, Genetics and Evolution. 2013;14(1):282&#x2013;293. doi: 10.1016/j.meegid.2012.10.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.meegid.2012.10.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23201849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strikas R. A., Anderson L. J., Parker R. A. Temporal and geographic patterns of isolates of nonpolio enterovirus in the United States, 1970&#x2013;1983. Journal of Infectious Diseases. 1986;153(2):346&#x2013;351. doi: 10.1093/infdis/153.2.346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/153.2.346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3003207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathanson N., Kew O. M. From emergence to eradication: the epidemiology of poliomyelitis deconstructed. American Journal of Epidemiology. 2010;172(11):1213&#x2013;1229. doi: 10.1093/aje/kwq320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwq320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2991634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20978089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation. Enterovirus Surveillance Guidelines: Guidelines for Enterovirus Surveillance in Support of the Polio Eradication Initiative. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organisation; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilpatrick D. R., Nottay B., Yang C.-F., et al. Serotype-specific identification of polioviruses by PCR using primers containing mixed-base or deoxyinosine residues at positions of codon degeneracy. Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 1998;36(2):352&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9466740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste M. S., Maher K., Kilpatrick D. R., Pallansch M. A. Molecular evolution of the human enteroviruses: correlation of serotype with VP1 sequence and application to picornavirus classification. Journal of Virology. 1999;73(3):1941&#x2013;1948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9971773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste M. S., Maher K., Flemister M. R., Marchetti G., Kilpatrick D. R., Pallansch M. A. Comparison of classic and molecular approaches for the identification of untypeable enteroviruses. Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 2000;38(3):1170&#x2013;1174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC86366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10699015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste M. S., Schnurr D., Maher K., al-Busaidy S., Pallansch M. A. Molecular identification of new picornaviruses and characterization of a proposed enterovirus 73 serotype. Journal of General Virology. 2001;82(2):409&#x2013;416. doi: 10.1099/0022-1317-82-2-409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/0022-1317-82-2-409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11161280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste M. S., Nix W. A., Maher K., Pallansch M. A. Improved molecular identification of enteroviruses by RT-PCR and amplicon sequencing. Journal of Clinical Virology. 2003;26(3):375&#x2013;377. doi: 10.1016/S1386-6532(03)00004-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1386-6532(03)00004-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12637088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casas I., Palacios G. F., Trallero G., Cisterna D., Freire M. C., Tenorio A. Molecular characterization of human enteroviruses in clinical samples: comparison between VP2, VP1, and RNA polymerase regions using RT nested PCR assays and direct sequencing of products. Journal of Medical Virology. 2001;65(1):138&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11505456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norder H., Bjerregaard L., Magnius L. O. Homotypic echoviruses share aminoterminal VP1 sequence homology applicable for typing. Journal of Medical Virology. 2001;63(1):35&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1002/1096-9071(200101)63:1&lt;35::AID-JMV1005&gt;3.0.CO;2-Q.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1096-9071(200101)63:1&lt;35::AID-JMV1005&gt;3.0.CO;2-Q</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11130885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caro V., Guillot S., Delpeyroux F., Crainic R. Molecular strategy for 'serotyping' of human enteroviruses. Journal of General Virology. 2001;82(1):79&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1099/0022-1317-82-1-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/0022-1317-82-1-79</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11125161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thoelen I., Lemey P., Van der Donck I., Beuselinck K., Lindberg A. M., Van Ranst M. Molecular typing and epidemiology of enteroviruses identified from an outbreak of aseptic meningitis in Belgium during the summer of 2000. Journal of Medical Virology. 2003;70(3):420&#x2013;429. doi: 10.1002/jmv.10412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.10412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12767006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomqvist S., Paananen A., Savolainen-Kopra C., Hovi T., Roivainen M. Eight years of experience with molecular identification of human enteroviruses. Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 2008;46(7):2410&#x2013;2413. doi: 10.1128/JCM.00313-08.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00313-08</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2446933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18463218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyero O. G., Adu F. D., Ayukekbong J. A. Molecular characterization of diverse species enterovirus-B types from children with acute flaccid paralysis and asymptomatic children in Nigeria. Virus Research. 2014;189:189&#x2013;193. doi: 10.1016/j.virusres.2014.05.029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.virusres.2014.05.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24915283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeniji J. A., Faleye T. O. C. Isolation and identification of enteroviruses from sewage and sewage contaminated water in Lagos, Nigeria. Food and Environmental Virology. 2014;6(2):75&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1007/s12560-014-9137-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12560-014-9137-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24566762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell E. J., Cosgrove B. P. Routine enterovirus diagnosis in a human rhabdomyosarcoma cell line. Bulletin of the World Health Organization. 1980;58(3):423&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2395914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6251982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamparian V. V., Ottolenghi A. C., Hughes J. H. Enteroviruses in sludge: multiyear experience with four wastewater treatment plants. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 1985;50(2):280&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC238616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2996422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bessaud M., Pillet S., Ibrahim W., et al. Molecular characterization of human enteroviruses in the Central African Republic: uncovering wide diversity and identification of a new human enterovirus A71 genogroup. Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 2012;50(5):1650&#x2013;1658. doi: 10.1128/jcm.06657-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jcm.06657-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3347117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22337981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao D. C., Ananda Babu M., Raghavendra A., Dhananjaya D., Kumar S., Maiya P. P. Non-polio enteroviruses and their association with acute diarrhea in children in India. Infection, Genetics and Evolution. 2013;17:153&#x2013;161. doi: 10.1016/j.meegid.2013.04.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.meegid.2013.04.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23602838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeuh-Mba S. A., Bessaud M., Massenet D., et al. High frequency and diversity of species C enteroviruses in Cameroon and neighboring countries. Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 2013;51(3):759&#x2013;770. doi: 10.1128/JCM.02119-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.02119-12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3592076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23254123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeniji J. A., Faleye T. O. Impact of cell lines included in enterovirus isolation protocol on perception of nonpolio enterovirus species C diversity. Journal of Virological Methods. 2014;207:238&#x2013;247. doi: 10.1016/j.jviromet.2014.07.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jviromet.2014.07.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25064357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyero O. G., Adu F. D. Non-polio enteroviruses serotypes circulating in Nigeria. African Journal of Medicine and Medical Sciences. 2010;39(supplement):201&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22416664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baba M. M., Oderinde B. S., Patrick P. Z., Jarmai M. M. Sabin and wild polioviruses from apparently healthy primary school children in northeastern Nigeria. Journal of Medical Virology. 2012;84(2):358&#x2013;364. doi: 10.1002/jmv.23184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmv.23184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22170559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nix W. A., Oberste M. S., Pallansch M. A. Sensitive, seminested PCR amplification of VP1 sequences for direct identification of all enterovirus serotypes from original clinical specimens. Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 2006;44(8):2698&#x2013;2704. doi: 10.1128/jcm.00542-06.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jcm.00542-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1594621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16891480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organisation. Guidelines for Environmental Surveillance of Poliovirus Circulation. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organisation; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organzation. Polio Laboratory Manual. 4th. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organzation; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroneman A., Vennema H., Deforche K., et al. An automated genotyping tool for enteroviruses and noroviruses. Journal of Clinical Virology. 2011;51(2):121&#x2013;125. doi: 10.1016/j.jcv.2011.03.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcv.2011.03.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21514213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamura K., Peterson D., Peterson N., Stecher G., Nei M., Kumar S. MEGA5: molecular evolutionary genetics analysis using maximum likelihood, evolutionary distance, and maximum parsimony methods. Molecular Biology and Evolution. 2011;28(10):2731&#x2013;2739. doi: 10.1093/molbev/msr121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/molbev/msr121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3203626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21546353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura M. A simple method for estimating evolutionary rates of base substitutions through comparative studies of nucleotide sequences. Journal of Molecular Evolution. 1980;16(2):111&#x2013;120. doi: 10.1007/bf01731581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/bf01731581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7463489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao C. D., Yergolkar P., Subbanna K. S. Antigenic diversity of enteroviruses associated with nonpolio acute flaccid paralysis, India, 2007&#x2013;2009. Emerging Infectious Diseases. 2012;18(11):1833&#x2013;1840. doi: 10.3201/eid1811.111457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid1811.111457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3559176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23092622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste M. S., Maher K., Williams A. J., et al. Species-specific RT-PCR amplification of human enterovirus: a tool for rapid species identification of uncharacterized enteroviruses. Journal of General Virology. 2006;87(1):119&#x2013;128. doi: 10.1099/vir.0.81179-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/vir.0.81179-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16361424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeniji J. A., Faleye T. O. C. Enterovirus C strains circulating in Nigeria and their contribution to the emergence of recombinant circulating vaccine-derived polioviruses. Archives of Virology. 2015;160(3):675&#x2013;683. doi: 10.1007/s00705-014-2322-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00705-014-2322-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25559670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bessaud M., Razafindratsimandresy R., Nougair&#xe8;de A., et al. Molecular comparison and evolutionary analyses of VP1 nucleotide sequences of new African human enterovirus 71 isolates reveal a wide genetic diversity. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(3) doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0090624.e90624</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0090624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3944068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24598878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M., Kilpatrick D. R., Nakamura T., et al. Development of an efficient entire-capsid-coding-region amplification method for direct detection of poliovirus from stool extracts. Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 2015;53(1):73&#x2013;78. doi: 10.1128/jcm.02384-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/jcm.02384-14</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4290957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25339406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>