<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">25880767</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1935-2735</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PLoS neglected tropical diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS Negl Trop Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neglected tropical diseases among the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN): overview and update.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0003575</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0003575</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0003575</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pntd.0003575</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The ten member states of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) constitute an economic powerhouse, yet these countries also harbor a mostly hidden burden of poverty and neglected tropical diseases (NTDs). Almost 200 million people live in extreme poverty in ASEAN countries, mostly in the low or lower middle-income countries of Indonesia, the Philippines, Myanmar, Viet Nam, and Cambodia, and many of them are affected by at least one NTD. However, NTDs are prevalent even among upper middle-income ASEAN countries such as Malaysia and Thailand, especially among the indigenous populations. The three major intestinal helminth infections are the most common NTDs; each helminthiasis is associated with approximately 100 million infections in the region. In addition, more than 10 million people suffer from either liver or intestinal fluke infections, as well as schistosomiasis and lymphatic filariasis (LF). Intestinal protozoan infections are widespread, while leishmaniasis has emerged in Thailand, and zoonotic malaria (Plasmodium knowlesi infection) causes severe morbidity in Malaysia. Melioidosis has emerged as an important bacterial NTD, as have selected rickettsial infections, and leptospirosis. Leprosy, yaws, and trachoma are still endemic in focal areas. Almost 70 million cases of dengue fever occur annually in ASEAN countries, such that this arboviral infection is now one of the most common and economically important NTDs in the region. A number of other arboviral and zoonotic viral infections have also emerged, including Japanese encephalitis; tick-borne viral infections; Nipah virus, a zoonosis present in fruit bats; and enterovirus 71 infection. There are urgent needs to expand surveillance activities in ASEAN countries, as well as to ensure mass drug administration is provided to populations at risk for intestinal helminth and fluke infections, LF, trachoma, and yaws. An ASEAN Network for Drugs, Diagnostics, Vaccines, and Traditional Medicines Innovation provides a policy framework for the development of new control and elimination tools. Together with prominent research institutions and universities, the World Health Organization (WHO), and its regional offices, these organizations could implement important public health improvements through NTD control and elimination in the coming decade.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hotez</LastName><ForeName>Peter J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sabin Vaccine Institute and Texas Children's Hospital Center for Vaccine Development, Departments of Pediatrics and Molecular Virology and Microbiology, National School of Tropical Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas, United States of America; Department of Biology, Baylor University, Waco, Texas, United States of America; James A. Baker III Institute for Public Policy, Rice University, Houston, Texas, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bottazzi</LastName><ForeName>Maria Elena</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sabin Vaccine Institute and Texas Children's Hospital Center for Vaccine Development, Departments of Pediatrics and Molecular Virology and Microbiology, National School of Tropical Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas, United States of America; Department of Biology, Baylor University, Waco, Texas, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strych</LastName><ForeName>Ulrich</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sabin Vaccine Institute and Texas Children's Hospital Center for Vaccine Development, Departments of Pediatrics and Molecular Virology and Microbiology, National School of Tropical Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Li-Yen</ForeName><Initials>LY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tropical Infectious Diseases Research and Education Centre, Department of Medical Microbiology, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>Yvonne A L</ForeName><Initials>YA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Parasitology, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goodenow</LastName><ForeName>Maureen M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Immunology, and Laboratory Medicine, University of Florida, College of Medicine, Gainesville, Florida, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>AbuBakar</LastName><ForeName>Sazaly</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tropical Infectious Diseases Research and Education Centre, Department of Medical Microbiology, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2015</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS Negl Trop Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101291488</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1935-2727</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001210" MajorTopicYN="N">Asia, Southeastern</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003140" MajorTopicYN="N">Communicable Disease Control</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058069" MajorTopicYN="N">Neglected Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012959" MajorTopicYN="N">Socioeconomic Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014330" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tropical Medicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interest exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25880767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4400050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0003575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PNTD-D-14-01710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ASEAN Secretariat hwao. (2014) Association of Southeast Asian Nations. http://www.asean.org/. Accessed September 11, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Central Intelligence Agency. The World Factbook. https://www.cia.gov/library/publications/the-world-factbook/wfbExt/region_eas.html. Accessed June 15, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worldometers. Current World Population. http://www.worldometers.info/world-population/. Accessed September 11, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>OECD. ASEAN countries returning to pre-crisis growth. http://www.oecd.org/dev/aseancountriesreturningtopre-crisisgrowth.htm. Accessed June 27, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The World Bank Group. (2014) Poverty headcount ratio at $1.25 a day (PPP) (% of population). http://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SI.POV.DDAY. Accessed June 15, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group TWB. (2014) Poverty headcount at $2 a day (PPP) (% of population). http://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SI.POV.2DAY. Accessed September 11, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations. (2014) Resources for Speakers on Global Issues, Hunger, Vital Statistics. http://www.un.org/en/globalissues/briefingpapers/food/vitalstats.shtml. Accessed June 27, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngui R, Lim YA, Chong Kin L, Sek Chuen C, Jaffar S (2012) Association between anaemia, iron deficiency anaemia, neglected parasitic infections and socioeconomic factors in rural children of West Malaysia. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 6: e1550 10.1371/journal.pntd.0001550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0001550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3295806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22413027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngui R, Ishak S, Chuen CS, Mahmud R, Lim YA (2011) Prevalence and risk factors of intestinal parasitism in rural and remote West Malaysia. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 5: e974 10.1371/journal.pntd.0000974</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0000974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3046966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21390157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narain JP, Dash AP, Parnell B, Bhattacharya SK, Barua S, Bhatia R, et al. (2010) Elimination of neglected tropical diseases in the South-East Asia Region of the World Health Organization. Bull World Health Organ 88: 206&#x2013;210. 10.2471/BLT.09.072322</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2471/BLT.09.072322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2828791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20428388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotez PJ, Ehrenberg JP (2010) Escalating the global fight against neglected tropical diseases through interventions in the Asia Pacific region. Adv Parasitol 72: 31&#x2013;53. 10.1016/S0065-308X(10)72002-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0065-308X(10)72002-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20624527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pullan RL, Smith JL, Jasrasaria R, Brooker SJ (2014) Global numbers of infection and disease burden of soil transmitted helminth infections in 2010. Parasit Vectors 7: 37 10.1186/1756-3305-7-37</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-3305-7-37</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3905661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24447578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngui R, Ching LS, Kai TT, Roslan MA, Lim YA (2012) Molecular identification of human hookworm infections in economically disadvantaged communities in Peninsular Malaysia. Am J Trop Med Hyg 86: 837&#x2013;842. 10.4269/ajtmh.2012.11-0446</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.2012.11-0446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3335690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22556084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngui R, Lim YA, Traub R, Mahmud R, Mistam MS (2012) Epidemiological and genetic data supporting the transmission of Ancylostoma ceylanicum among human and domestic animals. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 6: e1522 10.1371/journal.pntd.0001522</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0001522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3274503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22347515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim YA, Romano N, Colin N, Chow SC, Smith HV (2009) Intestinal parasitic infections amongst Orang Asli (indigenous) in Malaysia: has socioeconomic development alleviated the problem? Trop Biomed 26: 110&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19901897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezeamama AE, Friedman JF, Acosta LP, Bellinger DC, Langdon GC, Manalo DL, et al. (2005) Helminth infection and cognitive impairment among Filipino children. Am J Trop Med Hyg 72: 540&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1382476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15891127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezeamama AE, Friedman JF, Olveda RM, Acosta LP, Kurtis JD, Mor V, et al. (2005) Functional significance of low-intensity polyparasite helminth infections in anemia. J Infect Dis 192: 2160&#x2013;2170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16288383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakti H, Nokes C, Hertanto WS, Hendratno S, Hall A, Bundy DA, et al. (1999) Evidence for an association between hookworm infection and cognitive function in Indonesian school children. Trop Med Int Health 4: 322&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10402967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad AF, Hadip F, Ngui R, Lim YA, Mahmud R (2013) Serological and molecular detection of Strongyloides stercoralis infection among an Orang Asli community in Malaysia. Parasitol Res 112: 2811&#x2013;2816. 10.1007/s00436-013-3450-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-013-3450-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23666229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romano N, Nor Azah MO, Rahmah N, Lim YA, Rohela M (2010) Seroprevalence of toxocariasis among Orang Asli (Indigenous people) in Malaysia using two immunoassays. Trop Biomed 27: 585&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21399601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2014) Neglected Tropical Diseases, PCT databank, Soil-transmitted helminthiases. http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/preventive_chemotherapy/sth/en/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>(2014) Soil-transmitted helminthiases: number of children treated in 2012. Weekly Epidemiol Rec 89: 133&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24707519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2014) Neglected tropical diseases, PCT databank, Lymphatic filariasis. http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/preventive_chemotherapy/lf/en/. Accessed July 4, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2013) Rolling out and scaling up integrated preventive chemotherapy for selected neglected tropical diseases. Wkly Epidemiol Rec 88: 161&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23620908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu S, Nutman TB (2012) Immunopathogenesis of lymphatic filarial disease. Semin Immunopathol 34: 847&#x2013;861. 10.1007/s00281-012-0346-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00281-012-0346-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3498535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23053393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2010) Global Programme to eliminate Lymphatic Filariasis: Progress report 2000&#x2013;2009 and strategic plan 2010&#x2013;2020. http://www.searo.who.int/entity/vector_borne_tropical_diseases/topics/lymphatic_filariasis/LFREP.pdf. Accessed November 18, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, Savioli L, Daumerie D, World Health Organization. Department of Control of Neglected Tropical Diseases. (2013) Sustaining the drive to overcome the global impact of neglected tropical diseases: second WHO report on neglected tropical diseases Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization; xii, 138 pages p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furst T, Keiser J, Utzinger J (2012) Global burden of human food-borne trematodiasis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Infect Dis 12: 210&#x2013;221. 10.1016/S1473-3099(11)70294-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(11)70294-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22108757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miwa M, Honjo S, You G, Tanaka M, Uchida K, Srivatanakul P, et al. (2014) Genetic and environmental determinants of risk for cholangiocarcinoma in Thailand. World J Gastrointest Pathophysiol 5: 570&#x2013;578. 10.4291/wjgp.v5.i4.570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4291/wjgp.v5.i4.570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4231521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25401000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sripa B, Tangkawattana S, Laha T, Kaewkes S, Mallory FF, Smith JF, et al. (2014) Toward integrated opisthorchiasis control in Northeast Thailand: The Lawa project. Acta Trop.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4454771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25102053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bragazzi MC, Cardinale V, Carpino G, Venere R, Semeraro R, Gentile R, et al. (2012) Cholangiocarcinoma: Epidemiology and risk factors. Transl Gastrointest Cancer 1: 21&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonardo L, Rivera P, Saniel O, Villacorte E, Lebanan MA, Crisostomo B, et al. (2012) A national baseline prevalence survey of schistosomiasis in the Philippines using stratified two-step systematic cluster sampling design. J Trop Med 2012: 936128 10.1155/2012/936128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/936128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3306976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2014) Neglected tropical diseases, PCT databank, Schistosomiasis. http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/preventive_chemotherapy/sch/en/. Accessed July 4, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross AG, Olveda RM, Chy D, Olveda DU, Li Y, Harn DA, et al. (2014) Can Mass Drug Administration Lead to the Sustainable Control of Schistosomiasis? J Infect Dis.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25070942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eamsobhana P (2013) Angiostrongyliasis in Thailand: epidemiology and laboratory investigations. Hawaii J Med Public Health 72: 28&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3689488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23901379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trung DD, Praet N, Cam TD, Lam BV, Manh HN, Gabri&#xeb;l S, et al. (2013) Assessing the burden of human cysticercosis in Vietnam. Trop Med Int Health 18: 352&#x2013;356. 10.1111/tmi.12043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tmi.12043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23279716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wandra T, Sudewi AA, Swastika IK, Sutisna P, Dharmawan NS, Yulfi H, et al. (2011) Taeniasis/cysticercosis in Bali, Indonesia. Southeast Asian J Trop Med Public Health 42: 793&#x2013;802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22299461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManus DP (2010) Echinococcosis with particular reference to Southeast Asia. Adv Parasitol 72: 267&#x2013;303. 10.1016/S0065-308X(10)72010-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0065-308X(10)72010-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20624535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leelayoova S, Siripattanapipong S, Hitakarun A, Kato H, Tan-ariya P, Siriyasatien P, et al. (2013) Multilocus characterization and phylogenetic analysis of Leishmania siamensis isolated from autochthonous visceral leishmaniasis cases, southern Thailand. BMC Microbiol 13: 60 10.1186/1471-2180-13-60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2180-13-60</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3724499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23506297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kattipathanapong P, Akaraphanth R, Krudsood S, Riganti M, Viriyavejakul P (2012) The first reported case of autochthonous cutaneous leishmaniasis in Thailand. Southeast Asian J Trop Med Public Health 43: 17&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23082549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Harazi T, Ghani MK, Othman H (2013) Prevalence of intestinal protozoan infections among Orang Asli schoolchildren in Pos Senderut, Pahang, Malaysia. J Egypt Soc Parasitol 43: 561&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24640856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mekhlafi HM, Al-Maktari MT, Jani R, Ahmed A, Anuar TS, Moktar N, et al. (2013) Burden of Giardia duodenalis infection and its adverse effects on growth of schoolchildren in rural Malaysia. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 7: e2516 10.1371/journal.pntd.0002516</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0002516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3814875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24205426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mekhlafi HM, Mahdy MA, Azlin MY, Fatmah MS, Norhayati M (2011) Childhood Cryptosporidium infection among aboriginal communities in Peninsular Malaysia. Ann Trop Med Parasitol 105: 135&#x2013;143. 10.1179/136485911X12899838683368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/136485911X12899838683368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4084658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21396250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pipatsatitpong D, Rangsin R, Leelayoova S, Naaglor T, Mungthin M (2012) Incidence and risk factors of Blastocystis infection in an orphanage in Bangkok, Thailand. Parasit Vectors 5: 37 10.1186/1756-3305-5-37</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-3305-5-37</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3299613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22330427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandramathi S, Suresh K, Sivanandam S, Kuppusamy UR (2014) Stress exacerbates infectivity and pathogenicity of Blastocystis hominis: in vitro and in vivo evidences. PLoS One 9: e94567 10.1371/journal.pone.0094567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0094567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24788756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandramathi S, Suresh K, Anita ZB, Kuppusamy UR (2012) Infections of Blastocystis hominis and microsporidia in cancer patients: are they opportunistic? Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg 106: 267&#x2013;269. 10.1016/j.trstmh.2011.12.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trstmh.2011.12.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22340948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idris NS, Dwipoerwantoro PG, Kurniawan A, Said M (2010) Intestinal parasitic infection of immunocompromised children with diarrhoea: clinical profile and therapeutic response. J Infect Dev Ctries 4: 309&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20539063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurniawan A, Karyadi T, Dwintasari SW, Sari IP, Yunihastuti E, Djauzi S, et al. (2009) Intestinal parasitic infections in HIV/AIDS patients presenting with diarrhoea in Jakarta, Indonesia. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg 103: 892&#x2013;898. 10.1016/j.trstmh.2009.02.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trstmh.2009.02.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19327806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onichandran S, Kumar T, Salibay CC, Dungca JZ, Tabo HA, Tabo N, et al. (2014) Waterborne parasites: a current status from the Philippines. Parasit Vectors 7: 244 10.1186/1756-3305-7-244</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-3305-7-244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4049382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24885105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar T, Onichandran S, Lim YA, Sawangjaroen N, Ithoi I, Andiappan H, et al. (2014) Comparative study on waterborne parasites between Malaysia and Thailand: A new insight. Am J Trop Med Hyg 90: 682&#x2013;689. 10.4269/ajtmh.13-0266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.13-0266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3973513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24567315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngui R, Lim YA, Amir NF, Nissapatorn V, Mahmud R (2011) Seroprevalence and sources of toxoplasmosis among Orang Asli (indigenous) communities in Peninsular Malaysia. Am J Trop Med Hyg 85: 660&#x2013;666. 10.4269/ajtmh.2011.11-0058</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.2011.11-0058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3183774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21976569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2013) WHO Global Malaria Programme World Malaria Report 2013. Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2014) Global Health Observatory Data Repository, Estimated cases Data by country. http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.A1372?lang=en. Accessed September 11, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2014) Global Health Observatory (GHO) Number of malaria cases.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B, Daneshvar C (2013) Human infections and detection of Plasmodium knowlesi. Clin Microbiol Rev 26: 165&#x2013;184. 10.1128/CMR.00079-12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CMR.00079-12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3623376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23554413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moyes CL, Henry AJ, Golding N, Huang Z, Singh B, Baird JK, et al. (2014) Defining the geographical range of the Plasmodium knowlesi reservoir. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 8: e2780 10.1371/journal.pntd.0002780</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0002780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3967999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24676231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusof R, Lau YL, Mahmud R, Fong MY, Jelip J, Ngian HU, et al. (2014) High proportion of knowlesi malaria in recent malaria cases in Malaysia. Malar J 13: 168 10.1186/1475-2875-13-168</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-2875-13-168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4016780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24886266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASEAN Affairs. (2014) Is Tuberculosis still a threat? http://www.aseanaffairs.com/page/1161183. Accessed September 11, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng KP, Yew SM, Chan CL, Chong J, Tang SN, Soo-Hoo TS, et al. (2013) Draft Genome Sequence of the First Isolate of Extensively Drug-Resistant (XDR) Mycobacterium tuberculosis in Malaysia. Genome Announc 1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3569299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23405310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merritt RW, Walker ED, Small PL, Wallace JR, Johnson PD, Benbow ME, et al. (2010) Ecology and transmission of Buruli ulcer disease: a systematic review. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 4: e911 10.1371/journal.pntd.0000911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0000911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3001905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21179505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan M, Kusriastuti R, Savioli L, Hotez PJ (2014) Indonesia: an emerging market economy beset by neglected tropical diseases (NTDs). PLoS Negl Trop Dis 8: e2449 10.1371/journal.pntd.0002449</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0002449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3937254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24587452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotez PJ, Dumonteil E, Betancourt Cravioto M, Bottazzi ME, Tapia-Conyer R, Meymandi S, et al. (2013) An unfolding tragedy of Chagas disease in North America. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 7: e2300 10.1371/journal.pntd.0002300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0002300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3814410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24205411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2014) Neglected tropical diseases, PCT databank, Trachoma. http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/preventive_chemotherapy/trachoma/en/. Accessed June 27, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acestor N, Cooksey R, Newton PN, Menard D, Guerin PJ, Nakagawa J, et al. (2012) Mapping the aetiology of non-malarial febrile illness in Southeast Asia through a systematic review&#x2014;terra incognita impairing treatment policies. PLoS One 7: e44269 10.1371/journal.pone.0044269</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0044269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3435412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22970193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aung AK, Spelman DW, Murray RJ, Graves S (2014) Rickettsial Infections in Southeast Asia: Implications for Local Populace and Febrile Returned Travelers. Am J Trop Med Hyg 91: 451&#x2013;460. 10.4269/ajtmh.14-0191</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.14-0191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4155544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24957537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currie BJ, Dance DA, Cheng AC (2008) The global distribution of Burkholderia pseudomallei and melioidosis: an update. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg 102 Suppl 1: S1&#x2013;4. 10.1016/S0035-9203(08)70002-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0035-9203(08)70002-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19121666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limmathurotsakul D, Wongratanacheewin S, Teerawattanasook N, Wongsuvan G, Chaisuksant S, Chetchotisakd P, et al. (2010) Increasing incidence of human melioidosis in Northeast Thailand. Am J Trop Med Hyg 82: 1113&#x2013;1117. 10.4269/ajtmh.2010.10-0038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.2010.10-0038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2877420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20519609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limmathurotsakul D, Dance DA, Wuthiekanun V, Kaestli M, Mayo M, Warner J, et al. (2013) Systematic review and consensus guidelines for environmental sampling of Burkholderia pseudomallei. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 7: e2105 10.1371/journal.pntd.0002105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0002105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3605150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23556010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito M, Miyahara S, Villanueva SY, Aramaki N, Ikejiri M, Kobayashi Y, et al. (2014) PCR and culture identification of pathogenic Leptospira from coastal soil in Leyte, Philippines after a storm surge during Super Typhoon Haiyan (Yolanda). Appl Environ Microbiol.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4248998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25172869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaipadungpanit J, Wuthiekanun V, Chantratita N, Yimsamran S, Amornchai P, Boonsilp S, et al. (2013) Leptospira species in floodwater during the 2011 floods in the Bangkok Metropolitan Region, Thailand. Am J Trop Med Hyg 89: 794&#x2013;796. 10.4269/ajtmh.13-0124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.13-0124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3795115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24002484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendoza MT, Roxas EA, Ginete JK, Alejandria MM, Roman AD, Leyritana KT, et al. (2013) Clinical profile of patients diagnosed with leptospirosis after a typhoon: a multicenter study. Southeast Asian J Trop Med Public Health 44: 1021&#x2013;1035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24450239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thayaparan S, Robertson ID, Fairuz A, Suut L, Abdullah MT (2013) Leptospirosis, an emerging zoonotic disease in Malaysia. Malays J Pathol 35: 123&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24362475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt S, Gething PW, Brady OJ, Messina JP, Farlow AW, Moyes C, et al. (2013) The global distribution and burden of dengue. Nature 496: 504&#x2013;507. 10.1038/nature12060</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature12060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3651993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23563266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepard DS, Undurraga EA, Halasa YA (2013) Economic and disease burden of dengue in Southeast Asia. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 7: e2055 10.1371/journal.pntd.0002055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0002055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3578748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23437406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dash AP, Bhatia R, Sunyoto T, Mourya DT (2013) Emerging and re-emerging arboviral diseases in Southeast Asia. J Vector Borne Dis 50: 77&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23995308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myint KS, Kosasih H, Artika IM, Perkasa A, Puspita M, Ma'roef CN, et al. (2014) West Nile virus documented in Indonesia from acute febrile illness specimens. Am J Trop Med Hyg 90: 260&#x2013;262. 10.4269/ajtmh.13-0445</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.13-0445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3919227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24420775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie JS, Williams DT (2009) The zoonotic flaviviruses of southern, south-eastern and eastern Asia, and Australasia: the potential for emergent viruses. Zoonoses Public Health 56: 338&#x2013;356. 10.1111/j.1863-2378.2008.01208.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1863-2378.2008.01208.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19486319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weissenb&#xf6;ck H, Hub&#xe1;lek Z, Bakonyi T, Nowotny N (2010) Zoonotic mosquito-borne flaviviruses: worldwide presence of agents with proven pathogenicity and potential candidates of future emerging diseases. Vet Microbiol 140: 271&#x2013;280. 10.1016/j.vetmic.2009.08.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vetmic.2009.08.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19762169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu XB, Na RH, Wei SS, Zhu JS, Peng HJ (2013) Distribution of tick-borne diseases in China. Parasit Vectors 6: 119 10.1186/1756-3305-6-119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-3305-6-119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3640964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23617899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshii K, Mottate K, Omori-Urabe Y, Chiba Y, Seto T, Sanada T, et al. (2011) Epizootiological study of tick-borne encephalitis virus infection in Japan. J Vet Med Sci 73: 409&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21060247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar S, Chang LY, Ali AR, Sharifah SH, Yusoff K, Zamrod Z. (2004) Isolation and molecular identification of Nipah virus from pigs. Emerg Infect Dis 10: 2228&#x2013;2230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3323361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15663869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar S, Chee HY, Al-Kobaisi MF, Xiaoshan J, Chua KB, Lam SK. (1999) Identification of enterovirus 71 isolates from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) with fatal cases of encephalomyelitis in Malaysia. Virus Res 61: 1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10426204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (2013) Japanese encephalitis surveillance and immunization&#x2014;Asia and the Western Pacific, 2012. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 62: 658&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4604796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23965828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labeaud AD, Bashir F, King CH (2011) Measuring the burden of arboviral diseases: the spectrum of morbidity and mortality from four prevalent infections. Popul Health Metr 9: 1 10.1186/1478-7954-9-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1478-7954-9-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3024945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21219615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu ZF (2008) The rabies situation in Far East Asia. Dev Biol (Basel) 131: 55&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18634466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimaano EM, Scholand SJ, Alera MT, Belandres DB (2011) Clinical and epidemiological features of human rabies cases in the Philippines: a review from 1987 to 2006. Int J Infect Dis 15: e495&#x2013;499. 10.1016/j.ijid.2011.03.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2011.03.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21600825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngui R, Shafie A, Chua KH, Mistam MS, Al-Mekhlafi HM, Sulaiman WW, et al. (2014) Mapping and modelling the geographical distribution of soil-transmitted helminthiases in Peninsular Malaysia: implications for control approaches. Geospat Health 8: 365&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24893014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>USAID's NTD Program. (2014) Countries Supported by USAID's NTD Program. http://www.neglecteddiseases.gov/countries/index.html. Accessed</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotez PJ (2014) Could nitazoxanide be added to other essential medicines for integrated neglected tropical disease control and elimination? PLoS Negl Trop Dis 8: e2758 10.1371/journal.pntd.0002758</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0002758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3967954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24675990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speich B, Ame SM, Ali SM, Alles R, Hattendorf J, Utzinger J, et al. (2012) Efficacy and safety of nitazoxanide, albendazole, and nitazoxanide-albendazole against Trichuris trichiura infection: a randomized controlled trial. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 6: e1685 10.1371/journal.pntd.0001685</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0001685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3367984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22679525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman MC, Ogden S, Jacobson J, Abbott D, Addiss DG, Amnie AG, et al. (2013) Integration of water, sanitation, and hygiene for the prevention and control of neglected tropical diseases: a rationale for inter-sectoral collaboration. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 7: e2439 10.1371/journal.pntd.0002439</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0002439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3784463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24086781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou XN, Olveda R, Sripa B, Yang GJ, Leonardo L, Bergquist R. (2013) From gap analysis to solution and action: The RNAS model. Acta Trop.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23831926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olveda R, Leonardo L, Zheng F, Sripa B, Bergquist R, Zhou XN. (2010) Coordinating research on neglected parasitic diseases in Southeast Asia through networking. Adv Parasitol 72: 55&#x2013;77. 10.1016/S0065-308X(10)72003-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0065-308X(10)72003-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20624528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASEAN-NDI. (2014) ASEAN Network for Drugs, Diagnostics, Vaccines and Traditional Medicines Innovation. http://www.asean-ndi.org/. Accessed September 15, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. (2014) TDR- Special Programme for Research and Training in Tropical Diseases. http://www.who.int/tdr/en/. Accessed September 15, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoya JC, Rebulanan CL, Parungao NA, Ramirez B (2014) A look at the ASEAN-NDI: building a regional health R&amp;D innovation network. Infect Dis Poverty 3: 15 10.1186/2049-9957-3-15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2049-9957-3-15</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4021759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24834349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ADB (2014) Addressing Diseases of Poverty. http://www.adb.org/publications/addressing-diseases-poverty. Accessed September 15, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organiztion (2012) Regional Strategic Plan for Integrated Neglected Tropical Diseases Control in South-East Asia Region: 2012&#x2013;2016. http://www.searo.who.int/entity/leprosy/documents/SEA_CD_250/en/. Accessed September 29, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2012) Regional Office of the Western Pacific: Neglected tropical diseases. http://www.wpro.who.int/about/regional_committee/63/documents/RC63_06_Item_11_NTD_FINAL_COMPLETE.pdf. Accessed September 15, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2014) Addressing diseases of poverty: an initiative to reduce the unacceptable burden of neglected tropical diseases in the Asia Pacific region. http://www.adb.org/sites/default/files/pub/2014/addressing-diseases-poverty.pdf. Accessed September 24, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASEANSTATS. (2014) Aseanstats&#x2014;building knowledge in the ASEAN community. http://aseanstats.asean.org/Menu.aspx?rxid=9a788c80-779e-4447-b03d-79b2a7573da3&amp;px_language=en&amp;px_db=6-Millennium+Development+Goals&amp;px_type=PX. Accessed September September 24, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Population Balance (2014) The global population situation. http://www.worldpopulationbalance.org/global_population. Accessed 09-24-2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2012) Leprosy situation in 2012. http://www.searo.who.int/entity/leprosy/topics/LEP2012/en/. Accessed September 24, 2014.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>