<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">15066808</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2004</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>70</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2004</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Detection of noroviruses in tap water in Japan by means of a new method for concentrating enteric viruses in large volumes of freshwater.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2154</StartPage><EndPage>2160</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2154-60</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>A virus concentration method using a cation-coated filter was developed for large-volume freshwater applications. Poliovirus type 1 (LSc 2ab Sabin strain) inoculated into 40 ml of MilliQ (ultrapure) water was adsorbed effectively to a negatively charged filter (Millipore HA, 0.45- micro m pore size) coated with aluminum ions, 99% (range, 81 to 114%) of which were recovered by elution with 1.0 mM NaOH (pH 10.8) following an acid rinse with 0.5 mM H(2)SO(4) (pH 3.0). More than 80% poliovirus recovery yields were obtained from 500-ml, 1,000-ml, and 10-liter MilliQ water samples and from tap water samples. This method, followed by TaqMan PCR detection, was applied to determine the presence of noroviruses in tap water in Tokyo, Japan. In a 14-month survey, 4 (4.1%) and 7 (7.1%) of 98 tap water samples (100 to 532 liters) contained a detectable amount of noroviruses of genotype 1 and genotype 2, respectively. This method was proved to be useful for surveying the occurrence of enteric viruses, including noroviruses, in large volumes of freshwater.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haramoto</LastName><ForeName>Eiji</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urban Engineering, School of Engineering, University of Tokyo, Bunkyo-ku, Tokyo 113-8656, Japan. haramoto@env.t.u-tokyo.ac.jp</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katayama</LastName><ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohgaki</LastName><ForeName>Shinichiro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002412">Cations</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017931">DNA Primers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000327" MajorTopicYN="N">Adsorption</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001483" MajorTopicYN="N">Base Sequence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002412" MajorTopicYN="N">Cations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017931" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA Primers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005618" MajorTopicYN="N">Fresh Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007564" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Japan</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008851" MajorTopicYN="N">Micropore Filters</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029322" MajorTopicYN="N">Norovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017955" MajorTopicYN="N">Poliovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016133" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014773" MajorTopicYN="N">Virology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014881" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water Supply</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2004</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2004</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2004</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2004</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15066808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC383138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.70.4.2154-2160.2004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbaszadegan, M., M. S. Huber, C. P. Gerba, and I. L. Pepper. 1993. Detection of enteroviruses in groundwater with the polymerase chain reaction. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 59:1318-1324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7685998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Water Works Association. 1979. Viruses in drinking water, committee report. J. Am. Water Works Assoc. 71:441-444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando, T., S. S. Monroe, J. R. Gentsch, Q. Jin, D. C. Lewis, and R. I. Glass. 1995. Detection and differentiation of antigenically distinct small round-structured viruses (Norwalk-like viruses) by reverse transcription-PCR and Southern hybridization. J. Clin. Microbiol. 33:64-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC227881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7699068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anonymous. 1999. Food safety standards, costs and benefits. Australia&#x2014;New Zealand Food Authority, Commonwealth Government of Australia, Canberra, Australia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beller, M., A. Ellis, S.-H. Lee, M. A. Drebot, S. A. Jenkerson, E. Funk, M. D. Sobsey, O. D. Simmons III, S. S. Monroe, T. Ando, J. Noel, M. Petric, J. P. Middaugh, and J. S. Spika. 1997. Outbreak of viral gastroenteritis due to a contaminated well: international consequences. JAMA 278:563-568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9268277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beuret, C., D. Kohler, and T. Luthi. 2000. Norwalk-like virus sequences detected by reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction in mineral waters imported into or bottled in Switzerland. J. Food Prot. 63:1576-1582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11079703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beuret, C., D. Kohler, A. Baumgartner, and T. M. L&#xfc;thi. 2002. Norwalk-like virus sequences in mineral waters: one-year monitoring of three brands. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:1925-1931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC123876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11916714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crerar, S. K., C. B. Dalton, H. M. Longbottom, and E. Kraa. 1996. Foodborne diseases: current trends and future surveillance needs in Australia. Med. J. Aust. 165:672-675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8985456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson, K. A., D. W. Griffin, and J. H. Paul. 2002. Detection, quantitation and identification of enteroviruses from surface waters and sponge tissue from the Florida Keys using real-time RT-PCR. Water Res. 36:2505-2514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12153016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fankhauser, R. L., J. S. Noel, S. S. Monroe, T. Ando, and R. I. Glass. 1998. Molecular epidemiology of &#x201c;Norwalk-like viruses&#x201d; in outbreaks of gastroenteritis in the United States. J. Infect. Dis. 178:1571-1578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9815206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujito, B. T., and C. D. Lytle. 1996. Elution of viruses by ionic and nonionic surfactants. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 62:3470-3473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC168146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8795240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilgen, M., D. Germann, J. L&#xfc;thy, and P. H&#xfc;bner. 1997. Three-step isolation method for sensitive detection of enterovirus, rotavirus, hepatitis A virus, and small round structured viruses in water samples. Int. J. Food Microbiol. 37:189-199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9310854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grabow, W. O. K., M. B. Taylor, and J. C. De Villiers. 2001. New methods for the detection of viruses: call for review of drinking water quality guidelines. Water Sci. Technol. 43:1-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11464736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, K. Y. 1997. The role of human caliciviruses in epidemic gastroenteritis. Arch. Virol. Suppl. 13:153-165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9413535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, K. Y., R. M. Chanock, and A. Z. Kapikian. 2001. Human caliciviruses, p. 841-873. In D. M. Knipe, P. M. Howley, D. E. Grinnin, R. A. Lamb, M. A. Martin, B. Roizman, and S. E. Strauss (ed.), Fields virology, 4th ed. Lippincott Williams and Wilkins, Philadelphia, Pa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green, S. M., K. E. Dingle, P. R. Lambden, E. O. Caul, C. R. Ashley, and I. N. Clarke. 1994. Human enteric Caliciviridae: a new prevalent small round-structured virus group by RNA-dependent RNA polymerase and capsid diversity. J. Gen. Virol. 75:1883-1888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8046390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellard, M. E., and C. K. Findlay. 1997. Gastroenteritis in Australia: who, what, where, and how much? Aust. N. Z. J. Med. 27:147-149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9145176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henshilwood, K., J. Green, and D. N. Lees. 1998. Monitoring the marine environment for small round structured viruses (SRSVs): a new approach to combating the transmission of these viruses by molluscan shellfish. Water Sci. Technol. 38:51-56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kageyama, T., S. Kojima, M. Shinohara, K. Uchida, S. Fukushi, F. B. Hoshino, N. Takeda, and K. Katayama. 2003. Broadly reactive and highly sensitive assay for Norwalk-like viruses based on real-time quantitative reverse transcription-PCR. J. Clin. Microbiol. 41:1548-1557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC153860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12682144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katayama, H., A. Shimasaki, and S. Ohgaki. 2002. Development of a virus concentration method and its application to detection of enterovirus and Norwalk virus from coastal seawater. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:1033-1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC123733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11872447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keswick, B. H., C. P. Gerba, S. L. Secor, and I. Cech. 1982. Survival of enteric viruses and indicator bacteria in groundwater. J. Environ. Sci. Health Part A 17:903-912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keswick, B. H., T. K. Satterwhite, P. C. Johnson, H. L. Du Point, S. L. Secor, J. A. Bitsura, G. W. Gary, and J. C. Hoff. 1985. Inactivation of Norwalk virus in drinking water by chlorine. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 50:261-264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC238613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2996421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kukkula, M., L. Maunula, E. Silvennoinen, and C.-H. von Bonsdorff. 1999. Outbreak of viral gastroenteritis due to drinking water contaminated by Norwalk-like viruses. J. Infect. Dis. 180:1771-1776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10558930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S.-H., and S.-J. Kim. 2002. Detection of infectious enteroviruses and adenoviruses in tap water in urban areas in Korea. Water Res. 36:248-256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11766801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lees, D. N., K. Henshilwood, and W. J. Dor&#xe9;. 1994. Development of a method for detection of enteroviruses in shellfish by PCR with poliovirus as a model. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 60:2999-3005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7521997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lees, D. N., K. Henshilwood, J. Green, C. L. Gallimore, and D. W. G. Brown. 1995. Detection of small round structured viruses in shellfish by reverse transcription-PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 61:4418-4424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8534105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Guyader, F., L. Haugarreau, L. Miossec, E. Dubois, and M. Pommepuy. 2000. Three-year study to assess human enteric viruses in shellfish. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 66:3241-3248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10919776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Limsawat, S., and S. Ohgaki. 1997. Fate of liberated viral RNA in wastewater determined by PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 63:2932-2933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1389215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16535660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lodder, W. J., J. Vinj&#xe9;, R. van de Heide, A. M. de Roda Husman, E. J. T. M. Leenen, and M. P. G. Koopmans. 1999. Molecular detection of Norwalk-like caliciviruses in sewage. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 65:5624-5627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC91771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10584031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan, K. B., G. E. Rees, N. D. Seeley, and S. B. Primrose. 1980. Rapid concentration of bacteriophages from large volumes of freshwater: evaluation of positively charged microporous filters. J. Virol. Methods 1:87-97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7014575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukasik, J., T. M. Scott, D. Andryshak, and S. R. Farrah. 2000. Influence of salts on virus adsorption to microporous filters. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 66:2914-2920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lytle, C. D., and L. B. Routson. 1995. Minimized virus binding for tests of barrier materials. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 61:643-649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7574603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mix, T. W. 1974. The physical chemistry of membrane-virus interaction. Dev. Ind. Microbiol. 15:136-142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuanualsuwan, S., and D. O. Cliver. 2002. Pretreatment to avoid positive RT-PCR results with inactivated viruses. J. Virol. Methods 104:217-225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12088831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz, B.-A., R. Bange, T. W. Vahlenkamp, R. Johne, and H. M&#xfc;ller. 2002. Detection and quantitation of group A rotaviruses by competitive and real-time reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction. J. Virol. Methods 105:277-285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12270660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shieh, Y.-S. C., D. Wait, L. Tai, and M. D. Sobsey. 1995. Methods to remove inhibitors in sewage and other fecal wastes for enterovirus detection by the polymerase chain reaction. J. Virol. Methods 54:51-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7559857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey, M. D., C. Wallis, M. Henderson, and J. L. Melnick. 1973. Concentration of enteroviruses from large volumes of water. Appl. Microbiol. 26:529-534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC379842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16349972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soule, H., O. Genoulaz, B. Gratacap-Cavallier, P. Chevallier, J.-X. Liu, and J.-M. Seigneurin. 2000. Ultrafiltration and reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction: an efficient process for poliovirus, rotavirus and hepatitis A virus detection in water. Water Res. 34:1063-1067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strappe, P. 1991. Rotavirus detection&#x2014;a problem that needs concentration. Water Sci. Technol. 24:221-223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai, Y. L., B. Tran, and C. J. Palmer. 1995. Analysis of viral RNA persistence in seawater by reverse transcriptase-PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 61:363-366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7887616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 1998. Announcement of the drinking water contaminant candidate list. Fed. Regist. 63:10273-10287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilagin&#xe8;s, P., B. Sarrette, G. Husson, and R. Vilagin&#xe8;s. 1993. Glass wool for virus concentration at ambient water pH level. Water Sci. Technol. 27:299-306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfaardt, M., M. B. Taylor, H. F. Booysen, L. Engelbrecht, W. O. K. Grabow, and X. Jiang. 1997. Incidence of human calicivirus and rotavirus infection in patients with gastroenteritis in South Africa. J. Med. Virol. 51:290-296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9093943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yano, K., Y. Yoshida, T. Shinkai, and M. Kaneko. 1993. A practical method for the concentration of viruses from water using fibriform cellulose and organic coagulant. Water Sci. Technol. 27:295-298.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>