<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">28979010</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1998-3611</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>62</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year><Season>Sep-Oct</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Indian journal of dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Indian J Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease in West Bengal, India: A Preliminary Report on Clinicovirological Trend over 3 Successive Years (2013-2015).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>486</StartPage><EndPage>490</EndPage><MedlinePgn>486-490</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/ijd.IJD_381_17</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD), an enteroviral disease has emerged as a major emerging infection in India. This is caused most commonly by enterovirus 71 (EV71) and coxsackievirus A16 (CVA16) but can also be due to CVA4-10, CVA24, CVB2-5, and echovirus 18 (Echo18). Virological analysis of the cases of HFMD has been infrequently done in India. West Bengal is one of the worst affected states in India.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To document the clinical and etiological aspect, the changing patterns and clinic-virological correlation. Method: a total of 62 samples of throat swab were collected from affected children over 3 successive years in Kolkata, West Bengal, India.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Five cases had a previous history of HFMD during the last 1-5 years. Fever was usually of mild degree (highest 102&#xb0;C). There was no apparent correlation between fever of &gt;100&#xb0;C and a positive test. There was no correlation of viral strain and clinical severity. A test positive for the Viral RNA was noted among 64.51% (40/62) cases. Multiple strains were characteristically present in each year. CVA6, EV71 were found in 2013, CVA6, EV71 in 2014, and CVA6, CVA16 in 2015.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Presence of multiple strains explained the frequent occurrence of relapses. We expect this small study will serve as an important document for all future studies on HFMD.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarma</LastName><ForeName>Nilendu</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Dr. B C Roy Post Graduate Institute of Pediatric Sciences, Kolkata - 700 010, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chakraborty</LastName><ForeName>Sayantani</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, R G Kar Medical College, Kolkata - 700 010, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dutta</LastName><ForeName>Abira</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICMR Virus Unit, I.D &amp; B.G Hospital Campus, GB-4, Beliaghata, Kolkata - 700 010, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sadhukhan</LastName><ForeName>Provash Chandra</ForeName><Initials>PC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICMR Virus Unit, I.D &amp; B.G Hospital Campus, GB-4, Beliaghata, Kolkata - 700 010, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Indian J Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370750</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0019-5154</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coxsackievirus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">West Bengal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">and mouth disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiological trend</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foot</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest. What is new? Multiple strains of HFMD virus are presently circulating in West Bengal. There is no apparent correlation between viral strains and clinical severity but frequent relapse might be due to the circulation of multiple strains.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28979010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5618835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijd.IJD_381_17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJD-62-486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sarma N. Hand, foot, and mouth disease: Current scenario and Indian perspective. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2013;79:165&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23442455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma N, Sarkar A, Mukherjee A, Ghosh A, Dhar S, Malakar R. Epidemic of hand, foot and mouth disease in West Bengal, India in August, 2007: A multicentric study. Indian J Dermatol. 2009;54:26&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2800866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20049265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma N. Relapse of hand foot and mouth disease: Are we at more risk? Indian J Dermatol. 2013;58:78&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3555383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23372222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Lewthwaite P, Cardosa MJ, Solomon T. Clinical features, diagnosis, and management of enterovirus 71. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9:1097&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang PC, Chen SC, Chen KT. The current status of the disease caused by Enterovirus 71 infections: Epidemiology, pathogenesis, molecular epidemiology, and vaccine development. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2016;13 pii: E890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5036723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27618078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng W, Shi H, Chen Y, Xu Z, Chen J, Jin L. Alteration of serum high-mobility group protein 1 (HMGB1) levels in children with enterovirus 71-induced hand, foot, and mouth disease. Medicine (Baltimore) 2017;96:e6764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5413272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28445307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown BA, Oberste MS, Alexander JP, Jr, Kennett ML, Pallansch MA. Molecular epidemiology and evolution of enterovirus 71 strains isolated from 1970 to 1998. J Virol. 1999;73:9969&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10559310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Z, Zhang W, Zhang D, Hao Y. Estimating the basic reproduction rate of HFMD using the time series SIR model in Guangdong, China. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0179623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5503211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28692654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Hsia SH, Huang YC, Wu CT, Chang LY. Proinflammatory cytokine reactions in enterovirus 71 infections of the central nervous system. Clin Infect Dis. 2003;36:269&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12539066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang ZL, Mao QY, Wang YP, Zhu FC, Li JX, Yao X, et al. Progress on the research and development of inactivated EV71 whole-virus vaccines. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2013;9:1701&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3906269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23744508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>In HJ, Lim H, Lee JA, Kim HJ, Kim JW, Hyeon JY, et al. An inactivated hand-foot-and-mouth disease vaccine using the enterovirus 71 (C4a) strain isolated from a Korean patient induces a strong immunogenic response in mice. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0178259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5443535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28542556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinsbroek E, Ruitenberg EJ. The global introduction of inactivated polio vaccine can circumvent the oral polio vaccine paradox. Vaccine. 2010;28:3778&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20362626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Q, Li N, Yu X, Yao X, Li F, Lu F, et al. Antigenicity, animal protective effect and genetic characteristics of candidate vaccine strains of enterovirus 71. Arch Virol. 2012;157:37&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21984267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalkrishna V, Patil PR, Patil GP, Chitambar SD. Circulation of multiple enterovirus serotypes causing hand, foot and mouth disease in India. J Med Microbiol. 2012;61(Pt 3):420&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22052995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanda C, Singh R, Rana SK. An outbreak of hand-foot-mouth disease: A report from the hills of northern India. Natl Med J India. 2015;28:126&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26724340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar BR, Dwibedi B, Kar SK. An outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Bhubaneswar, Odisha. Indian Pediatr. 2013;50:139&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22728634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegde R, Kowalli S, Nagaraja K, Dharanesha NK, Seema CM, Khan TA, et al. Serosurveillance of foot and mouth disease in Karnataka state, India: A 3 years study. Virusdisease. 2016;27:294&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5394695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28466042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palani S, Nagarajan M, Biswas AK, Maile A, Paluru V. B1c genetic subtype of coxsackievirus A16 associated with hand, foot and mouth disease in Andaman Islands, India. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 2016;110:421&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27496517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganorkar NN, Patil PR, Tikute SS, Gopalkrishna V. Genetic characterization of enterovirus strains identified in Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease (HFMD): Emergence of B1c, C1 subgenotypes, E2 sublineage of CVA16, EV71 and CVA6 strains in India. Infect Genet Evol. 2017;54:192&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28577914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha DP, Raut CG, Jayaprakash H, Hanumaiah H, Shaikh NJ, Manjunatha MJ. Molecular diagnosis of enteroviruses associated with Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease (HFMD) Indian J Pediatr. 2014;81:1242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>