<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">20089660</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2010</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>84</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evolutionary genetics of human enterovirus 71: origin, population dynamics, natural selection, and seasonal periodicity of the VP1 gene.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3339</StartPage><EndPage>3350</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3339-50</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.01019-09</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Human enterovirus 71 (EV-71) is one of the major etiologic causes of hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) among young children worldwide, with fatal instances of neurological complications becoming increasingly common. Global VP1 capsid sequences (n = 628) sampled over 4 decades were collected and subjected to comprehensive evolutionary analysis using a suite of phylogenetic and population genetic methods. We estimated that the common ancestor of human EV-71 likely emerged around 1941 (95% confidence interval [CI], 1929 to 1952), subsequently diverging into three genogroups: B, C, and the now extinct genogroup A. Genealogical analysis revealed that diverse lineages of genogroup B and C (subgenogroups B1 to B5 and C1 to C5) have each circulated cryptically in the human population for up to 5 years before causing large HFMD outbreaks, indicating the quiescent persistence of EV-71 in human populations. Estimated phylogenies showed a complex pattern of spatial structure within well-sampled subgenogroups, suggesting endemicity with occasional lineage migration among locations, such that past HFMD epidemics are unlikely to be linked to continuous transmission of a single strain of virus. In addition, rises in genetic diversity are correlated with the onset of epidemics, driven in part by the emergence of novel EV-71 subgenogroups. Using subgenogroup C1 as a model, we observe temporal strain replacement through time, and we investigate the evidence for positive selection at VP1 immunogenic sites. We discuss the consequences of the evolutionary dynamics of EV-71 for vaccine design and compare its phylodynamic behavior with that of influenza virus.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tee</LastName><ForeName>Kok Keng</ForeName><Initials>KK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Molecular Virology and Epidemiology, AIDS Research Center, National Institute of Infectious Diseases, 1-23-1 Toyama, Shinjuku-ku, Tokyo 162-8640, Japan. k2tee@yahoo.com</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lam</LastName><ForeName>Tommy Tsan-Yuk</ForeName><Initials>TT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chan</LastName><ForeName>Yoke Fun</ForeName><Initials>YF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bible</LastName><ForeName>Jon M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamarulzaman</LastName><ForeName>Adeeba</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tong</LastName><ForeName>C Y William</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takebe</LastName><ForeName>Yutaka</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pybus</LastName><ForeName>Oliver G</ForeName><Initials>OG</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D036022">Capsid Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036022" MajorTopicYN="N">Capsid Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019143" MajorTopicYN="Y">Evolution, Molecular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011995" MajorTopicYN="N">Recombination, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012621" MajorTopicYN="N">Seasons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012641" MajorTopicYN="Y">Selection, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20089660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2838098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.01019-09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.01019-09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar, S., H. Y. Chee, M. F. Al-Kobaisi, J. Xiaoshan, K. B. Chua, and S. K. Lam. 1999. Identification of enterovirus 71 isolates from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) with fatal cases of encephalomyelitis in Malaysia. Virus Res. 61:1-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10426204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abubakar, S., H. Y. Chee, N. Shafee, K. B. Chua, and S. K. Lam. 1999. Molecular detection of enteroviruses from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Malaysia in 1997. Scand. J. Infect. Dis. 31:331-335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10528868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar, S., I. C. Sam, J. Yusof, M. K. Lim, S. Misbah, N. MatRahim, and P. S. Hooi. 2009. Enterovirus 71 outbreak, Brunei. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 15:79-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19116058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander, J. P., Jr., L. Baden, M. A. Pallansch, and L. J. Anderson. 1994. Enterovirus 71 infections and neurologic disease-United States, 1977-1991. J. Infect. Dis. 169:905-908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8133108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anonymous. 2008. Outbreak news. Enterovirus, China. Wkly. Epidemiol. Rec. 83:169-170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18472450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita, M., N. Nagata, N. Iwata, Y. Ami, Y. Suzaki, K. Mizuta, T. Iwasaki, T. Sata, T. Wakita, and H. Shimizu. 2007. An attenuated strain of enterovirus 71 belonging to genotype a showed a broad spectrum of antigenicity with attenuated neurovirulence in cynomolgus monkeys. J. Virol. 81:9386-9395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17567701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao, Y., P. Bolotov, D. Dernovoy, B. Kiryutin, L. Zaslavsky, T. Tatusova, J. Ostell, and D. Lipman. 2008. The influenza virus resource at the National Center for Biotechnology Information. J. Virol. 82:596-601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2224563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17942553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bible, J. M., M. Iturriza-Gomara, B. Megson, D. Brown, P. Pantelidis, P. Earl, J. Bendig, and C. Y. Tong. 2008. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 in the United Kingdom from 1998 to 2006. J. Clin. Microbiol. 46:3192-3200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2566106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18650362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bible, J. M., P. Pantelidis, P. K. Chan, and C. Y. Tong. 2007. Genetic evolution of enterovirus 71: epidemiological and pathological implications. Rev. Med. Virol. 17:371-379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17487831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard, M. J., D. H. Lam, and V. R. Racaniello. 1995. Determinants of attenuation and temperature sensitivity in the type 1 poliovirus Sabin vaccine. J. Virol. 69:4972-4978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC189313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7609067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, B. A., M. S. Oberste, J. P. Alexander, Jr., M. L. Kennett, and M. A. Pallansch. 1999. Molecular epidemiology and evolution of enterovirus 71 strains isolated from 1970 to 1998. J. Virol. 73:9969-9975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10559310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron-Wilson, C. L., Y. A. Pandolfino, H. Y. Zhang, B. Pozzeto, and L. C. Archard. 1998. Nucleotide sequence of an attenuated mutant of coxsackievirus B3 compared with the cardiovirulent wildtype: assessment of candidate mutations by analysis of a revertant to cardiovirulence. Clin. Diagn. Virol. 9:99-105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9645991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., S. Krishnan, P. H. Tio, D. Perera, and S. C. Wong. 1999. Isolation of subgenus B adenovirus during a fatal outbreak of enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sibu, Sarawak. Lancet 354:987-991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10501361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., D. Perera, B. A. Brown, D. Cheon, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, H. Cho, and P. McMinn. 2003. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 strains and recent outbreaks in the Asia-Pacific region: comparative analysis of the VP1 and VP4 genes. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:461-468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12702227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K. P., K. T. Goh, C. Y. Chong, E. S. Teo, G. Lau, and A. E. Ling. 2003. Epidemic hand, foot and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:78-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, L. G., U. D. Parashar, M. S. Lye, F. G. Ong, S. R. Zaki, J. P. Alexander, K. K. Ho, L. L. Han, M. A. Pallansch, A. B. Suleiman, M. Jegathesan, and L. J. Anderson for the Outbreak Study Group. 2000. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. Clin. Infect. Dis. 31:678-683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., C. C. King, K. H. Hsu, H. C. Ning, K. C. Tsao, C. C. Li, Y. C. Huang, S. R. Shih, S. T. Chiou, P. Y. Chen, H. J. Chang, and T. Y. Lin. 2002. Risk factors of enterovirus 71 infection and associated hand, foot, and mouth disease/herpangina in children during an epidemic in Taiwan. Pediatrics 109:e88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, and Office of the World Health Organization in China. 2008. Report on the hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in Fuyang City, Anhui Province and the prevention and control in China. World Health Organization, Beijing, China. http://www.wpro.who.int/china.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua, B. H., P. C. McMinn, S. K. Lam, and K. B. Chua. 2001. Comparison of the complete nucleotide sequences of echovirus 7 strain UMMC and the prototype (Wallace) strain demonstrates significant genetic drift over time. J. Gen. Virol. 82:2629-2639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11602774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua, B. H., P. Phuektes, S. A. Sanders, P. K. Nicholls, and P. C. McMinn. 2008. The molecular basis of mouse adaptation by human enterovirus 71. J. Gen. Virol. 89:1622-1632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18559932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov, M., M. Voroshilova, L. Shindarov, I. Lavrova, L. Gracheva, G. Koroleva, S. Vasilenko, I. Brodvarova, M. Nikolova, S. Gyurova, M. Gacheva, G. Mitov, N. Ninov, E. Tsylka, I. Robinson, M. Frolova, V. Bashkirtsev, L. Martiyanova, and V. Rodin. 1979. Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch. Virol. 60:329-340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond, A. J., S. Y. Ho, M. J. Phillips, and A. Rambaut. 2006. Relaxed phylogenetics and dating with confidence. PLoS Biol. 4:e88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1395354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16683862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond, A. J., G. K. Nicholls, A. G. Rodrigo, and W. Solomon. 2002. Estimating mutation parameters, population history and genealogy simultaneously from temporally spaced sequence data. Genetics 161:1307-1320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1462188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12136032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond, A. J., and A. Rambaut. 2007. BEAST: Bayesian evolutionary analysis by sampling trees. BMC Evol. Biol. 7:214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2247476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17996036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond, A. J., A. Rambaut, B. Shapiro, and O. G. Pybus. 2005. Bayesian coalescent inference of past population dynamics from molecular sequences. Mol. Biol. Evol. 22:1185-1192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15703244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitch, W. M., R. M. Bush, C. A. Bender, and N. J. Cox. 1997. Long term trends in the evolution of H(3) HA1 human influenza type A. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 94:7712-7718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC33681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9223253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo, D. G., S. Alonso, V. T. Chow, and C. L. Poh. 2007. Passive protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by neutralizing antibodies elicited by a synthetic peptide. Microbes Infect. 9:1299-1306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17890123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert, G. L., K. E. Dickson, M. J. Waters, M. L. Kennett, S. A. Land, and M. Sneddon. 1988. Outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Victoria, Australia, with a high incidence of neurologic involvement. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 7:484-488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2841639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grenfell, B. T., O. G. Pybus, J. R. Gog, J. L. Wood, J. M. Daly, J. A. Mumford, and E. C. Holmes. 2004. Unifying the epidemiological and evolutionary dynamics of pathogens. Science 303:327-332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14726583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halim, S., and A. I. Ramsingh. 2000. A point mutation in VP1 of coxsackievirus B4 alters antigenicity. Virology 269:86-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10725201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper, S. A., K. Fukuda, T. M. Uyeki, N. J. Cox, and C. B. Bridges. 2004. Prevention and control of influenza: recommendations of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices (ACIP). MMWR Recommend. Rep. 53:1-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15163927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa, M., H. Kishino, and T. Yano. 1985. Dating of the human-ape splitting by a molecular clock of mitochondrial DNA. J. Mol. Evol. 22:160-174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3934395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M., E. R. Chen, K. H. Hsu, S. J. Twu, K. T. Chen, S. F. Tsai, J. R. Wang, and S. R. Shih, for the Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929-935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorba, J., R. Campagnoli, L. De, and O. Kew. 2008. Calibration of multiple poliovirus molecular clocks covering an extended evolutionary range. J. Virol. 82:4429-4440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2293050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18287242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsson Hedestam, G. B., R. A. Fouchier, S. Phogat, D. R. Burton, J. Sodroski, and R. T. Wyatt. 2008. The challenges of eliciting neutralizing antibodies to HIV-1 and to influenza virus. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 6:143-155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18197170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingman, J. F. C. 1982. The coalescent. Stochastic Processes Appl. 13:235-248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu, H., Y. Shimizu, Y. Takeuchi, H. Ishiko, and H. Takada. 1999. Outbreak of severe neurologic involvement associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr. Neurol. 20:17-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, L., Y. He, H. Yang, J. Zhu, X. Xu, J. Dong, Y. Zhu, and Q. Jin. 2005. Genetic characteristics of human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 circulating from 1999 to 2004 in Shenzhen, People's Republic of China. J. Clin. Microbiol. 43:3835-3839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1233905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, K. H., K. P. Hwang, G. M. Ke, C. F. Wang, L. Y. Ke, Y. T. Hsu, Y. C. Tung, P. Y. Chu, B. H. Chen, H. L. Chen, C. L. Kao, J. R. Wang, H. L. Eng. S. Y. Wang, L. C. Hsu, and H. Y. Chen. 2006. Evolution of EV71 genogroup in Taiwan from 1998 to 2005: an emerging of subgenogroup C4 of EV71. J. Med. Virol. 78:254-262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16372302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., S. J. Twu, M. S. Ho, L. Y. Chang, and C. Y. Lee. 2003. Enterovirus 71 outbreaks, Taiwan: occurrence and recognition. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:291-293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12643822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipkin, W. I. 2009. Microbe hunting in the 21st century. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 106:6-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2629212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19118201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, C. Y., C. Y. Lee, C. L. Kao, W. Y. Shao, P. I. Lee, S. J. Twu, C. C. Yeh, S. C. Lin, W. Y. Shih, S. I. Wu, and L. M. Huang. 2002. Incidence and case-fatality rates resulting from the 1998 enterovirus 71 outbreak in Taiwan. J. Med. Virol. 67:217-223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11992582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum, L. C., K. T. Wong, S. K. Lam, K. B. Chua, A. Y. Goh, W. L. Lim, B. B. Ong, G. Paul, S. AbuBakar, and M. Lambert. 1998. Fatal enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. J. Pediatr. 133:795-798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, D. P., C. Williamson, and D. Posada. 2005. RDP2: recombination detection and analysis from sequence alignments. Bioinformatics 21:260-262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15377507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, J., G. Dunn, R. Hull, V. Patel, and P. D. Minor. 2000. Evolution of the Sabin strain of type 3 poliovirus in an immunodeficient patient during the entire 637-day period of virus excretion. J. Virol. 74:3001-3010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC111798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10708414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., K. Lindsay, D. Perera, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, and M. J. Cardosa. 2001. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J. Virol. 75:7732-7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick, J. L. 1984. Enterovirus type 71 infections: a varied clinical pattern sometimes mimicking paralytic poliomyelitis. Rev. Infect. Dis. 6(Suppl. 2):S387-S390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta, K., C. Abiko, T. Murata, Y. Matsuzaki, T. Itagaki, K. Sanjoh, M. Sakamoto, S. Hongo, S. Murayama, and K. Hayasaka. 2005. Frequent importation of enterovirus 71 from surrounding countries into the local community of Yamagata, Japan, between 1998 and 2003. J. Clin. Microbiol. 43:6171-6175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16333123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta, K., Y. Aoki, A. Suto, K. Ootani, N. Katsushima, T. Itagaki, A. Ohmi, M. Okamoto, H. Nishimura, Y. Matsuzaki, S. Hongo, K. Sugawara, H. Shimizu, and T. Ahiko. 2009. Cross-antigenicity among EV71 strains from different genogroups isolated in Yamagata, Japan, between 1990 and 2007. Vaccine 27:3153-3158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19446185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modlin, J. F. 2007. Enterovirus deja vu. N. Engl. J. Med. 356:1204-1205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17377157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morens, D. M., G. K. Folkers, and A. S. Fauci. 2008. Emerging infections: a perpetual challenge. Lancet Infect. Dis. 8:710-719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2599922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18992407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy, G., S. Takatsy, E. Kukan, I. Mihaly, and I. Domok. 1982. Virological diagnosis of enterovirus type 71 infections: experiences gained during an epidemic of acute CNS diseases in Hungary in 1978. Arch. Virol. 71:217-227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6285858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navascues, M., and B. C. Emerson. 2009. Elevated substitution rate estimates from ancient DNA: model violation and bias of Bayesian methods. Mol. Ecol. 18:4390-4397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19735451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong, K. C., S. Devi, M. J. Cardosa, and K. T. Wong. 2010. Formaldehyde-inactivated whole virus vaccine protects a murine model of enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis against disease. J. Virol. 84:661-665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2798416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi, M. H., S. C. Wong, Y. Podin, W. Akin, S. del Sel, A. Mohan, C. H. Chieng, D. Perera, D. Clear, D. Wong, E. Blake, J. Cardosa, and T. Solomon. 2007. Human enterovirus 71 disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: a prospective clinical, virological, and molecular epidemiological study. Clin. Infect. Dis. 44:646-656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17278054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera, D., M. A. Yusof, Y. Podin, M. H. Ooi, N. T. Thao, K. K. Wong, A. Zaki, K. B. Chua, Y. A. Malik, P. V. Tu, N. T. Tien, P. Puthavathana, P. C. McMinn, and M. J. Cardosa. 2007. Molecular phylogeny of modern coxsackievirus A16. Arch. Virol. 152:1201-1208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17308978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podin, Y., E. L. Gias, F. Ong, Y. W. Leong, S. F. Yee, M. A. Yusof, D. Perera, B. Teo, T. Y. Wee, S. C. Yao, S. K. Yao, A. Kiyu, M. T. Arif, and M. J. Cardosa. 2006. Sentinel surveillance for human enterovirus 71 in Sarawak, Malaysia: lessons from the first 7 years. BMC Public Health 6:180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1543637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16827926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pond, S. L., S. D. Frost, and S. V. Muse. 2005. HyPhy: hypothesis testing using phylogenies. Bioinformatics 21:676-679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15509596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pupko, T., I. Pe'er, R. Shamir, and D. Graur. 2000. A fast algorithm for joint reconstruction of ancestral amino acid sequences. Mol. Biol. Evol. 17:890-896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10833195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pybus, O. G., A. J. Drummond, T. Nakano, B. H. Robertson, and A. Rambaut. 2003. The epidemiology and iatrogenic transmission of hepatitis C virus in Egypt: a Bayesian coalescent approach. Mol. Biol. Evol. 20:381-387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12644558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pybus, O. G., A. Rambaut, R. Belshaw, R. P. Freckleton, A. J. Drummond, and E. C. Holmes. 2007. Phylogenetic evidence for deleterious mutation load in RNA viruses and its contribution to viral evolution. Mol. Biol. Evol. 24:845-852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17218639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu, J. 2008. Enterovirus 71 infection: a new threat to global public health? Lancet Neurol. 7:868-869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18848307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu, J. 2009. Viral outbreak in China tests government efforts. Nature 458:554-555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19340040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rambaut, A., and A. J. Drummond. 2007. Tracer v1.4. Institute of Evolutionary Biology, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Scotland. http://tree.bio.ed.ac.uk.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rambaut, A., O. G. Pybus, M. I. Nelson, C. Viboud, J. K. Taubenberger, and E. C. Holmes. 2008. The genomic and epidemiological dynamics of human influenza A virus. Nature 453:615-619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2441973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18418375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranganathan, S., S. Singh, C. L. Poh, and V. T. Chow. 2002. The hand, foot and mouth disease virus capsid: sequence analysis and prediction of antigenic sites from homology modelling. Appl. Bioinformatics 1:43-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15130856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins, K. E., P. Lemey, O. G. Pybus, H. W. Jaffe, A. S. Youngpairoj, T. M. Brown, M. Salemi, A. M. Vandamme, and M. L. Kalish. 2003. U.S. Human immunodeficiency virus type 1 epidemic: date of origin, population history, and characterization of early strains. J. Virol. 77:6359-6366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC155028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12743293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez, F., J. L. Oliver, A. Marin, and J. R. Medina. 1990. The general stochastic model of nucleotide substitution. J. Theor. Biol. 142:485-501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2338834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuda, G. M., W. K. Chang, C. Y. Yeung, and P. S. Tang. 1987. Monoplegia caused by enterovirus 71: an outbreak in Hong Kong. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 6:206-208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3562141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders, S. A., L. J. Herrero, K. McPhie, S. S. Chow, M. E. Craig, D. E. Dwyer, W. Rawlinson, and P. C. McMinn. 2006. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 over two decades in an Australian urban community. Arch. Virol. 151:1003-1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16369861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, N. J., E. H. Lennette, and H. H. Ho. 1974. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J. Infect. Dis. 129:304-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu, H., A. Utama, K. Yoshii, H. Yoshida, T. Yoneyama, M. Sinniah, M. A. Yusof, Y. Okuno, N. Okabe, S. R. Shih, H. Y. Chen, G. R. Wang, C. L. Kao, K. S. Chang, T. Miyamura, and A. Hagiwara. 1999. Enterovirus 71 from fatal and nonfatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease epidemics in Malaysia, Japan and Taiwan in 1997-1998. Jpn. J. Infect. Dis. 52:12-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10808253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmonds, P., and J. Welch. 2006. Frequency and dynamics of recombination within different species of human enteroviruses. J. Virol. 80:483-493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16352572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S., V. T. Chow, K. P. Chan, A. E. Ling, and C. L. Poh. 2000. RT-PCR, nucleotide, amino acid and phylogenetic analyses of enterovirus type 71 strains from Asia. J. Virol. Methods 88:193-204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10960707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S., V. T. Chow, M. C. Phoon, K. P. Chan, and C. L. Poh. 2002. Direct detection of enterovirus 71 (EV71) in clinical specimens from a hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak in Singapore by reverse transcription-PCR with universal enterovirus and EV71-specific primers. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:2823-2827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12149336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, D. J., A. S. Lapedes, J. C. de Jong, T. M. Bestebroer, G. F. Rimmelzwaan, A. D. Osterhaus, and R. A. Fouchier. 2004. Mapping the antigenic and genetic evolution of influenza virus. Science 305:371-376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15218094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchard, M. A., R. E. Weiss, and J. S. Sinsheimer. 2001. Bayesian selection of continuous-time Markov chain evolutionary models. Mol. Biol. Evol. 18:1001-1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11371589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swofford, D. L. 2003. PAUP*, phylogenetic analysis using parsimony (*and other methods), 4.0 beta ed. Sinauer Associates, Sunderland, MA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda, N., M. Tanimura, and K. Miyamura. 1994. Molecular evolution of the major capsid protein VP1 of enterovirus 70. J. Virol. 68:854-862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC236522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8289388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tee, K. K., O. G. Pybus, X. J. Li, X. Han, H. Shang, A. Kamarulzaman, and Y. Takebe. 2008. Temporal and spatial dynamics of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 circulating recombinant forms 08_BC and 07_BC in Asia. J. Virol. 82:9206-9215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2546895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18596096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu, P. V., N. T. T. Thao, D. Perera, T. H. Khanh, N. T. K. Tien, T. C. Thuong, O. M. How, M. J. Cardosa, and P. C. McMinn. 2007. Epidemiologic and virologic Invest. of hand, food, and mouth disease, southern Vietnam, 2005. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 13:1733-1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. R., Y. C. Tuan, H. P. Tsai, J. J. Yan, C. C. Liu, and I. J. Su. 2002. Change of major genotype of enterovirus 71 in outbreaks of hand-foot- and-mouth disease in Taiwan between 1998 and 2000. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:10-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, T. C., Y. F. Wang, Y. P. Lee, J. R. Wang, C. C. Liu, S. M. Wang, H. Y. Lei, I. J. Su, and C. K. Yu. 2007. Immunity to avirulent enterovirus 71 and coxsackie A16 virus protects against enterovirus 71 infection in mice. J. Virol. 81:10310-10315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2045469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17626076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Z. 1994. Maximum likelihood phylogenetic estimation from DNA sequences with variable rates over sites: approximate methods. J. Mol. Evol. 39:306-314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7932792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoke-Fun, C., and S. AbuBakar. 2006. Phylogenetic evidence for intertypic recombination in the emergence of human enterovirus 71 subgenotypes. BMC Microbiol. 6:74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1569848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16939656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>