<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33299997</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2692-8205</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>bioRxiv : the preprint server for biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>bioRxiv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Amilorides inhibit SARS-CoV-2 replication in vitro by targeting RNA structures.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2020.12.05.409821</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1101/2020.12.05.409821</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The SARS-CoV-2 pandemic, and the likelihood of future coronavirus pandemics, has rendered our understanding of coronavirus biology more essential than ever. Small molecule chemical probes offer to both reveal novel aspects of virus replication and to serve as leads for antiviral therapeutic development. The RNA-biased amiloride scaffold was recently tuned to target a viral RNA structure critical for translation in enterovirus 71, ultimately uncovering a novel mechanism to modulate positive-sense RNA viral translation and replication. Analysis of CoV RNA genomes reveal many conserved RNA structures in the 5'-UTR and proximal region critical for viral translation and replication, including several containing bulge-like secondary structures suitable for small molecule targeting. Following phylogenetic conservation analysis of this region, we screened an amiloride-based small molecule library against a less virulent human coronavirus, OC43, to identify lead ligands. Amilorides inhibited OC43 replication as seen in viral plaque assays. Select amilorides also potently inhibited replication competent SARS-CoV-2 as evident in the decreased levels of cell free virions in cell culture supernatants of treated cells. Reporter screens confirmed the importance of RNA structures in the 5'-end of the viral genome for small molecule activity. Finally, NMR chemical shift perturbation studies of the first six stem loops of the 5'-end revealed specific amiloride interactions with stem loops 4, 5a, and 6, all of which contain bulge like structures and were predicted to be strongly bound by the lead amilorides in retrospective docking studies. Taken together, the use of multiple orthogonal approaches allowed us to identify the first small molecules aimed at targeting RNA structures within the 5'-UTR and proximal region of the CoV genome. These molecules will serve as chemical probes to further understand CoV RNA biology and can pave the way for the development of specific CoV RNA-targeted antivirals.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martina</LastName><ForeName>Zafferani</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemistry Department, Duke University, 124 Science Drive; Durham, NC USA 27705.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Christina</LastName><ForeName>Haddad</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland OH 441106.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Le</LastName><ForeName>Luo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland OH 441106.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jesse</LastName><ForeName>Davila-Calderon</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland OH 441106.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Yuan-Chiu</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland OH 441106.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Christian</LastName><ForeName>Shema Mugisha</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Microbiology, Washington University School of Medicine, Saint Louis, MO 63110, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monaghan</LastName><ForeName>Adeline G</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemistry Department, Duke University, 124 Science Drive; Durham, NC USA 27705.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kennedy</LastName><ForeName>Andrew A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine and Department of Microbiology &amp; Immunology, University of Michigan, 1150 W Medical Center Dr, Ann Arbor MI 48109.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yesselman</LastName><ForeName>Joseph D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, University of Nebraska-Lincoln, Lincoln, NE 68588 USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gifford</LastName><ForeName>Robert R</ForeName><Initials>RR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC-University of Glasgow Centre for Virus Research, 464 Bearsden Rd, Bearsden, Glasgow, UK, G61 1QH.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tai</LastName><ForeName>Andrew W</ForeName><Initials>AW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine and Department of Microbiology &amp; Immunology, University of Michigan, 1150 W Medical Center Dr, Ann Arbor MI 48109.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kutluay</LastName><ForeName>Sebla B</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Microbiology, Washington University School of Medicine, Saint Louis, MO 63110, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Mei-Ling</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Rutgers Robert Wood Johnson Medical School, 675 Hoes Lane West, Piscataway, NJ USA 08854.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brewer</LastName><ForeName>Gary</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Rutgers Robert Wood Johnson Medical School, 675 Hoes Lane West, Piscataway, NJ USA 08854.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tolbert</LastName><ForeName>Blanton S</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland OH 441106.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hargrove</LastName><ForeName>Amanda E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemistry Department, Duke University, 124 Science Drive; Durham, NC USA 27705.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MC_UU_12014/12</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 GM126833</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R35 GM124785</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000076942">Preprint</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>bioRxiv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101680187</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2692-8205</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateIn"><RefSource>Sci Adv. 2021 Nov 26;7(48):eabl6096. doi: 10.1126/sciadv.abl6096</RefSource><PMID Version="1">34826236</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest. The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33299997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7724665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.12.05.409821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2020.12.05.409821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>He D.; Zhao S.; Li Y.; Cao P.; Gao D.; Lou Y.; Yang L., Comparing COVID-19 and the 1918&#x2013;19 influenza pandemics in the United Kingdom. Int J Infect Dis 2020, 98, 67&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7318986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32599281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization, W. H.
WHO Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) Dashboard. https://covid19.who.int/?gclid=CjwKCAiA-_L9BRBQEiwA-bm5fnQaim9DGoFrly-d6ub-z4qZtLahcCVJtlPSNw8L-zqZnsHZteCfqBoCbkwQAvD_BwE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B.; Tian E.-K.; He B.; Tian L.; Han R.; Wang S.; Xiang Q.; Zhang S.; El Arnaout T.; Cheng W., Overview of lethal human coronaviruses. Signal Transduction and Targeted Therapy 2020, 5 (1), 89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7289715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32533062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Costa V. G.; Moreli M. L.; Saivish M. V., The emergence of SARS, MERS and novel SARS-2 coronaviruses in the 21st century. Arch Virol 2020, 165 (7), 1517&#x2013;1526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7176030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32322993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui J.; Li F.; Shi Z. L., Origin and evolution of pathogenic coronaviruses. Nat Rev Microbiol 2019, 17 (3), 181&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30531947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Release, F. N.
Coronavirus (COVID-19) Update: FDA Authorizes Drug Combination for Treatment of COVID-19. https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/coronavirus-covid-19-update-fda-authorizes-drug-combination-treatment-covid-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon A.; Le N. T.-T.; Selisko B.; Eydoux C.; Alvarez K.; Guillemot J.-C.; Decroly E.; Peersen O.; Ferron F.; Canard B., Remdesivir and SARS-CoV-2: Structural requirements at both nsp12 RdRp and nsp14 Exonuclease active-sites. Antiviral Res 2020, 178, 104793&#x2013;104793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7151495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32283108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A. K.; Singh A.; Singh R.; Misra A., Remdesivir in COVID-19: A critical review of pharmacology, pre-clinical and clinical studies. Diabetes Metab Syndr 2020, 14 (4), 641&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7214279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32428865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genovese M. C.; Smolen J. S.; Takeuchi T.; Burmester G.; Brinker D.; Rooney T. P.; Zhong J.; Daojun M.; Saifan C.; Cardoso A.; Issa M.; Wu W.-S.; Winthrop K. L., Safety profile of baricitinib for the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis over a median of 3 years of treatment: an updated integrated safety analysis. The Lancet Rheumatology 2020, 2 (6), e347&#x2013;e357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38273598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu F.; Zhao S.; Yu B.; Chen Y. M.; Wang W.; Song Z. G.; Hu Y.; Tao Z. W.; Tian J. H.; Pei Y. Y.; Yuan M. L.; Zhang Y. L.; Dai F. H.; Liu Y.; Wang Q. M.; Zheng J. J.; Xu L.; Holmes E. C.; Zhang Y. Z., A new coronavirus associated with human respiratory disease in China. Nature 2020, 579 (7798), 265&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7094943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singal C. M. S.; Jaiswal P.; Seth P., SARS-CoV-2, More than a Respiratory Virus: Its Potential Role in Neuropathogenesis. ACS Chemical Neuroscience 2020, 11 (13), 1887&#x2013;1899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32491829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari V.; Beer J. C.; Sankaranarayanan N. V.; Swanson-Mungerson M.; Desai U. R., Discovering small-molecule therapeutics against SARS-CoV-2. Drug Discov Today 2020, 25 (8), 1535&#x2013;1544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7305878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32574699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy P. D.; Pogany J., The dependence of viral RNA replication on co-opted host factors. Nature Reviews Microbiology 2012, 10 (2), 137&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22183253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermann T., Small molecules targeting viral RNA. Wiley Interdiscip Rev RNA 2016, 7 (6), 726&#x2013;743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27307213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manfredonia I.; Nithin C.; Ponce-Salvatierra A.; Ghosh P.; Wirecki T. K.; Marinus T.; Ogando N. S.; Snider E. J.; van Hemert M. J.; Bujnicki J. M.; Incarnato D., Genome-wide mapping of therapeutically-relevant SARS-CoV-2 RNA structures. bioRxiv 2020, 2020.06.15.151647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huston N. C.; Wan H.; Araujo Tavares R. d. C.; Wilen C.; Pyle A. M., Comprehensive in-vivo secondary structure of the SARS-CoV-2 genome reveals novel regulatory motifs and mechanisms. bioRxiv 2020, 2020.07.10.197079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7775661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33444546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manfredonia I.; Nithin C.; Ponce-Salvatierra A.; Ghosh P.; Wirecki T. K.; Marinus T.; Ogando N. S.; Snijder Eric J.; van Hemert M. J.; Bujnicki J. M.; Incarnato D., Genome-wide mapping of SARS-CoV-2 RNA structures identifies therapeutically-relevant elements. Nucleic Acids Research 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan T. C. T.; Allan M. F.; Malsick L. E.; Khandwala S.; Nyeo S. S. Y.; Bathe M.; Griffiths A.; Rouskin S., Structure of the full SARS-CoV-2 RNA genome in infected cells. bioRxiv 2020, 2020.06.29.178343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wacker A.; Weigand J. E.; Akabayov S. R.; Altincekic N.; Bains J. K.; Banijamali E.; Binas O.; Castillo-Martinez J.; Cetiner E.; Ceylan B.; Chiu L.-Y.; Davila-Calderon J.; Dhamotharan K.; Duchardt-Ferner E.; Ferner J.; Frydman L.; F&#xfc;rtig B.; Gallego J.; Gr&#xfc;n J. T.; Hacker C.; Haddad C.; H&#xe4;hnke M.; Hengesbach M.; Hiller F.; Hohmann K. F.; Hymon D.; de Jesus V.; Jonker H.; Keller H.; Knezic B.; Landgraf T.; L&#xf6;hr F.; Luo L.; Mertinkus K. R.; Muhs C.; Novakovic M.; Oxenfarth A.; Palomino-Sch&#xe4;tzlein M.; Petzold K.; Peter S. A.; Pyper D. J.; Qureshi N. S.; Riad M.; Richter C.; Saxena K.; Schamber T.; Scherf T.; Schlagnitweit J.; Schlundt A.; Schnieders R.; Schwalbe H.; Simba-Lahuasi A.; Sreeramulu S.; Stirnal E.; Sudakov A.; Tants J.-N.; Tolbert B. S.; V&#xf6;gele J.; Wei&#xdf; L.; Wirmer-Bartoschek J.; Wirtz Martin M. A.; W&#xf6;hnert J.; Zetzsche H., Secondary structure determination of conserved SARS-CoV-2 RNA elements by NMR spectroscopy. Nucleic Acids Research 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7736788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33167030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhatlani B. Y., In silico identification of conserved cis-acting RNA elements in the SARS-CoV-2 genome. Future Virology 2020, 15 (7), 409&#x2013;417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7507811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33005212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan B.-J.; Su Y.-P.; Wu H.-Y.; Brian D. A., Genetic Evidence of a Long-Range RNA-RNA Interaction between the Genomic 5&#x2032; Untranslated Region and the Nonstructural Protein 1 Coding Region in Murine and Bovine Coronaviruses. Journal of Virology 2012, 86 (8), 4631&#x2013;4643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3318640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22345457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sola I.; Mateos-Gomez P. A.; Almazan F.; Zu&#xf1;iga S.; Enjuanes L., RNA-RNA and RNA-protein interactions in coronavirus replication and transcription. RNA Biol 2011, 8 (2), 237&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3230552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21378501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schubert K.; Karousis E. D.; Jomaa A.; Scaiola A.; Echeverria B.; Gurzeler L.-A.; Leibundgut M.; Thiel V.; M&#xfc;hlemann O.; Ban N., SARS-CoV-2 Nsp1 binds the ribosomal mRNA channel to inhibit translation. Nature Structural &amp; Molecular Biology 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32908316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Keefe L.
FDA Approves Oral Treatment for Spinal Muscular Atrophy. https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-approves-oral-treatment-spinal-muscular-atrophy.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermann T., Viral RNA Targets and Their Small Molecule Ligands. In RNA Therapeutics, Garner A. L., Ed. Springer International Publishing: Cham, 2018; pp 111&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lozano G.; Trapote A.; Ramajo J.; Elduque X.; Grandas A.; Robles J.; Pedroso E.; Mart&#xed;nez-Salas E., Local RNA flexibility perturbation of the IRES element induced by a novel ligand inhibits viral RNA translation. RNA Biol 2015, 12 (5), 555&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4615676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25775053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davila-Calderon J.; Patwardhan N. N.; Chiu L.-Y.; Sugarman A.; Cai Z.; Penutmutchu S. R.; Li M.-L.; Brewer G.; Hargrove A. E.; Tolbert B. S., IRES-targeting small molecule inhibits enterovirus 71 replication via allosteric stabilization of a ternary complex. Nature Communications 2020, 11 (1), 4775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32963221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly J. A.; Olson A. N.; Neupane K.; Munshi S.; San Emeterio J.; Pollack L.; Woodside M. T.; Dinman J. D., Structural and functional conservation of the programmed &#x2212;1 ribosomal frameshift signal of SARS coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2). J Biol Chem 2020, 295 (31), 10741&#x2013;10748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7397099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32571880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haniff H. S.; Tong Y.; Liu X.; Chen J. L.; Suresh B. M.; Andrews R. J.; Peterson J. M.; O&#x2019;Leary C. A.; Benhamou R. I.; Moss W. N.; Disney M. D., Targeting the SARS-CoV-2 RNA Genome with Small Molecule Binders and Ribonuclease Targeting Chimera (RIBOTAC) Degraders. ACS Central Science 2020, 6 (10), 1713&#x2013;1721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7553039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33140033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefebvre D. J.; De Vleeschauwer A. R.; Goris N.; Van Borm S.; Chimirri A.; Monforte A. M.; Valdazo-Gonzalez B.; King D. P.; Neyts J.; De Clercq K., A thiazepino[4,5-a]benzimidazole derivative hampers the RNA replication of Eurasian serotypes of foot-and-mouth disease virus. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications 2014, 455 (3), 378&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25446115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davila-Calderon J.; Patwardhan N.; Chiu L.-Y.; Sugarman A.; Cai Z.; Penutmutchu S. R.; Li M.-L.; Brewer G.; Hargrove A. E.; Tolbert B. S., Small Molecule Targeting IRES Domain Inhibits Enterovirus 71 Replication via an Allosteric Mechanism that Stabilizes a Ternary Complex. bioRxiv 2020, 2020.03.10.981167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32963221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shema Mugisha C.; Vuong H. R.; Puray-Chavez M.; Bailey A. L.; Fox J. M.; Chen R. E.; Wessel A. W.; Scott J. M.; Harastani H. H.; Boon A. C. M.; Shin H.; Kutluay S. B., A Simplified Quantitative Real-Time PCR Assay for Monitoring SARS-CoV-2 Growth in Cell Culture. mSphere 2020, 5 (5).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7471006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32878932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miao Z.; Adamiak R. W.; Antczak M.; Batey R. T.; Becka A. J.; Biesiada M.; Boniecki M. J.; Bujnicki J. M.; Chen S. J.; Cheng C. Y.; Chou F. C.; Ferr&#xe9;-D&#x2019;Amar&#xe9; A. R.; Das R.; Dawson W. K.; Ding F.; Dokholyan N. V.; Dunin-Horkawicz S.; Geniesse C.; Kappel K.; Kladwang W.; Krokhotin A.; &#x141;ach G. E.; Major F.; Mann T. H.; Magnus M.; Pachulska-Wieczorek K.; Patel D. J.; Piccirilli J. A.; Popenda M.; Purzycka K. J.; Ren A.; Rice G. M.; Santalucia J. Jr.; Sarzynska J.; Szachniuk M.; Tandon A.; Trausch J. J.; Tian S.; Wang J.; Weeks K. M.; Williams B. 2nd; Xiao Y.; Xu X.; Zhang D.; Zok T.; Westhof E., RNA-Puzzles Round III: 3D RNA structure prediction of five riboswitches and one ribozyme. Rna 2017, 23 (5), 655&#x2013;672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5393176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28138060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheridan R. P.; Maiorov V. N.; Holloway M. K.; Cornell W. D.; Gao Y. D., Drug-like density: a method of quantifying the &#x201c;bindability&#x201d; of a protein target based on a very large set of pockets and drug-like ligands from the Protein Data Bank. J Chem Inf Model 2010, 50 (11), 2029&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20977231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewitt W. M.; Calabrese D. R.; Schneekloth J. S. Jr., Evidence for ligandable sites in structured RNA throughout the Protein Data Bank. Bioorg Med Chem 2019, 27 (11), 2253&#x2013;2260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8283815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30982658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan B. S.; Forte J. E.; Hargrove A. E., Insights into the development of chemical probes for RNA. Nucleic Acids Research 2018, 46 (16), 8025&#x2013;8037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6144806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30102391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan A. P.; Choi Y.; Schork N. J., Conserved Genomic Terminals of SARS-CoV-2 as Co-evolving Functional Elements and Potential Therapeutic Targets. bioRxiv 2020, 2020.07.06.190207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7690956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iserman C.; Roden C.; Boerneke M.; Sealfon R.; McLaughlin G.; Jungreis I.; Park C.; Boppana A.; Fritch E.; Hou Y. J.; Theesfeld C.; Troyanskaya O. G.; Baric R. S.; Sheahan T. P.; Weeks K.; Gladfelter A. S., Specific viral RNA drives the SARS CoV-2 nucleocapsid to phase separate. bioRxiv 2020, 2020.06.11.147199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefkowitz E. J.; Dempsey D. M.; Hendrickson R. C.; Orton R. J.; Siddell S. G.; Smith D. B., Virus taxonomy: the database of the International Committee on Taxonomy of Viruses (ICTV). Nucleic acids research 2018, 46 (D1), D708&#x2013;D717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5753373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29040670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altschul S. F.; Madden T. L.; Sch&#xe4;ffer A. A.; Zhang J.; Zhang Z.; Miller W.; Lipman D. J., Gapped BLAST and PSI-BLAST: a new generation of protein database search programs. Nucleic acids research 1997, 25 (17), 3389&#x2013;3402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC146917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9254694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katoh K.; Standley D. M., MAFFT multiple sequence alignment software version 7: improvements in performance and usability. Mol Biol Evol 2013, 30 (4), 772&#x2013;780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3603318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23329690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer J. B.; Thomson E. C.; McLauchlan J.; Hughes J.; Gifford R. J., GLUE: a flexible software system for virus sequence data. BMC Bioinformatics 2018, 19 (1), 532&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6299651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterhouse A. M.; Procter J. B.; Martin D. M. A.; Clamp M.; Barton G. J., Jalview Version 2--a multiple sequence alignment editor and analysis workbench. Bioinformatics (Oxford, England) 2009, 25 (9), 1189&#x2013;1191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2672624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19151095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milligan J. F.; Uhlenbeck O. C., Synthesis of small RNAs using T7 RNA polymerase. Methods Enzymol 1989, 180, 51&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2482430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milligan J. F.; Groebe D. R.; Witherell G. W.; Uhlenbeck O. C., Oligoribonucleotide synthesis using T7 RNA polymerase and synthetic DNA templates. Nucleic Acids Research 1987, 15 (21), 8783&#x2013;8798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC306405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3684574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delaglio F.; Grzesiek S.; Vuister G. W.; Zhu G.; Pfeifer J.; Bax A., NMRPipe: A multidimensional spectral processing system based on UNIX pipes. Journal of Biomolecular NMR 1995, 6 (3), 277&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8520220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson B. A.; Blevins R. A., NMR View: A computer program for the visualization and analysis of NMR data. Journal of Biomolecular NMR 1994, 4 (5), 603&#x2013;614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22911360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee W.; Tonelli M.; Markley J. L., NMRFAM-SPARKY: enhanced software for biomolecular NMR spectroscopy. Bioinformatics 2014, 31 (8), 1325&#x2013;1327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4393527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25505092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abagyan R.; Totrov M.; Kuznetsov D., ICM&#x2014;A new method for protein modeling and design: Applications to docking and structure prediction from the distorted native conformation. Journal of Computational Chemistry 1994, 15 (5), 488&#x2013;506.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>