<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16269784</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Real-time PCR quantification of human adenoviruses in urban rivers indicates genome prevalence but low infectivity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7426</StartPage><EndPage>7433</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7426-33</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Real-time PCR was applied to quantify the abundance of human adenoviruses in two southern California urban rivers, the San Gabriel and Los Angeles. A total of 114 river samples from five different locations were collected over a 1-year period and analyzed for human adenoviruses, along with fecal indicator bacteria and coliphages. Adenoviruses were detected by real-time PCR in approximately 16% of the samples, with concentrations ranging from 10(2) to 10(4) genomes per liter. However, a plaque assay using two human tissue culture cell lines, HEK-293A and A549, yielded negative results, suggesting that adenoviruses detected by real-time PCR are likely noninfectious. Enterovirus genome was detected in approximately 7% of the samples by reverse transcription-PCR. Analysis by Spearman's rho rank order correlation showed significant correlations between fecal indicator bacteria and indicator virus (total coliform, fecal coliform, enterococcus, and coliphage values). However, no significant correlations were found between human adenoviruses quantified by real-time PCR and culturable coliphages or fecal indicator bacteria. Kruskal-Wallis chi-square analysis showed significant seasonal variability of all fecal indicator bacteria and coliphages, while no significant variability was observed for adenoviruses or enteroviruses. This study presents the first quantitative measurement of human adenovirus genomes in urban rivers and their statistical relationship to fecal indicator bacteria and coliphages. The uncoupling between high-number genome copies of adenoviruses detected by real-time PCR and the absence of infectivity detected by tissue culture suggests that genome-based detection methods are inadequate for direct assessment of human health risk.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Environmental Health, Science, and Policy, University of California, Irvine, CA 92697-7070, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Sunny C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D023362">Evaluation Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000260" MajorTopicYN="N">Adenoviruses, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002947" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Cities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003090" MajorTopicYN="N">Coliphages</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004755" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterobacteriaceae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005243" MajorTopicYN="N">Feces</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016680" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome, Bacterial</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016133" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045483" MajorTopicYN="N">Rivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012621" MajorTopicYN="N">Seasons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16269784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1287606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.11.7426-7433.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">71/11/7426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alexander, L. M., A. Heaven, A. Tennant, and R. Morris. 1992. Symptomatology of children in contact with sea water contaminated with sewage. J. Epidemiol. Community Health 46:340-344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1059596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1431703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg, G. 1983. Viral pollution of the environment. CRC Press, Boca Raton, Fla.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boom, R., C. Sol, M. Beld, J. Weel, J. Goudsmit, and P. Wertheim-Van Dillen. 1999. Improved silica-guanidiniumthiocyanate DNA isolation procedure based on selective binding of bovine alpha-casein to silica particles. J. Clin. Microbiol. 37:615-619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC84491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9986822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byappanahalli, M. N., and R. S. Fujioka. 1998. Evidence that tropical soil environment can support the growth of Escherichia coli. Water Sci. Technol. 38:171-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castignolles, N., F. Petit, I. Mendel, L. Simon, L. Cattolico, and C. Buffet-Janvresse. 1998. Detection of adenovirus in the waters of the Seine River estuary by nested-PCR. Mol. Cell. Probes 12:175-180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9664580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 1988. Water-related disease outbreaks, 1985. Morb. Mortal. Wkly. Rep. 37:15-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapron, C. D., N. A. Ballester, J. H. Fontaine, C. N. Frades, and A. B. Margolin. 2000. The detection of astrovirus, enteroviruses, adenovirus type 40 and 41, and rotavirus in surface water samples collected and evaluated by the Information Collection Rule and an integrated cell culture-nested PCR procedure, p. 547. Abstr. 100th Gen. Meet. Am. Soc. Microbiol. American Society for Microbiology, Washington, D.C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC110573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10831432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung, W. H., K. C. Chang, R. P. Hung, and J. W. Kleevens. 1990. Health effects of beach water pollution in Hong Kong. Epidemiol. Infect. 105:139-162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2271797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2384140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung, H., and M. D. Sobsey. 1993. Comparative survival of indicator viruses and enteric viruses in seawater and sediment. Water Sci. Technol. 27:425-428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clesceri, L. S., A. E. Greenberg, and A. D. Eaton (ed.). 1998. Standard methods for the examination of water and wastewater, 20th ed. American Public Health Association, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLeon, R., Y. S. C. Shieh, R. S. Baric, and M. D. Sobey. 1990. Presented at the Water Quality Conference, San Diego, Calif.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desmarais, T. R., H. M. Solo-Gabriele, and C. J. Palmer. 2002. Influence of soil on fecal indicator organisms in a tidally influenced subtropical environment. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:1165-1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC123749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11872464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson, K. A., D. W. Griffin, and J. H. Paul. 2002. Detection, quantitation and identification of enteroviruses from surface waters and sponge tissue from the Florida Keys using real-time RT-PCR. Water Res. 36:2505-2514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12153016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujioka, R., C. Sian-Denton, M. Borja, J. Castro, and K. Morphew. 1999. Soil: the environmental source of Escherichia coli and enterococci in Guam's streams. J. Appl. Microbiol. 85:83s-89s.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21182696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giard, D. J. S., A. Aaronson, G. J. Todaro, P. Arnstein, J. H. Kersey, H. Dosik, and W. P. Parks. 1973. In vitro cultivation of human tumors: Establishment of cell lines derived from a series of solid tumors. J. Natl. Cancer Inst. 51:1417-1423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4357758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldsmith, K. T., L. D. Dion, D. T. Curiel, and R. I. Garver, Jr. 1998. Trans E1 component requirements for maximal replication of E1-defective recombinant adenovirus. Virology 248:406-419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9721248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham, F. L., J. Smiley, W. C. Russell, and R. Nairn. 1977. Characteristics of a human cell line transformed by DNA from human adenovirus type 5. J. Gen. Virol. 36:59-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">886304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harm, W. 1980. Biological effects of ultraviolet radiation. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, United Kingdom.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, J. W., and S. Jiang. 2005. Quantification of enterococci and human adenoviruses in environmental samples by real-time PCR. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 71:2250-2255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1087545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15870308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, S., R. Noble, and W. Chu. 2001. Human adenoviruses and coliphages in urban runoff-impacted coastal waters of southern California. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 67:179-184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11133443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, S., H. Dezfulian, and W. Chu. 2005. Real time quantitative PCR for enteric adenovirus serotype 40 in environmental waters. Can. J. Microbiol. 51:393-398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16088334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, S. C., and W. Chu. 2004. PCR detection of pathogenic viruses in southern California urban rivers. J. Appl. Microbiol. 97:17-28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15186438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, S. C., C. A. Kellogg, and J. H. Paul. 1998. Characterization of marine temperate phage-host systems isolated from Mamala Bay, Oahu, Hawaii. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 64:535-542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC106079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9464390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallenbach, N. R., P. A. Cornelius, D. Negus, D. Montgomerie, and S. Englander. 1989. Inactivation of viruses by ultraviolet light, vol. 56. Karger, Basel, Switzerland.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2491986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, J. H., S. B. Grant, C. D. McGee, B. F. Sanders, and J. L. Largier. 2004. Locating sources of surf zone pollution: a mass budget analysis of fecal indicator bacteria at Huntington Beach, California. Environ. Sci. Technol. 38:2626-2636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15180059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knipe, D. M., P. M. Howley, D. E. Griffin, R. A. Lamb, M. A. Martin, B. Roizman, and S. E. Straus (ed.). 2001. Fields virology, 4th ed. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, Philadelphia, Pa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Cann, P., S. Ranarijaona, S. Monpoeho, F. Le Guyader, and V. Ferre. 2004. Quantification of human astroviruses in sewage using real-time RT-PCR. Res. Microbiol. 155:11-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14759703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipp, E. K., R. Kurz, R. Vincent, C. Rodriguez-Palacios, S. R. Farrah, and J. B. Rose. 2001. The effects of seasonal variability and weather on microbial fecal pollution and enteric pathogens in a subtropical estuary. Estuaries 24:266-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monpoeho, S., M. Coste-Burel, M. Coste-Mattioli, B. Besse, J. J. Chomel, S. Billaudel, and V. Ferre. 2002. Application of a real-time polymerase chain reaction with internal positive control for detection and quantification of enterovirus in cerebrospinal fluid. Eur. J. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Dis. 21:532-536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7088111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12172744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monpoeho, S., A. Maul, C. Bonnin, L. Patria, S. Ranarijaona, S. Billaudel, and V. Ferre. 2004. Clearance of human-pathogenic viruses from sludge: study of four stabilization processes by real-time reverse transcription-PCR and cell culture. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 70:5434-5440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC520849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15345430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble, R. T., S. B. Weisberg, M. K. Leecaster, C. D. McGee, J. H. Dorsey, P. M. Vainik, and V. Orozco-Borbon. 2003. Storm effects on regional beach water quality along the southern California shoreline. J. Water Health 1:23-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15384270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payment, P., and E. Franco. 1993. Clostridium perfringens and somatic coliphages as indicators of the efficiency of drinking water treatment for viruses and protozoan cysts. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 59:2418-2424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8368831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pina, S., M. Puig, F. Lucena, J. Jofre, and R. Girones. 1998. Viral pollution in the environment and in shellfish: human adenovirus detection by PCR as an index of human viruses. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 64:3376-3382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC106735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9726885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puig, M., J. Jofre, F. Lucena, A. Allard, G. Wadell, and R. Girones. 1994. Detection of adenoviruses and enteroviruses in polluted waters by nested PCR amplification. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 60:2963-2970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8085832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeves, R. L., S. B. Grant, R. D. Mrse, C. M. Copil Oancea, B. F. Sanders, and A. B. Boehm. 2004. Scaling and management of fecal indicator bacteria in runoff from a coastal urban watershed in southern California. Environ. Sci. Technol. 38:2637-2648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15180060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roll, B. M., and R. S. Fujioka. 1997. Sources of faecal indicator bacteria in a brackish, tropical stream and their impact on recreational water quality. Water Sci. Technol. 35:179-186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sambrook, J., E. F. Fritsch, and T. Maniatis. 1989. Molecular cloning: a laboratory manual, 2nd ed. Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press, Cold Spring Harbor, N.Y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, C. D., D. W. Craft, R. S. Shiromoto, and P. O. Yan. 1986. Alternative cell-line for virus isolation. J. Clin. Microbiol. 24:265-268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC268886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3018038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey, M. D., D. A. Battigelli, G. A. Shin, and S. Newland. 1998. RT-PCR amplification detects inactivated viruses in water and wastewater. Water Sci. Technol. 38:91-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tani, N., Y. Dohi, N. Kurumatani, and K. Yonemasu. 1995. Seasonal distribution of adenoviruses, enteroviruses and reoviruses in urban river water. Microbiol. Immunol. 39:577-580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7494496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurston-Enriquez, J. A., C. N. Haas, J. Jacangelo, K. Riley, and C. P. Gerba. 2003. Inactivation of feline calicivirus and adenovirus type 40 by UV radiation. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 69:577-582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC152434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12514044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toranzos, G. A., H. Hanssen, and C. P. Gerba. 1986. Occurrence of enteroviruses and rotaviruses in drinking-water in Colombia. Water Sci. Technol. 18:109-114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai, Y. L., M. D. Sobsey, L. R. Sangermano, and C. J. Palmer. 1993. Simple method of concentrating enteroviruses and hepatitis A virus from sewage and ocean water for rapid detection by reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 59:3488-3491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7504433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>