<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34260497</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Parent-administered Neurodevelopmental Follow up in Children After Picornavirus CNS Infections.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>867</StartPage><EndPage>872</EndPage><MedlinePgn>867-872</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000003192</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Data on the neurodevelopment of children who experienced central nervous system (CNS) infections with enteroviruses (EV) or parechoviruses (hPeV) is scarce and mostly limited to follow up of short-term outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Parents of children who presented between 2014 and 2019, underwent a lumbar puncture and whose cerebrospinal fluid was polymerase chain reaction positive for EV or hPeV, were asked to complete a care-giver-administered neurodevelopmental assessment tool (The Ages and Stages Instrument [ASQ3]). Clinical data of the infective episode were collected from patient notes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Of 101 children, 43 (10 hPeV+, 33 EV+) submitted ASQ3 results. Median age at assessment was 38.9 months (interquartile range, 15.4-54.8), the follow-up interval 3 years (median 37 months; interquartile range, 13.9-53.1). Age, inflammatory markers, and cerebrospinal fluid pleocytosis during the infective event were not associated with ASQ3 scores. In 23 children (17 EV+, 6 hPeV+), no neurodevelopmental concerns were reported. Two more had preexisting developmental delay and were excluded. Of the remaining, 18/41 (43.9%) reported ASQ3 scores indicating need for monitoring or professional review in at least 1 category, not differing by pathogen (EV 14/31, 45.2%; hPeV 4/10, 40%; P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.71). Seven children will require formal review, scoring &#x2265;2 SD below the mean in at least 1 category (6/31 EV+, 1/10 hPeV+, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.7), 3 scored &#x2265;2 SD below the mean in more than 1 area.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Parent-administered developmental assessment of children with a history of early picornavirus infection of the CNS identified a subgroup that requires formal neurodevelopmental review. Wider application of community-based developmental screening will complement our understanding of the impact of CNS infections in early childhood.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stephens</LastName><ForeName>Carol</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Pediatrics, Cork University Hospital, Wilton, Cork, Republic of Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reynolds</LastName><ForeName>Clare</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Pediatrics, Cork University Hospital, Wilton, Cork, Republic of Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cremin</LastName><ForeName>Molly</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Pediatrics, Cork University Hospital, Wilton, Cork, Republic of Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barry</LastName><ForeName>Rachel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Cork University Hospital, Wilton, Cork, Republic of Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morley</LastName><ForeName>Ursula</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Virus Reference Laboratory, University College Dublin, Dublin, Republic of Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gibson</LastName><ForeName>Louise</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Pediatrics, Cork University Hospital, Wilton, Cork, Republic of Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Gascun</LastName><ForeName>Cillian F</ForeName><Initials>CF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Virus Reference Laboratory, University College Dublin, Dublin, Republic of Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Felsenstein</LastName><ForeName>Susana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, Alder Hey Children's Hospital NHS Trust, East Prescot Road, Liverpool, Great Britain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002494" MajorTopicYN="N">Central Nervous System Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008403" MajorTopicYN="N">Mass Screening</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065886" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodevelopmental Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D030061" MajorTopicYN="N">Parechovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010290" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parents</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010849" MajorTopicYN="N">Picornaviridae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010850" MajorTopicYN="N">Picornaviridae Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000134" MajorTopicYN="N">cerebrospinal fluid</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34260497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000003192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-202110000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Petel D, Barton M, Renaud C, et al. Enteroviral and herpes simplex virus central nervous system infections in infants &lt;&#x2009;90&#x2009;days old: a Paediatric Investigators&#x2019; Collaborative Network on Infections in Canada (PICNIC) study. BMC Pediatr. 2020;20:252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin NG, Iro MA, Sadarangani M, et al. Hospital admissions for viral meningitis in children in England over five decades: a population-based observational study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2016;16:1279&#x2013;1287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvala H, Simmonds P. Viral meningitis: epidemiology and diagnosis. Lancet Infect Dis. 2016;16:1211&#x2013;1212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khandaker GM, Zimbron J, Dalman C, et al. Childhood infection and adult schizophrenia: a meta-analysis of population-based studies. Schizophr Res. 2012;139:161&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rantakallio P, Jones P, Moring J, et al. Association between central nervous system infections during childhood and adult onset schizophrenia and other psychoses: a 28-year follow-up. Int J Epidemiol. 1997;26:837&#x2013;843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalman C, Allebeck P, Gunnell D, et al. Infections in the CNS during childhood and the risk of subsequent psychotic illness: a cohort study of more than one million Swedish subjects. Am J Psychiatry. 2008;165:59&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanson D. Meningitis. Pediatr Rev. 2015;36:514&#x2013;524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CG102 N. Meningitis (bacterial) and meningococcal septicaemia in under 16s: recognition, diagnosis and management. 2010. Available at: https://www.nice.org.uk/Guidance/CG102 . Accessed May 7, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christie D, Rashid H, El-Bashir H, et al. Impact of meningitis on intelligence and development: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0175024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudson JA, Broad J, Martin NG, et al. Outcomes beyond hospital discharge in infants and children with viral meningitis: a systematic review. Rev Med Virol. 2020;30:e2083.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khetsuriani N, Lamonte-Fowlkes A, Oberst S, et al.; Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Enterovirus surveillance&#x2013;United States, 1970-2005. MMWR Surveill Summ. 2006;55:1&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadambari S, Braccio S, Ribeiro S, et al. Enterovirus and parechovirus meningitis in infants younger than 90 days old in the UK and Republic of Ireland: a British Paediatric Surveillance Unit study. Arch Dis Child. 2019;104:552&#x2013;557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai J, Xie Z, Liu G, et al. Etiology and prognosis of acute viral encephalitis and meningitis in Chinese children: a multicentre prospective study. BMC Infect Dis. 2017;17:494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasbun R, Wootton SH, Rosenthal N, et al. Epidemiology of meningitis and encephalitis in infants and children in the United States, 2011-2014. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2019;38:37&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatami A, Burrell R, McMullan BJ, et al. Epidemic and inter-epidemic burden of pediatric human parechovirus infection in New South Wales, Australia, 2017-2018. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2020;39:507&#x2013;511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergnano S, Kadambari S, Whalley K, et al. Characteristics and outcomes of human parechovirus infection in infants (2008-2012). Eur J Pediatr. 2015;174:919&#x2013;924.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wildenbeest JG, Benschop KS, Minnaar RP, et al. Clinical relevance of positive human parechovirus type 1 and 3 PCR in stool samples. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2014;20:O640&#x2013;O647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadambari S, Harvala H, Simmonds P, et al. Strategies to improve detection and management of human parechovirus infection in young infants. Lancet Infect Dis. 2019;19:e51&#x2013;e58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp J, Harrison CJ, Puckett K, et al. Characteristics of young infants in whom human parechovirus, enterovirus or neither were detected in cerebrospinal fluid during sepsis evaluations. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2013;32:213&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry R, Dempsey C, Barry L, et al. On-site multiplex PCR for CSF diagnostics in an acute hospital versus referral to reference laboratories: assessing economic factors, length of stay and antimicrobial stewardship. J Infect. 2021;82:414&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llano L&#xf3;pez LH, Reischl AT, Gr&#xf6;ndahl B, et al. The BioFireFilmArray enables point of care diagnostic in neonatal parechovirus meningitis. Infect Dis (Lond). 2017;49:705&#x2013;707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson J, Sucharew H, Cruz AT, et al.; Pediatric Emergency Medicine Collaborative Research Committee (PEM CRC) HSV Study Group. Cerebrospinal fluid reference values for young infants undergoing lumbar puncture. Pediatrics. 2018;141:e20173405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troude P, Squires J, L&#x2019;H&#xe9;lias LF, et al. Ages and Stages Questionnaires: feasibility of postal surveys for child follow-up. Early Hum Dev. 2011;87:671&#x2013;676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Squires J, Bricker D, Potter L. Revision of a parent-completed development screening tool: Ages and Stages Questionnaires. J Pediatr Psychol. 1997;22:313&#x2013;328.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASQ3. ASQ-3 Technical Report. 2017. Available at: https://agesandstages.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/ASQ-3-Technical-Appendix_web.pdf . Accessed May 7, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDC. Birth to Five watch me Thrive. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg RG, Smith PB, Cotten CM, et al. Traumatic lumbar punctures in neonates: test performance of the cerebrospinal fluid white blood cell count. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2008;27:1047&#x2013;1051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonsu BK, Harper MB. Corrections for leukocytes and percent of neutrophils do not match observations in blood-contaminated cerebrospinal fluid and have no value over uncorrected cells for diagnosis. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2006;25:8&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hinsbergh TMT, Elbers RG, Hans Ket JCF, et al. Neurological and neurodevelopmental outcomes after human parechovirus CNS infection in neonates and young children: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2020;4:592&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sridhar A, Karelehto E, Brouwer L, et al. Parechovirus A pathogenesis and the enigma of genotype A-3. Viruses. 2019;11:E1062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sanden SM, Koopmans MP, van der Avoort HG. Detection of human enteroviruses and parechoviruses as part of the national enterovirus surveillance in the Netherlands, 1996-2011. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2013;32:1525&#x2013;1531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvala H, McLeish N, Kondracka J, et al. Comparison of human parechovirus and enterovirus detection frequencies in cerebrospinal fluid samples collected over a 5-year period in Edinburgh: HPeV type 3 identified as the most common picornavirus type. J Med Virol. 2011;83:889&#x2013;896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elling R, B&#xf6;ttcher S, du Bois F, et al. Epidemiology of human parechovirus type 3 upsurge in 2 Hospitals, Freiburg, Germany, 2018. Emerg Infect Dis. 2019;25:1384&#x2013;1388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tapia G, Cinek O, Wits&#xf8; E, et al. Longitudinal observation of parechovirus in stool samples from Norwegian infants. J Med Virol. 2008;80:1835&#x2013;1842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#x2019;Huillier AG, Mardegan C, Cordey S, et al. Enterovirus, parechovirus, adenovirus and herpes virus type 6 viraemia in fever without source. Arch Dis Child. 2020;105:180&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wildenbeest JG, Wolthers KC, Straver B, et al. Successful IVIG treatment of human parechovirus-associated dilated cardiomyopathy in an infant. Pediatrics. 2013;132:e243&#x2013;e247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuzurihara SS, Ao K, Hara T, et al. Human parechovirus-3 infection in nine neonates and infants presenting symptoms of hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis. J Infect Chemother. 2013;19:144&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hara S, Kawada J, Kawano Y, et al. Hyperferritinemia in neonatal and infantile human parechovirus-3 infection in comparison with other infectious diseases. J Infect Chemother. 2014;20:15&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatami A, McMullan BJ, Webber M, et al. Sepsis-like disease in infants due to human parechovirus type 3 during an outbreak in Australia. Clin Infect Dis. 2015;60:228&#x2013;236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midgley CM, Jackson MA, Selvarangan R, et al. Severe parechovirus 3 infections in Young Infants-Kansas and Missouri, 2014. J Pediatric Infect Dis Soc. 2018;7:104&#x2013;112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braccio S, Kapetanstrataki M, Sharland M, et al. Intensive care admissions for children with enterovirus and human parechovirus infections in the United Kingdom and The Republic of Ireland, 2010-2014. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2017;36:339&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerhuis BM, Koen G, Wildenbeest JG, et al. Specific cell tropism and neutralization of human parechovirus types 1 and 3: implications for pathogenesis and therapy development. J Gen Virol. 2012;93(pt 11):2363&#x2013;2370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen NM, Midgley SE, Nielsen AC, et al. Severe human parechovirus infections in infants and the role of older siblings. Am J Epidemiol. 2016;183:664&#x2013;670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izumita R, Deuchi K, Aizawa Y, et al. Intrafamilial transmission of parechovirus a and enteroviruses in neonates and young infants. J Pediatric Infect Dis Soc. 2019;8:501&#x2013;506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aizawa Y, Watanabe K, Oishi T, et al. Role of maternal antibodies in infants with severe diseases related to human parechovirus type 3. Emerg Infect Dis. 2015;21:1966&#x2013;1972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karelehto E, Wildenbeest JG, Benschop KSM, et al. Human parechovirus 1, 3 and 4 neutralizing antibodies in Dutch mothers and infants and their role in protection against disease. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2018;37:1304&#x2013;1308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerhuis B, Kolehmainen P, Benschop K, et al. Human parechovirus seroprevalence in Finland and the Netherlands. J Clin Virol. 2013;58:211&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta K, Komabayashi K, Aoki Y, et al. Seroprevalence of parechovirus A1, A3 and A4 antibodies in Yamagata, Japan, between 1976 and 2017. J Med Microbiol. 2020;69:1381&#x2013;1387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karelehto E, Brouwer L, Benschop K, et al. Seroepidemiology of parechovirus A3 neutralizing antibodies, Australia, the Netherlands, and United States. Emerg Infect Dis. 2019;25:148&#x2013;152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bissel SJ, Auer RN, Chiang CH, et al. Human parechovirus 3 meningitis and fatal leukoencephalopathy. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2015;74:767&#x2013;777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma A, Hanzlik E, Krishnasarma R, et al. Human parechovirus meningoencephalitis: neuroimaging in the era of polymerase chain reaction-based testing. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2019;40:1418&#x2013;1421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habuka R, Aizawa Y, Izumita R, et al. Innate immune responses in serum and cerebrospinal fluid from neonates and infants infected with parechovirus-A3 or enteroviruses. J Infect Dis. 2020;222:681&#x2013;689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SE, Song D, Shin K, et al. Prospective research of human parechovirus and cytokines in cerebrospinal fluid of young children less than one year with sepsis-like illness: comparison with enterovirus. J Clin Virol. 2019;119:11&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feuer R, Pagarigan RR, Harkins S, et al. Coxsackievirus targets proliferating neuronal progenitor cells in the neonatal CNS. J Neurosci. 2005;25:2434&#x2013;2444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feuer R, Mena I, Pagarigan RR, et al. Coxsackievirus B3 and the neonatal CNS: the roles of stem cells, developing neurons, and apoptosis in infection, viral dissemination, and disease. Am J Pathol. 2003;163:1379&#x2013;1393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker RC, Kummer AW, Schultz JR, et al. Neurodevelopmental outcome of infants with viral meningitis in the first three months of life. Clin Pediatr (Phila). 1996;35:295&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung TH, Chen VC, Yang YH, et al. Association between enterovirus infection and speech and language impairments: a nationwide population-based study. Res Dev Disabil. 2018;77:76&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin CH, Lin WD, Chou IC, et al. Epilepsy and neurodevelopmental outcomes in children with etiologically diagnosed central nervous system infections: a retrospective cohort study. Front Neurol. 2019;10:528.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balasubramanian H, Wagh D, Rao S, et al. Developmental outcomes in cerebrospinal fluid proven enteroviral meningitis in neonates&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;32&#x2009;weeks of gestation. J Paediatr Child Health. 2016;52:327&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jong EP, Holscher HC, Steggerda SJ, et al. Cerebral imaging and neurodevelopmental outcome after entero- and human parechovirus sepsis in young infants. Eur J Pediatr. 2017;176:1595&#x2013;1602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Huang LM, Gau SS, et al. Neurodevelopment and cognition in children after enterovirus 71 infection. N Engl J Med. 2007;356:1226&#x2013;1234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Lin HY, Gau SS, et al. Enterovirus A71 neurologic complications and long-term sequelae. J Biomed Sci. 2019;26:57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul H. Brookes Publishing I. Ages and Stages. 3rd ed. Brookes Publishing;2020:1&#x2013;21. Available at: https://agesandstages.com/products-pricing/asq3/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Squires J, Potter L, Bricker DD, et al. Parent-completed developmental questionnaires: effectiveness with low and middle income parents. Early Child Res Q. 1998;13:345&#x2013;354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul H. Concurrent Validity for ASQ-3 Questionnaire Intervals. Brookes Publishing I; 2020. Available at: https://agesandstages.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/asq3_concurrent_validity.pdf . Accessed May 7, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamsal R, Dutton DJ, Zwicker JD. Using the ages and stages questionnaire in the general population as a measure for identifying children not at risk of a neurodevelopmental disorder. BMC Pediatr. 2018;18:122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Small JW, Hix-Small H, Vargas-Baron E, et al. Comparative use of the ages and stages questionnaires in low- and middle-income countries. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2019;61:431&#x2013;443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guevara JP, Gerdes M, Localio R, et al. Effectiveness of developmental screening in an urban setting. Pediatrics. 2013;131:30&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radecki L, Sand-Loud N, O&#x2019;Connor KG, et al. Trends in the use of standardized tools for developmental screening in early childhood: 2002-2009. Pediatrics. 2011;128:14&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>San Antonio M, Fenick A, Shabanova V, et al. Developmental screening using the ages and stages questionnaire: standardized versus real-world conditions. Infants Young Children. 2014;27:111&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skellern CY, Rogers Y, O&#x2019;Callaghan MJ. A parent-completed developmental questionnaire: follow up of ex-premature infants. J Paediatr Child Health. 2001;37:125&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attell JE, Rose C, Bertolli J, et al. Adapting the ages and stages questionnaire to identify and quantify development among children with evidence of zika infection. Infants Young Child. 2020;33:95&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>