<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29108321</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1949-2553</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>45</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Oncotarget</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Oncotarget</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association study of inflammatory cytokine and chemokine expression in hand foot and mouth disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>79425</StartPage><EndPage>79432</EndPage><MedlinePgn>79425-79432</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.18632/oncotarget.18341</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine the relationship of cytokine/chemokine expression with the clinical presentation of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All cytokine/chemokine levels were higher in severe HFMD patients than in mild HFMD patients or controls (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.01). RANTES, MCP-1, IL-4, IL-12 and IL-18 levels were higher in mild HFMD patients than in the controls (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). In severe HFMD, all levels (except IL-8 and IL-4) were higher in patients with encephalitis plus pulmonary edema than in those with encephalitis alone (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). All levels (except IL-8) were higher in EV71-positive patients than in EV71-negative patients (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). In mild HFMD, all levels (except IL-8 and IL-4) were higher in EV71-positive patients than in EV71-negative patients (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). In severe HFMD, only RANTES, IP-10 and IFN-&#x3b3; levels were higher in EV71-positive patients than in EV71-negative patients (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). In the EV71-negative group, all levels were higher in severe HFMD than in mild HFMD (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.01). In the EV71-positive group, all levels (except IL-8) were higher in severe HFMD than in mild HFMD (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.01).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study involved 28 mild HFMD patients, 44 severe HFMD patients and 26 healthy children. Venous blood was tested for cytokines (IL-4, IL-12, IL-18, TNF-&#x3b1;, IFN-&#x3b3;) and chemokines (IL-8, RANTES, MCP-1, IP-10). Stool samples from the patients were tested for EV71 nucleic acid using reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Cytokines/chemokines participate in HFMD pathogenesis, and could have potential value in monitoring disease progression and predicting prognosis.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shang</LastName><ForeName>Wenzhong</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>People's Hospital of Fuyang District, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qian</LastName><ForeName>Suying</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Second Hospital of Ningbo, Ningbo, Zhejiang, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Lijuan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Fourth Hospital of Xiaoshan District, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Tumor Molecular Diagnosis and Individualized Medicine of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang Provincial People's Hospital, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Cuiping</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dingli Hospital of Wenzhou Medical School, Wezhou Central Hospital, Zhejiang, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Oncotarget</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101532965</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1949-2553</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemokines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foot and mouth disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammatory cytokines</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>CONFLICTS OF INTEREST The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29108321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5668054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.18341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">18341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xing W, Liao Q, Viboud C, Zhang J, Sun J, Wu JT, Chang Z, Liu F, Fang VJ, Zheng Y, Cowling BJ, Varma JK, Farrar JJ, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China, 2008-12: an epidemiological study. The Lancet Infectious diseases. 2014;14:308&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24485991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Huo X, Dai Y, Yang Z, Lei Y, Jiang Y, Li G, Zhan J, Zhan F. Evidences for intertypic and intratypic recombinant events in EV71 of hand, foot and mouth disease during an epidemic in Hubei Province, China, 2011. Virus research. 2012;169:195&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22922556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Ling, Hu Jing-wei, Zhou Zhong-shu. Central Nervous System Damage Associated with Hand-Foot-Mouth Disease Induced by Enterovirus 71. [Article in Chinese] J Appl Clin Pediatr. 2008;23:1782&#x2013;1785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu RN, Qian Y, Deng J, Xing JF, Zhao LQ, Wang F, Liao B, Ren XX, Li Y, Zhang Q, Li J. Study on the association of hand, foot and mouth disease and enterovirus 71/CA16 among children in Beijing, 2007. [Article in Chinese] Zhonghua liuxingbingxue zazhi. 2007;28:1004&#x2013;1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18399150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Hsiung CA, Lu CY, Lin TY, Huang FY, Lai YH, Chiang YP, Chiang BL, Lee CY, Huang LM. Status of cellular rather than humoral immunity is correlated with clinical outcome of enterovirus 71. Pediatric research. 2006;60:466&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7086547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16940249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Chang LY, Huang YC, Hsu KH, Chiu CH, Yang KD. Different proinflammatory reactions in fatal and non-fatal enterovirus 71 infections: implications for early recognition and therapy. Acta paediatrica (Oslo, Norway : 1992) 2002;91:632&#x2013;635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12162592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Yu CK, Wang JR, Su IJ, Liu CC. Acute chemokine response in the blood and cerebrospinal fluid of children with enterovirus 71-associated brainstem encephalitis. The Journal of infectious diseases. 2008;198:1002&#x2013;1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18710325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei L, Zhou C, Bao F, Liu J, Li Y, Wang G, Song C. The expression and the clinical significance of blood and immunological changes of child patients with HFMD. [Article in Chinese] Henan Medical Res. 2011;20:406&#x2013;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuang W, Yan Z, Xin Z. Multiplex serum cytokine levels in patients with severe HFMD determined by Luminex suspension array. [Article in Chinese] Beijing Medical Journal. 2012;34:185&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu D, Li CR, He YX, Zu Y, Cao DZ, Wang GB, Deng JK, Wang HP. Changes of immune function in patients with enterovirus 71 infection. Chinese journal of pediatrics. 2009;47:829&#x2013;834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20078993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbloom AJ, Linden PK, Dorrance A, Penkosky N, Cohen-Melamed MH, Pinsky MR. Effect of granulocyte-monocyte colony-stimulating factor therapy on leukocyte function and clearance of serious infection in nonneutropenic patients. Chest. 2005;127:2139&#x2013;2150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Berghe G, Wouters P, Weekers F, Verwaest C, Bruyninckx F, Schetz M, Vlasselaers D, Ferdinande P, Lauwers P, Bouillon R. Intensive insulin therapy in critically ill patients. The New England journal of medicine. 2001;345:1359&#x2013;1367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11794168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lekkou A, Karakantza M, Mouzaki A, Kalfarentzos F, Gogos CA. Cytokine production and monocyte HLA-DR expression as predictors of outcome for patients with community-acquired severe infections. Clinical and diagnostic laboratory immunology. 2004;11:161&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC321326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14715564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan S, Xia C, Morel L. IL-6 produced by dendritic cells from lupus-prone mice inhibits CD4+CD25+ T cell regulatory functions. Journal of immunology. 2007;178:271&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17182564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Huang MC, Su LY, Lin HC, Yu CK, Wang JL, Liu CC. Modulation of cytokine production by intravenous immunoglobulin in patients with enterovirus 71-associated brainstem encephalitis. Journal of clinical virology. 2006;37:47&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16861032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palumbo GA, Scisciani C, Pediconi N, Lupacchini L, Alfalate D, Guerrieri F, Calvo L, Salerno D, Di Cocco S, Levrero M, Belloni L. IL6 Inhibits HBV Transcription by Targeting the Epigenetic Control of the Nuclear cccDNA Minichromosome. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0142599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4651563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26580974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramshaw IA, Ramsay AJ, Karupiah G, Rolph MS, Mahalingam S, Ruby JC. Cytokines and immunity to viral infections. Immunological reviews. 1997;159:119&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9416507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou M, Zhang Y. Advances in the cytokines related to hand, foot and mouth disease. Infectious Disease Information. [Article in Chinese] 2013;26:53&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Su LY, Wu JM, Yu CK, Wang JR, Liu CC. Cerebrospinal fluid cytokines in enterovirus 71 brain stem encephalitis and echovirus meningitis infections of varying severity. Clinical microbiology and infection. 2007;13:677&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17441979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>