<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">19386699</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2009</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>83</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate><Year>2009</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lymphocyte and antibody responses reduce enterovirus 71 lethality in mice by decreasing tissue viral loads.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6477</StartPage><EndPage>6483</EndPage><MedlinePgn>6477-83</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.00434-09</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) infects the central nervous system and causes death and long-term neurological sequelae in hundreds of thousands of young children, but its pathogenesis remains elusive. Immunopathological mechanisms have been suspected to contribute to the pathogenesis of neurological symptoms, so anti-inflammatory agents have been used to treat patients with neurological symptoms. The present study was therefore designed to investigate the functions of lymphocyte and antibody responses in EV71 infection using a mouse model. Immunohistochemical staining analysis revealed virus and three types of lymphocytes, B cells, CD4 T cells, and CD8 T cells, in the spinal cord of an EV71-infected patient who died. A study of mice showed that the levels of virus and lymphocytes in brains and antibody titers in sera were elevated during the time when the mice succumbed to death in a phenomenon analogous to that observed in patients. Further studies demonstrated that after infection, the disease severity, mortality, and tissue viral loads of mice deficient in B, CD4 T, or CD8 T cells were significantly higher than those of wild-type mice. In addition, treatment with a virus-specific antibody, but not a control antibody, before or after infection significantly reduced the disease severity, mortality, and tissue viral loads of mice deficient in B cells. Our results show that both lymphocyte and antibody responses protect mice from EV71 infection. Our study suggests the use of vaccines and virus-specific antibodies to control fatal outbreaks and raises caution over the use of corticosteroids to treat EV71-infected patients with neurological symptoms.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Wen</ForeName><Initials>YW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Sciences, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan 701, Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Kung-Chao</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kao</LastName><ForeName>Chia-Min</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Shih-Ping</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tung</LastName><ForeName>Yuk-Ying</ForeName><Initials>YY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Shun-Hua</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2009</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000914">Antibodies, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000914" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001402" MajorTopicYN="N">B-Lymphocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015496" MajorTopicYN="N">CD4-Positive T-Lymphocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018414" MajorTopicYN="N">CD8-Positive T-Lymphocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007150" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunohistochemistry</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008810" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred C57BL</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008813" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred ICR</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009500" MajorTopicYN="N">Neutralization Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019562" MajorTopicYN="Y">Viral Load</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.00434-09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.00434-09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abzug, M. J., H. L. Keyserling, M. L. Lee, M. J. Levin, and H. A. Rotbart. 1995. Neonatal enterovirus infection: virology, serology, and effects of intravenous immune globulin. Clin. Infect. Dis. 201201-1206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7620000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashwell, J. D., F. W. Lu, and M. S. Vacchio. 2000. Glucocorticoids in T cell development and function. Annu. Rev. Immunol. 18309-345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10837061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control. 22 January 2009. Cases of notifiable diseases, Taiwan, R.O.C., vol. 25, no. 1. Taiwan Epidemiology Bulletin. Centers for Disease Control, Department of Health, Executive Yuan, Taiwan, Republic of China. https://teb.cdc.gov.tw/main_e/main.aspx#.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., C. A. Hsiung, C. Y. Lu, T. Y. Lin, F. Y. Huang, Y. H. Lai, Y. P. Chiang, B. L. Chiang, C. Y. Lee, and L. M. Huang. 2006. Status of cellular rather than humoral immunity is correlated with clinical outcome of enterovirus 71. Pediatr. Res. 60466-471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7086547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16940249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., S. H. Hsia, C. T. Wu, Y. C. Huang, K. L. Lin, T. Y. Fang, and T. Y. Lin. 2004. Outcome of enterovirus 71 infections with or without stage-based management: 1998 to 2002. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 23327-331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15071287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., L. M. Huang, S. S. Gau, Y. Y. Wu, S. H. Hsia, T. Y. Fan, K. L. Lin, Y. C. Huang, C. Y. Lu, and T. Y. Lin. 2007. Neurodevelopment and cognition in children after enterovirus 71 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 3561226-1234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17377160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M., E. R. Chen, K. H. Hsu, S. J. Twu, K. T. Chen, S. F. Tsai, J. R. Wang, and S. R. Shih for The Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. N. Engl. J. Med. 341929-935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsia, S. H., C. T. Wu, J. J. Chang, T. Y. Lin, H. T. Chung, K. L. Lin, M. S. Hwang, M. L. Chou, and L. Y. Chang. 2005. Predictors of unfavorable outcomes in enterovirus 71-related cardiopulmonary failure in children. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 24331-334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15818293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C. C., C. C. Liu, Y. C. Chang, C. Y. Chen, S. T. Wang, and T. F. Yeh. 1999. Neurologic complications in children with enterovirus 71 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 341936-942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. H., C. M. Li, P. Ling, F. H. Shen, S. H. Chen, C. C. Liu, C. K. Yu, and S. H. Chen. 2008. Ribavirin reduces mortality in enterovirus 71-infected mice by decreasing viral replication. J. Infect. Dis. 197854-857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7109938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18279075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., C. Chu, and C. H. Chiu. 2002. Lactoferrin inhibits enterovirus 71 infection of human embryonal rhabdomyosarcoma cells in vitro. J. Infect. Dis. 1861161-1164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12355368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum, L. C., K. T. Wong, S. K. Lam, K. B. Chua, A. Y. Goh, W. L. Lim, B. B. Ong, G. Paul, S. AbuBakar, and M. Lambert. 1998. Fatal enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. J. Pediatr. 133795-798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKinney, R. E., Jr., S. L. Katz, and C. M. Wilfert. 1987. Chronic enteroviral meningoencephalitis in agammaglobulinemic patients. Rev. Infect. Dis. 9334-356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3296100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., I. Stratov, L. Nagarajan, and S. Davis. 2001. Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin. Infect. Dis. 32236-242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolan, M. A., M. E. Craig, M. M. Lahra, W. D. Rawlinson, P. C. Prager, G. D. Williams, A. M. Bye, and P. I. Andrews. 2003. Survival after pulmonary edema due to enterovirus 71 encephalitis. Neurology 601651-1656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12771257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu, J. 2008. Enterovirus 71 infection: a new threat to global public health? Lancet Neurol. 7868-869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18848307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., H. Y. Lei, K. J. Huang, J. M. Wu, J. R. Wang, C. K. Yu, I. J. Su, and C. C. Liu. 2003. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J. Infect. Dis. 188564-570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., H. Y. Lei, M. C. Huang, L. Y. Su, H. C. Lin, C. K. Yu, J. L. Wang, and C. C. Liu. 2006. Modulation of cytokine production by intravenous immunoglobulin in patients with enterovirus 71-associated brainstem encephalitis. J. Clin. Virol. 3747-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16861032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., C. C. Liu, H. W. Tseng, J. R. Wang, C. C. Huang, Y. J. Chen, Y. J. Yang, S. J. Lin, and T. F. Yeh. 1999. Clinical spectrum of enterovirus 71 infection in children in southern Taiwan, with an emphasis on neurological complications. Clin. Infect. Dis. 29184-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10433583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. F., C. T. Chou, H. Y. Lei, C. C. Liu, S. M. Wang, J. J. Yan, I. J. Su, J. R. Wang, T. M. Yeh, S. H. Chen, and C. K. Yu. 2004. A mouse-adapted enterovirus 71 strain causes neurological disease in mice after oral infection. J. Virol. 787916-7924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC446098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, C. N., Y. C. Lin, C. Fann, N. S. Liao, S. R. Shih, and M. S. Ho. 2001. Protection against lethal enterovirus 71 infection in newborn mice by passive immunization with subunit VP1 vaccines and inactivated virus. Vaccine 20895-904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, J. J., J. R. Wang, C. C. Liu, H. B. Yang, and I. J. Su. 2000. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan 1998: a comprehensive pathological, virological, and molecular study on a case of fulminant encephalitis. J. Clin. Virol. 1713-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, C. K., C. C. Chen, C. L. Chen, J. R. Wang, C. C. Liu, J. J. Yan, and I. J. Su. 2000. Neutralizing antibody provided protection against enterovirus type 71 lethal challenge in neonatal mice. J. Biomed. Sci. 7523-528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11060501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>