<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">17537928</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2007</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0095-1137</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2007</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>High-throughput, sensitive, and accurate multiplex PCR-microsphere flow cytometry system for large-scale comprehensive detection of respiratory viruses.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2626</StartPage><EndPage>2634</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2626-34</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Human respiratory viruses are a diverse group of pathogens composed of hundreds of virus strains, and this presents a major challenge for diagnostic laboratories. To efficiently detect numerous viruses in a large epidemiologic study, we developed a fast, multitarget, sensitive, and specific assay named the Respiratory MultiCode-PLx Assay (RMA). The RMA utilizes improved multiplex PCR chemistry (EraGen MultiCode-PLx technology) coupled with high-throughput microsphere flow cytometry (Luminex). Eighteen sets of virus-specific multiplex PCR primers were developed based on the conserved sequences of all available respiratory-virus sequences for eight distinct groups: human rhinovirus (HRV), respiratory syncytial virus (RSV), parainfluenza virus (PIV), influenza virus (InfV), metapneumovirus, adenovirus (Ad), coronavirus, and enterovirus. Each primer set detected 20 cDNA copies of the intended target per sample and had no reaction with 60,000 copies of human genomic DNA. The accuracy and sensitivity of the RMA for detecting respiratory viruses in human samples were tested with two sets of clinical specimens. First, 101 nasal-wash specimens that were positive for HRV, RSV, InfV, PIV, or Ad by traditional techniques were reanalyzed by RMA, and all target viruses were detected with an overall sensitivity of 94% and specificity of 99%. Second, 103 nasal-wash samples from 5-year-old children with asthma and respiratory symptoms were analyzed; RMA detected viruses in 74 specimens (71.8%) compared to only 24 (23.3%) by traditional culture and immunofluorescent-staining techniques. These results show that RMA is an accurate, sensitive, and practical test for respiratory-virus infections.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Wai-Ming</ForeName><Initials>WM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Medicine, University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wisconsin, USA. wlee5@wisc.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grindle</LastName><ForeName>Kris</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pappas</LastName><ForeName>Tressa</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marshall</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moser</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beaty</LastName><ForeName>Edward L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shult</LastName><ForeName>Peter A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prudent</LastName><ForeName>James R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gern</LastName><ForeName>James E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>U19 AI070503</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D023362">Evaluation Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2007</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505564</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0095-1137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017931">DNA Primers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017931" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA Primers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005434" MajorTopicYN="N">Flow Cytometry</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005455" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluorescent Antibody Technique</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017817" MajorTopicYN="N">Nasal Lavage Fluid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016133" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012141" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Tract Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012680" MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity and Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014773" MajorTopicYN="N">Virology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014776" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Cultivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014780" MajorTopicYN="N">Viruses</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="Y">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2007</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2007</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2007</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2007</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17537928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.02501-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JCM.02501-06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Allander, T., M. T. Tammi, M. Eriksson, A. Bjerkner, A. Tiveljung-Lindell, and B. Andersson. 2005. Cloning of a human parvovirus by molecular screening of respiratory tract samples. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 102:12891-12896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1200281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16118271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ausubel, F. M., R. Brent, R. E. Kingston, D. D. Moore, J. G. Seidman, J. A. Smith, and K. Struhl (ed.). 1987. Current protocols in molecular biology. John Wiley and Sons, New York, NY.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastien, N., K. Brandt, K. Dust, D. Ward, and Y. Li. 2006. Human bocavirus infection, Canada. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 12:848-850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3374420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16704852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beasley, R. 2002. The burden of asthma with specific reference to the United States. J. Allergy Clin. Immunol. 109:S482-S489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11994720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman, N. M., S. Tracy, C. J. Gauntt, and U. Fortmueller. 1990. Molecular detection and identification of enteroviruses using enzymatic amplification and nucleic acid hybridization. J. Clin. Microbiol. 28:843-850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC267821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2161866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coiras, M. T., J. C. Aguilar, M. L. Garcia, I. Casas, and P. Perez-Brena. 2004. Simultaneous detection of fourteen respiratory viruses in clinical specimens by two multiplex reverse transcription nested-PCR assays. J. Med. Virol. 72:484-495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7166637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14748074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coiras, M. T., M. R. Lopez-Huertas, G. Lopez-Campos, J. C. Aguilar, and P. Perez-Brena. 2005. Oligonucleotide array for simultaneous detection of respiratory viruses using a reverse-line blot hybridization assay. J. Med. Virol. 76:256-264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15834876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couch, R. B. 2001. Rhinoviruses, p. 777-797. In D. M. Knipe, P. M. Howley, D. E. Griffin, et al. (ed.), Fields virology, 4th ed., vol. 1. Lippincott Williams and Wilkins, Philadephia, PA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake, J. W. 1993. Rates of spontaneous mutation among RNA viruses. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 90:4171-4175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC46468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8387212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drosten, C., S. Gunther, W. Preiser, S. van der Werf, H. R. Brodt, S. Becker, H. Rabenau, M. Panning, L. Kolesnikova, R. A. Fouchier, A. Berger, A. M. Burguiere, J. Cinatl, M. Eickmann, N. Escriou, K. Grywna, S. Kramme, J. C. Manuguerra, S. Muller, V. Rickerts, M. Sturmer, S. Vieth, H. D. Klenk, A. D. Osterhaus, H. Schmitz, and H. W. Doerr. 2003. Identification of a novel coronavirus in patients with severe acute respiratory syndrome. N. Engl. J. Med. 348:1967-1976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12690091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esper, F., C. Weibel, D. Ferguson, M. L. Landry, and J. S. Kahn. 2006. Coronavirus HKU1 infection in the United States. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 12:775-779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3374449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16704837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan, J., K. J. Henrickson, and L. L. Savatski. 1998. Rapid simultaneous diagnosis of infections with respiratory syncytial viruses A and B, influenza viruses A and B, and human parainfluenza virus types 1, 2, and 3 by multiplex quantitative reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction-enzyme hybridization assay (Hexaplex). Clin. Infect. Dis. 26:1397-1402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9636869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foulongne, V., M. Rodiere, and M. Segondy. 2006. Human bocavirus in children. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 12:862-863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3374421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16710957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gern, J. E., and R. F. J. Lemanske. 2003. Infectious triggers of pediatric asthma. Pediatr. Clin. N. Am. 50:555-575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12877236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gern, J. E., M. S. Martin, K. A. Anklam, K. Shen, K. A. Roberg, K. T. Carlson-Dakes, K. Adler, S. Gilbertson-White, R. Hamilton, P. A. Shult, C. J. Kirk, D. F. Da Silva, S. A. Sund, M. R. Kosorok, and R. F. J. Lemanske. 2002. Relationships among specific viral pathogens, virus-induced interleukin-8, and respiratory symptoms in infancy. Pediatr. Allergy Immunol. 13:386-393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12485313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grondahl, B., W. Puppe, A. Hoppe, I. Kuhne, J. A. Weigl, and H. J. Schmitt. 1999. Rapid identification of nine microorganisms causing acute respiratory tract infections by single-tube multiplex reverse transcription-PCR: feasibility study. J. Clin. Microbiol. 37:1-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC84151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9854054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henrickson, K. J. 2004. Advances in the laboratory diagnosis of viral respiratory disease. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 23:S6-S10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14730264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hindiyeh, M., D. R. Hillyard, and K. C. Carroll. 2001. Evaluation of the Prodesse Hexaplex multiplex PCR assay for direct detection of seven respiratory viruses in clinical specimens. Am. J. Clin. Pathol. 116:218-224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11488068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Illi, S., E. von Mutius, S. Lau, R. Bergmann, B. Niggemann, C. Sommerfeld, U. Wahn, et al. 2001. Early childhood infectious diseases and the development of asthma up to school age: a birth cohort study. Br. Med. J. 322:390-395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC26566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11179155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, S. C., D. J. Marshall, G. Harms, C. M. Miller, C. B. Sherrill, E. L. Beaty, S. A. Lederer, E. B. Roesch, G. Madsen, G. L. Hoffman, R. H. Laessig, G. J. Kopish, M. W. Baker, S. A. Benner, P. M. Farrell, and J. R. Prudent. 2004. Multiplexed genetic analysis using an expanded genetic alphabet. Clin. Chem. 50:2019-2027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1592527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15319316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston, S. L. 2005. Overview of virus-induced airway disease. Proc. Am. Thoracic Soc. 2:150-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16113484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller, M. B., and S. R. Lowenstein. 2002. Epidemiology of asthma. Sem. Respir. Crit. Care. Med. 23:317-329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16088625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ksiazek, T. G., D. Erdman, C. S. Goldsmith, S. R. Zaki, T. Peret, S. Emery, S. Tong, C. Urbani, J. A. Comer, W. Lim, P. E. Rollin, S. F. Dowell, A. E. Ling, C. D. Humphrey, W. J. Shieh, J. Guarner, C. D. Paddock, P. Rota, B. Fields, J. DeRisi, J. Y. Yang, N. Cox, J. M. Hughes, J. W. LeDuc, W. J. Bellini, and L. J. Anderson. 2003. A novel coronavirus associated with severe acute respiratory syndrome. N. Engl. J. Med. 348:1953-1966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12690092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, W. M., S. S. Monroe, and R. R. Rueckert. 1993. Role of maturation cleavage in infectivity of picornaviruses: activation of an infectosome. J. Virol. 67:2110-2122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC240305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8383233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, W. M., and W. Wang. 2003. Human rhinovirus type 16: mutant V1210A requires capsid-binding drug for assembly of pentamers to form virions during morphogenesis. J. Virol. 77:6235-6244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC154994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12743280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemanske, R. F. 2004. Viral infections and asthma inception. J. Allergy Clin. Immunol. 114:1023-1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15536404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemanske, R. F. J. 2002. The childhood origins of asthma (COAST) study. Pediatr. Allergy Immunol. 13:38-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12688623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemanske, R. F. J., D. J. Jackson, R. E. Gangnon, M. D. Evans, Z. Li, P. A. Shult, C. J. Kirk, E. Reisdorf, K. A. Roberg, E. L. Anderson, K. T. Carlson-Dakes, K. J. Adler, S. Gilbertson-White, T. E. Pappas, D. F. Dasilva, C. J. Tisler, and J. E. Gern. 2005. Rhinovirus illnesses during infancy predict subsequent childhood wheezing. J. Allergy Clin. Immunol. 116:571-577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16159626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liolios, L., A. Jenney, D. Spelman, T. Kotsimbos, M. Catton, and S. Wesselingh. 2001. Comparison of a multiplex reverse transcription-PCR-enzyme hybridization assay with conventional viral culture and immunofluorescence techniques for the detection of seven viral respiratory pathogens. J. Clin. Microbiol. 39:2779-2783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11473991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, X., R. Endo, N. Ishiguro, T. Ebihara, H. Ishiko, T. Ariga, and H. Kikuta. 2006. Detection of human bocavirus in Japanese children with lower respiratory tract infections. J. Clin. Microbiol. 44:1132-1134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1393160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16517912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mifflin, T. E. 2003. Setting up a PCR laboratory, p. 5-14. In C. W. Dieffenbach and G. S. Dveksler (ed.), PCR primer: a laboratory manual. Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press, Cold Spring Harbor, NY.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolan, J. P., and F. Mandy. 2006. Multiplexed and microparticle-based analyses: quantitative tools for the large-scale analysis of biological systems. Cytometry A 69:318-325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2200865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16604537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novinska, M. S., B. C. Pietz, T. M. Ellis, D. K. Newman, and P. J. Newman. 2006. The alleles of PECAM-1. Gene 376:95-101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2965460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16581204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pehler-Harrington, K., M. Khanna, C. R. Waters, and K. J. Henrickson. 2004. Rapid detection and identification of human adenovirus species by adenoplex, a multiplex PCR-enzyme hybridization assay. J. Clin. Microbiol. 42:4072-4076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC516351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15364992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietz, B. C., M. B. Warden, B. K. DuChateau, and T. M. Ellis. 2005. Multiplex genotyping of human minor histocompatibility antigens. Hum. Immunol. 66:1174-1182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16571418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigurs, N., R. Bjarnason, F. Sigurbergsson, and B. Kjellman. 2000. Respiratory syncytial virus bronchiolitis in infancy is an important risk factor for asthma and allergy at age 7. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 161:1501-1507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10806145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sigurs, N., P. M. Gustafsson, R. Bjarnason, F. Lundberg, S. Schmidt, F. Sigurbergsson, and B. Kjellman. 2005. Severe respiratory syncytial virus bronchiolitis in infancy and asthma and allergy at age 13. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 171:137-141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15516534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein, R. T., D. Sherrill, W. J. Morgan, C. J. Holberg, M. Halonen, L. M. Taussig, A. L. Wright, and F. D. Martinez. 1999. Respiratory syncytial virus in early life and risk of wheeze and allergy by age 13 years. Lancet 354:541-545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10470697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storch, G. A. 2001. Diagnostic virology, p. 493-531. In D. M. Knipe, P. M. Howley, D. E. Griffin, et al. (ed.), Fields virology, 4th ed., vol. 1. Lippincott Williams and Wilkins, Philadelphia, PA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syrmis, M. W., D. M. Whiley, M. Thomas, I. M. Mackay, J. Williamson, D. J. Siebert, M. D. Nissen, and T. P. Sloots. 2004. A sensitive, specific, and cost-effective multiplex reverse transcriptase-PCR assay for the detection of seven common respiratory viruses in respiratory samples. J. Mol. Diagn. 6:125-131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1867476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15096568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Templeton, K. E., S. A. Scheltinga, M. F. Beersma, A. C. Kroes, and E. C. Claas. 2004. Rapid and sensitive method using multiplex real-time PCR for diagnosis of infections by influenza A and influenza B viruses, respiratory syncytial virus, and parainfluenza viruses 1, 2, 3, and 4. J. Clin. Microbiol. 42:1564-1569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC387552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15071005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, J. D., T. J. Gibson, F. Plewniak, F. Jeanmougin, and D. G. Higgins. 1997. The ClustalX windows interface: flexible strategies for multiple sequence alignment aided by quality analysis tools. Nucleic Acids Res. 24:4876-4882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC147148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9396791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vabret, A., J. Dina, S. Gouarin, J. Petitjean, S. Corbet, and F. Freymuth. 2006. Detection of the new human coronavirus HKU1: a report of 6 cases. Clin. Infect. Dis. 42:634-639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7107802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16447108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Hoogen, B. G., J. C. de Jong, J. Groen, T. Kuiken, R. de Groot, R. A. Fouchier, and A. D. Osterhaus. 2001. A newly discovered human pneumovirus isolated from young children with respiratory tract disease. Nat. Med. 7:719-724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11385510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Hoogen, B. G., D. M. Osterhaus, and R. A. Fouchier. 2004. Clinical impact and diagnosis of human metapneumovirus infection. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 23:S25-S32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14730267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Hoek, L., K. Pyrc, M. F. Jebbink, W. Vermeulen-Oost, R. J. Berkhout, K. C. Wolthers, P. M. Wertheim-van Dillen, J. Kaandorp, J. Spaargaren, and B. Berkhout. 2004. Identification of a new human coronavirus. Nat. Med. 10:368-373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7095789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15034574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Elden, L. J., M. G. van Kraaij, M. Nijhuis, K. A. Hendriksen, A. W. Dekker, M. Rozenberg-Arska, and A. M. van Loon. 2002. Polymerase chain reaction is more sensitive than viral culture and antigen testing for the detection of respiratory viruses in adults with hematological cancer and pneumonia. Clin. Infect. Dis. 34:177-183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7109912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11740705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo, P. C., S. K. Lau, C. M. Chu, K. H. Chan, H. W. Tsoi, Y. Huang, B. H. Wong, R. W. Poon, J. J. Cai, W. K. Luk, L. L. Poon, S. S. Wong, Y. Guan, J. S. Peiris, and K. Y. Yuen. 2005. Characterization and complete genome sequence of a novel coronavirus, coronavirus HKU1, from patients with pneumonia. J. Virol. 79:884-895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC538593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15613317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>