<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32838942</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-0341</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>548</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Virology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association of CD14 rs2569190&#xa0;G/A genetic polymorphism with the severity of enterovirus 71 infection in Chinese children.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>25</StartPage><EndPage>30</EndPage><MedlinePgn>25-30</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.virol.2020.06.001</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0042-6822(20)30103-3</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Ya</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, No. 16 Jiangsu Road, Qingdao, Shandong, 266000, PR China; Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, The University of Mississippi Medical Center, No. 2500 North State Street, Jackson, MS, 39216, USA. Electronic address: guoyaqingda@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yedan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, No. 16 Jiangsu Road, Qingdao, Shandong, 266000, PR China; Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, The University of Mississippi Medical Center, No. 2500 North State Street, Jackson, MS, 39216, USA. Electronic address: liuyedan1010@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, No. 16 Jiangsu Road, Qingdao, Shandong, 266000, PR China. Electronic address: songjie838369595@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Peipei</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, No. 16 Jiangsu Road, Qingdao, Shandong, 266000, PR China. Electronic address: lqq-800@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Sifei</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, No. 16 Jiangsu Road, Qingdao, Shandong, 266000, PR China. Electronic address: 294418213@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Yuxia</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, No. 16 Jiangsu Road, Qingdao, Shandong, 266000, PR China; Department of Pediatrics, Zibo City Maternal and Child Health Hospital, No. 11 Xingyuandong Road, Zibo, Shandong, 255029, PR China. Electronic address: tanyx2009@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Fan</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, The University of Mississippi Medical Center, No. 2500 North State Street, Jackson, MS, 39216, USA. Electronic address: Ffanumc@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zongbo</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University, No. 16 Jiangsu Road, Qingdao, Shandong, 266000, PR China. Electronic address: drchen001cls@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P20 GM104357</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG057842</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R21 AG050049</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Virology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0110674</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0042-6822</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018950">Lipopolysaccharide Receptors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044466" MajorTopicYN="N">Asian People</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018950" MajorTopicYN="N">Lipopolysaccharide Receptors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest. The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32838942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1647878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7724738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.virol.2020.06.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0042-6822(20)30103-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Areeshi MY, Mandal RK, Panda AK, Bisht SC, Haque S, 2013. CD14 &#x2212;159 C&gt;T gene polymorphism with increased risk of tuberculosis: evidence from a meta-analysis. PLoS One 8, e64747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3669331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23741383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Lin TY, Hsu KH, Huang YC, Lin KL, Hsueh C, Shih SR, Ning HC, Hwang MS, Wang HS, Lee CY, 1999. Clinical features and risk factors of pulmonary oedema after enterovirus-71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet 354, 1682&#x2013;1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang PC, Chen SC, Chen KT, 2016. The Current Status of the Disease Caused by Enterovirus 71 Infections: Epidemiology, Pathogenesis, Molecular Epidemiology, and Vaccine Development. Int J Environ Res Public Health 13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5036723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27618078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dezfuli HT, Shahbazzadeh D, Eidi A, Bagheri KP, Pakravan N, Amini S, Aghasadeghi MR, Mahdavi M, 2014. Induction of IFN-gamma cytokine response against hepatitis B surface antigen using melittin. Gastroenterol Hepatol Bed Bench 7, 108&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4017562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24834302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu W, Dong H, Jiang DP, Zhou J, Du DY, Gao JM, Yao YZ, Zhang LY, Wen AQ, Liu Q, Wang ZG, Jiang JX, 2008. Functional significance of CD14 promoter polymorphisms and their clinical relevance in a Chinese Han population. Crit Care Med 36, 2274&#x2013;2280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18596635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao J, Li P, Tian Y, Wang Y, Li S, Wang L, Li S, 2018. Crosstalk between Toll-like receptor 3 and Notch signaling contributes to CD14(+) monocytes activity in enterovirus 71 infected hand, foot, and mouth disease. Int Immunopharmacol 60, 26&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29702280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H, Liu S, Liu PP, Li QB, Tan YX, Guo Y, Li F, Wang YY, Liu YD, Yang CQ, Chen ZB, 2017. Association of Toll-like receptor 3 gene polymorphism with the severity of enterovirus 71 infection in Chinese children. Arch Virol 162, 1717&#x2013;1723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28190199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang PN, Shih SR, 2014. Update on enterovirus 71 infection. Curr Opin Virol 5, 98&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24727707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubacek JA, Stuber F, Frohlich D, Book M, Wetegrove S, Rothe G, Schmitz G, 2000. The common functional C(&#x2212;159)T polymorphism within the promoter region of the lipopolysaccharide receptor CD14 is not associated with sepsis development or mortality. Genes Immun 1, 405&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11196689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Zhang R, Wu W, Duan G, 2018. Antiviral and Inflammatory Cellular Signaling Associated with Enterovirus 71 Infection. Viruses 10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5923449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29597291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapil S, Duseja A, Sharma BK, Singla B, Chakraborti A, Das A, Ray P, Dhiman RK, Chawla Y, 2016. Genetic polymorphism in CD14 gene, a co-receptor of TLR4 associated with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. World J Gastroenterol 22, 9346&#x2013;9355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5107698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27895422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kataoka C, Suzuki T, Kotani O, Iwata-Yoshikawa N, Nagata N, Ami Y, Wakita T, Nishimura Y, Shimizu H, 2015. The Role of VP1 Amino Acid Residue 145 of Enterovirus 71 in Viral Fitness and Pathogenesis in a Cynomolgus Monkey Model. PLoS Pathog 11, e1005033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4504482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26181772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KY, 2016. Enterovirus 71 infection and neurological complications. Korean J Pediatr 59, 395&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5099286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27826325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy MM, Fink MP, Marshall JC, Abraham E, Angus D, Cook D, Cohen J, Opal SM, Vincent JL, Ramsay G, Sccm/Esicm/Accp/Ats/Sis, 2003. 2001 SCCM/ESICM/ACCP/ATS/SIS International Sepsis Definitions Conference. Crit Care Med 31, 1250&#x2013;1256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12682500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Liu XP, Li JA, Han ZL, Liu PP, Wang YY, Song L, Chen ZB, 2015. Correlation of an interleukin-4 gene polymorphism with susceptibility to severe enterovirus 71 infection in Chinese children. Arch Virol 160, 1035&#x2013;1042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25666199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Yang Z, Wang Z, Xu Y, Luo S, Yu X, Liu J, Zhou Y, Tong W, Zeng P, 2019. The surveillance of the epidemiological and serotype characteristics of hand, foot, mouth disease in Neijiang city, China, 2010-2017: A retrospective study. PLoS One 14, e0217474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6553746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31170178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K, Dan Z, Hu XJ, Gesang LB, Ze YG, Bianba ZX, Ciren CM, Nie YQ, 2014a. Association of CD14/&#x2212;260 polymorphism with gastric cancer risk in Highland Tibetans. World J Gastroenterol 20, 2688&#x2013;2694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3949278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24627605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Teng G, Tong H, Jiao Y, Zhang T, Chen H, Wu H, 2014b. Study on risk factors for severe hand, foot and mouth disease in China. PLoS One 9, e87603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3906182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24489943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu SL, Pan H, Liu P, Amer S, Chan TC, Zhan J, Huo X, Liu Y, Teng Z, Wang L, Zhuang H, 2015. Comparative epidemiology and virology of fatal and nonfatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease in mainland China from 2008 to 2014. Reviews in medical virology 25, 115&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25704797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Liu P, Liu S, Guo Y, He H, Yang C, Song J, Zhang N, Cheng J, Chen Z, 2018. Oligoadenylate synthetase 3 S381R gene polymorphism is associated with severity of EV71 infection in Chinese children. J Clin Virol 101, 29&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29414184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Z, Ge M, Chen J, Geng Q, Tian M, Qiao Z, Bai L, Zhang Q, Zhu C, Xiong Y, Wu K, Liu F, Liu Y, Wu J, 2017. HRS plays an important role for TLR7 signaling to orchestrate inflammation and innate immunity upon EV71 infection. PLoS Pathog 13, e1006585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5595348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28854257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv T, Li J, Han Z, Chen Z, 2013. Association of interleukin-17F gene polymorphism with enterovirus 71 encephalitis in patients with hand, foot, and mouth disease. Inflammation 36, 977&#x2013;981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23519962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad Alizadeh AH, Ranjbar M, Hajilooi M, Fallahian F, 2006. Association of promoter polymorphism of the CD14 C (&#x2212;159) T endotoxin receptor gene with chronic hepatitis B. World J Gastroenterol 12, 5717&#x2013;5720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4088176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17007028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negishi H, Osawa T, Ogami K, Ouyang X, Sakaguchi S, Koshiba R, Yanai H, Seko Y, Shitara H, Bishop K, Yonekawa H, Tamura T, Kaisho T, Taya C, Taniguchi T, Honda K, 2008. A critical link between Toll-like receptor 3 and type II interferon signaling pathways in antiviral innate immunity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 105, 20446&#x2013;20451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2629334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19074283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathinayake PS, Hsu AC, Wark PA, 2015. Innate Immunity and Immune Evasion by Enterovirus 71. Viruses 7, 6613&#x2013;6630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4690884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26694447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun BJ, Chen HJ, Chen Y, An XD, Zhou BS, 2018. The Risk Factors of Acquiring Severe Hand, Foot, and Mouth Disease: A Meta-Analysis. The Canadian journal of infectious diseases &amp; medical microbiology = Journal canadien des maladies infectieuses et de la microbiologie medicale 2018, 2751457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6038695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30046361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triantafilou M, Triantafilou K, 2002. Lipopolysaccharide recognition: CD14, TLRs and the LPS-activation cluster. Trends Immunol 23, 301&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12072369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sanden SMG, Sachs N, Koekkoek SM, Koen G, Pajkrt D, Clevers H, Wolthers KC, 2018. Enterovirus 71 infection of human airway organoids reveals VP1-145 as a viral infectivity determinant. Emerg Microbes Infect 7, 84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5943241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29743570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Guo X, Yu S, Song J, Zhang J, Cao Z, Wang J, Liu M, Dong W, 2014. Association between CD14 gene polymorphisms and cancer risk: a meta-analysis. PLoS One 9, e100122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4076245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24978812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Teng Z, Cui X, Li C, Pan H, Zheng Y, Mao S, Yang Y, Wu L, Guo X, Zhang X, Zhu Y, 2018. Epidemiological and serological surveillance of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Shanghai, China, 2012-2016. Emerg Microbes Infect 7, 8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5837173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29362406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Hu J, Fan R, Zhou J, Zhong J, 2012. Association between CD14 gene C-260T polymorphism and inflammatory bowel disease: a meta-analysis. PLoS One 7, e45144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3458839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23049772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Xu X, Ren J, Liu S, Liao X, Wu X, Hu D, Wang G, Gu G, Kang Y, Li J, 2017. Association between the &#x2212;159C/T polymorphism in the promoter region of the CD14 gene and sepsis: a meta-analysis. BMC Anesthesiol 17, 11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5264438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28122493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yen TY, Shih WL, Huang YC, Lee JT, Huang LM, Chang LY, 2018. Polymorphisms in enterovirus 71 receptors associated with susceptibility and clinical severity. PLoS One 13, e0206769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6218064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30395634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi EJ, Shin YJ, Kim JH, Kim TG, Chang SY, 2017. Enterovirus 71 infection and vaccines. Clinical and experimental vaccine research 6, 4&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5292356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28168168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q, MacDonald NE, Smith JC, Cai K, Yu H, Li H, Lei C, 2014. Severe enterovirus type 71 nervous system infections in children in the Shanghai region of China: clinical manifestations and implications for prevention and care. Pediatr Infect Dis J 33, 482&#x2013;487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24732390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L, Bracken MB, 2011. Association of CD14 &#x2212;260 (&#x2212;159) C&gt;T and asthma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Med Genet 12, 93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3148550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21745379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao N, Chen HL, Chen ZZ, Li J, Chen ZB, 2017. IL-10-592 polymorphism is associated with IL-10 expression and severity of enterovirus 71 infection in chinese children. J Clin Virol 95, 42&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28843383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Zhang H, Liu H, Zhang J, He L, Sun H, Huang X, Yang Z, Ma S, 2018. Molecular characteristics of hand, foot, and mouth disease for hospitalized pediatric patients in Yunnan, China. Medicine (Baltimore) 97, e11610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6081097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30075535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Li W, Qi G, Liu N, Sheng L, Shang L, Qi B, 2017. The immune mechanism of intestinal tract Toll-like receptor in mediating EV71 virus type severe hand-foot-and-mouth disease and the MAPK pathway. Exp Ther Med 13, 2263&#x2013;2266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5443248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28565836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>