<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21715481</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>85</Volume><Issue>19</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Host factors in enterovirus 71 replication.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9658</StartPage><EndPage>9666</EndPage><MedlinePgn>9658-66</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.05063-11</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) infections continue to remain an important public health problem around the world, especially in the Asia-Pacific region. There is a significant mortality rate following such infections, and there is neither any proven therapy nor a vaccine for EV71. This has spurred much fundamental research into the replication of the virus. In this review, we discuss recent work identifying host cell factors which regulate the synthesis of EV71 RNA and proteins. Three of these proteins, heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein A1 (hnRNP A1), far-upstream element-binding protein 2 (FBP2), and FBP1 are nuclear proteins which in EV71-infected cells are relocalized to the cytoplasm, and they influence EV71 internal ribosome entry site (IRES) activity. hnRNP A1 stimulates IRES activity but can be replaced by hnRNP A2. FBP2 is a negative regulatory factor with respect to EV71 IRES activity, whereas FBP1 has the opposite effect. Two other proteins, hnRNP K and reticulon 3, are required for the efficient synthesis of viral RNA. The cleavage stimulation factor 64K subunit (CstF-64) is a host protein that is involved in the 3' polyadenylation of cellular pre-mRNAs, and recent work suggests that in EV71-infected cells, it may be cleaved by the EV71 3C protease. Such a cleavage would impair the processing of pre-mRNA to mature mRNAs. Host cell proteins play an important role in the replication of EV71, but much work remains to be done in order to understand how they act.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shih</LastName><ForeName>Shin-Ru</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Emerging Viral Infections, Chang Gung University, Tao-Yuan, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stollar</LastName><ForeName>Victor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Mei-Ling</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R03 AI070668</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>AI-70668</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014764">Viral Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="Y">growth &amp; development</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054884" MajorTopicYN="Y">Host-Pathogen Interactions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000096" MajorTopicYN="N">biosynthesis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014764" MajorTopicYN="N">Viral Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000096" MajorTopicYN="N">biosynthesis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014779" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Replication</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21715481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.05063-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.05063-11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar S., et al. 2009. Enterovirus 71 outbreak, Brunei. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 15:79&#x2013;82</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19116058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander J. P., Jr., Baden L., Pallansch M. A., Anderson L. J. 1994. Enterovirus 71 infections and neurologic disease&#x2014;United States, 1977-1991. J. Infect. Dis. 169:905&#x2013;908</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8133108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreev D. E., et al. 2007. Differential factor requirement to assemble translation initiation complexes at the alternative start codons of foot-and-mouth disease virus RNA. RNA 13:1366&#x2013;1374</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1924898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17592045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argos P., Kamer G., Nicklin M. J., Wimmer E. 1984. Similarity in gene organization and homology between proteins of animal picornaviruses and a plant comovirus suggest common ancestry of these virus families. Nucleic Acids Res. 12:7251&#x2013;7267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC320155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6384934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedard K. M., Semler B. L. 2004. Regulation of picornavirus gene expression. Microbes Infect. 6:702&#x2013;713</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15158778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belsham G. J. 2009. Divergent picornavirus IRES elements. Virus Res. 139:183&#x2013;192</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18675861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borman A. M., Bailly J. L., Girard M., Kean K. M. 1995. Picornavirus internal ribosome entry segments: comparison of translation efficiency and the requirements for optimal internal initiation of translation in vitro. Nucleic Acids Res. 23:3656&#x2013;3663</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC307262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7478993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borman A. M., Michel Y. M., Kean K. M. 2001. Detailed analysis of the requirements of hepatitis A virus internal ribosome entry segment for the eukaryotic initiation factor complex eIF4F. J. Virol. 75:7864&#x2013;7871</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11483730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown B. A., Oberste M. S., Alexander J. P., Jr., Kennett M. L., Pallansch M. A. 1999. Molecular epidemiology and evolution of enterovirus 71 strains isolated from 1970 to 1998. J. Virol. 73:9969&#x2013;9975</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10559310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant H. E., et al. 2000. Interaction between herpes simplex virus type 1 IE63 protein and cellular protein p32. J. Virol. 74:11322&#x2013;11328</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11070032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnham A. J., Gong L., Hardy R. W. 2007. Heterogeneous nuclear ribonuclear protein K interacts with Sindbis virus nonstructural proteins and viral subgenomic mRNA. Virology 367:212&#x2013;221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17561226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cammas A., et al. 2007. Cytoplasmic relocalization of heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein A1 controls translation initiation of specific mRNAs. Mol. Biol. Cell 18:5048&#x2013;5059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2096577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17898077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartegni L., Chew S. L., Krainer A. R. 2002. Listening to silence and understanding nonsense: exonic mutations that affect splicing. Nat. Rev. Genet. 3:285&#x2013;298</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11967553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C. J., et al. 2001. The heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein K (hnRNP K) interacts with dengue virus core protein. DNA Cell Biol. 20:569&#x2013;577</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11747608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M., Manley J. L. 2009. Mechanisms of alternative splicing regulation: insights from molecular and genomics approaches. Nat. Rev. Mol. Cell Biol. 10:741&#x2013;754</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2958924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19773805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R., et al. 2011. Reticulon 3 attenuates the clearance of cytosolic prion aggregates via inhibiting autophagy. Autophagy 7:205&#x2013;216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21119307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheunim T., Zhang J., Milligan S. G., McPhillips M. G., Graham S. V. 2008. The alternative splicing factor hnRNP A1 is up-regulated during virus-infected epithelial cell differentiation and binds the human papillomavirus type 16 late regulatory element. Virus Res. 131:189&#x2013;198</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2635527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17950949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien H. L., Liao C. L., Lin Y. L. 2011. The FUSE binding protein 1 interacts with untranslated regions of Japanese encephalitis virus RNA and negatively regulates viral replication. J. Virol. 85:4698&#x2013;4706</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3126168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21367899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chook Y. M., Blobel G. 1999. Structure of the nuclear transport complex karyopherin-&#x3b2;2-Ran&#xb7;GppNHp. Nature 399:230&#x2013;237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10353245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colgan D. F., Manley J. L. 1997. Mechanism and regulation of mRNA polyadenylation. Genes Dev. 11:2755&#x2013;2766</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9353246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis-Smyth T., Duncan R. C., Zheng T., Michelotti G., Levens D. 1996. The far upstream element-binding proteins comprise an ancient family of single-strand DNA-binding transactivators. J. Biol. Chem. 271:31679&#x2013;31687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8940189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Breyne S., Yu Y., Unbehaun A., Pestova T. V., Hellen C. U. 2009. Direct functional interaction of initiation factor eIF4G with type 1 internal ribosomal entry sites. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 106:9197&#x2013;9202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2695064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19470487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Jesus N. H. 2007. Epidemics to eradication: the modern history of poliomyelitis. Virol. J. 4:70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1947962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17623069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobbyn H. C., et al. 2008. Regulation of BAG-1 IRES-mediated translation following chemotoxic stress. Oncogene 27:1167&#x2013;1174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2570717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17700523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyfuss G., Matunis M. J., Pinol-Roma S., Burd C. G. 1993. hnRNP proteins and the biogenesis of mRNA. Annu. Rev. Biochem. 62:289&#x2013;321</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8352591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan R., et al. 1994. A sequence-specific, single-strand binding protein activates the far upstream element of c-myc and defines a new DNA-binding motif. Genes Dev. 8:465&#x2013;480</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8125259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engidawork E., Afjehi-Sadat L., Yang J. W., Slavc I., Lubec G. 2006. Protein chemical identification and characterization of the human variants of far upstream element binding protein in medulloblastoma DAOY cell line. Int. J. Oncol. 29:721&#x2013;736</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16865290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzgerald K. D., Semler B. L. 2009. Bridging IRES elements in mRNAs to the eukaryotic translation apparatus. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 1789:518&#x2013;528</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2783899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19631772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamarnik A. V., Andino R. 1998. Switch from translation to RNA replication in a positive-stranded RNA virus. Genes Dev. 12:2293&#x2013;2304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC317040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9694795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman J. S., et al. 1998. The use of antibodies to the polypyrimidine tract binding protein (PTB) to analyze the protein components that assemble on alternatively spliced pre-mRNAs that use distant branch points. RNA 4:613&#x2013;625</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1369644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9622121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gui H., Lu C. W., Adams S., Stollar V., Li M. L. 2010. hnRNP A1 interacts with the genomic and subgenomic RNA promoters of Sindbis virus and is required for the synthesis of G and SG RNA. J. Biomed. Sci. 17:59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2916895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20663119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L., Weber A., Levens D. 2000. Nuclear targeting determinants of the far upstream element binding protein, a c-myc transcription factor. Nucleic Acids Res. 28:4558&#x2013;4565</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11071946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellen C. U. 2009. IRES-induced conformational changes in the ribosome and the mechanism of translation initiation by internal ribosomal entry. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 1789:558&#x2013;570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2935204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19539793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M., et al. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929&#x2013;935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh T. Y., et al. 1998. Hepatitis C virus core protein interacts with heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein K. J. Biol. Chem. 273:17651&#x2013;17659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9651361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reference deleted.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin N., Baekelandt V., Goritchenko L., Benowitz L. I. 1997. Identification of two proteins that bind to a pyrimidine-rich sequence in the 3&#x2032;-untranslated region of GAP-43 mRNA. Nucleic Acid Res. 25:1281&#x2013;1288</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC146556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9092640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang S. K., et al. 1988. A segment of the 5&#x2032; nontranslated region of encephalomyocarditis virus RNA directs internal entry of ribosomes during in vitro translation. J. Virol. 62:2636&#x2013;2643</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC253694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2839690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joachims M., Van Breugel P. C., Lloyd R. E. 1999. Cleavage of poly(A)-binding protein by enterovirus proteases concurrent with inhibition of translation in vitro. J. Virol. 73:718&#x2013;727</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC103879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9847378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehle J., Roth B., Metzger C., Pfitzner A., Enders G. 2003. Molecular characterization of an enterovirus 71 causing neurological disease in Germany. J. Neurovirol. 9:126&#x2013;128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12587076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim C. S., Seol S. K., Song O. K., Park J. H., Jang S. K. 2007. An RNA-binding protein, hnRNP A1, and a scaffold protein, septin 6, facilitate hepatitis C virus replication. J. Virol. 81:3852&#x2013;3865</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1866118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17229681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolupaeva V. G., de Breyne S., Pestova T. V., Hellen C. U. 2007. In vitro reconstitution and biochemical characterization of translation initiation by internal ribosomal entry. Methods Enzymol. 430:409&#x2013;439</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17913647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koroleva G. A., Gracheva L. A., Voroshilova M. K. 1978. Isolation of type 71 enterovirus from patients with a poliomyelitis-like disease during an outbreak in Bulgaria. Vopr. Virusol. 5:611&#x2013;618 (In Russian)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">216154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krausslich H. G., Nicklin M. J., Toyoda H., Etchison D., Wimmer E. 1987. Poliovirus proteinase 2A induces cleavage of eucaryotic initiation factor 4F polypeptide p220. J. Virol. 61:2711&#x2013;2718</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC255777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3039165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee B. Y., et al. 2010. Forecasting the economic value of an enterovirus 71 (EV71) vaccine. Vaccine 28:7731&#x2013;7736</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2989421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20923711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis S. M., Holcik M. 2008. For IRES trans-acting factors, it is all about location. Oncogene 27:1033&#x2013;1035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17767196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis S. M., et al. 2007. Subcellular relocalization of a trans-acting factor regulates XIAP IRES-dependent translation. Mol. Biol. Cell 18:1302&#x2013;1311</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1838995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17287399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M. L., et al. 2002. The 3C protease activity of enterovirus 71 induces human neural cell apoptosis. Virology 293:386&#x2013;395</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11886259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J. C., Hsu M., Tarn W. Y. 2007. Cell stress modulates the function of splicing regulatory protein RBM4 in translation control. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 104:2235&#x2013;2240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1893002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17284590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J. Y., et al. 2009. Viral and host proteins involved in picornavirus life cycle. J. Biomed. Sci. 16:103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2785775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19925687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J. Y., et al. 2008. Heterogeneous nuclear ribonuclear protein K interacts with the enterovirus 71 5&#x2032; untranslated region and participates in virus replication. J. Gen. Virol. 89:2540&#x2013;2549</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18796723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J. Y., Li M. L., Shih S. R. 2009. Far upstream element binding protein 2 interacts with enterovirus 71 internal ribosomal entry site and negatively regulates viral translation. Nucleic Acids Res. 37:47&#x2013;59</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2615614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19010963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J. Y., et al. 2009. hnRNP A1 interacts with the 5&#x2032; untranslated regions of enterovirus 71 and Sindbis virus RNA and is required for viral replication. J. Virol. 83:6106&#x2013;6114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2687368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19339352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDonald C. C., Wilusz J., Shenk T. 1994. The 64-kilodalton subunit of the CstF polyadenylation factor binds to pre-mRNAs downstream of the cleavage site and influences cleavage site location. Mol. Cell. Biol. 14:6647&#x2013;6654</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC359194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7935383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Salas E. 2008. The impact of RNA structure on picornavirus IRES activity. Trends Microbiol. 16:230&#x2013;237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18420413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P. C. 2002. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 26:91&#x2013;107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick J. L. 1984. Enterovirus type 71 infections: a varied clinical pattern sometimes mimicking paralytic poliomyelitis. Rev. Infect. Dis. 6(Suppl. 2):S387&#x2013;S390</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michlewski G., Caceres J. F. 2010. Antagonistic role of hnRNP A1 and KSRP in the regulation of let-7a biogenesis. Nat. Struct. Mol. Biol. 17:1011&#x2013;1018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2923024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20639884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min H., Turck C. W., Nikolic J. M., Black D. L. 1997. A new regulatory protein, KSRP, mediates exon inclusion through an intronic splicing enhancer. Genes Dev. 11:1023&#x2013;1036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9136930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy G., Takatsy S., Kukan E., Mihaly I., Domok I. 1982. Virological diagnosis of enterovirus type 71 infections: experiences gained during an epidemic of acute CNS diseases in Hungary in 1978. Arch. Virol. 71:217&#x2013;227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6285858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niepmann M. 2009. Internal translation initiation of picornaviruses and hepatitis C virus. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 1789:529&#x2013;541</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y., et al. 2009. Human P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 is a functional receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15:794&#x2013;797</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oertle T., Schwab M. E. 2003. Nogo and its paRTNers. Trends Cell Biol. 13:187&#x2013;194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12667756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi M. H., Wong S. C., Lewthwaite P., Cardosa M. J., Solomon T. 2010. Clinical features, diagnosis, and management of enterovirus 71. Lancet Neurol. 9:1097&#x2013;1105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacheco A., Martinez-Salas E. 2010. Insights into the biology of IRES elements through riboproteomic approaches. J. Biomed. Biotechnol. 2010:458927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2817807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20150968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paranjape S. M., Harris E. 2007. Y box-binding protein-1 binds to the dengue virus 3&#x2032;-untranslated region and mediates antiviral effects. J. Biol. Chem. 282:30497&#x2013;30508</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17726010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul A. V., Molla A., Wimmer E. 1994. Studies of a putative amphipathic helix in the N-terminus of poliovirus protein 2C. Virology 199:188&#x2013;199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8116242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelletier J., Sonenberg N. 1988. Internal initiation of translation of eukaryotic mRNA directed by a sequence derived from poliovirus RNA. Nature 334:320&#x2013;325</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2839775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettit Kneller E. L., Connor J. H., Lyles D. S. 2009. hnRNPs relocalize to the cytoplasm following infection with vesicular stomatitis virus. J. Virol. 83:770&#x2013;780</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2612367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19004954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilipenko E. V., Viktorova E. G., Guest S. T., Agol V. I., Roos R. P. 2001. Cell-specific proteins regulate viral RNA translation and virus-induced disease. EMBO J. 20:6899&#x2013;6908</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC125770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11726525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racaniello V. R. 2007. Picornaviridae: the viruses and their replication, p. 796&#x2013;838 In Knipe D. M., et al. (ed.), Fields virology, 5th ed Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, Philadelphia, PA</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuda G. M., Chang W. K., Yeung C. Y., Tang P. S. 1987. Monoplegia caused by enterovirus 71: an outbreak in Hong Kong. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 6:206&#x2013;208</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3562141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanz M. A., Welnowska E., Redondo N., Carrasco L. 2010. Translation driven by picornavirus IRES is hampered from Sindbis virus replicons: rescue by poliovirus 2A protease. J. Mol. Biol. 402:101&#x2013;117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20643140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt N. J., Lennette E. H., Ho H. H. 1974. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J. Infect. Dis. 129:304&#x2013;309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi S. T., Huang P., Li H. P., Lai M. M. 2000. Heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein A1 regulates RNA synthesis of a cytoplasmic virus. EMBO J. 19:4701&#x2013;4711</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC302072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10970862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih S. R., et al. 2004. Identification of genes involved in the host response to enterovirus 71 infection. J. Neurovirol. 10:293&#x2013;304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimada K., Kondo K., Yamanishi K. 2004. Human herpesvirus 6 immediate-early 2 protein interacts with heterogeneous ribonucleoprotein K and casein kinase 2. Microbiol. Immunol. 48:205&#x2013;210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15031534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu H., et al. 1999. Enterovirus 71 from fatal and nonfatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease epidemics in Malaysia, Japan and Taiwan in 1997-1998. Jpn. J. Infect. Dis. 52:12&#x2013;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10808253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shindarov L. M., et al. 1979. Epidemiological, clinical, and pathomorphological characteristics of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease caused by enterovirus 71. J. Hyg. Epidemiol. Microbiol. Immunol. 23:284&#x2013;295</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">231067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvestri L. S., Parilla J. M., Morasco B. J., Ogram S. A., Flanegan J. B. 2006. Relationship between poliovirus negative-strand RNA synthesis and the length of the 3&#x2032; poly(A) tail. Virology 345:509&#x2013;519</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16297425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siomi H., Dreyfuss G. 1995. A nuclear localization domain in the hnRNP A1 protein. J. Cell Biol. 129:551&#x2013;560</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2120450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7730395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siomi H., Matunis M. J., Michael W. M., Dreyfuss G. 1993. The pre-mRNA binding K protein contains a novel evolutionarily conserved motif. Nucleic Acids Res. 21:1193&#x2013;1198</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC309281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8464704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T., et al. 2010. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect. Dis. 10:778&#x2013;790</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang W. F., et al. 2007. Reticulon 3 binds the 2C protein of enterovirus 71 and is required for viral replication. J. Biol. Chem. 282:5888&#x2013;5898</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17182608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson S. R., Sarnow P. 2003. Enterovirus 71 contains a type I IRES element that functions when eukaryotic initiation factor eIF4G is cleaved. Virology 315:259&#x2013;266</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14592777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ting N. S., Pohorelic B., Yu Y., Lees-Miller S. P., Beattie T. L. 2009. The human telomerase RNA component, hTR, activates the DNA-dependent protein kinase to phosphorylate heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein A1. Nucleic Acids Res. 37:6105&#x2013;6115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2764450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19656952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomonaga T., Levens D. 1995. Heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein K is a DNA-binding transactivator. J. Biol. Chem. 270:4875&#x2013;4881</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7876260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vindigni A., Ochem A., Triolo G., Falaschi A. 2001. Identification of human DNA helicase V with the far upstream element-binding protein. Nucleic Acids Res. 29:1061&#x2013;1067</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC29729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11222755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt D. A., Andino R. 2010. An RNA element at the 5&#x2032;-end of the poliovirus genome functions as a general promoter for RNA synthesis. PLoS Pathog. 6:e1000936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2880563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20532207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y. F., Chen S. C., Wu F. Y., Wu C. W. 1997. The interaction between human cytomegalovirus immediate-early gene 2 (IE2) protein and heterogeneous ribonucleoprotein A1. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 232:590&#x2013;594</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9126318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weighardt F., Biamonti G., Riva S. 1995. Nucleo-cytoplasmic distribution of human hnRNP proteins: a search for the targeting domains in hnRNP A1. J. Cell Sci. 108:545&#x2013;555</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7769000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weighardt F., Biamonti G., Riva S. 1996. The roles of heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoproteins (hnRNP) in RNA metabolism. Bioessays 18:747&#x2013;756</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8831291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng K. F., Chen L. L., Huang P. N., Shih S. R. 2010. Neural pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 infection. Microbes. Infect. 12:505&#x2013;510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20348010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng K. F., Li M. L., Hung C. T., Shih S. R. 2009. Enterovirus 71 3C protease cleaves a novel target CstF-64 and inhibits cellular polyadenylation. PLoS Pathog. 5:e1000593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2742901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19779565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wimmer E., Nomoto A. 1993. Molecular biology and cell-free synthesis of poliovirus. Biologicals 21:349&#x2013;356</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8024750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu K. X., Ng M. M., Chu J. J. 2010. Developments towards antiviral therapies against enterovirus 71. Drug Discov. Today 15:1041&#x2013;1051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7108380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20974282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamayoshi S., et al. 2009. Scavenger receptor B2 is a cellular receptor for enterovirus 71. Nat. Med. 15:798&#x2013;801</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F., et al. 2009. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in the People's Republic of China in 2008. J. Clin. Microbiol. 47:2351&#x2013;2352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2708525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y. S., Strittmatter S. M. 2007. The reticulons: a family of proteins with diverse functions. Genome Biol. 8:234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2246256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18177508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y., Abaeva I. S., Marintchev A., Pestova T. V., Hellen C. U. 2011. Common conformational changes induced in type 2 picornavirus IRESs by cognate trans-acting factors. Nucleic Acids Res. 39:4851&#x2013;4865</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3113573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21306989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., et al. 2008. Cytidine deaminase APOBEC3B interacts with heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein K and suppresses hepatitis B virus expression. Cell Microbiol. 10:112&#x2013;121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17672864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z., Harris D., Pandey V. N. 2008. The FUSE binding protein is a cellular factor required for efficient replication of hepatitis C virus. J. Virol. 82:5761&#x2013;5773</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2395142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18400844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X., Rush M., Schwartz S. 2004. Identification of an hnRNP A1-dependent splicing silencer in the human papillomavirus type 16 L1 coding region that prevents premature expression of the late L1 gene. J. Virol. 78:10888&#x2013;10905</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC521837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15452209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoll J., Heus H. A., van Kuppeveld F. J., Melchers W. J. 2009. The structure-function relationship of the enterovirus 3&#x2032;-UTR. Virus Res. 139:209&#x2013;216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18706945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou H., Henzel W. J., Liu X., Lutschg A., Wang X. 1997. Apaf-1, a human protein homologous to C. elegans CED-4, participates in cytochrome c-dependent activation of caspase-3. Cell 90:405&#x2013;413</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9267021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>