<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21189926</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2092-7258</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Korean journal of pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Korean J Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enterovirus 71 infection: An experience in Korea, 2009.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>616</StartPage><EndPage>622</EndPage><MedlinePgn>616-22</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3345/kjp.2010.53.5.616</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) has been recognized as a frequent cause of epidemics of hand-foot-and-mouth disease (HFMD) associated with severe neurological symptoms. In the spring of 2009, HFMD was epidemic in Korea. Severe cases with complication, including death, have been reported and it has become a public health issue. Most symptomatic EV71 infections commonly result in HFMD or herpangina. These clinical manifestations can be associated with neurologic syndromes frequently. Neurologic syndromes observed in EV71 include meningitis, meningoencephalomyelitis, poliomyelitis-like paralytic disease, Guillain-Barr&#xe9; syndrome, transverse myelitis, cerebellar ataxia, opsoclonus-myoclonus syndrome, benign intracranial hypertension, and brainstem encephalitis. Examinations for EV 71 were performed from the stools, respiratory secretion or CSF of the children by realtime PCR. Gene analysis showed that most of them were caused by EV71 subgenotype C4a which was prevalent in China, 2008. Public health measures including personal and environmental hygiene, must to target daycare centers, kindergartens, and schools where highly susceptible children congregate. To prevent the spread of infection, preschools where transmission persists for more than 2 incubation periods, have been recommended for closure, and trigger criteria for voluntary closure was instituted. During closure, operators are to thoroughly clean the centers before they are allowed to reopen. In addition, parents are advised to ensure that their children adopt a high standard of personal hygiene and to keep the infected child at home until full recovery. Because the outbreaks occur in a cyclical pattern, surveillance system to predict next outbreaks and adequate public health measures to control need to be planned for future. Control of EV71 epidemics through surveillance and public health intervention needs to be maintained in Korea. Future research should focus on understanding of EV71 virulence, identification of the receptor(s) for EV71, development of antiviral agents and development of vaccine.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Kyung Hyo</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, School of Medicine, Ewha Womans University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Korean J Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101215374</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1738-1061</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hand-foot-mouth disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Outbreaks</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2010</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21189926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2994121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3345/kjp.2010.53.5.616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cho HK, Lee H, Kim HS, Seo JW, Lee SH, Kim JH, et al. Hand, Foot and Mouth Diseases Associated with Neurologic Symptoms Related to Enterovirus 71 in Korea, 2009. Korean J Pediatr. 2010 in press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2994124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21189930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt NJ, Lennette EH, Ho HH. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J Infect Dis. 1974;129:304&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abzug MJ. Nonpolio Enteroviruses. In: Kliegman RM, Behrman RE, Jenson HB, Stanton BF, editors. Nelson textbook of pediatrics. 18th ed. Philadelphia: WB Saunders Co; 2007. pp. 1350&#x2013;1356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa MJ, Perera D, Brown BA, Cheon D, Chan HM, Chan KP, et al. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 strains and recent outbreaks in the Asia-Pacific region: comparative analysis of the VP1 and VP4 genes. Emerg Infect Dis. 2003;9:461&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12702227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P, Lindsay K, Perera D, Chan HM, Chan KP, Cardosa MJ. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J Virol. 2001;75:7732&#x2013;7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar S, Sam IC, Yusof J, Lim MK, Misbah S, MatRahim N, et al. Enterovirus 71 outbreak, Brunei. Emerg Infect Dis. 2009;15:79&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19116058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Ren L, Xiong Z, Li J, Xiao Y, Zhao R, et al. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in the People's Republic of China in 2008. J Clin Microbiol. 2009;47:2351&#x2013;2352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2708525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Tan XJ, Wang HY, Yan DM, Zhu SL, Wang DY, et al. An outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with subgenotype C4 of human enterovirus 71 in Shandong, China. J Clin Virol. 2009;44:262&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19269888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoke-Fun C, AbuBakar S. Phylogenetic evidence for inter-typic recombination in the emergence of human enterovirus 71 subgenotypes. BMC Microbiol. 2006;6:74&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1569848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16939656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jee YM, Cheon DS, Kim K, Cho JH, Chung YS, Lee J, et al. Genetic analysis of the VP1 region of human enterovirus 71 strains isolated in Korea during 2000. Arch Virol. 2003;148:1735&#x2013;1746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14505086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortner B, Huang CW, Schmid D, Mutz I, Wewalka G, Allerberger F, et al. Epidemiology of enterovirus types causing neurological disease in Austria 1999-2007: detection of clusters of echovirus 30 and enterovirus 71 and analysis of prevalent genotypes. J Med Virol. 2009;81:317&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19107980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2002;26:91&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang LW, Koh BK, Chan KP, Chua LT, James L, Goh KT. Epidemiology and control of hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore, 2001-2007. Ann Acad Med Singapore. 2009;38:106&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19271036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Tsao KC, Hsia SH, Shih SR, Huang CG, Chan WK, et al. Transmission and clinical features of enterovirus 71 infections in household contacts in Taiwan. JAMA. 2004;291:222&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14722149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung PW, Huang YC, Chang LY, Lin TY, Ning HC. Duration of enterovirus shedding in stool. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2001;34:167&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11605806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Lin TY, Huang YC, Tsao KC, Shih SR, Kuo ML, et al. Comparison of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 clinical illnesses during the Taiwan enterovirus epidemic, 1998. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1999;18:1092&#x2013;1096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10608631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M. Enterovirus 71: the virus, its infections and outbreaks. J Microbiol Immunol Infect. 2000;33:205&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11269363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Hsiung CA, Lu CY, Lin TY, Huang FY, Lai YH, et al. Status of cellular rather than humoral immunity is correlated with clinical outcome of enterovirus 71. Pediatr Res. 2006;60:466&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7086547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16940249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Hsia SH, Wu CT, Huang YC, Lin KL, Fang TY, et al. Outcome of enterovirus 71 infections with or without stage-based management: 1998 to 2002. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2004;23:327&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15071287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Ho TS, Shen CF, Liu CC. Enterovirus 71, One virus and many stories. Pediatr Neonatol. 2008;49:113&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19054915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Huang KJ, Wu JM, Wang JR, Yu CK, et al. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J Infect Dis. 2003;188:564&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherry JD, Krogstad P. Enteroviruses and parechoviruses. In: Feigin RD, Cherry JD, Demmler-Harrison GJ, Kaplan SL, editors. Textbook of pediatric infectious diseases. 6th ed. Philadelphia: Elsevier Saunders; 2009. pp. 2110&#x2013;2170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CC, Liu CC, Chang YC, Chen CY, Wang ST, Yeh TF. Neurologic complications in children with enterovirus 71 infection. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:936&#x2013;942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, Twu SJ, Chen KT, Tsai SF, et al. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P, Stratov I, Nagarajan L, Davis S. Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin Infect Dis. 2001;32:236&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu H, Utama A, Onnimala N, Li C, Li-Bi Z, Yu-Jie M, et al. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection in the Western Pacific Region. Pediatr Int. 2004;46:231&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu J. Enterovirus 71 infection: a new threat to global public health? Lancet Neurol. 2008;7:868&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18848307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KP, Goh KT, Chong CY, Teo ES, Lau G, Ling AE. Epidemic hand, foot and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg Infect Dis. 2003;9:78&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hand, foot and mouth disease. Sarawak Health Department/Ministry of Health Malaysia.  [cited 2008 Sep 1].  Available from: URL://  http://www.sarawak.health.gov.my/hfmd.htm#INFO9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TY, Twu SJ, Ho MS, Chang LY, Lee CY. Enterovirus 71 outbreaks, Taiwan: occurrence and recognition. Emerg Infect Dis. 2003;9:291&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12643822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong CY, Chan KP, Shah VA, Ng WY, Lau G, Teo TE, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore: a comparison of fatal and non-fatal cases. Acta Paediatr. 2003;92:1163&#x2013;1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14632332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Mohan A, Podin Y, Perera D, Clear D, et al. Identification and validation of clinical predictors for the risk of neurological involvement in children with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak. BMC Infect Dis. 2009;9:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2637878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19152683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shindarov LM, Chumakov MP, Voroshilova MK, Bojinov S, Vasilenko SM, Iordanov I, et al. Epidemiological, clinical, and pathomorphological characteristics of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease caused by enterovirus 71. J Hyg Epidemiol Microbiol Immunol. 1979;23:284&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">231067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy G, Tak&#xe1;tsy S, Kuk&#xe1;n E, Mih&#xe1;ly I, D&#xf6;m&#xf6;k I. Virological diagnosis of enterovirus type 71 infections: experiences gained during an epidemic of acute CNS diseases in Hungary in 1978. Arch Virol. 1982;71:217&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6285858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan LG, Parashar UD, Lye MS, Ong FG, Zaki SR, Alexander JP, et al. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in sarawak, malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. For the Outbreak Study Group. Clin Infect Dis. 2000;31:678&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Liu CC. Enterovirus 71: epidemiology, pathogenesis and management. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2009;7:735&#x2013;742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19681701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Lei HY, Huang MC, Su LY, Lin HC, Yu CK, et al. Modulation of cytokine production by intravenous immunoglobulin in patients with enterovirus 71-associated brainstem encephalitis. J Clin Virol. 2006;37:47&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16861032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>