<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">33181780</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Virus Shedding in Patients With Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease Induced by EV71, CA16 or CA6: Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>289</StartPage><EndPage>294</EndPage><MedlinePgn>289-294</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000002985</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">As the highly contagious hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) spreads rapidly among children, isolation is the most effective way to control its spread. However, studies on the duration of virus shedding of the HFMD-related enterovirus and a reasonable quarantine period for HFMD patients are inconsistent.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We undertook a systematic review and meta-analysis evaluating the viral shedding of patients with HFMD caused by Enterovirus 71 (EV71) and coxsackievirus A16 (CVA16) and coxsackievirus A6.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 17 observational studies evaluating 626 participants were included. In the first 5 weeks after onset, the pooled virus positive rate in specimens of EV71-related patients decreased from 0.79 (P &lt; 0.001 for heterogeneity) to 0.38 (P &lt; 0.001 for heterogeneity). The positive rate of CVA16 was reduced from 0.91 (P &lt; 0.001 for heterogeneity) to 0.29 (P &lt; 0.001 for heterogeneity). The positive rates of CVA16 and coxsackievirus A6 were approximately 50% in the third week after onset, while a 50% positive rate appeared in the fourth week in EV71 related cases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">We found the positive rates of virus shedding were still high among the patients released from quarantine, and the duration of viral shedding was inconsistent among HFMD patients caused by different serotypes. Our findings provide comprehensive evidence for a possible flexible quarantine period according to the serotype.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoxia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zhenhua</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology Laboratory, Chengdu Municipal Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xianzhi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Ping</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064887" MajorTopicYN="N">Observational Studies as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017201" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Shedding</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000002985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-202104000-00005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cox B, Levent F. Hand, foot, and mouth disease. JAMA. 2018; 320:2492</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B, Luo L, Yan S, et al. Clinical features for mild hand, foot and mouth disease in China. PLoS One. 2015; 10:e0135503</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad K. Hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak reported in Singapore. Lancet. 2000; 356:1338</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa MJ, Krishnan S, Tio PH, et al. Isolation of subgenus B adenovirus during a fatal outbreak of enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sibu, Sarawak. Lancet. 1999; 354:987&#x2013;991</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization Regional Office for the Western Pacific. A Guide to Clinical Management and Public Health Response for Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease (HFMD). 2011, WHO Regional Office for the Western Pacific</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, et al. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect Dis. 2010; 10:778&#x2013;790</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar S, Shafee N, Chee HY. Adenovirus in EV71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet. 2000; 355:146</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogi M, Yano Y, Chikahira M, et al. Characterization of genome sequences and clinical features of coxsackievirus A6 strains collected in Hyogo, Japan in 1999-2013. J Med Virol. 2017; 89:1395&#x2013;1403</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanda C, Singh R, Rana SK. An outbreak of hand-foot-mouth disease: a report from the hills of northern India. Natl Med J India. 2015; 28:126&#x2013;128</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downing C, Ramirez-Fort MK, Doan HQ, et al. Coxsackievirus A6 associated hand, foot and mouth disease in adults: clinical presentation and review of the literature. J Clin Virol. 2014; 60:381&#x2013;386</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broccolo F, Drago F, Ciccarese G, et al. Severe atypical hand-foot-and-mouth disease in adults due to coxsackievirus A6: clinical presentation and phylogenesis of CV-A6 strains. J Clin Virol. 2019; 110:1&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin W, Su Y, Jiang M, et al. Clinical features for 89 deaths of hand, foot and mouth disease in Guangxi, China, 2014. Int J Infect Dis. 2017; 64:15&#x2013;19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goksugur N, Goksugur S. Images in clinical medicine. Hand, foot, and mouth disease. N Engl J Med. 2010; 362:e49</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji H, Fan H, Lu PX, et al. Surveillance for severe hand, foot, and mouth disease from 2009 to 2015 in Jiangsu province: epidemiology, etiology, and disease burden. BMC Infect Dis. 2019; 19:79</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang MTV, Nguyen TA, Tran TT, et al. Clinical and aetiological study of hand, foot and mouth disease in southern Vietnam, 2013-2015: inpatients and outpatients. Int J Infect Dis. 2019; 80:1&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JT, Jit M, Zheng Y, et al. Routine pediatric enterovirus 71 vaccination in China: a cost-effectiveness analysis. PLoS Med. 2016; 13:e1001975</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigonan AS, Mann L, Chonmaitree T. Use of monoclonal antibodies to identify serotypes of enterovirus isolates. J Clin Microbiol. 1998; 36:1877&#x2013;1881</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modlin JF. Update on enterovirus infections in infants and children. Adv Pediatr Infect Dis. 1996; 12:155&#x2013;180</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J, Ma XJ, Wan JF, et al. Long persistence of EV71 specific nucleotides in respiratory and feces samples of the patients with Hand-Foot-Mouth Disease after recovery. BMC Infect Dis. 2010; 10:178</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al.; PRISMA Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. BMJ. 2009; 339:b2535</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruggeman PlotReader tool. 2010. Available at: https://jornbr.home.xs4all.nl/plotreader/ . Accessed October 29, 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y, Wei Z, Wang W, et al. The incidence and distribution of surgical site infection in mainland China: a meta-analysis of 84 prospective observational studies. Sci Rep. 2014; 4:6783</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoy D, Brooks P, Woolf A, et al. Assessing risk of bias in prevalence studies: modification of an existing tool and evidence of interrater agreement. J Clin Epidemiol. 2012; 65:934&#x2013;939</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbert K, Plugge E, Foster C, et al. Prevalence of risk factors for non-communicable diseases in prison populations worldwide: a systematic review. Lancet. 2012; 379:1975&#x2013;1982</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiyong Z, Juan W, Shu T, et al. Observation on intestinal viral shedding time of hand, foot and mouth disease induced by coxsackievirus A6. Zhonghua er ke za zhi/Chinese J Pediatr. 2017; 55:369&#x2013;372</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meihua L, Yanfeng H, Chaomin Z, et al. Viral load and the duration of virus shedding of enterviru 71 in stool samples of children with hand, food and mouth disease and its related factors. Chong qing Yi ke da xue Xue bao/J Chongqing Med Univ. 2015; 40:1582&#x2013;1586</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu T, Shi-yong Z, Yi W, et al. Observation on virus shedding periods of enterovirus-71 and coxsackievirus A 16 monitored by nucleic acids determination in stool samples of children with hand, foot and mouth disease. Zhonghua er ke za zhi/Chinese J Pediatr. 2013; 51:787&#x2013;792</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue M. The Study of Detoxification After Incidence and Risk Factors in Patients with Hand-Foot-Mouth Disease in Yuxi City. 2013, Kunming Medical University</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi-lin H, Xiang Z, Jie Z, et al. Analysis on detection of enterovirus nucleotides in feces samples of hand-foot-mouth disease patients after recovery. Zhonghua Yu Fang Yi Xue Za Zhi/Chinese J Preventive Med. 2011; 45:1073&#x2013;1076</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong C, Chuanwu S, Yonghong S, et al. Detoxification of severe hand-foot-mouth disease patients and virus carrying status of close contacts in Xuzhou City in 2010. Zhonghua Yu Fang Yi Xue Za Zhi/Chinese J Preventive Med. 2011; 45:1117&#x2013;1118</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li-juan C, Ren-qing L, He-run Z, et al. Tracking investigating of the carriage status of virus among HFMD patients with EV71 and their close contacts. Guo ji bing du xue za zhi/Int J Virol. 2011; 18:134&#x2013;138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao P, Ye-fei Z, Xian Q, et al. Analysis on the epidemiological and genetic characteristics of enterovirus type 71 and Coxsackie A16 virus infection in Jiangsu, China, 2008. Zhonghua liu Xing Bing Xue Za Zhi/Chinese J Epidemiol. 2009; 30:339&#x2013;343</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Fu X, Jiang L, et al. Prevalence of enteroviruses in healthy populations and excretion of pathogens in patients with hand, foot, and mouth disease in a highly endemic area of southwest China. PLoS One. 2017; 12:e0181234</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng S, Wei Y, Zhao SY, et al. Intestinal detoxification time of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in children with EV71 infection and the related factors. World J Pediatr. 2015; 11:380&#x2013;385</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiyong Z, Xianyao L, Shu T, et al. Survey of virus shedding and spread mechanism in children infected with EV71. Ji Bing Jian Ce/Disease Surveillance. 2015; 30:23&#x2013;26</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jianming C, Shengdi C, Qiyun H, et al. Study of negative-conversion time of enterovirus nucleic acids in children with hand-foot-mouth disease. Xin Yi Xue/Journal of New Medicine. 2018; 49:651&#x2013;655</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Lin C, Qu M, et al. Excretion of enterovirus 71 in persons infected with hand, foot and mouth disease. Virol J. 2013; 10:31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention. Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease Prevention and Control Guidelines (2009 Edition). 2009. Available at: http://www.chinacdc.cn/jkzt/crb/bl/szkb/jszl_2275/200906/t20090612_24707.html . Accessed October 29, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abad FX, Pint&#xf3; RM, Bosch A. Survival of enteric viruses on environmental fomites. Appl Environ Microbiol. 1994; 60:3704&#x2013;3710</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Solomon T, Podin Y, et al. Evaluation of different clinical sample types in diagnosis of human enterovirus 71-associated hand-foot-and-mouth disease. J Clin Microbiol. 2007; 45:1858&#x2013;1866</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>