<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21847753</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1995-820X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Virologica Sinica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Virol Sin</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hand foot and mouth disease due to enterovirus 71 in Malaysia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>221</StartPage><EndPage>228</EndPage><MedlinePgn>221-8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">221</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12250-011-3195-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hand foot and mouth disease is a febrile sickness complex characterized by cutaneous eruption (exanthem) on the palms and soles with simultaneous occurrence of muco-cutanous vesiculo-ulcerative lesions (enanthem) affecting the mouth. The illness is caused by a number of enteroviruses with coxsackievirus A16 and enterovirus 71 as the main causative agents. Human enterovirus 71 (EV71) belongs to the species Human enterovirus A under the genus Enterovirus within the family Picornaviridae. EV71 has been associated with an array of clinical diseases including hand foot and mouth disease (HFMD), aseptic meningitis, encephalitis and poliomyelitis-like acute flaccid paralysis. A large outbreak of HFMD due to highly neurovirulent EV71 emerged in Malaysia in 1997, and caused 41 deaths amongst young children. In late 2000, a recurrence of an outbreak of HFMD occurred in Malaysia with 8 fatalities in peninsular Malaysia. Outbreak of HFMD due to EV71 recurred in 2003 with an unknown number of cases and mortalities. A similar outbreak of HFMD with 2 recorded deaths in young children occurred in peninsular Malaysia in late 2005 and this was followed by a larger outbreak in Sarawak (Malaysian Borneo) with 6 reported fatalities in the early part of 2006. The current on-going outbreak of HFMD started in peninsular Malaysia in epidemiological week 12 of 2010. As with other HFMD outbreaks in Malaysia, both EV71 and CA16 were the main aetiological viruses isolated. In similarity with the HFMD outbreak in 2005, the isolation of CA16 preceded the appearance of EV71. Based on the VP1 gene nucleotide sequences, 4 sub-genogroups of EV71 (C1, C2, B3 and B4) co-circulated and caused the outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in peninsular Malaysia in 1997. Two sub-genogroups (C1 and B4) were noted to cause the outbreak in 2000 in both peninsular Malaysia and Sarawak. EV71 of sub-genogroup B5 with smaller contribution from sub-genogroup C1 caused the outbreak in 2003. In the 2005 outbreak, besides the EV71 strains of sub-genogroup C1, EV71 strains belonging to sub-genogroup B5 were isolated but formed a cluster which was distinct from the EV71 strains from the sub-genogroup B5 isolated in 2003. The four EV71 strains isolated from clinical specimens of patients with hand, foot and mouth disease in the Sarawak outbreak in early 2006 also belonged to sub-genogroup B5. Phylogenetic analysis of the VP1 gene suggests that the EV71 strains causing the outbreak in Sarawak could have originated from peninsular Malaysia. Epidemiological and molecular data since 1997 show the recurrence of HFMD due to EV71 in Malaysia every 2 to 4 years. In each of the past outbreaks, more than one sub-genogroup of the virus co-circulate.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chua</LastName><ForeName>Kaw Bing</ForeName><Initials>KB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Public Health Laboratory, Ministry of Health, Lot 1853, 47000 Sungai Buloh, Selangor, Malaysia. chuakawbing@yahoo.com.sg</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kasri</LastName><ForeName>Abdul Rasid</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Virol Sin</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101514185</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1995-820X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008296" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Malaysia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21847753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8222466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12250-011-3195-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alexander J. P., Baden L., Pallansch M. A., et al. Enterovirus 71 infection and neurologic disease &#x2014; United States, 1977&#x2013;1991. J Infect Dis. 1994;169:905&#x2013;908. doi: 10.1093/infdis/169.4.905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/169.4.905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8133108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson S. O., Bjorksten B., Burman L. A. A comparative study of meningoencephalitis epidemics caused by echovirus type 7 and coxsackievirus type B5. Clinical and virological observation during two epidemics in northern Sweden. Scandinavian J Infect Dis. 1975;7:233&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1209167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomberg J., Lycke E., Ahlfors K., et al. New enterovirus type associated with epidemic of aseptic meningitis and/or hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet. 1974;2:112. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(74)91684-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(74)91684-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4136956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown B. A., Oberste M. S., Alexander J. P., et al. Molecular epidemiology and evolution of enterovirus 71 strains isolated from 1970 to 1998. J Virol. 1999;73:9969&#x2013;9975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10559310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown B. A., Pallansch M. A. Complete nucleotide sequence of enterovirus 71 is distinct from poliovirus. Virus Res. 1995;39:195&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1016/0168-1702(95)00087-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0168-1702(95)00087-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8837884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa M. J., Perera D., Brown B. A., et al. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 strains and recent outbreaks in the Asia-Pacific region: Comparative analysis of the VP1 and VP4 genes. Emerg Infect Dis. 2003;9:461&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12702227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang L. Y., Huang Y. C., Lin T. Y. Fulminant neurogenic pulmonary oedema with hand, foot and mouth disease. Lancet. 1998;352:367&#x2013;368. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(98)24031-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(98)24031-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9717926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chomnaitree T., Menegus M. A., Schervish-swierkosz E. M., et al. Enterovirus 71 infection: a report of an outbreak with two cases of paralysis and a review of the literature. Pediatrics. 1982;671:489&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7254970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua K. B., Chua B. H., Lee C. S. M., et al. Genetic diversity of enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of hand, foot and mouth disease in the 1997, 2000 and 2005 outbreaks, Peninsular Malaysia. Malaysian J Pathol. 2007;29:69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19108398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov M., Voroshilova M., Shindarov L. M., et al. Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch Virol. 1979;60:329&#x2013;340. doi: 10.1007/BF01317504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01317504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deibel R., Gross L. L., Collins D. N. Isolation of a new enterovirus. Proc Soc Exp Biolo Med. 1975;148:203&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">165523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert G. L., Dickson K. E., Waters M. J., et al. Outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Victoria, Australia, with a high incidence of neurologic involvement. Pediatr Infect Dis. 1988;7:484&#x2013;488. doi: 10.1097/00006454-198807000-00007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00006454-198807000-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2841639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara A., Tagaya I., Yoneyama T. Epidemic of hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Intervirology. 1978;9:60&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1159/000148922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000148922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">202573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara A., Yoneyama T., Hashimoto I. Isolation of a temperature-sensitive strain of enterovirus 71 with reduced neurovirulence for monkeys. J Gen Virol. 1983;64:499&#x2013;502. doi: 10.1099/0022-1317-64-2-499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/0022-1317-64-2-499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6300298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayward J. C., Gillespie S. M., Kaplan K. M., et al. Outbreak of poliomyelitis-like paralysis associated with enterovirus 71. Pediatr Infect Dis. 1989;8:611&#x2013;616. doi: 10.1097/00006454-198909000-00009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00006454-198909000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2797956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooi P. S., Chua B. H., Lee C. S. M., et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease: University Malaya Medical Centre Experience. Med J Malaysia. 2002;57:88&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14569723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho-Yen D. O., Hardie R., McClure J., et al. Fatal outcome of echovirus 7 infection. Scandinavian J Infect Dis. 1989;21:459&#x2013;461. doi: 10.3109/00365548909167452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/00365548909167452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2587948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishimaru Y., Nakano S., Yamaoka K., et al. Outbreaks of hand, foot, mouth disease by enterovirus 71: high incidence of complication disorders of central nervous system. Arch Dis Child. 1980;55:583&#x2013;588. doi: 10.1136/adc.55.8.583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/adc.55.8.583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1627055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6254449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennett M., Birch C. J., Lewis F. A., et al. Enterovirus type 71 infection in Melbourne. Bull EHO. 1974;51:609&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2366271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4377551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C. C., Tseng H. W., Wang S. M., et al. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998: epidemiologic and clinical manifestations. J Clin Virol. 2000;17:23&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1016/S1386-6532(00)00068-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1386-6532(00)00068-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum L. C. S., Chua K. B., McMinn P. C., et al. Echovirus 7 associated with encephalomyelitis. Clin Diag Virol. 2002;23:153&#x2013;160. doi: 10.1016/S1386-6532(01)00214-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1386-6532(01)00214-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11595594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum L. C. S., Lam S. K., Wong K. T., et al. Neurologic pulmonary oedema and enterovirus 71 encephalomyelitis. Lancet. 1998;352:1391. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(05)60789-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(05)60789-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9802304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lum L. C. S., Wong K. T., Lam S. K., et al. Fatal Enterovirus 71 encephalitis. J Pediatr. 1998;133:795&#x2013;798. doi: 10.1016/S0022-3476(98)70155-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-3476(98)70155-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhaven H. N., Sharma K. B. Enteroviruses from cases of encephalitis in Pondicherry. Indian J Med Res. 1969;57:1607&#x2013;1610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4313049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P. C., Lindsay K., Perera D., et al. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J Virol. 2001;75:7732&#x2013;7738. doi: 10.1128/JVI.75.16.7732-7738.2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.75.16.7732-7738.2001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick J. L., et al. Enteroviruses: Polioviruses, Coxsackieviruses, Echoviruses, and Newer Enteroviruses. In: Fields B. N., Knipe D. M., Howley P. M., et al., editors. Fields Virology. 3rd ed. Philadelphia.: Lippincott-Raven; 1996. pp. 655&#x2013;712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy G., Takatsy S., Kukan E., et al. Virological diagnosis of enterovirus type 71 infections: experiences gained during an epidemic of acute CNS diseases in Hungary in 1978. Arch Virol. 1982;71:217&#x2013;227. doi: 10.1007/BF01314873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01314873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6285858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podin Y., Gias E. L. M., Ong F., et al. Sentinel surveillance for human enterovirus 71 in Sarawak, Malaysia: lessons from the first 7 years. BMC Public Health. 2006;6:180. doi: 10.1186/1471-2458-6-180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-6-180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1543637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16827926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuda G. M., Chang W. K., Yeung C. Y., et al. Monoplegia caused by enterovirus 71: an outbreak in Hong Kong. Pediatr Infect Dis. 1987;6:206&#x2013;208. doi: 10.1097/00006454-198702000-00013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00006454-198702000-00013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3562141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt N. J., Lennette E. H., Ho H. H. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J Infect Dis. 1974;129:304&#x2013;309. doi: 10.1093/infdis/129.3.304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/129.3.304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shindarov L. M., Chumakov M. P., Voroshilova M. K., et al. Epidemiological, clinical and pathomorphological characteristics of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease caused by enterovirus 71. J Hyg Epid Microbiol Immun. 1979;3:284&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">231067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tagaya I., Takayama R., Hagiwara A. A large scale epidemic of hand, foot, mouth disease associated with enterovirus 71 infection in Japan in 1978. Jpn J Med Sci Biol. 1981;34:191&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6273621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J. R., Tsai H. P., Chen P. F., et al. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998. II. Laboratory diagnosis and genetic analysis. J Clin Virol. 2000;17:91&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1016/S1386-6532(00)00079-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1386-6532(00)00079-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10942089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Sarawak. Cluster of deaths among infants and young children. Wkly Epidemiol Rec. 1997;72:211&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9329278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wreghitt T. G., Sutehall G. M., King A., et al. Fatal echovirus 7 infection during an outbreak in a special care baby unit. J Infect. 1989;19:229&#x2013;236. doi: 10.1016/S0163-4453(89)90709-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0163-4453(89)90709-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2600441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J. J., Wang R., Liu C., et al. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan 1998: A comprehensive pathological, virological, and molecular study on a case of fulminant encephalitis. J Clin Virol. 2000;17:13&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1016/S1386-6532(00)00067-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1386-6532(00)00067-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>