<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">12136651</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2002</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0387-5911</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>76</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2002</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Kansenshogaku zasshi. The Journal of the Japanese Association for Infectious Diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Kansenshogaku Zasshi</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[The usefulness of human lung embryonal fibroblast cells (MRC-5) for isolation of enteroviruses and adenoviruses].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>432</StartPage><EndPage>438</EndPage><MedlinePgn>432-8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Although various cell lines have been used for virus isolation, few study of virus isolation using MRC-5 cell, a human embryonic lung fibroblasts, have been reported in Japan. MRC-5 and other cell lines (Caco-2, Vero, RD-18s, LLC-MK2, HeLa, MDCK, FL, B95a and HMV-II), and suckling mouse were compared for isolation of viruses from clinical specimens. A total of 3,284 specimens, collected from clinics and hospitals in Saitama Prefecture between July 1997 and August 2001, were inoculated in these cells. A total of 1,252 viral strains were isolated and 1,190 viral strains of these were identified. MRC-5 detected 209 of specimens positive for various viruses. As for adenovirus, a total of 132 viral strains were isolated using cell lines described above, and 100 of 132 viral strains were isolated in MRC-5. MRC-5 showed the highest sensitivity for isolation of adenovirus 3 and 7 (79.1% and 100%) of all other cells. The sensitivity in isolation of these viruses in HeLa was 58.1% and 50.0%, respectively. It showed that MRC-5 is able to isolate enterovirus, especially coxsackie virus A16 and enterovirus 71 with a high sensitivity (85.7% and 73.7%). RD-18s detected 35.7% and 26.3% of coxsackie virus A16 and enterovirus 71 isolates, LLC-MK2 detected 60.7% and 47.4%, and Vero detected 48.6% and 52.6%, respectively. Coxsackie virus B group was not isolated, except for a few coxsackie virus B 5 strains. Enteroviruses except coxsackie virus A16 and enterovirus 71 were isolated more frequently in Caco-2 and RD-18s. Seven hundred thirteen strains of influenza viruses were isolated in MDCK and Caco-2, but none was isolated in MRC-5. It was probably due to the maintenance medium without trypsin. The isolation rate of herpes simplex virus in Vero was 88.9% and MRC-5 showed 77.8%, it was high secondary to Vero by MRC-5. However, the CPE was detected in a few days in MRC-5, it was earlier than in Vero. The MRC-5 is possible to be maintained without changing the maintenance medium and passaged for 2 weeks, and clear CPE was observed. On the other hand, the disadvantages in using the MRC-5 were that the passage was limited and that the split ratio was only 1:2. However, the MRC-5 was used successfully for virus isolation, especially coxsackie virus A16, enterovirus 71 and adenoviruses, from clinical specimens.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shinohara</LastName><ForeName>Michiyo</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uchida</LastName><ForeName>Kazue</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimada</LastName><ForeName>Shin-ichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Segawa</LastName><ForeName>Yukari</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hirose</LastName><ForeName>Yoshifumi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>jpn</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Kansenshogaku Zasshi</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0236671</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0387-5911</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000256" MajorTopicYN="N">Adenoviridae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005347" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibroblasts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000196" MajorTopicYN="N">embryology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2002</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2002</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2002</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12136651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11150/kansenshogakuzasshi1970.76.432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>