<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">15812040</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0099-2240</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>71</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Molecular assays for targeting human and bovine enteric viruses in coastal waters and their application for library-independent source tracking.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2070</StartPage><EndPage>2078</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2070-8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Rapid population growth and urban development along waterways and coastal areas have led to decreasing water quality. To examine the effects of upstream anthropogenic activities on microbiological water quality, methods for source-specific testing are required. In this study, molecular assays targeting human enteroviruses (HEV), bovine enteroviruses (BEV), and human adenoviruses (HAdV) were developed and used to identify major sources of fecal contamination in the lower Altamaha River, Georgia. Two-liter grab samples were collected monthly from five tidally influenced stations between July and December 2002. Samples were analyzed by reverse transcription- and nested-PCR. PCR results were confirmed by dot blot hybridization. Eleven and 17 of the 30 surface water samples tested positive for HAdV and HEV, respectively. Two-thirds of the samples tested positive for either HEV or HAdV, and the viruses occurred simultaneously in 26% of samples. BEV were detected in 11 of 30 surface water samples. Binary logistic regression analysis showed that the presence of both human and bovine enteric viruses was not significantly related to either fecal coliform or total coliform levels. The presence of these viruses was directly related to dissolved oxygen and streamflow but inversely related to water temperature, rainfall in the 30 days preceding sampling, and chlorophyll-a concentrations. The stringent host specificity of enteric viruses makes them good library-independent indicators for identification of water pollution sources. Viral pathogen detection by PCR is a highly sensitive and easy-to-use tool for rapid assessment of water quality and fecal contamination when public health risk characterization is not necessary.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fong</LastName><ForeName>Theng-Theng</ForeName><Initials>TT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Envieronmental Health Science, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Griffin</LastName><ForeName>Dale W</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lipp</LastName><ForeName>Erin K</ForeName><Initials>EK</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D023362">Evaluation Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004279">DNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012367">RNA, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000260" MajorTopicYN="N">Adenoviruses, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002417" MajorTopicYN="N">Cattle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004279" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029650" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus, Bovine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005243" MajorTopicYN="N">Feces</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015723" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Library</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005845" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Georgia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016133" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012367" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045483" MajorTopicYN="N">Rivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012680" MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity and Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014876" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water Pollution</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2005</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15812040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1082535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.71.4.2070-2078.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">71/4/2070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abad, F., R. Pinto, C. Villena, R. Gajardo, and A. Bosch. 1997. Astrovirus survival in drinking water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 63:3119-3122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC168609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9251198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allard, A., B. Albinsson, and G. Wadell. 1992. Detection of adenoviruses in stools from healthy persons and patients with diarrhea by two-step polymerase chain reaction. J. Med. Virol. 37:149-157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1629713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anonymous. 2004, posting date. The Altamaha River. [Online.] http://www.altamahariverkeeper.org/river_news/altamaha/altamaha_river.asp.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anonymous. 2004, posting date. James Holland and the Altamaha Riverkeeper. [Online.] http://www.altamahariverkeeper.org/river_news/altamaha/altamaha_river_keeper.asp.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boom, R., C. J. A. Sol, M. M. M. Salimans, C. L. Jansen, P. M. E. Wertheim-Dillen, and J. Van Der Noordaa. 1990. Rapid and simple method for purification of nucleic acids. J. Clin. Microbiol. 28:495-503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC269651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1691208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch, A. 1998. Hum. enteric viruses in the water environment: a minireview. Int. Microbiol. 1:191-196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10943359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch, A. 1995. The survival of enteric viruses in the water environment. Microbiologia SEM 11:393-396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7576360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch, A., F. Lucena, J. M. Diez, R. Gajardo, M. Blasi, J. Jofre. 1991. Waterborne viruses associated with hepatitis outbreak. J. Am. Water Works Assoc. 83:80-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapron, C. D., N. A. Ballester, J. H. Fontaine, C. N. Frades, and A. B. Margolin. 2000. Detection of astroviruses, enteroviruses, and adenovirus types 40 and 41 in surface waters collected and evaluated by the information collection rule and an integrated cell culture-nested PCR procedure. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 66:2520-2525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC110573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10831432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung, H., L. Jaykus, and M. Sobsey. 1996. Detection of human enteric viruses in oysters by in vivo and in vitro amplification of nucleic acids. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 62:3772-3778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC168185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8837433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craun, G. F. 1991. Causes of waterborne outbreaks in the United States. Water Sci. Technol. 24:17-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Leon, R., C. Shieh, R. S. Baric, and M. D. Sobsey. 1990. Detection of enteroviruses and hepatitis A virus in environmental samples by gene probes and polymerase chain reaction, p. 833-853. In Proceedings of the 1990 Water Quality Technology Conference, Denver, Colorado, American Water Works Association, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dombek, P. E., L. K. Johnson, S. T. Zimmerley, and M. J. Sadowsky. 2000. Use of repetitive DNA sequences and the PCR to differentiate Escherichia coli isolates from human and animal sources. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 66:2572-2577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC110583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10831440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson, K. A., D. W. Griffin, and J. H. Paul. 2002. Detection, quantitation and identification of enteroviruses from surface waters and sponge tissue from the Florida Keys using real-time RT-PCR. Water Res. 36:2505-2514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12153016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enriquez, C. E., C. J. Hurst, and C. P. Gerba. 1995. Survival of the enteric adenoviruses 40 and 41 in tap, sea, and waste water. Water Res. 29:2548-2553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanning, J. L. 1999. Water use in coastal Georgia by county and source, 1997; and water-use trends, 1980-97. U.S. Geological Survey, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing, M. J. G. 1989. Viruses and the gut. Smith Kline &amp; French, Walwyn Garden City, Hertfordshire, United Kingdom.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feachem, R. G., D. J. Bradley, H. Garelick, and D. D. Mara. 1983. Sanitation and disease: health aspects of excreta and wastewater management. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., New York, N.Y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgia Department of Natural Resources. 2002. Altamaha River basin dissolved oxygen TMDLs. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Region 4. Georgia Department of Natural Resources, Atlanta, Ga.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgia Department of Natural Resources. 2002. Total maximum daily loads (TMDLs) for fecal coliform in 303(d) Listed Streams in The Altamaha River Basin. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Region 4. Georgia Department of Natural Resources, Atlanta, Ga.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgia Department of Natural Resources. 2004. State of Georgia rules and regulations for water quality control chapter 391-3-6. Georgia Department of Natural Resources, Atlanta, Ga.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba, C. P. 2000. Assessment of enteric pathogen shedding during recreational activity and its impact on water quality. Quant. Microbiol. 2:55-68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba, C. P., S. M. Goyal, R. L. Labelle, I. Cech, and G. F. Bodgan. 1979. Failure of indicator bacteria to reflect the occurrence of enteroviruses in marine waters. Am. J. Pub. Health. 69:1116-1119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1619291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba, C. P., D. M. Gramos, and N. Nwachuku. 2002. Comparative inactivation of enteroviruses and adenovirus 2 by UV light. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:5167-5169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC126408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12324370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerba, C. P., J. B. Rose, C. N. Haas, and K. D. Crabtree. 1996. Waterborne rotavirus: a risk assessment. Water Res. 30:2929-2940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal, S. M., and C. P. Gerba. 1983. Viradel method for detection of rotavirus from seawater. J. Virol. Methods 7:279-285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal, S. M., C. P. Gerba, and J. L. Melnick. 1979. Human enteroviruses in oysters and their overlying waters. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 37:572-581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">222210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin, D. W., C. J. Gibson, E. K. Lipp, K. Riley, J. H. Paul, and J. B. Rose. 1999. Detection of viral pathogens by reverse transcriptase PCR and of microbial indicators by standard methods in the canals of the Florida Keys. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 65:4118-4125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC99749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10473424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin, D. W., E. K. Lipp, M. R. McLaughlin, and J. B. Rose. 2001. Marine recreation and public health microbiology: quest for the ideal indicator. BioScience 51:817-825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafliger, D., M. Gligen, J. Luthy, and P. Hubner. 1997. Seminested RT-PCR systems for small round structured viruses and enteric viruses detection in seafood. Int. J. Food Microbiol. 37:27-36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9237119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hejkal, T. W., B. Keswick, R. L. LaBelle, C. P. Gerba, Y. Sanchez, G. Dreesman, B. Hafkin, and J. L. Melnick. 1982. Viruses in a community water supply associated with an outbreak of gastroenteritis and infectious hepatitis. J. Am. Water Works Assoc. 150:318-321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irving, L. G., and F. A. Smith. 1981. One-year survey of enteroviruses, adenoviruses, and reoviruses isolated from effluent at an activated-sludge purification plant. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 41:51-59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6261687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaykus, L. A., M. T. Hemard, and M. D. Sobsey. 1994. Human enteric pathogenic viruses, p. 92-153. In H. a. M. D. Pierson (ed.), Environmental indicators and shellfish safety. Chapman and Hall, New York, N.Y.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, S., R. Noble, and W. P. Chui. 2001. Human adenoviruses and coliphages in urban runoff-impacted coastal waters of Southern California. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 67:179-184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11133443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-Clavero, M. A., C. Fernandez, J. A. Ortiz, J. Pro, G. Carbonell, J. V. Tarazona, N. Roblas, and V. Ley. 2003. Teschoviruses as indicators of porcine fecal contamination of surface water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 69:6311-6315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14532098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katayama, H., A. Shimasaki, and S. Ohgaki. 2002. Development of a virus concentration method and its application to detection of enterovirus and Norwalk virus from coastal seawater. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:1033-1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC123733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11872447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krikelis, V., P. Markoulatos, N. Spyrou, and C. Serie. 1985. Detection of indigenous enteric viruses in raw sewage effluents of the city of Athens, Greece, during a two year survey. Water Sci. Technol. 17:159-164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S. H., and S. J. Kim. 2002. Detection of infectious enteroviruses and adenoviruses in tap water in urban areas in Korea. Water Res. 36:248-256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11766801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ley, V., J. Higgins, and R. Fayer. 2002. Bovine enteroviruses as indicators of fecal contamination. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:3455-3461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC126779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12089028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipp, E. K., R. Kurz, R. Vincent, C. Rodriguez-Palacios, S. R. Farrah, and J. B. Rose. 2001. The effects of seasonal variability and weather on microbial fecal pollution and enteric pathogens in a subtropical estuary. Estuaries 24:266-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipp, E. K., J. Lukasik, and J. B. Rose. 2001. Human enteric viruses and parasites in the marine environment, p. 559-588. In J. H. Paul (ed.), Methods in microbiology, vol. 30. Academic Press, London, United Kingdom.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maluquer de Motes, C., P. Clemente-Casares, A. Hundesa, M. Martin, and R. Girones. 2004. Detection of bovine and porcine adenoviruses for tracing the source of fecal contamination. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 70:1448-1454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC368300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15006765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick, J. L. 1984. Etiologic agents and their potential for causing waterborne virus diseases, p. 1-16. In J. L. Melnick (ed.), Enteric viruses in water, vol. 15. Karger, Basel, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick, J. L., and C. P. Gerba. 1989. The ecology of enteroviruses in natural waters. Crit. Rev. Environ. Control 10:65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, Q. S., and C. P. Gerba. 1996. Comparative inactivation of enteric adenovirus, poliovirus and coliphages by ultraviolet irradiation. Water Res. 30:2665-2668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasser, A. M., N. Zaruk, L. Tenenbaum, and Y. Netzan. 2003. Comparative survival of Cryptosporidium, coxsackievirus A9 and Escherichia coli in stream, brackish and sea waters. Water Sci. Technol. 47:91-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12639011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble, R. T., and J. A. Fuhrman. 1998. Use of SYBR Green I for rapid epifluorescence counts of marine viruses and bacteria. Aquat. Microb. Ecol. 14:113-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble, R. T., and J. A. Fuhrman. 2001. Enteroviruses detected by reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction from the coastal waters of Santa Monica Bay, California: low correlation to bacterial indicator levels. Hydrobiologia 460:175-184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noble, R. T., S. M. Allen, A. D. Blackwood, W. Chu, S. C. Jiang, G. L. Lovelace, M. D. Sobsey, J. R. Stewart, and D. A. Wait. 2003. Use of viral pathogens and indicators to differentiate between human and non-human fecal contamination in a microbial course tracking comparison study. J. Water Health 1:195-207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15382724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pina, S., M. Puig, F. Lucena, J. Jofre, and R. Girones. 1998. Viral pollution in the environment and in shellfish: human adenovirus detection by PCR as an index of human viruses. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 64:3376-3382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC106735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9726885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pommepuy, M., and F. Le Guyader. 1998. Molecular approaches to measuring microbial marine pollution. Curr. Opin. Biotechnol. 9:292-299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9650274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puig, M., J. Jofre, F. Lucena, A. Allard, G. Wadell, and R. Girones. 1994. Detection of adenoviruses and enteroviruses in polluted waters by nested-PCR amplification. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 60:2963-2970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8085832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao, V. C., and J. L. Melnick. 1986. Environmental biology. In J. A. Cole, C. J. Knowles, and D. Schlessinger (ed.), Aspects of microbiology, vol. 13. American Society of Microbiology, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose, J. B. 1986. Microbial aspects of wastewater reuse for irrigation. Crit. Rev. Environ. Control 16:231-256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiff, G. M., G. M. Stefanovic, B. Young, and J. K. Pennekamp. 1984. Minimum human infectious dose of enteric viruses (echovirus-12) in drinking water, p. 222-228. In J. L. Melnick (ed.), Enteric viruses in water, vol. 15. Karger, Basel, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott, T. M., J. B. Rose, T. M. Jenkins, S. R. Farrah, and J. Lukasik. 2002. Microbial source tracking: current methodology and future directions. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 68:5796-5803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC134426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12450798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobsey, M. D., P. A. Shields, F. S. Hauchman, R. L. Hazard, and L. W. Caton. 1986. Survival and transport of hepatitis A virus in soils, groundwater and wastewater. Water Sci. Technol. 18:97-106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straub, T. M., and D. P. Chandler. 2003. Towards a unified system for detecting waterborne pathogens. J. Microbiol. Methods 53:185-197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12654490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tani, N., Y. Dohi, N. Jurumatani, and K. Yonemasu. 1995. Seasonal distribution of adenoviruses, enteroviruses and reoviruses in urban river water. Microbiol. Immunol. 39:577-580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7494496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, M. B., P. J. Becker, E. J. Van-Rensburg, B. N. Harris, I. W. Bailey, and W. O. Grabow. 1995. A serosurvey of water-borne pathogens amongst canoeists in South Africa. Epidemiol. Infect. 115:299-307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2271398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7589269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurston-Enriquez, J. A., C. N. Haas, J. Jacangelo, and C. P. Gerba. 2003. Chlorine inactivation of adenovirus type 40 and feline calicivirus. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 69:3979-3985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC165174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12839771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurston-Enriquez, J. A., C. N. Haas, J. Jacangelo, K. Riley, and C. P. Gerba. 2003. Inactivation of feline calicivirus and adenovirus type 40 by UV radiation. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 69:577-582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC152434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12514044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai, Y. L., M. D. Sobsey, L. R. Sangermano, and C. J. Palmer. 1993. Simple method of concentrating enteroviruses and hepatitis A virus from sewage and ocean water for rapid detection by reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 59:3488-3491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7504433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 1988. Comparative health effects assessment of drinking water. U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, D.C.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency and U. S. Agency for International Development. 1992. Manual on guidelines for water reuse. EPA/625/R-92/004. Center for Environmental Reservation Information, Cincinnati, Ohio.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetz, J. J., E. K. Lipp, D. W. Griffin, J. Lukasik, D. Wait, M. D. Sobsey, T. M. Scott, and J. B. Rose. 2004. Presence, infectivity, and stability of enteric viruses in seawater: relationship to marine water quality in the Florida Keys. Mar. Pollut. Bull. 48:698-704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15041426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyer, M. D., J. M. Fleisher, J. Gough, D. Kay, and H. Merrett. 1995. An investigation into parametric relationships between enterovirus and faecal indicator organisms in the coastal waters of England and Wales. Water Res. 29:1863-1868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yates, M. V., C. P. Gerba, and L. M. Kelley. 1985. Virus persistence in groundwater. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 49:778-781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC238444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4004211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>