<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">20463159</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2010</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-660X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical and etiological characteristics of enterovirus 71-related diseases during a recent 2-year period in Korea.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2490</StartPage><EndPage>2494</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2490-4</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JCM.02369-09</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Human enterovirus 71 (EV 71) has caused large-scale outbreaks of hand-foot-and-mouth disease (HFMD), particularly in the Asian-Pacific region. In this study, we report a major outbreak of EV 71 infection in Korea and describe the clinical differences between EV 71 and non-EV 71 enterovirus infections. We prospectively enrolled patients with suspected viral infections during a recent 2-year period through a nationwide surveillance system. We identified 719 patients with suspected HFMD or herpangina using real-time PCR and genotyping based on VP1 sequence analysis. The major pathogen causing HFMD changed substantially from 2008 to 2009, with EV 71 becoming the most common cause of HFMD in Korea in 2009. We successfully identified the enteroviral genotypes for 218 of the 719 patients. Patients with EV 71 infections tended to be younger than those with non-EV 71 enteroviral infections and presented with HFMD and meningoencephalitis. In addition, the occurrence of fever, headache, and neck stiffness was significantly higher in patients with EV 71 infections. Multivariable analysis showed that for patients presenting with HFMD, fever, or a sore throat, each covariate was independently associated with EV 71 infection; the adjusted odds ratios (with 95% confidence intervals in parentheses) for these variables were 31.86 (10.04 to 101.09), 4.76 (1.71 to 13.25), and 0.18 (0.04 to 0.77), respectively. Our results indicate that EV 71 was a major cause of HFMD in Korea during the study period. In addition, we found that clinical symptoms may be helpful in the early identification of patients with EV 71 infections.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ryu</LastName><ForeName>Wi-Sun</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Enteric and Hepatitis Viruses, National Institute of Health, Korea Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Byounghak</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Jiyoung</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hwang</LastName><ForeName>Seoyeon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Jonghyun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheon</LastName><ForeName>Doo-Sung</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505564</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0095-1137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000704" MajorTopicYN="N">Analysis of Variance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003384" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coxsackievirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005843" MajorTopicYN="N">Geography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006557" MajorTopicYN="N">Herpangina</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056910" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Republic of Korea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20463159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2897491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.02369-09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JCM.02369-09</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar, S., I. C. Sam, J. Yusof, M. K. Lim, S. Misbah, N. MatRahim, and P. S. Hooi. 2009. Enterovirus 71 outbreak, Brunei. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 15:79-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19116058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aertsens, M., P. De Canniere, and H. Moors. 2003. Modelling of silica diffusion experiments with 32Si in Boom Clay. J. Contam. Hydrol. 61:117-129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12598099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, K. 2000. Hand, foot, and mouth disease outbreak reported in Singapore. Lancet 356:1338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11073035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, L. G., U. D. Parashar, M. S. Lye, F. G. Ong, S. R. Zaki, J. P. Alexander, K. K. Ho, L. L. Han, M. A. Pallansch, A. B. Suleiman, M. Jegathesan, and L. J. Anderson for the Outbreak Study Group. 2000. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. Clin. Infect. Dis. 31:678-683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., C. C. King, K. H. Hsu, H. C. Ning, K. C. Tsao, C. C. Li, Y. C. Huang, S. R. Shih, S. T. Chiou, P. Y. Chen, H. J. Chang, and T. Y. Lin. 2002. Risk factors of enterovirus 71 infection and associated hand, foot, and mouth disease/herpangina in children during an epidemic in Taiwan. Pediatrics 109:e88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diedrich, S., A. Weinbrecht, and E. Schreier. 2009. Seroprevalence and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in Germany. Arch. Virol. 154:1139-1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19506798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto, T., M. Chikahira, S. Yoshida, H. Ebira, A. Hasegawa, A. Totsuka, and O. Nishio. 2002. Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol. Immunol. 46:621-627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrero, L. J., C. S. Lee, R. J. Hurrelbrink, B. H. Chua, K. B. Chua, and P. C. McMinn. 2003. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in peninsular Malaysia, 1997-2000. Arch. Virol. 148:1369-1385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12827466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M., E. R. Chen, K. H. Hsu, S. J. Twu, K. T. Chen, S. F. Tsai, J. R. Wang, and S. R. Shih. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929-935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C. C., C. C. Liu, Y. C. Chang, C. Y. Chen, S. T. Wang, and T. F. Yeh. 1999. Neurologic complications in children with enterovirus 71 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:936-942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, S. W., Y. W. Hsu, D. J. Smith, D. Kiang, H. P. Tsai, K. H. Lin, S. M. Wang, C. C. Liu, I. J. Su, and J. R. Wang. 2009. Reemergence of enterovirus 71 in 2008 in Taiwan: dynamics of genetic and antigenic evolution from 1998 to 2008. J. Clin. Microbiol. 47:3653-3662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19776232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y. P., T. L. Lin, C. Y. Kuo, M. W. Lin, C. Y. Yao, H. W. Liao, L. C. Hsu, C. F. Yang, J. Y. Yang, P. J. Chen, and H. S. Wu. 2008. The circulation of subgenogroups B5 and C5 of enterovirus 71 in Taiwan from 2006 to 2007. Virus Res. 137:206-212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18706461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao, S. J., F. L. Yang, Y. H. Hsu, and H. I. Chen. 2004. Mechanism of fulminant pulmonary edema caused by enterovirus 71. Clin. Infect. Dis. 38:1784-1788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7107954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15227628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehle, J., B. Roth, C. Metzger, A. Pfitzner, and G. Enders. 2003. Molecular characterization of an enterovirus 71 causing neurological disease in Germany. J. Neurovirol. 9:126-128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12587076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., S. J. Twu, M. S. Ho, L. Y. Chang, and C. Y. Lee. 2003. Enterovirus 71 outbreaks, Taiwan: occurrence and recognition. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:291-293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12643822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, C. Y., C. Y. Lee, C. L. Kao, W. Y. Shao, P. I. Lee, S. J. Twu, C. C. Yeh, S. C. Lin, W. Y. Shih, S. I. Wu, and L. M. Huang. 2002. Incidence and case-fatality rates resulting from the 1998 enterovirus 71 outbreak in Taiwan. J. Med. Virol. 67:217-223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11992582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., I. Stratov, L. Nagarajan, and S. Davis. 2001. Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin. Infect. Dis. 32:236-242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P. C. 2002. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 26:91-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nix, W. A., M. S. Oberste, and M. A. Pallansch. 2006. Sensitive, seminested PCR amplification of VP1 sequences for direct identification of all enterovirus serotypes from original clinical specimens. J. Clin. Microbiol. 44:2698-2704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1594621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16891480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolan, M. A., M. E. Craig, M. M. Lahra, W. D. Rawlinson, P. C. Prager, G. D. Williams, A. M. Bye, and P. I. Andrews. 2003. Survival after pulmonary edema due to enterovirus 71 encephalitis. Neurology 60:1651-1656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12771257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi, M. H., S. C. Wong, Y. Podin, W. Akin, S. del Sel, A. Mohan, C. H. Chieng, D. Perera, D. Clear, D. Wong, E. Blake, J. Cardosa, and T. Solomon. 2007. Human enterovirus 71 disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: a prospective clinical, virological, and molecular epidemiological study. Clin. Infect. Dis. 44:646-656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17278054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortner, B., C. W. Huang, D. Schmid, I. Mutz, G. Wewalka, F. Allerberger, J. Y. Yang, and H. P. Huemer. 2009. Epidemiology of enterovirus types causing neurological disease in Austria 1999-2007: detection of clusters of echovirus 30 and enterovirus 71 and analysis of prevalent genotypes. J. Med. Virol. 81:317-324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19107980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piqueur, M. A., W. A. Verstrepen, P. Bruynseels, and A. H. Mertens. 2009. Improvement of a real-time RT-PCR assay for the detection of enterovirus RNA. Virol. J. 6:95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2716329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19583870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawyer, M. H. 1999. Enterovirus infections: diagnosis and treatment. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 18:1033-1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10608620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu, P. V., N. T. Thao, D. Perera, T. K. Huu, N. T. Tien, T. C. Thuong, O. M. How, M. J. Cardosa, and P. C. McMinn. 2007. Epidemiologic and virologic investigation of hand, foot, and mouth disease, southern Vietnam, 2005. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 13:1733-1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verstrepen, W. A., S. Kuhn, M. M. Kockx, M. E. Van De Vyvere, and A. H. Mertens. 2001. Rapid detection of enterovirus RNA in cerebrospinal fluid specimens with a novel single-tube real-time reverse transcription-PCR assay. J. Clin. Microbiol. 39:4093-4096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11682535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. N., C. T. Yao, C. N. Yeh, C. C. Huang, S. M. Wang, C. C. Liu, and J. M. Wu. 2006. Critical management in patients with severe enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr. Int. 48:250-256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16732789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., H. Y. Lei, L. Y. Su, J. M. Wu, C. K. Yu, J. R. Wang, and C. C. Liu. 2007. Cerebrospinal fluid cytokines in enterovirus 71 brain stem encephalitis and echovirus meningitis infections of varying severity. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. 13:677-682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17441979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., C. C. Liu, H. W. Tseng, J. R. Wang, C. C. Huang, Y. J. Chen, Y. J. Yang, S. J. Lin, and T. F. Yeh. 1999. Clinical spectrum of enterovirus 71 infection in children in southern Taiwan, with an emphasis on neurological complications. Clin. Infect. Dis. 29:184-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10433583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, F., L. Ren, Z. Xiong, J. Li, Y. Xiao, R. Zhao, Y. He, G. Bu, S. Zhou, J. Wang, and J. Qi. 2009. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in the People's Republic of China in 2008. J. Clin. Microbiol. 47:2351-2352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2708525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, K. D., M. Y. Yang, C. C. Li, S. F. Lin, M. C. Chong, C. L. Wang, R. F. Chen, and T. Y. Lin. 2001. Altered cellular but not humoral reactions in children with complicated enterovirus 71 infections in Taiwan. J. Infect. Dis. 183:850-856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11237800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y., X. J. Tan, H. Y. Wang, D. M. Yan, S. L. Zhu, D. Y. Wang, F. Ji, X. J. Wang, Y. J. Gao, L. Chen, H. Q. An, D. X. Li, S. W. Wang, A. Q. Xu, Z. J. Wang, and W. B. Xu. 2009. An outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with subgenotype C4 of human enterovirus 71 in Shandong, China. J. Clin. Virol. 44:262-267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19269888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>