<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">22039449</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Molecular analysis of virulent determinants of enterovirus 71.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e26237</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e26237</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e26237</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0026237</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is the most important causative agent of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) in children. In most cases, it is a self-limiting illness. However some EV71 infectious cases can develop severe clinical outcomes, such as encephalitis, meningitis, poliomyelitis like paralysis, and even death. To identify the determinants of virulence, the deduced amino acid sequence of polyprotein and nucleotide sequence of 5'-NTR and 3'-NTR in 25 SC-EV71 strains (strains from severe cases) and 31 MC-EV71 strains (strains from mild cases) were analyzed. Results showed four amino acids on two positions (Gly(P710)/Gln(P710)/Arg(P710) and Glu(P729)) on the DE and EF loop of VP1, one (Lys(P930)) on the surface of protease 2A and four nucleotides on three positions (G(P272), U(P488) and A(P700)/U(P700)) in the 5'-NTR region are associated with EV71 virulent phenotype. Predicted secondary structure of RNA using the consensus sequence of 5'-NTR by RNAStructure showed the mutation of nucleotide at position 488 in strain BJ08-Z004-3 (position 491 in prototype strain BrCr) can result in the discrepancy of an additional pair of nucleotides and thus change the stability of the second structure of IRES. Fragment base content analysis showed that in the region 696 to 714 bp at the 5'-NTR, where the A(P700)/U(P700) was located, the nucleotide constitution ratios differed significantly between SC-EV71 and MC-EV71 strains. In conclusion, comparative genomic analysis showed that virulence of EV71 strains are mainly determined by the amino acids on two positions of VP1, one position of protease 2A and the nucleotides on three positions in 5'-NTR.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Renqing</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Beijing Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Beijing, China. lirenqingz@sina.com</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zou</LastName><ForeName>Qinghua</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Lijuan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Herun</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yumei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008958" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Molecular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014774" MajorTopicYN="N">Virulence</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Competing Interests: </b>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22039449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0026237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-11-13022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McMinn PC. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2002;26:91&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar S, Chee HY, Al-Kobaisi MF, Xiaoshan J, Chua KB, et al. Identification of enterovirus 71 isolates from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) with fatal cases of encephalomyelitis in Malaysia. Virus Res. 1999;61:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10426204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, Twu SJ, Chen KT, et al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn P, Lindsay K, Perera D, Chan HM, Chan KP, et al. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J Virol. 2001;75:7732&#x2013;7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jee YM, Cheon DS, Kim K, Cho JH, Chung YS, et al. Genetic analysis of the VP1 region of human enterovirus 71 strains isolated in Korea during 2000. Arch Virol. 2003;148:1735&#x2013;1746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14505086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto T, Chikahira M, Yoshida S, Ebira H, Hasegawa A, et al. Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol Immunol. 2002;46:621&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Poh CL, Chow VT. Complete sequence analyses of enterovirus 71 strains from fatal and non-fatal cases of the hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in Singapore (2000). Microbiol Immunol. 2002;46:801&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12516778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu PV, Thao NT, Perera D, Huu TK, Tien NT, et al. Epidemiologic and virologic investigation of hand, foot, and mouth disease, southern Vietnam, 2005. Emerg Infect Dis. 2007;13:1733&#x2013;1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagiwara A, Yoneyama T, Takami S, Hashimoto I. Genetic and phenotypic characteristics of enterovirus 71 isolates from patients with encephalitis and with hand, foot and mouth disease. Arch Virol. 1984;79:273&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6320781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skinner MA, Racaniello VR, Dunn G, Cooper J, Minor PD, et al. New model for the secondary structure of the 5&#x2032; non-coding RNA of poliovirus is supported by biochemical and genetic data that also show that RNA secondary structure is important in neurovirulence. J Mol Biol. 1989;207:379&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2547075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson SR, Sarnow P. Enterovirus 71 contains a type I IRES element that functions when eukaryotic initiation factor eIF4G is cleaved. Virology. 2003;315:259&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14592777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christodoulou C, Colbere-Garapin F, Macadam A, Taffs LF, Marsden S, et al. Mapping of mutations associated with neurovirulence in monkeys infected with Sabin 1 poliovirus revertants selected at high temperature. J Virol. 1990;64:4922&#x2013;4929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC247983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2168976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGoldrick A, Macadam AJ, Dunn G, Rowe A, Burlison J, et al. Role of mutations G-480 and C-6203 in the attenuation phenotype of Sabin type 1 poliovirus. J Virol. 1995;69:7601&#x2013;7605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC189699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7494267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M, Shimizu H, Nagata N, Ami Y, Suzaki Y, et al. Temperature-sensitive mutants of enterovirus 71 show attenuation in cynomolgus monkeys. J Gen Virol. 2005;86:1391&#x2013;1401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melchers WJ, Hoenderop JG, Bruins Slot HJ, Pleij CW, Pilipenko EV, et al. Kissing of the two predominant hairpin loops in the coxsackie B virus 3&#x2032; untranslated region is the essential structural feature of the origin of replication required for negative-strand RNA synthesis. J Virol. 1997;71:686&#x2013;696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC191101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8985400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merkle I, van Ooij MJ, van Kuppeveld FJ, Glaudemans DH, Galama JM, et al. Biological significance of a human enterovirus B-specific RNA element in the 3&#x2032; nontranslated region. J Virol. 2002;76:9900&#x2013;9909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC136489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12208967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang GH, Lin L, Luo YJ, Cai LJ, Wu XY, et al. Sequence analysis of six enterovirus 71 strains with different virulences in humans. Virus Res. 2010;151:66&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20398708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick JL. Enterovirus type 71 infections: a varied clinical pattern sometimes mimicking paralytic poliomyelitis. Rev Infect Dis. 1984;6(Suppl 2):S387&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander JP, Jr, Baden L, Pallansch MA, Anderson LJ. Enterovirus 71 infections and neurologic disease&#x2013;United States, 1977&#x2013;1991. J Infect Dis. 1994;169:905&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8133108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Huang YC, Lin TY. Fulminant neurogenic pulmonary oedema with hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet. 1998;352:367&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9717926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arita M, Ami Y, Wakita T, Shimizu H. Cooperative effect of the attenuation determinants derived from poliovirus sabin 1 strain is essential for attenuation of enterovirus 71 in the NOD/SCID mouse infection model. J Virol. 2008;82:1787&#x2013;1797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2258712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18057246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua BH, Phuektes P, Sanders SA, Nicholls PK, McMinn PC. The molecular basis of mouse adaptation by human enterovirus 71. J Gen Virol. 2008;89:1622&#x2013;1632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18559932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gromeier M, Alexander L, Wimmer E. Internal ribosomal entry site substitution eliminates neurovirulence in intergeneric poliovirus recombinants. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1996;93:2370&#x2013;2375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC39803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8637880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernhart SH, Hofacker IL, Will S, Gruber AR, Stadler PF. RNAalifold: improved consensus structure prediction for RNA alignments. BMC Bioinformatics. 2008;9:474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2621365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19014431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofacker IL, Fekete M, Stadler PF. Secondary structure prediction for aligned RNA sequences. J Mol Biol. 2002;319:1059&#x2013;1066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12079347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruber AR, Lorenz R, Bernhart SH, Neubock R, Hofacker IL. The Vienna RNA websuite. Nucleic Acids Res. 2008;36:W70&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2447809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18424795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>