<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21359055</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2092-7258</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>54</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Korean journal of pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Korean J Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical manifestations of CNS infections caused by enterovirus type 71.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>11</StartPage><EndPage>16</EndPage><MedlinePgn>11-6</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3345/kjp.2011.54.1.11</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Enterovirus 71, one of the enteroviruses that are responsible for both hand-foot-and-mouth disease and herpangina, can cause neural injury. During periods of endemic spread of hand-foot-andmouth disease caused by enterovirus 71, CNS infections are also frequently diagnosed and may lead to increased complications from neural injury, as well as death. We present the results of our epidemiologic research on the clinical manifestations of children with CNS infections caused by enterovirus 71.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study group consisted of 42 patients admitted for CNS infection by enterovirus 71 between April 2009 and October 2009 at the Department of Pediatrics of 5 major hospitals affiliated with the Catholic University of Korea. We retrospectively reviewed initial symptoms and laboratory findings on admission, the specimen from which enterovirus 71 was isolated, fever duration, admission period, treatment and progress, and complications. We compared aseptic meningitis patients with encephalitis patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 42 patients (23 men, 19 women), hand-foot-and-mouth disease was most prevalent (n=39), followed by herpangina (n=3), upon initial clinical diagnosis. Among the 42 patients, 15 (35.7%) were classified as severe, while 27 (64.3%) were classified as mild. Factors such as age, fever duration, presence of seizure, and use of intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) were statistically different between the 2 groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results indicate that patients with severe infection caused by enterovirus 71 tended to be less than 3 years old, presented with at least 3 days of fever as well as seizure activity, and received IVIG treatment.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Cheol Soon</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, College of Medicine, The Catholic University of Korea, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Yun Jung</ForeName><Initials>YJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Ui Yoon</ForeName><Initials>UY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Ji Whan</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeong</LastName><ForeName>Dae Chul</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Hyun Hee</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Jong Hyun</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Jin Han</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Korean J Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101215374</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1738-1061</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Central nervous system infections</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Child</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Human</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2010</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2010</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21359055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3040360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3345/kjp.2011.54.1.11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mayo MA, Pringle CR. Virus taxonomy--1997. J Gen Virol. 1998;79:649&#x2013;657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9568957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pringle CR. Virus taxonomy at the XIth International Congress of Virology, Sydney, Australia, 1999. Arch Virol. 1999;144:2065&#x2013;2070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10550679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zell R, Sidigi K, Henke A, Schmidt-Brauns J, Hoey E, Martin S, et al. Functional features of the bovine enterovirus 5'-non-translated region. J Gen Virol. 1999;80:2299&#x2013;2309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10501480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick JL. Enteroviruses: polioviruses, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses and newer enteroviruses. In: Fields BN, Knipe DM, Howley PM, Griffin DE, Lamb RA, Martin MA, editors. Fields virology. 3rd ed. Philadelphia: Lippincott-Raven Publishers; 1996. pp. 655&#x2013;712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abzug MJ. Nonpolio Enteroviruses. In: Kliegman RM, Behrman RE, Jenson HB, Stanton BF, editors. Nelson textbook of pediatrics. 18th ed. Philadelphia: WB Saunders Co; 2007. pp. 1350&#x2013;1356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podin Y, Gias EL, Ong F, Leong YW, Yee SF, Yusof MA, et al. Sentinel surveillance for human enterovirus 71 in Sarawak, Malaysia: lessons from the first 7 years. BMC Public Health. 2006;6:180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1543637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16827926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, Twu SJ, Chen KT, Tsai SF, et al. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu PV, Thao NT, Perera D, Huu TK, Tien NT, Thuong TC, et al. Epidemiologic and virologic investigation of hand, foot, and mouth disease, southern Vietnam, 2005. Emerg Infect Dis. 2007;13:1733&#x2013;1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Tan XJ, Wang HY, Yan DM, Zhu SL, Wang DY, et al. An outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with subgenotype C4 of human enterovirus 71 in Shandong, China. J Clin Virol. 2009;44:262&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19269888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korea Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Case reports and genetic identification of serious infections by enterovirus 71 in Korea, 2009. Public Health Wkly Rep. 2009;2:328&#x2013;329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho JY, Kim HJ, Jung GY, Pang JK, Lee DB. Epidemic aseptic meningitis in 1993. J Korean Pediatr Soc. 1995;38:901&#x2013;906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung JA, Kim YJ, Choi HJ, Chung WK. An epidemic of aseptic meningitis in summer 1996 and global analysis and comparision of it with 1993. J Korean Pediatr Soc. 1997;40:1081&#x2013;1090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SY, Kwon OS, Kim WY, Jung WJ, Ma SH, Kim SK, et al. Epidemics of aseptic meningitis in Kyoungsangnamdo from March to October, 1997. Korean J Pediatr Infect Dis. 1998;5:104&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JS, Kim MR, Kim DH, Park CY, Lee KH, Lee HR, et al. Epidemiologic and clinical features of enteroviral infections in children; 1996-1998. Korean J Pediatr Infect Dis. 1999;6:210&#x2013;218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho KS, Jung MJ. Outbreak pattern of isolated enterovirus causing aseptic meningitis in Busan, 2002 years. Korean J Microbiol Biotechnol. 2004;32:179&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SM, Ho TS, Shen CF, Liu CC. Enterovirus 71, one virus and many stories. Pediatr Neonatol. 2008;49:113&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19054915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang LY, Lin TY, Hsu KH, Huang YC, Lin KL, Hsueh C, et al. Clinical features and risk factors of pulmonary edema after enterovirus-71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet. 1999;354:1682&#x2013;1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patrick RM, George SK, Michael AP, Ken SR. Medical microbiology. 2nd ed. St. Louis: Mosby; 1994. pp. 607&#x2013;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore M. Center for Disease Control. Enteroviral disease in the United States, 1970-1979. J Infect Dis. 1982;146:103&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6282988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagan R, Jenista JA, Menegus MA. Association of clinical presentation, laboratory findings, and virus serotypes with the presence of meningitis in hospital infants with enterovirus infection. J Pediatr. 1988;113:975&#x2013;978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2848117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JH, Kim SJ, Cheon DS. Hand-Foot-Mouth disease related to Enterovirus 71. J Korean Med Assoc. 2009;52:886&#x2013;894.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang LW, Koh BK, Chan KP, Chua LT, James L, Goh KT. Epidemiology and control of hand, foot and mouth disease in Singapore, 2001-2007. Ann Acad Med Singapore. 2009;38:106&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19271036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>