<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">27378138</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2017</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1541-0420</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>73</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biometrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biometrics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Time series modeling of pathogen-specific disease probabilities with subsampled data.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>283</StartPage><EndPage>293</EndPage><MedlinePgn>283-293</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/biom.12560</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Many diseases arise due to exposure to one of multiple possible pathogens. We consider the situation in which disease counts are available over time from a study region, along with a measure of clinical disease severity, for example, mild or severe. In addition, we suppose a subset of the cases are lab tested in order to determine the pathogen responsible for disease. In such a context, we focus interest on modeling the probabilities of disease incidence given pathogen type. The time course of these probabilities is of great interest as is the association with time-varying covariates such as meteorological variables. In this set up, a natural Bayesian approach would be based on imputation of the unsampled pathogen information using Markov Chain Monte Carlo but this is computationally challenging. We describe a practical approach to inference that is easy to implement. We use an empirical Bayes procedure in a first step to estimate summary statistics. We then treat these summary statistics as the observed data and develop a Bayesian generalized additive model. We analyze data on hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) in China in which there are two pathogens of primary interest, enterovirus 71 (EV71) and Coxackie A16 (CA16). We find that both EV71 and CA16 are associated with temperature, relative humidity, and wind speed, with reasonably similar functional forms for both pathogens. The important issue of confounding by time is modeled using a penalized B-spline model with a random effects representation. The level of smoothing is addressed by a careful choice of the prior on the tuning variance.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2016, The International Biometric Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fisher</LastName><ForeName>Leigh</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wakefield</LastName><ForeName>Jon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bauer</LastName><ForeName>Cici</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Self</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine and Infectious Disease Division, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center, Seattle, Washington, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 CA095994</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R21 AI119773</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Biometrics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370625</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0006-341X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001499" MajorTopicYN="N">Bayes Theorem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001699" MajorTopicYN="N">Biometry</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N">China</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003627" MajorTopicYN="Y">Data Interpretation, Statistical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D030016" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus D, Human</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008954" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Biological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011336" MajorTopicYN="Y">Probability</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Empirical Bayes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Generalized additive models</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infectious disease modeling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Subsampled data</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2016</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27378138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS794874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5224700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/biom.12560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andrieu C, Doucet A, Holenstein R. Particle Markov chain Monte Carlo methods. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society: Series B (Statistical Methodology) 2010;72:269&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer CXC. PhD thesis. University of Washington; 2012. Bayesian Modeling of Health Data in Space and Time.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bollaerts K, Antoine J, Van Casteren V, Ducoffre G, Hens N, Quoilin S. Contribution of respiratory pathogens to influenza-like illness consultations. Epidemiology &amp; Infection. 2013;141:2196&#x2013;2204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3757921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23217849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang H-L, Chio C-P, Su H-J, Liao C-M, Lin C-Y, Shau W-Y, Chi Y-C, Cheng Y-T, Chou Y-L, Li C-Y, et al. The association between enterovirus 71 infections and meteorological parameters in Taiwan. PLoS One. 2012;7:e46845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3465260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23071650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominici F, McDermott, Hastie T. Improved semi-parametric time series models of air pollution and mortality. Journal of the American Statistical Association. 2004;468:938&#x2013;948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dukic V, Lopes HF, Polson NG. Tracking epidemics with Google Flu Trends data and a state-space SEIR model. Journal of the American Statistical Association. 2012;107:1410&#x2013;1426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10426794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37583443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dushoff J, Plotkin JB, Viboud C, Earn DJ, Simonsen L. Mortality due to influenza in the United States&#x2014;an annualized regression approach using multiple-cause mortality data. American Journal of Epidemiology. 2006;163:181&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16319291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson GJ, Renshaw E. Estimating parameters in stochastic compartmental models using Markov chain methods. Mathematical Medicine and Biology. 1998;15:19&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held L, H&#xf6;hle M, Hofmann M. A statistical framework for the analysis of multivariate infectious disease surveillance counts. Statistical Modelling. 2005;5:187&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoadley B. The compound multinomial distribution and Bayesian analysis of categorical data from finite populations. Journal of the American Statistical Association. 1969;64:216&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Deng T, Yu S, Gu J, Huang C, Xiao G, Hao Y, et al. Effect of meteorological variables on the incidence of hand, foot, and mouth disease in children: a time-series analysis in Guangzhou, China. BMC Infectious Diseases. 2013;13:134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3626782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23497074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ionides E, Bret&#xf3; C, King A. Inference for nonlinear dynamical systems. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 2006;103:18438&#x2013;18443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3020138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17121996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lekone P, Finkenst&#xe4;dt B. Statistical inference in a stochastic epidemic SEIR model with control intervention: Ebola as a case study. Biometrics. 2006;62:1170&#x2013;1177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17156292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu MY, Liu W, Luo J, Liu Y, Zhu Y, Berman H, Wu J. Characterization of an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Nanchang, China in 2010. PLoS One. 2011;6:e25287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21980416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma E, Lam T, Wong C, Chuang S. Is hand, foot and mouth disease associated with meteorological parameters? Epidemiology and Infection. 2010;138:1779&#x2013;1788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20875200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKinley T, Cook A, Deardon R. Inference in epidemic models without likelihoods. The International Journal of Biostatistics. 2009;5:24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Neill PD, Roberts GO. Bayesian inference for partially observed stochastic epidemics. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society: Series A (Statistics in Society) 1999;162:121&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onozuka D, Hashizume M. The influence of temperature and humidity on the incidence of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan. Science of The Total Environment. 2011;410&#x2013;411:119&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22014509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng RD, Dominici F, Louis TA. Model choice in time series studies of air pollution and mortality. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society: Series A (Statistics in Society) 2006;169:179&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitman R, Melegaro A, Gelb D, Siddiqui M, Gay N, Edmunds W. Assessing the burden of influenza and other respiratory infections in England and Wales. Journal of Infection. 2007;54:530&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17097147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen DA, Ratmann O, Koelle K. Inference for nonlinear epidemio-logical models using genealogies and time series. PLoS Comput Biol. 2011;7:e1002136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3161897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21901082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rue H, Martino S, Chopin N. Approximate Bayesian inference for latent Gaussian models by using integrated nested Laplace approximations. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society Series B (Statistical Methodology) 2009;71:319&#x2013;392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruppert D, Wand M, Carroll R. Semiparametric Regression. Cambridge University Press; New York: 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong CW, Bible JM. Global epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Future Virology. 2009;4:501&#x2013;510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakefield JC, Best NG, Waller LA. Bayesian approaches to disease mapping. In: Elliott P, Wakefield JC, Best NG, Briggs D, editors. Spatial Epidemiology: Methods and Applications. Oxford University Press; Oxford: 2000. pp. 104&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Feng Z, Yang Y, Self S, Gao Y, Longini IM, Wakefield J, Zhang J, Wang L, Chen X, et al. Hand, foot and mouth disease in China: Patterns of spread and transmissibility during 2008-2009. Epidemiology (Cambridge, Mass.) 2011;22:781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3246273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21968769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H, Wang H, Wang Q, Xin Q, Lin H. The effect of meteorological factors on adolescent hand, foot, and mouth disease and associated effect modifiers. Global Health Action. 2014;7:24664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4124175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25098727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>