<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16081920</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2005</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0095-1137</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2005</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Genetic characteristics of human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 circulating from 1999 to 2004 in Shenzhen, People's Republic of China.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3835</StartPage><EndPage>3839</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3835-9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The genetic and phylogenetic characteristics of human enterovirus 71 (EV71) and coxsackievirus A16 (CA16) sampled from children with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Shenzhen, People's Republic of China, over a 6-year period (1999 to 2004) were examined with reverse transcription-PCR and DNA sequencing. Out of 147 stool specimens, 60 showed positive signals when screened with EV71- and CA16-specific primers. EV71 was identified in 19 specimens, and CA16 was identified in 41 specimens; coinfection by EV71 and CA16 was not observed. Phylogenetic analysis of all EV71 strains isolated from the mainland Chinese samples established C4 as the predominant genotype. Only one other known strain (3254-TAI-98; AF286531), isolated in Taiwan in 1998, was identified as belonging to genotype C4. Phylogenetic analysis of CA16 strains allowed us to identify three new genetic lineages (A, B, and C), with lineage C recently predominating in Asian countries, such as the People's Republic of China, Malaysia, and Japan. These new observations indicate that CA16 circulating in the People's Republic of China is genetically diverse, and additional surveillance is warranted.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Linlin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Molecular Virology and Genetic Engineering, National Institute for Viral Disease Control and Prevention, Chinese CDC, No. 6 Rongjing East Street, Yi zhuang, Beijing 100176, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Yaqing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Junping</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Xingye</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Yafang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Qi</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505564</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0095-1137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="Y">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017422" MajorTopicYN="N">Sequence Analysis, DNA</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2005</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2005</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2005</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2006</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1233905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.43.8.3835-3839.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">43/8/3835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>AbuBakar, S., H. Y. Chee, M. F. Al-Kobaisi, J. Xiaoshan, K. B. Chua, and S. K. Lam. 1999. Identification of enterovirus 71 isolates from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) with fatal cases of encephalomyelitis in Malaysia. Virus Res. 61:1-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10426204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendig, J. W., P. S. O'Brien, and P. Muir. 2001. Serotype-specific detection of coxsackievirus A16 in clinical specimens by reverse transcription-nested PCR. J. Clin. Microbiol. 39:3690-3692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11574592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, B. A., M. S. Oberste, J. P. Alexander, Jr., M. L. Kennett, and M. A. Pallansch. 1999. Molecular epidemiology and evolution of enterovirus 71 strains isolated from 1970 to 1998. J. Virol. 73:9969-9975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10559310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., D. Perera, B. A. Brown, D. Cheon, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, H. Cho, and P. McMinn. 2003. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 strains and recent outbreaks in the Asia-Pacific region: comparative analysis of the vp1 and vp4 genes. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:461-468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12702227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K. P., K. T. Goh, C. Y. Chong, E. S. Teo, G. Lau, and A. E. Ling. 2003. Epidemic hand, foot and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:78-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu, P. Y., K. H. Lin, K. P. Hwang, L. C. Chou, C. F. Wang, S. R. Shih, J. R. Wang, Y. Shimada, and H. Ishiko. 2001. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in Taiwan. Arch. Virol. 146:589-600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11338392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, A., W. Xu, and X. Li. 2004. Identification of enterovirus type 71 by RT-PCR and the gene characterization. Bingdu Xuebao 20:160-165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felsenstein, J. 1989. PHYLIP&#x2014;phylogeny inference package (version 3.5). Cladistics 5:164-166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, T. A. 1999. BioEdit: a user-friendly biological sequence alignment editor and analysis program for Windows 95/98/NT. Nucleic Acids Symp. 41:95-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jee, Y. M., D. S. Cheon, K. Kim, J. H. Cho, Y. S. Chung, J. Lee, S. H. Lee, K. S. Park, J. H. Lee, E. C. Kim, H. J. Chung, D. S. Kim, J. D. Yoon, and H. W. Cho. 2003. Genetic analysis of the VP1 region of human enterovirus 71 strains isolated in Korea during 2000. Arch. Virol. 148:1735-1746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14505086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo, H., N. Iritani, and Y. Seto. 2002. Molecular classification of enteroviruses not identified by neutralization tests. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 8:298-304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2732463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11927028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., S. J. Twu, S. M. Ho, L. Y. Chang, and C. Y. Lee. 2003. Enterovirus 71 outbreaks, Taiwan: occurrence and recognition. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:291-293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12643822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., I. Stratov, L. Nagarajan, and S. Davis. 2001. Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin. Infect. Dis. 32:236-242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P. C., K. Lindsay, D. Perera, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, and M. J. Cardosa. 2001. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J. Virol. 39:7732-7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munemura, T., M. Saikusa, C. Kawakami, H. Shimizu, M. Oseto, A. Hagiwara, H. Kimura, and T. Miyamura. 2003. Genetic diversity of enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of hand, foot and mouth disease in Yokohama City between 1982 and 2000. Arch. Virol. 148:253-263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12556991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, D. K., A. K. Law, S. W. Cherk, and K. L. Mak. 2001. First fatal case of enterovirus 71 infection in Hong Kong. Hong Kong Med. J. 7:193-196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11514756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste, M. S., S. Penaranda, K. Maher, and M. A. Pallansch. 2004. Complete genome sequences of all members of the species Human enterovirus A. J. Gen. Virol. 85:1597-1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15166444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page, R. D. 1996. TreeView: an application to display phylogenetic trees on personal computers. Comput. Appl. Biosci. 12:357-358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8902363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perera, D., Y. Podin, W. Akin, C. S. Tan, and M. J. Cardosa. 2004. Incorrect identification of recent Asian strains of Coxsackievirus A16 as human enterovirus 71: improved primers for the specific detection of human enterovirus 71 by RT PCR. BMC Infect. Dis. 4:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC415548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15122971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portolani, M., A. M. Bartoletti, P. Pietrosemoli, F. Beretti, E. Della Casa Muttini, M. F. Roversi, L. Livio, and F. Ferrari. 2004. Non-specific febrile illness by Coxsackievirus A16 in a 6-day-old newborn. Minerva Pediatr. 56:341-347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15252383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poyry, T., T. Hyypia, C. Horsnell, L. Kinnunen, T. Hovi, and G. Stanway. 1994. Molecular analysis of coxsackievirus A16 reveals a new genetic group of enteroviruses. Virology 202:982-987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8030260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuda, G. M., W. K. Chang, C. Y. Yeung, and P. S. Tang. 1987. Monoplegia caused by enterovirus 71: an outbreak in Hong Kong. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 6:206-208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3562141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santti, J., H. Harvala, L. Kinnunen, and T. Hyypia. 2000. Molecular epidemiology and evolution of coxsackievirus A9. J. Gen. Virol. 81:1361-1372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10769080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, N. J., E. H. Lennette, and H. H. Ho. 1974. An apparently new enterovirus isolated from patients with disease of the central nervous system. J. Infect. Dis. 129:304-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4361245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih, S. R., M. S. Ho, K. H. Lin, S. L. Wu, Y. T. Chen, C. N. Wu, T. Y. Lin, L. Y. Chang, K. C. Tsao, H. C. Ning, P. Y. Chang, S. M. Jung, C. Hsueh, and K. S. Chang. 2000. Genetic analysis of enterovirus 71 isolated from fatal and non-fatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease during and epidemic in Taiwan, 1998. Virus Res. 68:127-136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10958984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu, H., A. Utama, N. Onnimala, C. Li, Z. Li-Bi, M. Yu-Jie, Y. Pongsuwanna, and T. Miyamura. 2004. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 infection in the Western Pacific Region. Pediatr. Int. 46:231-235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15056257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu, H., A. Utama, K. Yoshii, H. Yoshida, T. Yoneyama, M. Sinniah, M. A. Yusof, Y. Okuno, N. Okabe, S. R. Shih, H. Y. Chen, G. R. Wang, C. L. Kao, K. S. Chang, T. Miyamura, and A. Hagiwara. 1999. Enterovirus 71 from fatal and nonfatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease epidemics in Malaysia, Japan and Taiwan in 1997-1998. Jpn. J. Infect. Dis. 52:12-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10808253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S., V. T. Chow, K. P. Chan, A. E. Ling, and C. L. Poh. 2000. RT-PCR, nucleotide, amino acid and phylogenetic analyses of enterovirus type 71 strains from Asia. J. Virol. Methods 88:193-204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10960707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, J. D., D. G. Higgins, and T. J. Gibson. 1994. CLUSTAL W: improving the sensitivity of progressive multiple sequence alignment through sequence weighting, position-specific gap penalties and weight matrix choice. Nucleic Acids Res. 22:4673-4680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC308517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7984417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, C. Y., F. Li Lu, M. H. Wu, C. Y. Lee, and L. M. Huang. 2004. Fatal coxsackievirus A16 infection. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 23:275-276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15014311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J.-R., Y.-C. Tuan, H.-P. Tsai, J.-J. Yan, C.-C. Liu, and I.-J. Su. 2002. Change of major genotype of enterovirus 71 in outbreaks of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Taiwan between 1998 and 2000. J. Clin. Microbiol. 40:10-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>