<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">17446325</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2007</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0095-1137</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2007</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of different clinical sample types in diagnosis of human enterovirus 71-associated hand-foot-and-mouth disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1858</StartPage><EndPage>1866</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1858-66</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 are important causes of hand-foot-and-mouth disease (HFMD). Like other enteroviruses, they can be isolated from a range of sterile and nonsterile sites, but which clinical sample, or combination of samples, is the most useful for laboratory diagnosis of HFMD is not clear. We attempted virus culture for 2,916 samples from 628 of 725 children with HFMD studied over a 3 1/2-year period, which included two large outbreaks. Overall, throat swabs were the single most useful specimen, being positive for any enterovirus for 288 (49%) of 592 patients with a full set of samples. Vesicle swabs were positive for 169 (48%) of 333 patients with vesicles, the yield being greater if two or more vesicles were swabbed. The combination of throat plus vesicle swabs enabled the identification of virus for 224 (67%) of the 333 patients with vesicles; for this patient group, just 27 (8%) extra patients were diagnosed when rectal and ulcer swabs were added. Of 259 patients without vesicles, use of the combination of throat plus rectal swab identified virus for 138 (53%). For 60 patients, virus was isolated from both vesicle and rectal swabs, but for 12 (20%) of these, the isolates differed. Such discordance occurred for just 11 (10%) of 112 patients with virus isolated from vesicle and throat swabs. During large HFMD outbreaks, we suggest collecting swabs from the throat plus one other site: vesicles, if these are present (at least two should be swabbed), or the rectum if there are no vesicles. Vesicle swabs give a high diagnostic yield, with the added advantage of being from a sterile site.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ooi</LastName><ForeName>Mong How</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Sibu Hospital, Ulu Oya Road, 96000 Sibu, Sarawak, Malaysia. monghow@pd.jaring.my</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solomon</LastName><ForeName>Tom</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Podin</LastName><ForeName>Yuwana</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohan</LastName><ForeName>Anand</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akin</LastName><ForeName>Winnie</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yusuf</LastName><ForeName>Mohd Apandi</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>del Sel</LastName><ForeName>Syvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kontol</LastName><ForeName>Kamsiah Mohd</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lai</LastName><ForeName>Boon Fu</ForeName><Initials>BF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clear</LastName><ForeName>Daniela</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chieng</LastName><ForeName>Chae Hee</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blake</LastName><ForeName>Emma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perera</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>See Chang</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cardosa</LastName><ForeName>Jane</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>G116/194</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D023362">Evaluation Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2007</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505564</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0095-1137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001769" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002555" MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebrospinal Fluid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004196" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Outbreaks</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="Y">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010614" MajorTopicYN="N">Pharynx</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012007" MajorTopicYN="N">Rectum</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013048" MajorTopicYN="N">Specimen Handling</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014456" MajorTopicYN="N">Ulcer</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014776" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Cultivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2007</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2007</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2007</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2007</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17446325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1933032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.01394-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JCM.01394-06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., S. Krishnan, P. H. Tio, D. Perera, and S. C. Wong. 1999. Isolation of subgenus B adenovirus during a fatal outbreak of enterovirus 71-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sibu, Sarawak. Lancet 354:987-991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10501361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardosa, M. J., D. Perera, B. A. Brown, D. Cheon, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, H. Cho, and P. McMinn. 2003. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 strains and recent outbreaks in the Asia-Pacific region: comparative analysis of the VP1 and VP4 genes. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:461-468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12702227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K. P., K. T. Goh, C. Y. Chong, E. S. Teo, G. Lau, and A. E. Ling. 2003. Epidemic hand, foot and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:78-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, L. G., U. D. Parashar, M. S. Lye, F. G. Ong, S. R. Zaki, J. P. Alexander, K. K. Ho, L. L. Han, M. A. Pallansch, A. B. Suleiman, M. Jegathesan, and L. J. Anderson. 2000. Deaths of children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Sarawak, Malaysia: clinical and pathological characteristics of the disease. For the Outbreak Study Group. Clin. Infect. Dis. 31:678-683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11017815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., T. Y. Lin, K. H. Hsu, Y. C. Huang, K. L. Lin, C. Hsueh, S. R. Shih, H. C. Ning, M. S. Hwang, H. S. Wang, and C. Y. Lee. 1999. Clinical features and risk factors of pulmonary oedema after enterovirus-71-related hand, foot, and mouth disease. Lancet 354:1682-1686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. Y., T. Y. Lin, Y. C. Huang, K. C. Tsao, S. R. Shih, M. L. Kuo, H. C. Ning, P. W. Chung, and C. M. Kang. 1999. Comparison of enterovirus 71 and coxsackie-virus A16 clinical illnesses during the Taiwan enterovirus epidemic, 1998. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 18:1092-1096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10608631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung, P. W., Y. C. Huang, L. Y. Chang, T. Y. Lin, and H. C. Ning. 2001. Duration of enterovirus shedding in stool. J. Microbiol. Immunol. Infect. 34:167-170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11605806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto, T., M. Chikahira, S. Yoshida, H. Ebira, A. Hasegawa, A. Totsuka, and O. Nishio. 2002. Outbreak of central nervous system disease associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease in Japan during the summer of 2000: detection and molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71. Microbiol. Immunol. 46:621-627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12437029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M., E. R. Chen, K. H. Hsu, S. J. Twu, K. T. Chen, S. F. Tsai, J. R. Wang, S. R. Shih, et al. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929-935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohler, K. A., W. G. Hlady, K. Banerjee, and R. W. Sutter. 2003. Outbreak of poliomyelitis due to type 3 poliovirus, northern India, 1999-2000: injections a major contributing factor. Int. J. Epidemiol. 32:272-277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12714548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komatsu, H., Y. Shimizu, Y. Takeuchi, H. Ishiko, and H. Takada. 1999. Outbreak of severe neurologic involvement associated with Enterovirus 71 infection. Pediatr. Neurol. 20:17-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lina, B., B. Pozzetto, L. Andreoletti, E. Beguier, T. Bourlet, E. Dussaix, L. Grangeot-Keros, B. Gratacap-Cavallier, C. Henquell, M. C. Legrand-Quillien, A. Novillo, P. Palmer, J. Petitjean, K. Sandres, P. Dubreuil, H. Fleury, F. Freymuth, I. Leparc-Goffart, D. Hober, J. Izopet, H. Kopecka, Y. Lazizi, H. Lafeuille, P. Lebon, A. Roseto, E. Marchadier, B. Masquelier, B. Picard, J. Puel, J. M. Seigneurin, P. Wattre, and M. Aymard. 1996. Multicenter evaluation of a commercially available PCR assay for diagnosing enterovirus infection in a panel of cerebrospinal fluid specimens. J. Clin. Microbiol. 34:3002-3006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC229449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8940438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., K. Lindsay, D. Perera, H. M. Chan, K. P. Chan, and M. J. Cardosa. 2001. Phylogenetic analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated during linked epidemics in Malaysia, Singapore, and Western Australia. J. Virol. 75:7732-7738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., I. Stratov, and G. Dowse. 1999. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in Western Australia associated with acute flaccid paralysis. Preliminary report. Commun. Dis. Intell. 23:199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10476610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P., I. Stratov, L. Nagarajan, and S. Davis. 2001. Neurological manifestations of enterovirus 71 infection in children during an outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Western Australia. Clin. Infect. Dis. 32:236-242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P. C. 2002. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 26:91-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuta, K., C. Abiko, T. Murata, Y. Matsuzaki, T. Itagaki, K. Sanjoh, M. Sakamoto, S. Kongo, S. Murayama, and K. Hayasaka. 2005. Frequent importation of enterovirus 71 from surrounding countries into the local community of Yamagata, Japan, between 1998 and 2003. J. Clin. Microbiol. 43:6171-6175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16333123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolan, M. A., M. E. Craig, M. M. Lahra, W. D. Rawlinson, P. C. Prager, G. D. Williams, A. M. Bye, and P. I. Andrews. 2003. Survival after pulmonary edema due to enterovirus 71 encephalitis. Neurology 60:1651-1656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12771257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi, M. H., S. C. Wong, D. Clear, D. Perera, S. Krishnan, T. Preston, P. H. Tio, H. J. Willison, B. Tedman, R. Kneen, M. J. Cardosa, and T. Solomon. 2003. Adenovirus-21 associated acute flaccid paralysis during a hand foot and mouth disease outbreak in Sarawak, Malaysia. Clin. Infect. Dis. 36:550-559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12594634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallansch, M. A., and R. P. Roos. 2001. Enteroviruses: polioviruses, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses and newer enteroviruses, p. 723-775. In D. M. Knipe and P. M. Howley (ed.), Fields Virology, vol. 1. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, Philadelphia, USA</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prager, P., M. Nolan, I. P. Andrews, and G. D. Williams. 2003. Neurogenic pulmonary edema in enterovirus 71 encephalitis is not uniformly fatal but causes severe morbidity in survivors. Pediatr. Crit. Care Med. 4:377-381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12831425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotbart, H. A. 1995. Enteroviral infections of the central nervous system. Clin. Infect. Dis. 20:971-981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7795102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotbart, H. A., A. Ahmed, S. Hickey, R. Dagan, G. H. McCracken Juniorperiod, R. J. Whitley, J. F. Modlin, M. Cascino, J. F. O'Connell, M. A. Menegus, and D. Blum. 1997. Diagnosis of enterovirus infection by polymerase chain reaction of multiple specimen types. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 16:409-411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9109145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotbart, H. A., and J. R. Romero. 1995. Laboratory diagnosis of enteroviral infection, p. 401-418. In H. A. Rotbart (ed.), Human Enterovirus Infection. American Society for Microbiology, Washington, DC.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thivierge, B., and G. Delage. 1982. Enterovirus infections of the CNS: 223 cases seen in a hospital for children from 1973 to 1981. Can. Med. Assoc. J. 127:1097-1102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1862050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6291736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. R., H. P. Tsai, P. F. Chen, Y. J. Lai, J. J. Yan, D. Kiang, K. H. Lin, C. C. Liu, and I. J. Su. 2000. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998. II. Laboratory diagnosis and genetic analysis. J. Clin. Virol. 17:91-99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10942089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., C. C. Liu, H. W. Tseng, J. R. Wang, C. C. Huang, Y. J. Chen, Y. J. Yang, S. J. Lin, and T. F. Yeh. 1999. Clinical spectrum of enterovirus 71 infection in children in southern Taiwan, with an emphasis on neurological complications. Clin. Infect. Dis. 29:184-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10433583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yerly, S., A. Gervaix, V. Simonet, M. Caflisch, L. Perrin, and W. Wunderli. 1996. Rapid and sensitive detection of enteroviruses in specimens from patients with aseptic meningitis. J. Clin. Microbiol. 34:199-201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC228761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8748304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>