<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32882061</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-1594</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Artificial organs</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Artif Organs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hyperferritinemia in patients with COVID-19: An opportunity for iron chelation?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>163</StartPage><EndPage>167</EndPage><MedlinePgn>163-167</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/aor.13812</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Studies from China on COVID-19 revealed that nonsurvivors had cytokine storm with high IL-6 and hyperferritinemia. Iron liberated from necrotic cells may catalyze free radical production and amplify lipid peroxidation causing membrane dysfunction and multiorgan failure. Consequently, iron chelators have been successfully utilized in various experimental and clinical models of cytokine storm and multiorgan damage, such as in ischemia-reperfusion injury, sepsis, and infections. Since viral replication may be influenced by iron accumulation, iron chelation has been proven beneficial in a variety of viral infections, such as HIV-1, hepatitis B virus, Mengovirus, Marburg hemorrhagic fever, Enterovirus 71, and West Nile virus. In this commentary, we elaborate on the idea of considering iron chelation as a therapeutic modality in patients with severe COVID-19 infection. For critically ill patients in the ICU, intravenous deferoxamine would provide sufficient and rapid iron chelation to ameliorate cytokine storm, whereas in less severe cases an oral chelator&#xa0;could prevent the development of excessive inflammatory response.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 International Center for Artificial Organ and Transplantation (ICAOT) and Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vlahakos</LastName><ForeName>Vassilios D</ForeName><Initials>VD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Services, Evangelismos Hospital, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marathias</LastName><ForeName>Katerina P</ForeName><Initials>KP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Onassis Cardiac Surgery Center, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arkadopoulos</LastName><ForeName>Nikolaos</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>4th Department of Surgery, Attikon University Hospital, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens Medical School, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vlahakos</LastName><ForeName>Demetrios V</ForeName><Initials>DV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8463-9607</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>2nd Department of Internal Medicine, Attikon University Hospital, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens Medical School, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Artif Organs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7802778</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0160-564X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007502">Iron Chelating Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>J06Y7MXW4D</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003676">Deferoxamine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000284" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Oral</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000080424" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokine Release Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003676" MajorTopicYN="N">Deferoxamine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000085583" MajorTopicYN="N">Hyperferritinemia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007262" MajorTopicYN="N">Infusions, Intravenous</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007502" MajorTopicYN="N">Iron Chelating Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000093485" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Drug Treatment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cytokine storm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">iron chelation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32882061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aor.13812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, Yu T, Du R, Fan G, Liu Y, Liu Z, et al. Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet. 2020;395:1054-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colafrancesco S, Alessandri C, Conti F, Priori R. COVID-19 gone bad: A new character in the spectrum of the hyperferritinemic syndrome? Autoimmun Rev. 2020;19:102573. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2020.102573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ros&#xe1;rio C, Zandman-Goddard G, Meyron-Holtz EG, D'Cruz DP, Shoenfeld Y. The hyperferritinemic syndrome: macrophage activation syndrome, Still's disease, septic shock and catastrophic antiphospholipid syndrome. BMC Med. 2013;22:185. https://doi.org/10.1186/1741-7015-11-185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian-Jiu SU, Zhang J-H, Gomez H, Murugan R, Hong X, Xu D, et al. Reactive oxygen species-induced lipid peroxidation in apoptosis, autophagy, and ferroptosis. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2019;2019:1-13. https://doi.org/10.1155/2019/5080843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menasch&#xe9; P, Antebi H, Alcindor LG, et al. Iron chelation by deferoxamine inhibits lipid peroxidation during cardiopulmonary bypass in humans. Circulation. 1990;82(5 Suppl):IV390-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira R, Burgos M, Milei J, Llesuy S, Molteni L, Hourquebie H, et al. Effect of supplementing cardioplegic solution with deferoxamine on reperfused human myocardium. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 1990;100:708-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costagliola DG, de Montalembert M, Lefr&#xe8;re JJ, Briand C, Rebulla P, Baruchel S, et al. Dose of desferrioxamine and evolution of HIV-1 infection in thalassaemic patients. Br J Haematol. 1994;87:849-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayraktar Y, Koseoglu T, Somner C, Kayhan B, Temizer A, Uzunalimoglu B, et al. The use of deferoxamine infusions to enhance the response rate to interferon-alpha treatment of chronic viral hepatitis B. J Viral Hepat. 1996;3:129-35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paraskevaidis IA, Iliodromitis EK, Vlahakos D, Tsiapras DP, Nikolaidis A, Marathias A, et al. Deferoxamine infusion during coronary artery bypass grafting ameliorates lipid peroxidation and protects the myocardium against reperfusion injury: immediate and long-term significance. Eur Heart J. 2005;26:263-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulvey MR, K&#xfc;hn LC, Scraba DG. Induction of ferritin synthesis in cells infected with Mengo virus. J Biol Chem. 1996;271:9851-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ignat'ev GM, Strel'tsova MA, Agafonov AP, Kashentseva EA, Prozorovski&#x12d; NS. Experimental study of possible treatment of Marburg hemorrhagic fever with desferal, ribavirin, and homologous interferon. Vopr Virusol. 1996;41:206-9. [Article in Russian].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritter C, Andrades ME, Reinke A, Menna-Barreto S, Moreira JC, Dal-Pizzol F. Treatment with N-acetylcysteine plus deferoxamine protects rats against oxidative stress and improves survival in sepsis. Crit Care Med. 2004;32:342-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arantes JM, Francisco AF, de Abreu Vieira PM, Silva M, Ara&#xfa;jo MSS, de Carvalho AT, et al. Trypanosoma cruzi: desferrioxamine decreases mortality and parasitemia in infected mice through a trypanostatic effect. Exp Parasitol. 2011;128:401-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arkadopoulos N, Demetrios Vlahakos D, Kostopanagiotou G, Panagopoulos D, Karvouni E, Routsi C, et al. Iron chelation attenuates intracranial pressure and improves survival in a swine model of acute liver failure. Liver Transpl. 2008;14:1116-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostopanagiotou GG, Kalimeris KA, Arkadopoulos NP, Pafiti A, Panagopoulos D, Smyrniotis V, et al. Desferrioxamine attenuates minor lung injury following surgical acute liver failure. Eur Respir J. 2009;33:1429-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlahakos D, Arkadopoulos N, Kostopanagiotou G, Siasiakou S, Kaklamanis L, Degiannis D, et al. Deferoxamine attenuates lipid peroxidation, blocks interleukin-6 production, ameliorates sepsis inflammatory response syndrome, and confers renoprotection after acute hepatic ischemia in pigs. Artif Organs. 2012;36:400-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Ma J, Xiu J, Bai L, Guan F, Zhang L, et al. Deferoxamine compensates for decreases in B cell counts and reduces mortality in enterovirus 71-infected mice. Mar Drugs. 2014;12:4086-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Liu C, Pan S, Miao Q, Xue J, Xun J, et al. Deferoxamine attenuates lipopolysaccharide-induced inflammatory responses and protects against endotoxic shock in mice. Biochem Biophys Res Comm. 2015;465:305-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchemin JB, Paradkar PN. Iron availability affects West Nile virus infection in its mosquito vector. Virol J. 2017;14:103. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12985-017-0770-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright SW, Valento M, Mazor SS, Chen BC. Severe iron poisoning treated with prolonged deferoxamine infusion: a case report. Toxicol Commun. 2018;2:6-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho BS, Jeon YW, Hahn AR, Lee T-H, Park S-S, Yoon J-H, et al. Improved survival outcomes and restoration of graft-vs-leukemia effect by deferasirox after allogeneic stem cell transplantation in acute myeloid leukemia. Cancer Med. 2019;8:501-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappellini MD, Pattoneri P. Oral iron chelators. Annu Rev Med. 2009;60:25-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howland MA. Risks of parenteral deferoxamine for acute iron poisoning. J Toxicol Clin Toxicol. 1996;34:491-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Zhang S, Nekhai S, Liu S. Depriving iron supply to the virus represents a promising adjuvant therapeutic against viral survival. Curr Clin Microbiol Rep. 2020;20:1-7. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40588-020-00140-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perricone C, Bartoloni E, Bursi R, Cafaro G, Guidelli GM, Shoenfeld Y, et al. COVID-19 as part of the hyperferritinemic syndromes: the role of iron depletion therapy. Immunol Res. 2020;68:213-224. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12026-020-09145-5.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>