<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">15254164</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2004</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-538X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>78</Volume><Issue>15</Issue><PubDate><Year>2004</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A mouse-adapted enterovirus 71 strain causes neurological disease in mice after oral infection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7916</StartPage><EndPage>7924</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7916-24</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>A mouse-adapted enterovirus 71 (EV71) strain with increased virulence in mice, MP4, was generated after four serial passages of the parental EV71 strain 4643 in mice. Strain MP4 exhibited a larger plaque size, grew more rapidly, and was more cytotoxic in vitro than strain 4643. Although strains 4643 and MP4 both induced apoptosis of SK-N-SH human neuroblastoma cells, MP4 was more virulent than 4643 in 1-day-old mice (50% lethal doses, 10(2) and 10(4) PFU/mouse, respectively). Strain MP4 (5 x 10(6) PFU/mouse), but not 4643, could orally infect 7-day-old mice, resulting in rear-limb paralysis followed by death 5 to 9 days after inoculation with the virus. Histopathologically, neuronal loss and apoptosis were evident in the spinal cords as well as the brain stems of the infected mice. The limb muscles displayed massive necrosis. There was early and transient virus replication in the intestines, whereas the spinal cord, brain, and muscle became the sites of viral replication during the late phase of the infection. Virus transmission occurred among infected and noninfected cagemates, as demonstrated by the occurrence of seroconversion and the presence of viable viruses in the stool samples of the latter. Protection against EV71 challenge was demonstrated following administration of hyperimmune serum 1 day after inoculation with the virus. Nucleotide sequence analysis of the genome of EV71 strain MP4 revealed four nucleotide changes on the 5' untranslated region, three on the VP2 region, and eight on the 2C region, resulting in one and four amino acid substitutions in the VP2 and 2C proteins, respectively.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ya-Fang</ForeName><Initials>YF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, College of Medicine, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan, Taiwan, Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chou</LastName><ForeName>Chun-Ting</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lei</LastName><ForeName>Huan-Yao</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Ching-Chuan</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shih-Min</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Jing-Jou</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Ih-Jen</ForeName><Initials>IJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jen-Reng</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yeh</LastName><ForeName>Trai-Ming</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Shun-Hua</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Chun-Keung</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020121">5' Untranslated Regions</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000914">Antibodies, Viral</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020121" MajorTopicYN="N">5' Untranslated Regions</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000914" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Viral</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017209" MajorTopicYN="N">Apoptosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002493" MajorTopicYN="N">Central Nervous System Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathogenicity</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004769" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008813" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Inbred ICR</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014774" MajorTopicYN="N">Virulence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014779" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Replication</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2004</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2004</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2004</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2004</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC446098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.78.15.7916-7924.2004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">78/15/7916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alexander, J. P., Jr., L. Baden, M. A. Pallansch, and L. J. Anderson. 1994. Enterovirus 71 infections and neurologic disease&#x2014;United States, 1977-1991. J. Infect. Dis. 169:905-908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8133108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, K. P., K. T. Goh, C. Y. Chong, E. S. Teo, G. Lau, and A. E. Ling. 2003. Epidemic hand, foot and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 9:78-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. C., C. K. Yu, Y. F. Wang, C. C. Liu, I. J. Su, and H. Y. Lei. 2004. A murine oral enterovirus 71 infection model with central nervous system involvement. J. Gen. Virol. 85:69-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14718621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chumakov, M., M. Voroshilova, L. Shindarov, I. Lavrova, L. Gracheva, G. Koroleva, S. Vasilenko, I. Brodvarova, M. Nikolova, S. Gyurova, M. Gacheva, G. Mitov, N. Ninov, E. Tsylka, I. Robinson, M. Frolova, V. Bashkirtsev, L. Martiyanova, and V. Rodin. 1979. Enterovirus 71 isolated from cases of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease in Bulgaria. Arch. Virol. 60:329-340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">228639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn, J. J., N. M. Chapman, S. Tracy, and J. R. Romero. 2000. Genomic determinants of cardiovirulence in coxsackievirus B3 clinical isolates: localization to the 5&#x2032; nontranslated region. J. Virol. 74:4787-4794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC112001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10775617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez, A. L., M. Denova-Ocampo, V. R. Racaniello, and R. M. del Angel. 1997. Attenuating mutations in the poliovirus 5&#x2032; untranslated region alter its interaction with polypyrimidine tract-binding protein. J. Virol. 71:3826-3833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC191533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9094658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto, I., and A. Hagiwara. 1982. Pathogenicity of a poliomyelitis-like disease in monkeys infected orally with enterovirus 71: a model for human infection. Neuropathol. Appl. Neurobiol. 8:149-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7048123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M., E. R. Chen, K. H. Hsu, S. J. Twu, K. T. Chen, S. F. Tsai, J. R. Wang, S. R. Shih, et al. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929-935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsiung, G. D. 1994. Virus assay, neutralization test and antiviral assay, p. 46-55. In G. D. Hsiung, C. K. Y. Fong, and M. L. Landry (ed.), Hsiung's diagnostic virology, 4th ed. Yale University Press, New Haven, Conn.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, C. C., C. C. Liu, Y. C. Chang, C. Y. Chen, S. T. Wang, and T. F. Yeh. 1999. Neurologic complications in children with enterovirus 71 infection. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:936-942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo, R. L., S. H. Kung, Y. Y. Hsu, and W. T. Liu. 2002. Infection with enterovirus 71 or expression of its 2A protease induces apoptotic cell death. J. Gen. Virol. 83:1367-1376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12029152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M. L., T. A. Hsu, T. C. Chen, S. C. Chang, J. C. Lee, C. C. Chen, V. Stollar, and S. R. Shih. 2002. The 3C protease activity of enterovirus 71 induces human neural cell apoptosis. Virology 293:386-395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11886259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., L. Y. Chang, S. H. Hsia, Y. C. Huang, C. H. Chiu, C. Hsueh, S. R. Shih, C. C. Liu, and M. H. Wu. 2002. The 1998 enterovirus 71 outbreak in Taiwan: pathogenesis and management. Clin. Infect. Dis. 34(Suppl. 2):S52-S57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11938497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., L. Y. Chang, Y. C. Huang, K. H. Hsu, C. H. Chiu, and K. D. Yang. 2002. Different proinflammatory reactions in fatal and non-fatal enterovirus 71 infections: implications for early recognition and therapy. Acta Paediatr. 91:632-635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12162592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin, T. Y., S. H. Hsia, Y. C. Huang, C. T. Wu, and L. Y. Chang. 2003. Proinflammatory cytokine reactions in enterovirus 71 infections of the central nervous system. Clin. Infect. Dis. 36:269-274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12539066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C. C., H. W. Tseng, S. M. Wang, J. R. Wang, and I. J. Su. 2000. An outbreak of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan, 1998: epidemiologic and clinical manifestations. J. Clin. Virol. 17:23-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10814935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malnou, C. E., T. A. P&#xf6;yry, R. J. Jackson, and K. M. Kean. 2002. Poliovirus internal ribosome entry segment structure alterations that specifically affect function in neuronal cells: molecular genetic analysis. J. Virol. 76:10617-10626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC136602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12368304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMinn, P. C. 2002. An overview of the evolution of enterovirus 71 and its clinical and public health significance. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 26:91-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12007645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minor, P. D. 1992. The molecular biology of poliovaccines. J. Gen. Virol. 73:3065-3077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1335021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata, N., H. Shimizu, Y. Ami, Y. Tano, A. Harashima, Y. Suzaki, Y. Sato, T. Miyamura, T. Sata, and T. Iwasaki. 2002. Pyramidal and extrapyramidal involvement in experimental infection of cynomolgus monkeys with enterovirus 71. J. Med. Virol. 67:207-216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11992581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolan, M. A., M. E. Craig, M. M. Lahra, W. D. Rawlinson, P. C. Prager, G. D. Williams, A. M. Bye, and P. I. Andrews. 2003. Survival after pulmonary edema due to enterovirus 71 encephalitis. Neurology 60:1651-1656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12771257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochs, K., A. Zeller, L. Saleh, G. Bassili, Y. Song, A. Sonntag, and M. Niepmann. 2003. Impaired binding of standard initiation factors mediates poliovirus translation attenuation. J. Virol. 77:115-122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC140626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12477816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racaniello, V. R. 2001. Picornaviridae: the viruses and their replication, p. 685-722. In D. M. Knipe and P. M. Howley (ed.), Fields virology, 4th ed., vol. 1. Lippincott Williams and Wilkins, Philadelphia, Pa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed, L. J., and H. Muench. 1938. A simple method of estimating 50 per cent end-points. Am. J. Hyg. 27:493-497.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinehart, J. E., R. M. G&#xf3;mez, and R. P. Roos. 1997. Molecular determinants for virulence in coxsackievirus B1 infection. J. Virol. 71:3986-3991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC191550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9094675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson, S. R., and P. Sarnow. 2003. Enterovirus 71 contains a type I IRES element that functions when eukaryotic initiation factor eIF4G is cleaved. Virology 315:259-266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14592777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu, Z., N. M. Chapman, G. Hufnagel, S. Tracy, J. R. Romero, W. H. Barry, L. Zhao, K. Currey, and B. Shapiro. 1995. The cardiovirulent phenotype of coxsackievirus B3 is determined at a single site in the genomic 5&#x2032; nontranslated region. J. Virol. 69:4607-4618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC189260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7609025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., H. Y. Lei, K. J. Huang, J. M. Wu, J. R. Wang, C. K. Yu, I. J. Su, and C. C. Liu. 2003. Pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 brainstem encephalitis in pediatric patients: roles of cytokines and cellular immune activation in patients with pulmonary edema. J. Infect. Dis. 188:564-570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. M., C. C. Liu, H. W. Tseng, J. R. Wang, C. C. Huang, Y. J. Chen, Y. J. Yang, S. J. Lin, and T. F. Yeh. 1999. Clinical spectrum of enterovirus 71 infection in children in southern Taiwan, with an emphasis on neurological complications. Clin. Infect. Dis. 29:184-190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10433583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, J. J., I. J. Su, P. F. Chen, C. C. Liu, C. K. Yu, and J. R. Wang. 2001. Complete genome analysis of enterovirus 71 isolated from an outbreak in Taiwan and rapid identification of enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 by RT-PCR. J. Med. Virol. 65:331-339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11536241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, K. D., M. Y. Yang, C. C. Li, S. F. Lin, M. C. Chong, C. L. Wang, R. F. Chen, and T. Y. Lin. 2001. Altered cellular but not humoral reactions in children with complicated enterovirus 71 infections in Taiwan. J. Infect. Dis. 183:850-856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11237800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, C. K., C. C. Chen, C. L. Chen, J. R. Wang, C. C. Liu, J. J. Yan, and I. J. Su. 2000. Neutralizing antibody provided protection against enterovirus type 71 lethal challenge in neonatal mice. J. Biomed. Sci. 7:523-528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11060501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Z. M., P. J. He, D. Caueffield, M. Neumann, S. Specter, C. C. Baker, and M. J. Bankowski. 1995. Enterovirus 71 isolated from China is serologically similar to the prototype E71 BrCr strain but differs in the 5&#x2032;-noncoding region. J. Med. Virol. 47:161-167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8830120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>