<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">22116146</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-660X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>50</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Simultaneously typing nine serotypes of enteroviruses associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease by a GeXP analyzer-based multiplex reverse transcription-PCR assay.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>288</StartPage><EndPage>293</EndPage><MedlinePgn>288-93</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JCM.05828-11</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) is a contagious enteroviral disease occurring primarily in young children and caused by enterovirus 71 (EV71), coxsackievirus A16 (CVA16), and other serotypes of coxsackievirus and echovirus. In this study, a GeXP analyzer-based multiplex reverse transcription (RT)-PCR assay (GeXP assay) consisting of chimeric primer-based PCR amplification with fluorescent labeling and capillary electrophoresis separation was developed to simultaneously identify nine serotypes of enteroviruses associated with HFMD in China, including EV71, CVA16, CVA4, -5, -9, and -10, and CVB1, -3, and -5. The RNAs extracted from cell cultures of viral isolates and synthetic RNAs via in vitro transcription were used to analyze the specificity and sensitivity of the assay. The GeXP assay detected as little as 0.03 tissue culture infective dose (TCID(50)) of EV71 and CVA16, 10 copies of panenterovirus, EV71, CVA16, CVB1, and CVB5, and 100 copies of 10 (including panenterovirus) premixed RNA templates. A total of 180 stool specimens collected from HFMD patients and persons suspected of having HFMD were used to evaluate the clinical performance of this assay. In comparison with the results of conventional methods, the sensitivities of the GeXP assay for detection of panenterovirus, EV71, and CVA16 were 98.79% (163/165), 91.67% (44/48), and 91.67% (33/36), respectively, and the specificities were 80.00% (12/15), 98.48% (130/132), and 100% (144/144), respectively. The concordance of typing seven other serotypes of enteroviruses with the results of conventional methods was 92.59% (25/27). In conclusion, the GeXP assay is a rapid, cost-effective, and high-throughput method for typing nine serotypes of HFMD-associated enteroviruses.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Xiumei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Genetic Engineering and Molecular Virology, National Institute for Viral Disease Control and Prevention, Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Xiaomian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Banglao</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Mengjie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Miao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bai</LastName><ForeName>Ruyin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Wenbo</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Xuejun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D023362">Evaluation Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505564</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0095-1137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019411" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Laboratory Techniques</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="Y">classification</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D025202" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Diagnostic Techniques</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060885" MajorTopicYN="N">Multiplex Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020133" MajorTopicYN="N">Reverse Transcriptase Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012680" MajorTopicYN="N">Sensitivity and Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014773" MajorTopicYN="N">Virology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2012</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22116146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3264198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.05828-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JCM.05828-11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abubakar S, Chee HY, Shafee N, Chua KB, Lam SK. 1999. Molecular detection of enteroviruses from an outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease in Malaysia in 1997. Scand. J. Infect. Dis. 31:331&#x2013;335</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10528868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apisarnthanarak A, Kitphati R, Pongsuwann Y, Tacharoenmueng R, Mundy LM. 2005. Echovirus type 11: outbreak of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in a Thai hospital nursery. Clin. Infect. Dis. 41:1361&#x2013;1362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16206118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barriere H, Berger M, Billaudel S. 1976. Hand, foot and mouth disease. Sem. Hop. 52:2215&#x2013;2220 [In French.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">186899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell EJ, McCartney RA, Basquill D, Chaudhuri AK. 1986. Mu-antibody capture ELISA for the rapid diagnosis of enterovirus infections in patients with aseptic meningitis. J. Med. Virol. 19:213&#x2013;217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3016164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomqvist S, Klemola P, Kaijalainen S, Paananen A, Simonen ML, Vuorinen T, Roivainen M. 2010. Co-circulation of coxsackieviruses A6 and A10 in hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in Finland. J. Clin. Virol. 48:49&#x2013;54</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20189452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SP, et al. 2010. Comparison of clinical features between coxsackievirus A2 and enterovirus 71 during the enterovirus outbreak in Taiwan, 2008: a children's hospital experience. J. Microbiol. Immunol. Infect. 43:99&#x2013;104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20457425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, et al. 2006. Combining multiplex reverse transcription-PCR and a diagnostic microarray to detect and differentiate enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16. J. Clin. Microbiol. 44:2212&#x2013;2219</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1489440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16757623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frydenberg A, Starr M. 2003. Hand, foot and mouth disease. Aust. Fam. Physician 32:594&#x2013;595</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12973865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han JF, et al. 2011. Echovirus 30 in EV71-associated hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak, Guangxi, China. J. Clin. Virol. 50:348&#x2013;349</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21306942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YF, et al. 2011. Complete genome analysis of coxsackievirus A2, A4, A5, and A10 strains isolated from hand, foot, and mouth disease patients in China revealing frequent recombination of human enterovirus A. J. Clin. Microbiol. 49:2426&#x2013;2434</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3147834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21543560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YS, et al. 2002. PCR-RFLP based molecular typing of enteroviruses isolated from patients with aseptic meningitis in Korea. Arch. Virol. 147:1711&#x2013;1720</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12209311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, et al. 2005. Genetic characteristics of human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 circulating from 1999 to 2004 in Shenzhen, People's Republic of China. J. Clin. Microbiol. 43:3835&#x2013;3839</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1233905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin TL, et al. 2008. Rapid and highly sensitive coxsackievirus A indirect immunofluorescence assay typing kit for enterovirus serotyping. J. Clin. Microbiol. 46:785&#x2013;788</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2238120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18032614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindenbaum JE, Van Dyck PC, Allen RG. 1975. Hand, foot and mouth disease associated with coxsackievirus group B. Scand. J. Infect. Dis. 7:161&#x2013;163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1179172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagel MA, Gilden D, Shade T, Gao B, Cohrs RJ. 2009. Rapid and sensitive detection of 68 unique varicella zoster virus gene transcripts in five multiplex reverse transcription-polymerase chain reactions. J. Virol. Methods 157:62&#x2013;68</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2829835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19109999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nix WA, Oberste MS, Pallansch MA. 2006. Sensitive, seminested PCR amplification of VP1 sequences for direct identification of all enterovirus serotypes from original clinical specimens. J. Clin. Microbiol. 44:2698&#x2013;2704</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1594621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16891480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste MS, Maher K, Kilpatrick DR, Pallansch MA. 1999. Molecular evolution of the human enteroviruses: correlation of serotype with VP1 sequence and application to picornavirus classification. J. Virol. 73:1941&#x2013;1948</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9971773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberste MS, Nix WA, Maher K, Pallansch MA. 2003. Improved molecular identification of enteroviruses by RT-PCR and amplicon sequencing. J. Clin. Virol. 26:375&#x2013;377</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12637088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin M, et al. 2010. Detection of pandemic influenza A H1N1 virus by multiplex reverse transcription-PCR with a GeXP analyzer. J. Virol. Methods 168:255&#x2013;258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20452377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai AJ, Kamath RM, Gerald W, Fleisher M. 2009. Analytical validation of the GeXP analyzer and design of a workflow for cancer-biomarker discovery using multiplexed gene-expression profiling. Anal. Bioanal. Chem. 393:1505&#x2013;1511</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18958454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rigonan AS, Mann L, Chonmaitree T. 1998. Use of monoclonal antibodies to identify serotypes of enterovirus isolates. J. Clin. Microbiol. 36:1877&#x2013;1881</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9650928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo DH, Luchs A, Machado BC, Carmona RC, Timenetsky MC. 2006. Echovirus 4 associated to hand, foot and mouth disease. Rev. Inst. Med. Trop. Sao Paulo 48:197&#x2013;199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17119674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi HJ, et al. 2010. Biological characters of a coxsackievirus B3 variant strain isolated from a hand-foot-mouth disease patient with severe clinical symptoms. Zhonghua Yi Xue Za Zhi 90:1141&#x2013;1144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20646436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susi P, et al. 2009. Typing of enteroviruses by use of microwell oligonucleotide arrays. J. Clin. Microbiol. 47:1863&#x2013;1870</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2691091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19357207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabone T, Mather DE, Hayden MJ. 2009. Temperature switch PCR (TSP): robust assay design for reliable amplification and genotyping of SNPs. BMC Genomics 10:580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2795770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19958555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao XL, et al. 2009. Simultaneous detection of human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 in clinical specimens by multiplex real-time PCR with an internal amplification control. Arch. Virol. 154:121&#x2013;125</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19057836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao XL, et al. 2009. Simultaneous detection of enterovirus 70 and coxsackievirus A24 variant by multiplex real-time RT-PCR using an internal control. J. Virol. Methods 159:23&#x2013;28</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19442840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang CF, et al. 1992. Genotype-specific in vitro amplification of sequences of the wild type 3 polioviruses from Mexico and Guatemala. Virus Res. 24:277&#x2013;296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1329370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, et al. 2009. An outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with subgenotype C4 of human enterovirus 71 in Shandong, China. J. Clin. Virol. 44:262&#x2013;267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19269888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, et al. 2010. Molecular evidence of persistent epidemic and evolution of subgenotype B1 coxsackievirus A16-associated hand, foot, and mouth disease in China. J. Clin. Microbiol. 48:619&#x2013;622</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2815627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20018819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou F, et al. 2009. Identification of 20 common human enterovirus serotypes by use of a reverse transcription-PCR-based reverse line blot hybridization assay. J. Clin. Microbiol. 47:2737&#x2013;2743</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2738090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19571022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, et al. 2007. Molecular epidemiological analysis of echovirus 19 isolated from an outbreak associated with hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) in Shandong Province of China. Biomed. Environ. Sci. 20:321&#x2013;328</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17948768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>