<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32702909</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>99</Volume><Issue>29</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Viral shedding in patients with hand, foot and mouth disease induced by EV71, CA16, or CA6: A protocol for systematic review and meta analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e21258</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e21258</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e21258</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000021258</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD) has been an important public health concern worldwide, especially in the Asia-Pacific region. Unfortunately, the effect of current measures on preventing and controlling HFMD may be limited. Isolation of infectious sources is reported as an important way to prevent and control this disease. The isolation period is determined on the basis of duration of viral shedding in patients with HFMD. However, the results of previous researches on duration of viral shedding remain controversial. Here, we present a protocol of a systematic review and single-arm meta-analysis for assessing the duration of viral shedding in patients with HFMD induced by Enterovirus 71 (EV71), Coxsackievirus A16 (CA16), or Coxsackievirus A6 (CA6).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS AND ANALYSIS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comprehensive literature search will be performed in PubMed, EMBASE, the Cochrane library, Chinese National Knowledge Infrastructure (CNKI), Chinese Biomedical Literature Database (CBM), and Wanfang Database, covering the period from inception to May 1, 2019. Point estimate of positive rate with corresponding 95% confidence intervals (CIs) of EV71, CA16, or CA6 in HFMD patients' fecal or throat samples will be carried out using STATA 14.0. Subgroup analyses will be performed for mild cases, severe cases, and close contacts. Sensitive analysis will also be performed to evaluate the influences of individual studies on the final effect by exclusion of a few articles of poor quality. We will assess the risk of bias for the final studies included in our meta-analysis using previously available tools and the modified risk of bias tool.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The results of this systematic review and meta-analysis will be published in a peer-reviewed journal.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">To the best of our knowledge, this paper will be the first systematic review and meta-analysis for assessing the duration of viral shedding in patients with HFMD induced by EV71, CA16, or CA6. The conclusions drawn from this review will provide the scientific basis to formulate the isolation period of HFMD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ETHICS AND DISSEMINATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Ethical review is not required as this article is for a systematic review since there is no direct involvement of patients in the whole process. We will publish the results of this systematic review and meta-analysis of single-arm studies in a peer-reviewed journal.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REGISTRATION NUMBER" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Prospero CRD42020139999.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xianzhi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qiuxia</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Tongji Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zhenhua</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology Laboratory, Chengdu Municipal Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoxia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Yutong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luan</LastName><ForeName>Rongsheng</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Health Statistics, West China School of Public Health and West China Fourth Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004770" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006232" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="Y">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017201" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virus Shedding</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015201" MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-Analysis as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078202" MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic Review as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose. Provenance and peer review: Not commissioned; externally peer reviewed.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32702909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7373557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000021258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202007170-00104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xing W, Liao Q, Viboud C, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China, 2008-12: an epidemiological study. Lancet Infect Dis 2014;14:308&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24485991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Lewthwaite P, et al. Clinical features, diagnosis, and management of enterovirus 71. Lancet Neurol 2010;9:1097&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopalkrishna V, Patil PR, Patil GP, et al. Circulation of multiple enterovirus serotypes causing hand, foot and mouth disease in India. J Med Microbiol 2012;61(Pt 3):420&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22052995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puenpa J, Chieochansin T, Linsuwanon P, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease caused by coxsackievirus A6, Thailand, 2012. Emerg Infect Dis 2013;19:641&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3647428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23631943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, et al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N Engl J Med 1999;341:929&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Tan XJ, Wang HY, et al. An outbreak of hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with subgenotype C4 of human enterovirus 71 in Shandong, China. J Clin Virol 2009;44:262&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19269888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirand A, Henquell C, Archimbaud C, et al. Outbreak of hand, foot and mouth disease/herpangina associated with coxsackievirus A6 and A10 infections in 2010, France: a large citywide, prospective observational study. Clin Microbiol Infect 2012;18:E110&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22404077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> China Food and Drug Administration, CFDA Pizhun Changdao Bingdu 71xing Miehuoyimiao Shengchan Shangshi. Available at  http://www.sfda.gov.cn/WS01/CL0051/136853.html. Accessed March 12, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Liu L, Mo Z, et al. An inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. N Engl J Med 2014;370:829&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F, Xu W, Xia J, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in China. N Engl J Med 2014;370:818&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Li JX, Jin PF, et al. Enterovirus 71: a whole virion inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine. Expert Rev Vac 2016;15:803&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27206811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J. Trend of epidemics and variation of pathogens of hand, foot and mouth disease in China: a dynamic series analysis, 2008-2017. Chin J Epidemiol 2019;40:147&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30744263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J, Ma XJ, Wan JF, et al. Long persistence of EV71 specific nucleotides in respiratory and feces samples of the patients with Hand-Foot-Mouth Disease after recovery. BMC Infect Dis 2010;10:178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2895604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20565813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Lin C, Qu M, et al. Excretion of enterovirus 71 in persons infected with hand, foot and mouth disease. Virol J 2013;10:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3560202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23343115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation> Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention. Guide of Prevention and Control for Hand, Foot and Mouth Disease; 2009. Available at  http://www.chinacdc.cn/jkzt/crb/bl/szkb/jszl_2275/200906/t20090612_24707.html. Accessed March 20, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng S, Wei Y, Zhao SY, et al. Intestinal detoxification time of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in children with EV71 infection and the related factors. World J Pediatr 2015;11:380&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26454441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung PW, Huang YC, Chang LY, et al. Duration of enterovirus shedding in stool. J Microbiol Immunol Infect 2001;34:167&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11605806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao SY, Wang J, Teng S, et al. Observation on intestinal viral shedding time of hand, foot and mouth disease induced by coxsackievirus A6. Zhonghua er ke za zhi (Chin J Pediatr) 2017;55:369&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28482389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan H, Zhu YF, Qi X, et al. Analysis on the epidemiological and genetic characteristics of enterovirus type 71 and Coxsackie A16 virus infection in Jiangsu, China. Zhonghua liu xing bing xue za zhi = Zhonghua liuxingbingxue zazhi 2009;30:339&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19731523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng S, Zhao SY, Wei Y, et al. Observation on virus shedding periods of enterovirus-71 and coxsackievirus A 16 monitored by nucleic acids determination in stool samples of children with hand, foot and mouth disease. Zhonghua er ke za zhi (Chin J Pediatr) 2013;51:787&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24406235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Fu X, Jiang L, et al. Prevalence of enteroviruses in healthy populations and excretion of pathogens in patients with hand, foot, and mouth disease in a highly endemic area of southwest China. PLoS One 2017;12:e0181234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5509318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28704524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XW, Ni X, Qian SY, et al. Chinese guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of hand, foot and mouth disease (2018 edition). World J Pediatr 2018;14:437&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30280313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis JM, Grosskurth H, Changalucha J, et al. Systematic review and meta-analysis: prevalence of alcohol use among young people in eastern Africa. Trop Med Int Health 2014;19:476&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4065366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24479379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y, Wei Z, Wang W, et al. The incidence and distribution of surgical site infection in mainland China: a meta-analysis of 84 prospective observational studies. Sci Rep 2014;4:6783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4214160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25356832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoy D, Brooks P, Woolf A, et al. Assessing risk of bias in prevalence studies: modification of an existing tool and evidence of interrater agreement. J Clin Epidemiol 2012;65:934&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22742910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Ren L, Xiong Z, et al. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in the People's Republic of China in 2008. J Clin microbiol 2009;47:2351&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2708525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>