<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30697739</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4652</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>234</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cellular physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cell Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>miR-545 promoted enterovirus 71 replication via directly targeting phosphatase and tensin homolog and tumor necrosis factor receptor-associated factor 6.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15686</StartPage><EndPage>15697</EndPage><MedlinePgn>15686-15697</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcp.28222</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is a small, nonenveloped icosahedral RNA virus and is the predominant causative pathogen of hand-foot-and-mouth disease. Recently, microRNAs (miRNAs) are reported to play important roles in the pathogenesis of EV71 replication. This study investigated the role of miR-545 in the EV71 replication and explored the underlying molecular mechanisms. We showed that miR-545 was upregulated in the EV71-infected human embryonic kidney (HEK) 293 cells and rhabdomyosarcoma (RD) cells. Overexpression of miR-545 promoted the viral replication of EV71 and attenuated the inhibitory effects of EV71 on cell viability in HEK293 and RD cells; while knockdown of miR-545 significantly suppressed the EV71 replication in these two cell lines. Bioinformatics analysis and luciferase reporter assay showed that miR-545 directly targeted the 3'untranslated region of phosphatase and tensin homolog (PTEN) and tumor necrosis factor receptor-associated factor 6 (TRAF6) in HEK293 cells. Furthermore, miR-545 negatively regulated the messenger RNA (mRNA) and protein expression of PTEN and TRAF6. The mRNA and protein expression of PTEN and TRAF6 was also suppressed by EV71 infection, which was attenuated by miR-545 knockdown in HEK293 cells. Overexpression of PTEN and TRAF6 both suppressed the EV71 replication in HKE293 cells, and also attenuated the enhanced effects of miR-545 overexpression on the EV71 replication in HEK293 cells. Collectively, our study for the first time showed that miR-545 had an enhanced effect on the EV71 replication in HEK293 and RD cells. Further mechanistic results indicated that miR-545 promoted EV71 replication at least partly via targeting PTEN and TRAF6.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2019 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Basic Medicine College, Henan University of Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory of Chinese Medicine for Respiratory Disease, Henan University of Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Collaborative Innovation Center for Respiratory Disease Diagnosis and Treatment &amp; Chinese Medicine Development of Henan Province, Henan University of Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Long</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Basic Medicine College, Henan University of Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jiansheng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6485-2371</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henan Key Laboratory of Chinese Medicine for Respiratory Disease, Henan University of Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Collaborative Innovation Center for Respiratory Disease Diagnosis and Treatment &amp; Chinese Medicine Development of Henan Province, Henan University of Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Huaming</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Basic Medicine College, Henan University of Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mei</LastName><ForeName>Xue</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Basic Medicine College, Henan University of Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Lingyan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical College, Jianghan University, Wuhan, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Huijuan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Basic Medicine College, Henan University of Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Jianfeng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Basic Medicine College, Henan University of Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoli</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Basic Medicine College, Henan University of Chinese Medicine, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>BSJJ2015-08</GrantID><Agency>Doctoral Scientific Fund Project of Henan University of Chinese Medicine</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>00104341</GrantID><Agency>Henan Province Postdoctoral Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>16A310019</GrantID><Agency>Key Program of Henan Colleges and Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2017M622352</GrantID><Agency>China Postdoctoral Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>81803863</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cell Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0050222</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0021-9541</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PTEN</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TRAF6</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hand-foot-and-mouth disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">miR-545</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viral replication</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30697739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcp.28222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ayukekbong, J. A., &amp; Bergstr&#xf6;m, T. (2014). Polio will go, acute flaccid paralysis will stay. Lancet (London, England), 383(9936), 2209-2210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernhardt, K., Haar, J., Tsai, M. H., Poirey, R., Feederle, R., &amp; Delecluse, H. J. (2016). A viral microRNA cluster regulates the expression of PTEN, p27, and of a bcl-2 homolog. PLOS Pathogens, 12(1), e1005405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, J. H., Law, C., Hamblion, E., Fung, H., &amp; Rudge, J. (2017). Best practices to prevent transmission and control outbreaks of hand, foot, and mouth disease in childcare facilities: A systematic review. Hong Kong Medical Journal&#x2009;=&#x2009;Xianggang yi xue za zhi, 23(2), 177-190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, Z., Wang, Y., Bian, L., Liu, Q., &amp; Long, J. E. (2017). Enterovirus 71 antagonizes the antiviral activity of host STAT3 and IL-6R with partial dependence on virus-induced miR-124. The Journal of General Virology, 98(12), 3008-3025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changjun, L., Feizhou, H., Dezhen, P., Zhao, L., &amp; Xianhai, M. (2018). miR-545-3p/MT1M axis regulates cell proliferation, invasion and migration in hepatocellular carcinoma. Biomedicine &amp; Pharmacotherapy&#x2009;=&#x2009;Biomedecine &amp; Pharmacotherapie, 108, 347-354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, L., Guo, X., Qi, Y., Qi, X., Ge, Y., Shi, Z., &#x2026; Wang, H. (2010). Identification of microRNAs involved in the host response to enterovirus 71 infection by a deep sequencing approach. Journal of Biomedicine &amp; Biotechnology, 2010, 425939.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, L., Qi, Y., Li, H., Ge, Y., Zhao, K., Qi, X., &#x2026; Wang, H. (2011). Serum microRNA expression profile distinguishes enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus 16 infections in patients with hand-foot-and-mouth disease. PLOS One, 6(11), e27071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, B., Wang, Z., Zhang, X., Feng, S., Wang, G., He, J., &amp; Zhang, B. (2014). MicroRNA-545 suppresses cell proliferation by targeting cyclin D1 and CDK4 in lung cancer cells. PLOS One, 9(2), e88022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, N., Zhou, Z., Li, Y., Zhao, L., Xue, Z., Lu, R., &amp; Jia, K. (2017). Enterovirus 71-induced has-miR-21 contributes to evasion of host immune system by targeting MyD88 and IRAK1. Virus Research, 237, 27-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo, D. G. W., Ang, R. X., Alonso, S., Chow, V. T. K., Quak, S. H., &amp; Poh, C. L. (2008). Identification of immunodominant VP1 linear epitope of enterovirus 71 (EV71) using synthetic peptides for detecting human anti-EV71 IgG antibodies in Western blots. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 14(3), 286-288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, Y., Zhang, L., Zhang, F., Tang, T., Zhou, Q., Feng, C., &#x2026; Wu, Z. (2017). Exosome-mediated miR-146a transfer suppresses type I interferon response and facilitates EV71 infection. PLOS Pathogens, 13(9), e1006611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Q. Q., Ren, S., Xia, Z. C., Cheng, Z. K., Peng, N. F., &amp; Zhu, Y. (2018). Fibronectin facilitates enterovirus 71 infection by mediating viral entry. Journal of Virology, 92(9), e02251-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, B. C., Yang, P. C., &amp; Yu, S. L. (2016). MicroRNA and pathogenesis of enterovirus infection. Viruses, 8(1), 11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, C., Wang, Y., Li, A., Zhang, J., Xue, F., &amp; Zhu, L. (2018). Overexpressed circ_0067934 acts as an oncogene to facilitate cervical cancer progression via the miR-545/EIF3C axis. Journal of Cellular Physiology. Advance online publication. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcp.2760</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, X., &amp; Lu, S. (2017). MicroR-545 mediates colorectal cancer cells proliferation through up-regulating epidermal growth factor receptor expression in HOTAIR long non-coding RNA dependent. Molecular and Cellular Biochemistry, 431(1-2), 45-54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, Y., Zhang, R., Wu, W., &amp; Duan, G. (2018). Antiviral and inflammatory cellular signaling associated with enterovirus 71 infection. Viruses, 10(4), 155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong, G., Zhang, J., Zhang, S., Shan, C., Ye, L., &amp; Zhang, X. (2011). Upregulated microRNA-29a by hepatitis B virus X protein enhances hepatoma cell migration by targeting PTEN in cell culture model. PLOS One, 6(5), e19518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konno, H., Yamamoto, T., Yamazaki, K., Gohda, J., Akiyama, T., Semba, K., &#x2026; Inoue, J. (2009). TRAF6 establishes innate immune responses by activating NF-kappaB and IRF7 upon sensing cytosolic viral RNA and DNA. PLOS One, 4(5), e5674.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, K. Y. (2016). Enterovirus 71 infection and neurological complications. Korean Journal of Pediatrics, 59(10), 395-401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, A., Qiu, M., Zhou, H., Wang, T., &amp; Guo, W. (2017). PTEN, insulin resistance and cancer. Current Pharmaceutical Design, 23(25), 3667-3676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Xie, J., Xu, X., Wang, J., Ao, F., Wan, Y., &amp; Zhu, Y. (2013). MicroRNA-548 down-regulates host antiviral response via direct targeting of IFN-lambda1. Protein &amp; Cell, 4(2), 130-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H., Tamashiro, S., Baritaki, S., Penichet, M., Yu, Y., Chen, H., &#x2026; Bonavida, B. (2012). TRAF6 activation in multiple myeloma: A potential therapeutic target. Clinical Lymphoma, Myeloma &amp; Leukemia, 12(3), 155-163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, M., Zhao, J., Wu, Q., Xiao, K., Li, S., Zhu, H., &#x2026; Zuo, C. (2018). miRNA-545 negatively regulates the oncogenic activity of EMS1 in gastric cancer. Cancer Medicine, 7(6), 2452-2462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao, Q., Wang, Y., Bian, L., Xu, M., &amp; Liang, Z. (2016). EV71 vaccine, a new tool to control outbreaks of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD). Expert Review of Vaccines, 15(5), 599-606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni, W. J., &amp; Leng, X. M. (2016). miRNA-dependent activation of mRNA translation. MicroRNA (Shariqah, United Arab Emirates), 5(2), 83-86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega-Molina, A., &amp; Serrano, M. (2013). PTEN in cancer, metabolism, and aging. Trends in Endocrinology and Metabolism: TEM, 24(4), 184-189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathinayake, P., Hsu, A., &amp; Wark, P. (2015). Innate immunity and immune evasion by enterovirus 71. Viruses, 7(12), 6613-6630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ventarola, D., Bordone, L., &amp; Silverberg, N. (2015). Update on hand-foot-and-mouth disease. Clinics in Dermatology, 33(3), 340-346.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B., Zhang, H., Zhu, M., Luo, Z., &amp; Peng, Y. (2012). MEK1-ERKs signal cascade is required for the replication of Enterovirus 71 (EV71). Antiviral Research, 93(1), 110-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B., Zhang, X., &amp; Zhao, Z. (2013). Validation-based insertional mutagenesis for identification of Nup214 as a host factor for EV71 replication in RD cells. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 437(3), 452-456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R. Y. L., Weng, K. F., Huang, Y. C., &amp; Chen, C. J. (2016). Elevated expression of circulating miR876-5p is a specific response to severe EV71 infections. Scientific Reports, 6, 24149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, W., Song, J., Wang, J., Li, Y., Deng, H., Li, M., &#x2026; Jia, X. (2017). Cost-effectiveness of a national enterovirus 71 vaccination program in China. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases, 11(9), e0005899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, J., Shen, L., Chen, J., Xu, H., &amp; Mao, L. (2015). The role of microRNAs in enteroviral infections. The Brazilian Journal of Infectious Diseases: An Official Publication of the Brazilian Society of Infectious Diseases, 19(5), 510-516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Q., Li, Z., Mellor, P., Zhou, Y., Anderson, D. H., &amp; Liu, Q. (2017). The role of PTEN - HCV core interaction in hepatitis C virus replication. Scientific Reports, 7(1), 3695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, C., He, X., Zheng, Z., Zhang, Z., Wei, C., Guan, K., &#x2026; Zhong, H. (2014). Downregulation of microRNA miR-526a by enterovirus inhibits RIG-I-dependent innate immune response. Journal of Virology, 88(19), 11356-11368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, C., Peng, Y., Zhang, Q., Xu, X.-P., Kong, X. -M., &amp; Shi, W.-F. (2018). USP4 positively regulates RLR-induced NF-&#x3ba;B activation by targeting TRAF6 for K48-linked deubiquitination and inhibits enterovirus 71 replication. Scientific Reports, 8(1), 13418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, E. J., Shin, Y. J., Kim, J. H., Kim, T. G., &amp; Chang, S. Y. (2017). Enterovirus 71 infection and vaccines. Clinical and Experimental Vaccine Research, 6(1), 4-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, Y., Li, Z., Li, P., Song, N., Li, B., Lin, W., &amp; Liu, S. (2017). Antiviral activity of a polysaccharide from Laminaria japonica against enterovirus 71. Biomedicine &amp; pharmacotherapy&#x2009;=&#x2009;Biomedecine &amp; pharmacotherapie, 96, 256-262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L., Chen, X., Shi, Y., Zhou, B., Du, C., Liu, Y., &#x2026; Liu, W. (2014). miR-27a suppresses EV71 replication by directly targeting EGFR. Virus Genes, 49(3), 373-382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. K., Lin, T., Zhu, S. L., Xianyu, L. Z., &amp; Lu, S. Y. (2015). Global quantitative proteomic analysis of human glioma cells profiled host protein expression in response to enterovirus type 71 infection. Proteomics, 15(22), 3784-3796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Q., Xiong, Y., Xu, J., Chen, S., Li, P., Huang, Y., &#x2026; Wang, B. (2018). Host microRNA hsa-miR-494-3p promotes EV71 replication by directly targeting PTEN. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology, 8, 278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, C., Zheng, Z., Sun, J., Zhang, Y., Wei, C., Ke, X., &#x2026; Wang, H. (2017). miR-16-5p mediates a positive feedback loop in EV71-induced apoptosis and suppresses virus replication. Scientific Reports, 7(1), 16422.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>