<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32818043</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1757-4749</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gut pathogens</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gut Pathog</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Molecular characteristics of the VP1 region of enterovirus 71 strains in China.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>38</StartPage><MedlinePgn>38</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">38</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13099-020-00377-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Enterovirus 71 (EV71) is the most commonly implicated causative agent of severe outbreaks of paediatric hand, foot, and mouth disease (HFMD).VP1 protein, a capsid protein of EV71, is responsible for the genotype of the virus and is essential for vaccine development and effectiveness. However, the genotypes of EV71 isolates in China are still not completely clear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The VP1 gene sequences of 3712 EV71 virus strains from China, excluding repetitive sequences and 30 known EV71 genotypes as reference strains, between 1986 and 2019 were obtained from GenBank. Phylogenetic tree, amino acid homology, genetic variation and genotype analyses of the EV71VP1 protein were performed with MEGA 6.0 software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The amino acid identity&#xa0;was found to be 88.33%-100% among the 3712 EV71 strains, 93.47%-100% compared with vaccine strain H07, and 93.04%-100% compared with vaccine strains FY7VP5 or FY-23&#xa0;K-B. Since 2000, the prevalent strains of EV71 were mainly of the C4 genotype. Among these, the C4a subgenotype was predominant, followed by the C4b subgenotype; other subgenotypes appeared sporadically between 2005 and 2018 in mainland China. The B4 genotype was the main genotype in Taiwan, and the epidemic strains were constantly changing. Some amino acid variations in VP1 of EV71 occurred with high frequencies, including A289T (20.99%), H22Q (16.49%), A293S (15.95%), S283T (15.11%), V249I (7.76%), N31D (7.25%), and E98K (6.65%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The C4 genotype of EV71 in China matches the vaccine and should effectively control EV71. However, the efficacy of the vaccine is partially affected by the continuous change in epidemic strains in Taiwan. These results suggest that the genetic characteristics of the EV71-VP1 region should be continuously monitored, which is critical for epidemic control and vaccine design to prevent EV71 infection in children.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2020.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Haiyan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Laboratory, Shaoxing Second Hospital, Shaoxing, 312000 Zhejiang China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.477955.d</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, Huzhou Central Hospital, Huzhou, 313003 Zhejiang China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.413679.e</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0517 0981</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Dawei</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3840-1486</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Blood Transfusion, The First Affiliated Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, 310003 Zhejiang China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.452661.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 1803 6319</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Clinical In Vitro Diagnostic Techniques of Zhejiang Province, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Gut Pathog</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101474263</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1757-4749</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus 71</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular characteristics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">VP1</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32818043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13099-020-00377-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Ren L, Xiong Z, et al. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in the People&#x2019;s Republic of China in 2008. J ClinMicrobiol. 2009;47(7):2351&#x2013;2352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2708525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Feng Z, Yang Y, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China: patterns of spread and transmissibility. Epidemiology. 2011;22(6):781&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3246273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21968769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing W, Liao Q, Viboud C, et al. Hand, foot, and mouth disease in China, 2008&#x2013;12: an epidemiological study. Lancet Infect Dis. 2014;14(4):308&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24485991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, et al. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect Dis. 2010;10(11):778&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Z, Su R, Wang W, et al. EV71 infection induces neurodegeneration via activating TLR7 signaling and IL-6 production. PLoSPathog. 2019;15(11):e1008142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6932824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31730654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antona D, Kossorotoff M, Schuffenecker I, et al. Severe paediatric conditions linked with EV-A71 and EV-D68, France, May to October 2016. Euro Surveill. 2016;21(46):30402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5144948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27918268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi MH, Wong SC, Lewthwaite P, et al. Clinical features, diagnosis, and management of enterovirus 71. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9(11):1097&#x2013;1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kok CC. Therapeutic and prevention strategies against human enterovirus 71 infection. World J Virol. 2015;4(2):78&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4419123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25964873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, et al. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N Engl J Med. 1999;341(13):929&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shih SR, Ho MS, Lin KH, et al. Genetic analysis of enterovirus 71 isolated from fatal and non-fatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease during an epidemic in Taiwan, 1998. Virus Res. 2000;68(2):127&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10958984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan KP, Goh KT, Chong CY, et al. Epidemic hand, foot and mouth disease caused by human enterovirus 71, Singapore. Emerg Infect Dis. 2003;9(1):78&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2873753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrero LJ, Lee CS, Hurrelbrink RJ, et al. Molecular epidemiology of enterovirus 71 in peninsular Malaysia, 1997&#x2013;2000. Arch Virol. 2003;148(7):1369&#x2013;1385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12827466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan D, van der Sanden S, Zeng H, et al. Population dynamics and genetic diversity of C4 strains of human enterovirus 71 in Mainland China, 1998&#x2013;2010. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(9):e44386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3440427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22984501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, Zhu S, Guo X, et al. Retrospective seroepidemiology indicated that human enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 circulated wildly in central and southern China before large-scale outbreaks from 2008. Virol J. 2010;7:300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2989968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21050463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JR, Tuan YC, Tsai HP, et al. Change of major genotype of enterovirus 71 in outbreaks of hand-foot-and-mouth disease in Taiwan between 1998 and 2000. J Clin Microbiol. 2002;40(1):10&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC120096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Chen W, Chang H, et al. Genetic analysis of the VP1 region of enterovirus 71 reveals the emergence of genotype A in central China in 2008. Virus Genes. 2010;41(1):1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20306124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sanden S, van der Avoort H, Lemey P, et al. Evolutionary trajectory of the VP1 gene of human enterovirus 71 genogroup B and C viruses. J GenVirol. 2010;91(Pt 8):1949&#x2013;1958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20375223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhu Z, Yang W, et al. An emerging recombinant human enterovirus 71 responsible for the 2008 outbreak of hand foot and mouth disease in Fuyang city of China. Virol J. 2010;7:94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20459851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KY. Enterovirus 71 infection and neurological complications. Korean J Pediatr. 2016;59(10):395&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5099286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27826325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan X, Huang X, Zhu S, et al. The persistent circulation of enterovirus 71 in People&#x2019;s Republic of China: causing emerging nationwide epidemics since 2008. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(9):e25662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3181342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21980521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao Z, Wang H, Xu A. Identification of a C2 subgenogroup strain of enterovirus 71 in a retrospective study in Shandong Province, China, from 1990 to 2010. J Clin Microbiol. 2012;50:1823&#x2013;1824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3347126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22357503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao Z, Wang H, Li Y, et al. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus associated with aseptic meningitis in Shandong Province, China, 2006&#x2013;2012. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(2):e89766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3931826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24587020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yip CC, Lau SK, Woo PC, et al. Human enterovirus 71 epidemics: what&#x2019;s next? EmergHealth Threats J. 2013;6:19780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24119538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chia MY, Chiang PS, Chung WY, et al. Epidemiology of enterovirus 71 infections in Taiwan. PediatrNeonatol. 2014;55(4):243&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24120535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SW, Cheng HL, Hsieh HY, et al. Mutations in the non-structural protein region contribute to intra-genotypic evolution of enterovirus 71. J Biomed Sci. 2014;21(1):33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4021180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24766641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong P, Liu CC, Chow YH, et al. Review of enterovirus 71 vaccines. Clin Infect Dis. 2015;60(5):797&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25352588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou AH, Liu CC, Chang JY, et al. Formalin-inactivated EV71 vaccine candidate induced cross-neutralizing antibody against subgenotypes B1, B4, B5 and C4A in adult volunteers. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(11):e79783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3836818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24278177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bible JM, Iturriza-Gomara M, Megson B, et al. Molecular epidemiology of human enterovirus 71 in the United Kingdom from 1998 to 2006. J Clin Mocrobiol. 2008;46(10):3192&#x2013;3200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2566106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18650362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SC, Hsu YW, Wang HC, et al. Appearance of intratypic recombination of enterovirus 71 in Taiwan from 2002 to 2005. Virus Res. 2008;131(2):250&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18036697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Sanden S, van Eek J, Martin DP, et al. Detection of recombination breakpoints in the genomes of human enterovirus 71 strains isolated in the Netherlands in epidemic and non-epidemic years, 1963&#x2013;2010. Infect Genet Evol. 2011;11(5):886&#x2013;894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21352955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McWilliam LE, Cabrerizo M, Cardosa J, et al. The association of recombination events in the founding and emergence of subgenogroup evolutionary lineages of human enterovirus 71. J Virol. 2012;86(5):2676&#x2013;2685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3302253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22205739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen S, Ma D, Lin Y, et al. Complete genome characterization of the 2017 dengue outbreak in Xishuangbanna, a Border City of China, Burma and Laos. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2018;8:148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5951998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29868504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Tan X, Cui A, et al. Complete genome analysis of the C4 subgenotype strains of enterovirus 71: predominant recombination C4 viruses persistently circulating in China for 14 years. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(2):e56341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3575343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23441179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Zhou Y, Cheng Y, et al. Effectiveness of EV-A71 vaccination in prevention of paediatric hand, foot, and mouth disease associated with EV-A71 virus infection requiring hospitalisation in Henan, China, 2017&#x2013;18: a test-negative case-control study. Lancet Child Adolesc Health. 2019;3(10):697&#x2013;704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8713082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31375313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng Y, Chen W, Huang M, et al. Epidemiology and etiology of hand, foot, and mouth disease in Fujian province, 2008&#x2013;2014. Arch Virol. 2017;162(2):535&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27796546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Fu C, Wu S, et al. A novel finding for enterovirus virulence from the capsid protein VP1 of EV71 circulating in mainland China. Virus Genes. 2014;48(2):260&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24442718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JS, Zhao N, Pan H, et al. Patterns of polymorphism and divergence in the VP1 gene of enterovirus 71 circulating in the Asia-Pacific region between 1994 and 2013. J Virol Methods. 2013;193(2):713&#x2013;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23933074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H, Cao Y, Su W, et al. Enterovirus A71 VP1 variation A289T decreases the central nervous system infectivity via attenuation of interactions between VP1 and vimentin in vitro and in vivo. Viruses. 2019;11(5):467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6563288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31121933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura Y, Lee H, Hafenstein S, et al. Enterovirus 71 binding to PSGL-1 on leukocytes: VP1-145 acts as a molecular switch to control receptor interaction. PLoS Pathog. 2013;9(7):e1003511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3723564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23935488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TC, Liu SC, Huang PN, et al. Antiviral activity of pyridyl imidazolidinones against enterovirus 71 variants. J Biome Sci. 2008;15(3):291&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18196474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le TV, Nguyen V, Nguyen QH, et al. Molecular epidemiology analysis of enterovirus 71 strains isolated in Dak Lak, Vietnam, 2011&#x2013;2016. J Med Virol. 2019;91(1):56&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30132913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, Wu X, Huang K, et al. The variations of VP1 protein might be associated with nervous system symptoms caused by enterovirus 71 infection. BMC Infect Dis. 2014;14:243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4101859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24886383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobayashi K, Sudaka Y, Takashino A, et al. Amino acid variation at VP1-145 of Enterovirus 71 determines attachment receptor usage and neurovirulence in human scavenger receptor B2 transgenic mice. J Virol. 2018;92(15):e00681&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6052303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29848584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Victorio CB, Xu Y, Ng Q, et al. Cooperative effect of the VP1 amino acids 98E, 145A and 169F in the productive infection of mouse cell lines by enterovirus 71 (BS strain) Emerg Microbes Infect. 2016;5(6):e60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4932649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27329847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang CH, Liang CT, Jiang ST, et al. A novel murine model expressing a chimeric mSCARB2/hSCARB2 receptor is highly susceptible to oral infection with clinical isolates of Enterovirus 71. J Virol. 2019;93(11):e00183&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6532076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30894476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Song Z, Zou J, et al. An infectious clone of enterovirus 71(EV71) that is capable of infecting neonatal immune competent mice without adaptive mutations. Emerg Microbes Infect. 2020;9(1):427&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7048218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32079505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu FC, Meng FY, Li JX, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunology of an inactivated alum-adjuvant enterovirus 71 vaccine in children in China: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2013;381(9882):2024&#x2013;2032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23726161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao QY, Wang Y, Bian L, et al. EV71 vaccine, a new tool to control outbreaks of hand, foot and mouth disease (HFMD) Expert Rev Vaccines. 2016;15(5):599&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26732723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang B, Liu F, Liao Q, et al. Epidemiology of hand, foot and mouth disease in China, 2008 to 2015 prior to theintroduction of EV-A71 vaccine. Euro Surveill. 2017;22(50):16&#x2013;00824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5743100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29258646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Liu L, Mo Z, et al. An inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in healthy children. N Engl J Med. 2014;370(9):829&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F, Xu W, Xia J, et al. Efficacy, safety, and immunogenicity of an enterovirus 71 vaccine in China. N Engl J Med. 2014;370(9):818&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu YM, Wang X, Wang JZ, et al. Immunogenicity, safety, and lot consistency of a novel inactivated enterovirus 71 vaccine in Chinese children aged 6 to 59 months. Clin Vaccine Immunol. 2013;20(12):1805&#x2013;1811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3889509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24108780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bessaud M, Razafindratsimandresy R, Nougairede A, et al. Molecular comparison and evolutionary analyses of VP1 nucleotide sequences of new African human enterovirus 71 isolates reveal a wide genetic diversity. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(3):e90624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3944068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24598878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>