<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2024//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_240101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23616646</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5514</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>87</Volume><Issue>13</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of virology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Virol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Conformational plasticity of the 2A proteinase from enterovirus 71.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7348</StartPage><EndPage>7356</EndPage><MedlinePgn>7348-56</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/JVI.03541-12</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The 2A proteinase (2A(pro)) is an enterovirally encoded cysteine protease that plays essential roles in both the processing of viral precursor polyprotein and the hijacking of host cell translation and other processes in the virus life cycle. Crystallographic studies of 2A(pro) from enterovirus 71 (EV71) and its interaction with the substrate are reported here. EV71 2A(pro) was comprised of an N-terminal domain of a four-stranded antiparallel &#x3b2; sheet and a C-terminal domain of a six-stranded antiparallel &#x3b2; barrel with a tightly bound zinc atom. Unlike in other 2A(pro) structures, there is an open cleft across the surface of the protein in an open conformation. As demonstrated by the crystallographic studies and modeling of the complex structure, the open cleft could be fitted with the substrate. On comparison 2A(pro) of EV71 to those of the human rhinovirus 2 and coxsackievirus B4, the open conformation could be closed with a hinge motion in the bII2 and cII &#x3b2; strands. This was supported by molecular dynamic simulation. The structural variation among different 2A(pro) structures indicates a conformational flexibility in the substrate-binding cleft. The open structure provides an accessible framework for the design and development of therapeutics against the viral target.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Qixu</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Cellular Stress Biology, School of Life Sciences, Xiamen University, Xiamen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yameen</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Weihua</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Zhenting</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yaozong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Xuanjia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Yaxian</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Caiming</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Tianwei</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Virol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0113724</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-538X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.22.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003546">Cysteine Endopeptidases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000595" MajorTopicYN="N">Amino Acid Sequence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018360" MajorTopicYN="N">Crystallography, X-Ray</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003546" MajorTopicYN="N">Cysteine Endopeptidases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="Y">chemistry</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D029821" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterovirus A, Human</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000201" MajorTopicYN="Y">enzymology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004926" MajorTopicYN="N">Escherichia coli</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D031541" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluorescence Resonance Energy Transfer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005822" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Vectors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008958" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Molecular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008969" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Sequence Data</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016296" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutagenesis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016133" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011487" MajorTopicYN="Y">Protein Conformation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016415" MajorTopicYN="N">Sequence Alignment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23616646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3700279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.03541-12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JVI.03541-12</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Racaniello VR. 2006. Picornavirdae: the viruses and their replication, p 795 In Knipe DM, Howley PM. (ed), Fields virology, 5th ed Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins Publishers, Hagerstown, MD</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallansch M, Roos R. 2006. Enteroviruses: polioviruses, coxsackieviruses, echoviruses, and newer enteroviruses, p 839 In Knipe DM, Howley PM. (ed), Fields virology, 5th ed Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins Publishers, Hagerstown, MD</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bible JM, Pantelidis P, Chan PK, Tong CY. 2007. Genetic evolution of enterovirus 71: epidemiological and pathological implications. Rev. Med. Virol. 17:371&#x2013;379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17487831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon T, Lewthwaite P, Perera D, Cardosa MJ, McMinn P, Ooi MH. 2010. Virology, epidemiology, pathogenesis, and control of enterovirus 71. Lancet Infect. Dis. 10:778&#x2013;790</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20961813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng KF, Chen LL, Huang PN, Shih SR. 2010. Neural pathogenesis of enterovirus 71 infection. Microbes Infect. 12:505&#x2013;510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20348010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deibel R, Gross LL, Collins DN. 1975. Isolation of a new enterovirus (38506). Proc. Soc. Exp. Biol. Med. 148:203&#x2013;207</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">165523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M, Chen ER, Hsu KH, Twu SJ, Chen KT, Tsai SF, Wang JR, Shih SR. 1999. An epidemic of enterovirus 71 infection in Taiwan. Taiwan Enterovirus Epidemic Working Group. N. Engl. J. Med. 341:929&#x2013;935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown BA, Oberste MS, Alexander JP, Jr, Kennett ML, Pallansch MA. 1999. Molecular epidemiology and evolution of enterovirus 71 strains isolated from 1970 to 1998. J. Virol. 73:9969&#x2013;9975</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC113047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10559310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention and Office of the World Health Organization in China
2008, posting date
Report on the hand, foot and mouth disease outbreak in Fuyang City, Anhui Province and the prevention and control in China. http://www2.wpro.who.int/NR/rdonlyres/591D6A7B-FB15-4E94-A1E9-1D3381847D60/0/HFMDCCDC20080515ENG.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koroleva GA, Gracheva LA, Voroshilova MK. 1978. Isolation of type 71 enterovirus from patients with a poliomyelitis-like disease during an outbreak in Bulgaria. Voprosy Virusolog ii:611&#x2013;618</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">216154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melnick JL. 1984. Enterovirus type 71 infections: a varied clinical pattern sometimes mimicking paralytic poliomyelitis. Rev. Infect. Dis. 6(Suppl 2):S387&#x2013;S390</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6330839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy G, Takatsy S, Kukan E, Mihaly I, Domok I. 1982. Virological diagnosis of enterovirus type 71 infections: experiences gained during an epidemic of acute CNS diseases in Hungary in 1978. Arch. Virol. 71:217&#x2013;227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6285858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuda GM, Chang WK, Yeung CY, Tang PS. 1987. Monoplegia caused by enterovirus 71: an outbreak in Hong Kong. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J. 6:206&#x2013;208</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3562141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu H, Utama A, Yoshii K, Yoshida H, Yoneyama T, Sinniah M, Yusof MA, Okuno Y, Okabe N, Shih SR, Chen HY, Wang GR, Kao CL, Chang KS, Miyamura T, Hagiwara A. 1999. Enterovirus 71 from fatal and nonfatal cases of hand, foot and mouth disease epidemics in Malaysia, Japan and Taiwan in 1997-1998. Jpn. J. Infect. Dis. 52:12&#x2013;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10808253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shindarov LM, Chumakov MP, Voroshilova MK, Bojinov S, Vasilenko SM, Iordanov I, Kirov ID, Kamenov E, Leshchinskaya EV, Mitov G, Robinson IA, Sivchev S, Staikov S. 1979. Epidemiological, clinical, and pathomorphological characteristics of epidemic poliomyelitis-like disease caused by enterovirus 71. J. Hyg. Epidemiol. Microbiol. Immunol. 23:284&#x2013;295</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">231067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Ren L, Xiong Z, Li J, Xiao Y, Zhao R, He Y, Bu G, Zhou S, Wang J, Qi J. 2009. Enterovirus 71 outbreak in the People's Republic of China in 2008. J. Clin. Microbiol. 47:2351&#x2013;2352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2708525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho M. 2000. Enterovirus 71: the virus, its infections and outbreaks. J. Microbiol. Immunol. Infect. 33:205&#x2013;216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11269363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gradi A, Svitkin YV, Imataka H, Sonenberg N. 1998. Proteolysis of human eukaryotic translation initiation factor eIF4GII, but not eIF4GI, coincides with the shutoff of host protein synthesis after poliovirus infection. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 95:11089&#x2013;11094</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC21600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9736694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd RE, Grubman MJ, Ehrenfeld E. 1988. Relationship of p220 cleavage during picornavirus infection to 2A proteinase sequencing. J. Virol. 62:4216&#x2013;4223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC253854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2845133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badorff C, Lee GH, Lamphear BJ, Martone ME, Campbell KP, Rhoads RE, Knowlton KU. 1999. Enteroviral protease 2A cleaves dystrophin: evidence of cytoskeletal disruption in an acquired cardiomyopathy. Nat. Med. 5:320&#x2013;326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10086389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustin KE, Sarnow P. 2001. Effects of poliovirus infection on nucleo-cytoplasmic trafficking and nuclear pore complex composition. EMBO J. 20:240&#x2013;249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC140206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11226174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustin KE, Sarnow P. 2002. Inhibition of nuclear import and alteration of nuclear pore complex composition by rhinovirus. J. Virol. 76:8787&#x2013;8796</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC136411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12163599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park N, Katikaneni P, Skern T, Gustin KE. 2008. Differential targeting of nuclear pore complex proteins in poliovirus-infected cells. J. Virol. 82:1647&#x2013;1655</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2258732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18045934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almstead LL, Sarnow P. 2007. Inhibition of U snRNP assembly by a virus-encoded proteinase. Genes Dev. 21:1086&#x2013;1097</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1855234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17473171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCoy AJ, Grosse-Kunstleve RW, Adams PD, Winn MD, Storoni LC, Read RJ. 2007. Phaser crystallographic software. J. Appl. Crystallogr. 40:658&#x2013;674</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2483472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19461840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emsley P, Lohkamp B, Scott WG, Cowtan K. 2010. Features and development of Coot. Acta Crystallogr. D Biol. Crystallogr. 66:486&#x2013;501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2852313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20383002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunger AT. 2007. Version 1.2 of the Crystallography and NMR system. Nat. Protoc. 2:2728&#x2013;2733</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18007608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunger AT, Adams PD, Clore GM, DeLano WL, Gros P, Grosse-Kunstleve RW, Jiang JS, Kuszewski J, Nilges M, Pannu NS, Read RJ, Rice LM, Simonson T, Warren GL. 1998. Crystallography &amp; NMR system: a new software suite for macromolecular structure determination. Acta Crystallogr. D Biol. Crystallogr. 54:905&#x2013;921</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9757107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murshudov GN, Skubak P, Lebedev AA, Pannu NS, Steiner RA, Nicholls RA, Winn MD, Long F, Vagin AA. 2011. REFMAC5 for the refinement of macromolecular crystal structures. Acta Crystallogr. D Biol. Crystallogr. 67:355&#x2013;367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3069751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21460454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murshudov GN, Vagin AA, Dodson EJ. 1997. Refinement of macromolecular structures by the maximum-likelihood method. Acta Crystallogr. D Biol. Crystallogr. 53:240&#x2013;255</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15299926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matayoshi ED, Wang GT, Krafft GA, Erickson J. 1990. Novel fluorogenic substrates for assaying retroviral proteases by resonance energy transfer. Science 247:954&#x2013;958</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2106161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen JF, Cherney MM, Liebig HD, Skern T, Kuechler E, James MN. 1999. The structure of the 2A proteinase from a common cold virus: a proteinase responsible for the shut-off of host-cell protein synthesis. EMBO J. 18:5463&#x2013;5475</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1171615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10523291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baxter NJ, Roetzer A, Liebig HD, Sedelnikova SE, Hounslow AM, Skern T, Waltho JP. 2006. Structure and dynamics of coxsackievirus B4 2A proteinase, an enyzme involved in the etiology of heart disease. J. Virol. 80:1451&#x2013;1462</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1346940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16415022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krissinel E, Henrick K. 2004. Secondary-structure matching (SSM), a new tool for fast protein structure alignment in three dimensions. Acta Crystallogr. D Biol. Crystallogr. 60:2256&#x2013;2268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15572779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schechter I, Berger A. 1967. On the size of the active site in proteases. I. Papain. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 27:157&#x2013;162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6035483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C, Cai Q, Chen C, Li N, Peng X, Cai Y, Yin K, Chen X, Wang X, Zhang R, Liu L, Chen S, Li J, Lin T. 2013. Crystal structure of an enterovirus 3C proteinase (strain: E2004104-TW-CDC) and its complex with rupintrivir. Acta Crystallogr. D Biol. Crystallogr. 69:866&#x2013;871</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23633597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birtley JR, Knox SR, Jaulent AM, Brick P, Leatherbarrow RJ, Curry S. 2005. Crystal structure of foot-and-mouth disease virus 3C protease. New insights into catalytic mechanism and cleavage specificity. J. Biol. Chem. 280:11520&#x2013;11527</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15654079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeney TR, Roque-Rosell N, Birtley JR, Leatherbarrow RJ, Curry S. 2007. Structural and mutagenic analysis of foot-and-mouth disease virus 3C protease reveals the role of the beta-ribbon in proteolysis. J. Virol. 81:115&#x2013;124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1797255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17065215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zunszain PA, Knox SR, Sweeney TR, Yang J, Roque-Rosell N, Belsham GJ, Leatherbarrow RJ, Curry S. 2010. Insights into cleavage specificity from the crystal structure of foot-and-mouth disease virus 3C protease complexed with a peptide substrate. J. Mol. Biol. 395:375&#x2013;389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7099390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19883658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommergruber W, Ahorn H, Zophel A, Maurer-Fogy I, Fessl F, Schnorrenberg G, Liebig HD, Blaas D, Kuechler E, Skern T. 1992. Cleavage specificity on synthetic peptide substrates of human rhinovirus 2 proteinase 2A. J. Biol. Chem. 267:22639&#x2013;22644</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1331062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu G, Qi J, Chen Z, Xu X, Gao F, Lin D, Qian W, Liu H, Jiang H, Yan J, Gao GF. 2011. Enterovirus 71 and coxsackievirus A16 3C proteases: binding to rupintrivir and their substrates and anti-hand, foot, and mouth disease virus drug design. J. Virol. 85:10319&#x2013;10331</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21795339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>